<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 35—</num>
<heading>COORDINATION OF FEDERAL INFORMATION POLICY</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>FEDERAL INFORMATION POLICY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3501.</num>
<heading> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes of this subchapter are to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> minimize the paperwork burden for individuals, small businesses, educational and nonprofit institutions, Federal contractors, State, local and tribal governments, and other persons resulting from the collection of information by or for the Federal Government;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> ensure the greatest possible public benefit from and maximize the utility of information created, collected, maintained, used, shared and disseminated by or for the Federal Government;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> coordinate, integrate, and to the extent practicable and appropriate, make uniform Federal information resources management policies and practices as a means to improve the productivity, efficiency, and effectiveness of Government programs, including the reduction of information collection burdens on the public and the improvement of service delivery to the public;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> improve the quality and use of Federal information to strengthen decisionmaking, accountability, and openness in Government and society;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> minimize the cost to the Federal Government of the creation, collection, maintenance, use, dissemination, and disposition of information;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> strengthen the partnership between the Federal Government and State, local, and tribal governments by minimizing the burden and maximizing the utility of information created, collected, maintained, used, disseminated, and retained by or for the Federal Government;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> provide for the dissemination of public information on a timely basis, on equitable terms, and in a manner that promotes the utility of the information to the public and makes effective use of information technology;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<chapeau> ensure that the creation, collection, maintenance, use, dissemination, and disposition of information by or for the Federal Government is consistent with applicable laws, including laws relating to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> privacy and confidentiality, including <ref>section 552a of title 5</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> security of information, including <ref>section 11332 of title 40</ref> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002032">1</ref> ; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> access to information, including <ref>section 552 of title 5</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> ensure the integrity, quality, and utility of the Federal statistical system;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> ensure that information technology is acquired, used, and managed to improve performance of agency missions, including the reduction of information collection burdens on the public; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> improve the responsibility and accountability of the Office of Management and Budget and all other Federal agencies to Congress and to the public for implementing the information collection review process, information resources management, and related policies and guidelines established under this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–13, § 2</ref>, <date date="1995-05-22">May 22, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 163</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title X, § 1064(b)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–275; <ref>Pub. L. 107–217, § 3</ref>(<i>l</i>)(3), <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1301</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3502.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this subchapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the term “agency” means any executive department, military department, Government corporation, Government controlled corporation, or other establishment in the executive branch of the Government (including the Executive Office of the President), or any independent regulatory agency, but does not include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Government Accountability Office;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Federal Election Commission;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the governments of the District of Columbia and of the territories and possessions of the United States, and their various subdivisions; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Government-owned contractor-operated facilities, including laboratories engaged in national defense research and production activities;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the term “burden” means time, effort, or financial resources expended by persons to generate, maintain, or provide information to or for a Federal agency, including the resources expended for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> reviewing instructions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> acquiring, installing, and utilizing technology and systems;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> adjusting the existing ways to comply with any previously applicable instructions and requirements;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> searching data sources;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> completing and reviewing the collection of information; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> transmitting, or otherwise disclosing the information;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> the term “collection of information”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> means the obtaining, causing to be obtained, soliciting, or requiring the disclosure to third parties or the public, of facts or opinions by or for an agency, regardless of form or format, calling for either—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> answers to identical questions posed to, or identical reporting or recordkeeping requirements imposed on, ten or more persons, other than agencies, instrumentalities, or employees of the United States; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> answers to questions posed to agencies, instrumentalities, or employees of the United States which are to be used for general statistical purposes; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> shall not include a collection of information described under section 3518(c)(1);</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the term “Director” means the Director of the Office of Management and Budget;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the term “independent regulatory agency” means the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Commodity Futures Trading Commission, the Consumer Product Safety Commission, the Federal Communications Commission, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, the Federal Housing Finance Agency, the Federal Maritime Commission, the Federal Trade Commission, the Interstate Commerce Commission, the Mine Enforcement Safety and Health Review Commission, the National Labor Relations Board, the Nuclear Regulatory Commission, the Occupational Safety and Health Review Commission, the Postal Regulatory Commission, the Securities and Exchange Commission, the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, the Office of Financial Research, Office of the Comptroller of the Currency, and any other similar agency designated by statute as a Federal independent regulatory agency or commission;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the term “information resources” means information and related resources, such as personnel, equipment, funds, and information technology;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the term “information resources management” means the process of managing information resources to accomplish agency missions and to improve agency performance, including through the reduction of information collection burdens on the public;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> the term “information system” means a discrete set of information resources organized for the collection, processing, maintenance, use, sharing, dissemination, or disposition of information;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> the term “information technology” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 11101 of title 40</ref> but does not include national security systems as defined in <ref>section 11103 of title 40</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> the term “person” means an individual, partnership, association, corporation, business trust, or legal representative, an organized group of individuals, a State, territorial, tribal, or local government or branch thereof, or a political subdivision of a State, territory, tribal, or local government or a branch of a political subdivision;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> the term “practical utility” means the ability of an agency to use information, particularly the capability to process such information in a timely and useful fashion;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> the term “public information” means any information, regardless of form or format, that an agency discloses, disseminates, or makes available to the public;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<chapeau> the term “recordkeeping requirement” means a requirement imposed by or for an agency on persons to maintain specified records, including a requirement to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> retain such records;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> notify third parties, the Federal Government, or the public of the existence of such records;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> disclose such records to third parties, the Federal Government, or the public; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> report to third parties, the Federal Government, or the public regarding such records;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> the term “penalty” includes the imposition by an agency or court of a fine or other punishment; a judgment for monetary damages or equitable relief; or the revocation, suspension, reduction, or denial of a license, privilege, right, grant, or benefit;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<content> the term “comprehensive data inventory” means the inventory created under section 3511(a), but does not include any underlying data asset listed on the inventory;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(16)</num>
<content> the term “data” means recorded information, regardless of form or the media on which the data is recorded;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(17)</num>
<content> the term “data asset” means a collection of data elements or data sets that may be grouped together;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(18)</num>
<content> the term “machine-readable”, when used with respect to data, means data in a format that can be easily processed by a computer without human intervention while ensuring no semantic meaning is lost;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(19)</num>
<content> the term “metadata” means structural or descriptive information about data such as content, format, source, rights, accuracy, provenance, frequency, periodicity, granularity, publisher or responsible party, contact information, method of collection, and other descriptions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(20)</num>
<chapeau> the term “open Government data asset” means a public data asset that is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> machine-readable;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> available (or could be made available) in an open format;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> not encumbered by restrictions, other than intellectual property rights, including under titles 17 and 35, that would impede the use or reuse of such asset; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> based on an underlying open standard that is maintained by a standards organization;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(21)</num>
<chapeau> the term “open license” means a legal guarantee that a data asset is made available—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> at no cost to the public; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> with no restrictions on copying, publishing, distributing, transmitting, citing, or adapting such asset;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(22)</num>
<content> the term “public data asset” means a data asset, or part thereof, maintained by the Federal Government that has been, or may be, released to the public, including any data asset, or part thereof, subject to disclosure under <ref>section 552 of title 5</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(23)</num>
<content> the term “statistical laws” means subchapter III of this chapter and other laws pertaining to the protection of information collected for statistical purposes as designated by the Director.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–13, § 2</ref>, <date date="1995-05-22">May 22, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 164</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. E, title LVI, § 5605(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 700</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title X, § 1073(h)(5)(A)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1907</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title X, § 1064(b)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–275; <ref>Pub. L. 107–217, § 3</ref>(<i>l</i>)(4), <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1301</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–271, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-07-07">July 7, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 814</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–435, title VI, § 604(e)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3242</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–289, div. A, title II, § 1216(e)</ref>, <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2792</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–203, title III, § 315</ref>, title X, § 1100D(a), <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 1524</ref>, 2111; <ref>Pub. L. 115–435, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-01-14">Jan. 14, 2019</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5534</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3503.</num>
<heading> Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> There is established in the Office of Management and Budget an office to be known as the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> There shall be at the head of the Office an Administrator who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. The Director shall delegate to the Administrator the authority to administer all functions under this subchapter, except that any such delegation shall not relieve the Director of responsibility for the administration of such functions. The Administrator shall serve as principal adviser to the Director on Federal information resources management policy.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–13, § 2</ref>, <date date="1995-05-22">May 22, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 166</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title X, § 1064(b)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–275.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3504.</num>
<heading> Authority and functions of Director</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Director shall oversee the use of information resources to improve the efficiency and effectiveness of governmental operations to serve agency missions, including burden reduction and service delivery to the public. In performing such oversight, the Director shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> develop, coordinate and oversee the implementation of Federal information resources management policies, principles, standards, and guidelines; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> provide direction and oversee—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the review and approval of the collection of information and the reduction of the information collection burden;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> agency dissemination of and public access to information;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> statistical activities;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> records management activities;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> privacy, confidentiality, security, disclosure, and sharing of information; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> the acquisition and use of information technology, including alternative information technologies that provide for electronic submission, maintenance, or disclosure of information as a substitute for paper and for the use and acceptance of electronic signatures.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The authority of the Director under this subchapter shall be exercised consistent with applicable law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> With respect to general information resources management policy, the Director shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> develop and oversee the implementation of uniform information resources management policies, principles, standards, and guidelines;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> foster greater sharing, dissemination, and access to public information, including through—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the use of comprehensive data inventories and the Federal data catalogue under section 3511; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the development and utilization of common standards for information collection, storage, processing and communication, including standards for security, interconnectivity and interoperability;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> initiate and review proposals for changes in legislation, regulations, and agency procedures to improve information resources management practices;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> oversee the development and implementation of best practices in information resources management, including training;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> oversee agency integration of program and management functions with information resources management functions; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> issue guidance for agencies to implement section 3506(b)(6) in a manner that takes into account—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> risks and restrictions related to the disclosure of personally identifiable information, including the risk that an individual data asset in isolation does not pose a privacy or confidentiality risk but when combined with other available information may pose such a risk;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> security considerations, including the risk that information in an individual data asset in isolation does not pose a security risk but when combined with other available information may pose such a risk;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the cost and benefits to the public of converting a data asset into a machine-readable format that is accessible and useful to the public;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> whether the application of the requirements described in such section to a data asset could result in legal liability;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<chapeau> a determination of whether a data asset—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is subject to intellectual property rights, including rights under titles 17 and 35;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> contains confidential business information, that could be withheld under <ref>section 552(b)(4) of title 5</ref>; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> is otherwise restricted by contract or other binding, written agreement;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the requirement that a data asset be disclosed, if it would otherwise be made available under <ref>section 552 of title 5</ref> (commonly known as the “Freedom of Information Act”); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> any other considerations that the Director determines to be relevant.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> With respect to the collection of information and the control of paperwork, the Director shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> review and approve proposed agency collections of information;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> coordinate the review of the collection of information associated with Federal procurement and acquisition by the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs with the Office of Federal Procurement Policy, with particular emphasis on applying information technology to improve the efficiency and effectiveness of Federal procurement, acquisition and payment, and to reduce information collection burdens on the public;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> minimize the Federal information collection burden, with particular emphasis on those individuals and entities most adversely affected;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> maximize the practical utility of and public benefit from information collected by or for the Federal Government;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> establish and oversee standards and guidelines by which agencies are to estimate the burden to comply with a proposed collection of information; <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002033">1</ref></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> publish in the Federal Register and make available on the Internet (in consultation with the Small Business Administration) on an annual basis a list of the compliance assistance resources available to small businesses, with the first such publication occurring not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of the Small Business Paperwork Relief Act of 2002.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> With respect to information dissemination, the Director shall develop and oversee the implementation of policies, principles, standards, and guidelines to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> apply to Federal agency dissemination of public information, regardless of the form or format in which such information is disseminated; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> promote public access to public information and fulfill the purposes of this subchapter, including through the effective use of information technology.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<chapeau> With respect to statistical policy and coordination, the Director shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> coordinate the activities of the Federal statistical system to ensure—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the efficiency and effectiveness of the system; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the integrity, objectivity, impartiality, utility, and confidentiality of information collected for statistical purposes;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> ensure that budget proposals of agencies are consistent with system-wide priorities for maintaining and improving the quality of Federal statistics and prepare an annual report on statistical program funding;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> develop and oversee the implementation of Governmentwide policies, principles, standards, and guidelines concerning—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> statistical collection procedures and methods;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> statistical data classification;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> statistical information presentation and dissemination;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> timely release of statistical data; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> such statistical data sources as may be required for the administration of Federal programs;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> evaluate statistical program performance and agency compliance with Governmentwide policies, principles, standards and guidelines;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> promote the sharing of information collected for statistical purposes consistent with privacy rights and confidentiality pledges;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> coordinate the participation of the United States in international statistical activities, including the development of comparable statistics;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> appoint a chief statistician who is a trained and experienced professional statistician to carry out the functions described under this subsection;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<chapeau> establish an Interagency Council on Statistical Policy to advise and assist the Director in carrying out the functions under this subsection that shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> be headed by the chief statistician; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> consist of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the heads of the major statistical programs; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> representatives of other statistical agencies under rotating membership;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<chapeau> provide opportunities for training in statistical policy functions to employees of the Federal Government under which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> each trainee shall be selected at the discretion of the Director based on agency requests and shall serve under the chief statistician for at least 6 months and not more than 1 year; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> all costs of the training shall be paid by the agency requesting training; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<chapeau> ensure that any change to the standards of core-based statistical area (as defined in section 4 of the MAPS Act of 2021) delineations pursuant to this subsection shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> be accompanied by a public report that explains—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the scientific basis, criteria, and methodology for such change to existing standards, including clear quantitative thresholds for determining any future statistical re-delineations; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the opinions of domestic and international experts in statistics and demographics, including government experts at the Bureau of the Census and other relevant agencies, who were consulted regarding such change to existing standards;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> not be influenced by any non-statistical considerations such as impact on program administration or service delivery; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> not propagate automatically for any non-statistical use by any domestic assistance program (as defined in section 4 of the MAPS Act of 2021).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<chapeau> With respect to records management, the Director shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provide advice and assistance to the Archivist of the United States and the Administrator of General Services to promote coordination in the administration of chapters 29, 31, and 33 of this title with the information resources management policies, principles, standards, and guidelines established under this subchapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> review compliance by agencies with—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the requirements of chapters 29, 31, and 33 of this title; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> regulations promulgated by the Archivist of the United States and the Administrator of General Services; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> oversee the application of records management policies, principles, standards, and guidelines, including requirements for archiving information maintained in electronic format, in the planning and design of information systems.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<chapeau> With respect to privacy and security, the Director shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> develop and oversee the implementation of policies, principles, standards, and guidelines on privacy, confidentiality, security, disclosure and sharing of information collected or maintained by or for agencies; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> oversee and coordinate compliance with sections 552 and 552a of title 5, sections 20 and 21 of the National Institute of Standards and Technology Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 278g–3</ref> and 278g–4), <ref>section 11331 of title 40</ref> and subchapter II of this chapter, and related information management laws.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<chapeau> With respect to Federal information technology, the Director shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> in consultation with the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology and the Administrator of General Services—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> develop and oversee the implementation of policies, principles, standards, and guidelines for information technology functions and activities of the Federal Government, including periodic evaluations of major information systems; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> oversee the development and implementation of standards under <ref>section 11331 of title 40</ref>; <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002034">2</ref></content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> monitor the effectiveness of, and compliance with, directives issued under subtitle III of title 40 and directives issued under section 322 <sup>2</sup> of title 40;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> coordinate the development and review by the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs of policy associated with Federal procurement and acquisition of information technology with the Office of Federal Procurement Policy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> ensure, through the review of agency budget proposals, information resources management plans and other means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> agency integration of information resources management plans, program plans and budgets for acquisition and use of information technology; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the efficiency and effectiveness of inter-agency information technology initiatives to improve agency performance and the accomplishment of agency missions; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> promote the use of information technology by the Federal Government to improve the productivity, efficiency, and effectiveness of Federal programs, including through dissemination of public information and the reduction of information collection burdens on the public.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–13, § 2</ref>, <date date="1995-05-22">May 22, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 167</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. E, title LI, § 5131(e)(1)</ref>, title LVI, § 5605(b), (c), <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 688</ref>, 700; <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title X, § 1073(h)(5)(B)</ref>, (C), <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1907</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. C, title XVII, § 1702</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–749</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title X, § 1064(b)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–275; <ref>Pub. L. 107–198, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-06-28">June 28, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 729</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–217, § 3</ref>(<i>l</i>)(5), <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1301</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–296, title X, § 1005(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2272</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–347, title III, § 305(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-17">Dec. 17, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2960</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–435, title II, § 202(b)</ref>, (d)(2)(B), <date date="2019-01-14">Jan. 14, 2019</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5535</ref>, 5541; <ref>Pub. L. 117–219, § 7</ref>, <date date="2022-12-05">Dec. 5, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2274</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3505.</num>
<heading> Assignment of tasks and deadlines</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> In carrying out the functions under this subchapter, the Director shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> in consultation with agency heads, set an annual Governmentwide goal for the reduction of information collection burdens by at least 10 percent during each of fiscal years 1996 and 1997 and 5 percent during each of fiscal years 1998, 1999, 2000, and 2001, and set annual agency goals to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> reduce information collection burdens imposed on the public that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> represent the maximum practicable opportunity in each agency; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> are consistent with improving agency management of the process for the review of collections of information established under section 3506(c); and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> improve information resources management in ways that increase the productivity, efficiency and effectiveness of Federal programs, including service delivery to the public;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> with selected agencies and non-Federal entities on a voluntary basis, conduct pilot projects to test alternative policies, practices, regulations, and procedures to fulfill the purposes of this subchapter, particularly with regard to minimizing the Federal information collection burden; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> in consultation with the Administrator of General Services, the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology, the Archivist of the United States, and the Director of the Office of Personnel Management, develop and maintain a Governmentwide strategic plan for information resources management, that shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a description of the objectives and the means by which the Federal Government shall apply information resources to improve agency and program performance;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> plans for—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> reducing information burdens on the public, including reducing such burdens through the elimination of duplication and meeting shared data needs with shared resources;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> enhancing public access to and dissemination of, information, using electronic and other formats; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> meeting the information technology needs of the Federal Government in accordance with the purposes of this subchapter; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a description of progress in applying information resources management to improve agency performance and the accomplishment of missions.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> For purposes of any pilot project conducted under subsection (a)(2), the Director may, after consultation with the agency head, waive the application of any administrative directive issued by an agency with which the project is conducted, including any directive requiring a collection of information, after giving timely notice to the public and the Congress regarding the need for such waiver.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002035">1</ref> <inline class="small-caps">Inventory of Major Information Systems</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The head of each agency shall develop and maintain an inventory of major information systems (including major national security systems) operated by or under the control of such agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The identification of information systems in an inventory under this subsection shall include an identification of the interfaces between each such system and all other systems or networks, including those not operated by or under the control of the agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> Such inventory shall be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> updated at least annually;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> made available to the Comptroller General; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> used to support information resources management, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> preparation and maintenance of the inventory of information resources under section 3506(b)(4);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> information technology planning, budgeting, acquisition, and management under section 3506(h), subtitle III of title 40, and related laws and guidance;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> monitoring, testing, and evaluation of information security controls under subchapter II;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> preparation of the index of major information systems required under <ref>section 552(g) of title 5</ref>, United States Code; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> preparation of information system inventories required for records management under chapters 21, 29, 31, and 33.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Director shall issue guidance for and oversee the implementation of the requirements of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading> <sup>1</sup> <inline class="small-caps">Inventory of Information Systems</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The head of each agency shall develop and maintain an inventory of the information systems (including national security systems) operated by or under the control of such agency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The identification of information systems in an inventory under this subsection shall include an identification of the interfaces between each such system and all other systems or networks, including those not operated by or under the control of the agency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> Such inventory shall be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> updated at least annually;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> made available to the Comptroller General; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> used to support information resources management, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> preparation and maintenance of the inventory of information resources under section 3506(b)(4);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> information technology planning, budgeting, acquisition, and management under section 3506(h), subtitle III of title 40, and related laws and guidance;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> monitoring, testing, and evaluation of information security controls under subchapter II;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> preparation of the index of major information systems required under <ref>section 552(g) of title 5</ref>, United States Code; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> preparation of information system inventories required for records management under chapters 21, 29, 31, and 33.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Director shall issue guidance for and oversee the implementation of the requirements of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–13, § 2</ref>, <date date="1995-05-22">May 22, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 170</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title X, § 1064(b)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–275; <ref>Pub. L. 107–296, title X, § 1005(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2272</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–347, title III, § 305(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-17">Dec. 17, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2961</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3506.</num>
<heading> Federal agency responsibilities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The head of each agency shall be responsible for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> carrying out the agency’s information resources management activities to improve agency productivity, efficiency, and effectiveness; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> complying with the requirements of this subchapter and related policies established by the Director.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Except as provided under subparagraph (B), the head of each agency shall designate a Chief Information Officer who shall report directly to such agency head to carry out the responsibilities of the agency under this subchapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Department of Defense and the Secretary of each military department may each designate Chief Information Officers who shall report directly to such Secretary to carry out the responsibilities of the department under this subchapter. If more than one Chief Information Officer is designated, the respective duties of the Chief Information Officers shall be clearly delineated.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Chief Information Officer designated under paragraph (2) shall head an office responsible for ensuring agency compliance with and prompt, efficient, and effective implementation of the information policies and information resources management responsibilities established under this subchapter, including the reduction of information collection burdens on the public. The Chief Information Officer and employees of such office shall be selected with special attention to the professional qualifications required to administer the functions described under this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Each agency program official shall be responsible and accountable for information resources assigned to and supporting the programs under such official. In consultation with the Chief Information Officer designated under paragraph (2) and the agency Chief Financial Officer (or comparable official), each agency program official shall define program information needs and develop strategies, systems, and capabilities to meet those needs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> With respect to general information resources management, each agency shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> manage information resources to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> reduce information collection burdens on the public;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> increase program efficiency and effectiveness; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> improve the integrity, quality, and utility of information to all users within and outside the agency, including capabilities for ensuring dissemination of public information, public access to government information, and protections for privacy and security;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> in accordance with guidance by the Director, develop and maintain a strategic information resources management plan that, to the extent practicable—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> describes how information resources management activities help accomplish agency missions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> includes an open data plan for data that does not concern monetary policy that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> requires the agency to develop processes and procedures that—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> require data collection mechanisms created on or after the date of the enactment of the OPEN Government Data Act to be available in an open format; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> facilitate collaboration with non-Government entities (including businesses), researchers, and the public for the purpose of understanding how data users value and use government data;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> identifies and implements methods for collecting and analyzing digital information on data asset usage by users within and outside of the agency, including designating a point of contact within the agency to assist the public and to respond to quality issues, usability issues, recommendations for improvements, and complaints about adherence to open data requirements within a reasonable period of time;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> develops and implements a process to evaluate and improve the timeliness, completeness, consistency, accuracy, usefulness, and availability of open Government data assets;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> includes requirements for meeting the goals of the agency open data plan, including the acquisition of technology, provision of training for employees, and the implementation of procurement standards, in accordance with existing law, regulation, and policy, that allow for the acquisition of innovative solutions from public and private sectors;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> identifies as priority data assets any data asset for which disclosure would be in the public interest and establishes a plan to evaluate each priority data asset for disclosure on the Federal Data Catalogue under section 3511 and for a determination under <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002036">1</ref> 3511(a)(2)(A)(iii)(I)(bb), including an accounting of which priority data assets have not yet been evaluated; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> requires the agency to comply with requirements under section 3511, including any standards established by the Director under such section, when disclosing a data asset pursuant to such section; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> is updated annually and made publicly available on the website of the agency not later than 5 days after each such update;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> develop and maintain an ongoing process to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> ensure that information resources management operations and decisions are integrated with organizational planning, budget, financial management, human resources management, and program decisions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in cooperation with the agency Chief Financial Officer (or comparable official), develop a full and accurate accounting of information technology expenditures, related expenses, and results; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> establish goals for improving information resources management’s contribution to program productivity, efficiency, and effectiveness, methods for measuring progress towards those goals, and clear roles and responsibilities for achieving those goals;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> in consultation with the Director, the Administrator of General Services, and the Archivist of the United States, maintain a current and complete inventory of the agency’s information resources, including directories necessary to fulfill the requirements of section 3511 of this subchapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> in consultation with the Director and the Director of the Office of Personnel Management, conduct formal training programs to educate agency program and management officials about information resources management; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> in accordance with guidance by the Director—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> make each data asset of the agency available in an open format; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> make each public data asset of the agency available—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> as an open Government data asset; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> under an open license.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> With respect to the collection of information and the control of paperwork, each agency shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> establish a process within the office headed by the Chief Information Officer designated under subsection (a), that is sufficiently independent of program responsibility to evaluate fairly whether proposed collections of information should be approved under this subchapter, to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> review each collection of information before submission to the Director for review under this subchapter, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an evaluation of the need for the collection of information;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a functional description of the information to be collected;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a plan for the collection of the information;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> a specific, objectively supported estimate of burden;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> a test of the collection of information through a pilot program, if appropriate; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> a plan for the efficient and effective management and use of the information to be collected, including necessary resources;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> ensure that each information collection—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is inventoried, displays a control number and, if appropriate, an expiration date;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> indicates the collection is in accordance with the clearance requirements of section 3507; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> informs the person receiving the collection of information of—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the reasons the information is being collected;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the way such information is to be used;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> an estimate, to the extent practicable, of the burden of the collection;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> whether responses to the collection of information are voluntary, required to obtain a benefit, or mandatory; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(V)</num>
<content> the fact that an agency may not conduct or sponsor, and a person is not required to respond to, a collection of information unless it displays a valid control number; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> assess the information collection burden of proposed legislation affecting the agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> except as provided under subparagraph (B) or section 3507(j), provide 60-day notice in the Federal Register, and otherwise consult with members of the public and affected agencies concerning each proposed collection of information, to solicit comment to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> evaluate whether the proposed collection of information is necessary for the proper performance of the functions of the agency, including whether the information shall have practical utility;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> evaluate the accuracy of the agency’s estimate of the burden of the proposed collection of information;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> enhance the quality, utility, and clarity of the information to be collected; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> minimize the burden of the collection of information on those who are to respond, including through the use of automated collection techniques or other forms of information technology; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for any proposed collection of information contained in a proposed rule (to be reviewed by the Director under section 3507(d)), provide notice and comment through the notice of proposed rulemaking for the proposed rule and such notice shall have the same purposes specified under subparagraph (A)(i) through (iv);</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> certify (and provide a record supporting such certification, including public comments received by the agency) that each collection of information submitted to the Director for review under section 3507—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is necessary for the proper performance of the functions of the agency, including that the information has practical utility;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is not unnecessarily duplicative of information otherwise reasonably accessible to the agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> reduces to the extent practicable and appropriate the burden on persons who shall provide information to or for the agency, including with respect to small entities, as defined under <ref>section 601(6) of title 5</ref>, the use of such techniques as—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> establishing differing compliance or reporting requirements or timetables that take into account the resources available to those who are to respond;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the clarification, consolidation, or simplification of compliance and reporting requirements; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> an exemption from coverage of the collection of information, or any part thereof;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> is written using plain, coherent, and unambiguous terminology and is understandable to those who are to respond;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> is to be implemented in ways consistent and compatible, to the maximum extent practicable, with the existing reporting and recordkeeping practices of those who are to respond;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> indicates for each recordkeeping requirement the length of time persons are required to maintain the records specified;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> contains the statement required under paragraph (1)(B)(iii);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> has been developed by an office that has planned and allocated resources for the efficient and effective management and use of the information to be collected, including the processing of the information in a manner which shall enhance, where appropriate, the utility of the information to agencies and the public;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> uses effective and efficient statistical survey methodology appropriate to the purpose for which the information is to be collected; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> to the maximum extent practicable, uses information technology to reduce burden and improve data quality, agency efficiency and responsiveness to the public; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> in addition to the requirements of this chapter regarding the reduction of information collection burdens for small business concerns (as defined in section 3 of the Small Business Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 632</ref>)), make efforts to further reduce the information collection burden for small business concerns with fewer than 25 employees.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> With respect to information dissemination, each agency shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> ensure that the public has timely and equitable access to the agency’s public information, including ensuring such access through—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> encouraging a diversity of public and private sources for information based on government public information;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in cases in which the agency provides public information maintained in electronic format, providing timely and equitable access to the underlying data (in whole or in part); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> agency dissemination of public information in an efficient, effective, and economical manner;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> regularly solicit and consider public input on the agency’s information dissemination activities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> provide adequate notice when initiating, substantially modifying, or terminating significant information dissemination products;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> not, except where specifically authorized by statute—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> establish an exclusive, restricted, or other distribution arrangement that interferes with timely and equitable availability of public information to the public;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> restrict or regulate the use, resale, or redissemination of public information by the public;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> charge fees or royalties for resale or redissemination of public information; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> establish user fees for public information that exceed the cost of dissemination;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> ensure that any public data asset of the agency is machine-readable; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> engage the public in using public data assets of the agency and encourage collaboration by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> publishing on the website of the agency, on a regular basis (not less than annually), information on the usage of such assets by non-Government users;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> providing the public with the opportunity to request specific data assets to be prioritized for disclosure and to provide suggestions for the development of agency criteria with respect to prioritizing data assets for disclosure;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> assisting the public in expanding the use of public data assets; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> hosting challenges, competitions, events, or other initiatives designed to create additional value from public data assets of the agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<chapeau> With respect to statistical policy and coordination, each agency shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> ensure the relevance, accuracy, timeliness, integrity, and objectivity of information collected or created for statistical purposes;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> inform respondents fully and accurately about the sponsors, purposes, and uses of statistical surveys and studies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> protect respondents’ privacy and ensure that disclosure policies fully honor pledges of confidentiality;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> observe Federal standards and practices for data collection, analysis, documentation, sharing, and dissemination of information;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> ensure the timely publication of the results of statistical surveys and studies, including information about the quality and limitations of the surveys and studies; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> make data available to statistical agencies and readily accessible to the public.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> With respect to records management, each agency shall implement and enforce applicable policies and procedures, including requirements for archiving information maintained in electronic format, particularly in the planning, design and operation of information systems.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<chapeau> With respect to privacy and security, each agency shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> implement and enforce applicable policies, procedures, standards, and guidelines on privacy, confidentiality, security, disclosure and sharing of information collected or maintained by or for the agency; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> assume responsibility and accountability for compliance with and coordinated management of sections 552 and 552a of title 5, subchapter II of this chapter, and related information management laws.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<chapeau> With respect to Federal information technology, each agency shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> implement and enforce applicable Governmentwide and agency information technology management policies, principles, standards, and guidelines;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> assume responsibility and accountability for information technology investments;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> promote the use of information technology by the agency to improve the productivity, efficiency, and effectiveness of agency programs, including the reduction of information collection burdens on the public and improved dissemination of public information;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> propose changes in legislation, regulations, and agency procedures to improve information technology practices, including changes that improve the ability of the agency to use technology to reduce burden; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> assume responsibility for maximizing the value and assessing and managing the risks of major information systems initiatives through a process that is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> integrated with budget, financial, and program management decisions; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> used to select, control, and evaluate the results of major information systems initiatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In addition to the requirements described in subsection (c), each agency shall, with respect to the collection of information and the control of paperwork, establish 1 point of contact in the agency to act as a liaison between the agency and small business concerns (as defined in section 3 of the Small Business Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 632</ref>)).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Each point of contact described under paragraph (1) shall be established not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of the Small Business Paperwork Relief Act of 2002.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–13, § 2</ref>, <date date="1995-05-22">May 22, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 171</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. E, title LI, § 5125(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 684</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title X, § 1064(b)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–275; <ref>Pub. L. 107–198, § 2(b)</ref>, (c), <date date="2002-06-28">June 28, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 729</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–217, § 3</ref>(<i>l</i>)(6), <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1302</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–296, title X, § 1005(c)(3)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2273</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–347, title III, § 305(c)(3)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-17">Dec. 17, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2961</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–435, title II, § 202(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2019-01-14">Jan. 14, 2019</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5536</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3507.</num>
<heading> Public information collection activities; submission to Director; approval and delegation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> An agency shall not conduct or sponsor the collection of information unless in advance of the adoption or revision of the collection of information—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the agency has—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> conducted the review established under section 3506(c)(1);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> evaluated the public comments received under section 3506(c)(2);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> submitted to the Director the certification required under section 3506(c)(3), the proposed collection of information, copies of pertinent statutory authority, regulations, and other related materials as the Director may specify; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> published a notice in the Federal Register—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> stating that the agency has made such submission; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> setting forth—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> a title for the collection of information;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> a summary of the collection of information;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> a brief description of the need for the information and the proposed use of the information;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> a description of the likely respondents and proposed frequency of response to the collection of information;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(V)</num>
<content> an estimate of the burden that shall result from the collection of information; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(VI)</num>
<content> notice that comments may be submitted to the agency and Director;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Director has approved the proposed collection of information or approval has been inferred, under the provisions of this section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the agency has obtained from the Director a control number to be displayed upon the collection of information.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Director shall provide at least 30 days for public comment prior to making a decision under subsection (c), (d), or (h), except as provided under subsection (j).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> For any proposed collection of information not contained in a proposed rule, the Director shall notify the agency involved of the decision to approve or disapprove the proposed collection of information.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Director shall provide the notification under paragraph (1), within 60 days after receipt or publication of the notice under subsection (a)(1)(D), whichever is later.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> If the Director does not notify the agency of a denial or approval within the 60-day period described under paragraph (2)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the approval may be inferred;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a control number shall be assigned without further delay; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the agency may collect the information for not more than 1 year.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> For any proposed collection of information contained in a proposed rule—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> as soon as practicable, but no later than the date of publication of a notice of proposed rulemaking in the Federal Register, each agency shall forward to the Director a copy of any proposed rule which contains a collection of information and any information requested by the Director necessary to make the determination required under this subsection; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> within 60 days after the notice of proposed rulemaking is published in the Federal Register, the Director may file public comments pursuant to the standards set forth in section 3508 on the collection of information contained in the proposed rule;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> When a final rule is published in the Federal Register, the agency shall explain—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> how any collection of information contained in the final rule responds to the comments, if any, filed by the Director or the public; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the reasons such comments were rejected.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> If the Director has received notice and failed to comment on an agency rule within 60 days after the notice of proposed rulemaking, the Director may not disapprove any collection of information specifically contained in an agency rule.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> No provision in this section shall be construed to prevent the Director, in the Director’s discretion—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> from disapproving any collection of information which was not specifically required by an agency rule;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> from disapproving any collection of information contained in an agency rule, if the agency failed to comply with the requirements of paragraph (1) of this subsection;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> from disapproving any collection of information contained in a final agency rule, if the Director finds within 60 days after the publication of the final rule that the agency’s response to the Director’s comments filed under paragraph (2) of this subsection was unreasonable; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> from disapproving any collection of information contained in a final rule, if—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Director determines that the agency has substantially modified in the final rule the collection of information contained in the proposed rule; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the agency has not given the Director the information required under paragraph (1) with respect to the modified collection of information, at least 60 days before the issuance of the final rule.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> This subsection shall apply only when an agency publishes a notice of proposed rulemaking and requests public comments.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The decision by the Director to approve or not act upon a collection of information contained in an agency rule shall not be subject to judicial review.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Any decision by the Director under subsection (c), (d), (h), or (j) to disapprove a collection of information, or to instruct the agency to make substantive or material change to a collection of information, shall be publicly available and include an explanation of the reasons for such decision.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any written communication between the Administrator of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs, or any employee of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs, and an agency or person not employed by the Federal Government concerning a proposed collection of information shall be made available to the public.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> This subsection shall not require the disclosure of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any information which is protected at all times by procedures established for information which has been specifically authorized under criteria established by an Executive order or an Act of Congress to be kept secret in the interest of national defense or foreign policy; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any communication relating to a collection of information which is not approved under this subchapter, the disclosure of which could lead to retaliation or discrimination against the communicator.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> An independent regulatory agency which is administered by 2 or more members of a commission, board, or similar body, may by majority vote void—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any disapproval by the Director, in whole or in part, of a proposed collection of information of that agency; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an exercise of authority under subsection (d) of section 3507 concerning that agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The agency shall certify each vote to void such disapproval or exercise to the Director, and explain the reasons for such vote. The Director shall without further delay assign a control number to such collection of information, and such vote to void the disapproval or exercise shall be valid for a period of 3 years.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> The Director may not approve a collection of information for a period in excess of 3 years.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> If an agency decides to seek extension of the Director’s approval granted for a currently approved collection of information, the agency shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> conduct the review established under section 3506(c), including the seeking of comment from the public on the continued need for, and burden imposed by the collection of information; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> after having made a reasonable effort to seek public comment, but no later than 60 days before the expiration date of the control number assigned by the Director for the currently approved collection of information, submit the collection of information for review and approval under this section, which shall include an explanation of how the agency has used the information that it has collected.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> If under the provisions of this section, the Director disapproves a collection of information contained in an existing rule, or recommends or instructs the agency to make a substantive or material change to a collection of information contained in an existing rule, the Director shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> publish an explanation thereof in the Federal Register; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> instruct the agency to undertake a rulemaking within a reasonable time limited to consideration of changes to the collection of information contained in the rule and thereafter to submit the collection of information for approval or disapproval under this subchapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> An agency may not make a substantive or material modification to a collection of information after such collection has been approved by the Director, unless the modification has been submitted to the Director for review and approval under this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> If the Director finds that a senior official of an agency designated under section 3506(a) is sufficiently independent of program responsibility to evaluate fairly whether proposed collections of information should be approved and has sufficient resources to carry out this responsibility effectively, the Director may, by rule in accordance with the notice and comment provisions of chapter 5 of title 5, United States Code, delegate to such official the authority to approve proposed collections of information in specific program areas, for specific purposes, or for all agency purposes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A delegation by the Director under this section shall not preclude the Director from reviewing individual collections of information if the Director determines that circumstances warrant such a review. The Director shall retain authority to revoke such delegations, both in general and with regard to any specific matter. In acting for the Director, any official to whom approval authority has been delegated under this section shall comply fully with the rules and regulations promulgated by the Director.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The agency head may request the Director to authorize a collection of information, if an agency head determines that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> a collection of information—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is needed prior to the expiration of time periods established under this subchapter; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> is essential to the mission of the agency; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> the agency cannot reasonably comply with the provisions of this subchapter because—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> public harm is reasonably likely to result if normal clearance procedures are followed;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> an unanticipated event has occurred; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the use of normal clearance procedures is reasonably likely to prevent or disrupt the collection of information or is reasonably likely to cause a statutory or court ordered deadline to be missed.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Director shall approve or disapprove any such authorization request within the time requested by the agency head and, if approved, shall assign the collection of information a control number. Any collection of information conducted under this subsection may be conducted without compliance with the provisions of this subchapter for a maximum of 180 days after the date on which the Director received the request to authorize such collection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–13, § 2</ref>, <date date="1995-05-22">May 22, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 176</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. E, title LVI, § 5605(d)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 700</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title X, § 1064(b)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–275.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3508.</num>
<heading> Determination of necessity for information; hearing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Before approving a proposed collection of information, the Director shall determine whether the collection of information by the agency is necessary for the proper performance of the functions of the agency, including whether the information shall have practical utility. Before making a determination the Director may give the agency and other interested persons an opportunity to be heard or to submit statements in writing. To the extent, if any, that the Director determines that the collection of information by an agency is unnecessary for any reason, the agency may not engage in the collection of information.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–13, § 2</ref>, <date date="1995-05-22">May 22, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 179</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3509.</num>
<heading> Designation of central collection agency</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director may designate a central collection agency to obtain information for two or more agencies if the Director determines that the needs of such agencies for information will be adequately served by a single collection agency, and such sharing of data is not inconsistent with applicable law. In such cases the Director shall prescribe (with reference to the collection of information) the duties and functions of the collection agency so designated and of the agencies for which it is to act as agent (including reimbursement for costs). While the designation is in effect, an agency covered by the designation may not obtain for itself information for the agency which is the duty of the collection agency to obtain. The Director may modify the designation from time to time as circumstances require. The authority to designate under this section is subject to the provisions of section 3507(f) of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–13, § 2</ref>, <date date="1995-05-22">May 22, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 180</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title X, § 1064(b)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–275.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3510.</num>
<heading> Cooperation of agencies in making information available</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Director may direct an agency to make available to another agency, or an agency may make available to another agency, information obtained by a collection of information if the disclosure is not inconsistent with applicable law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> If information obtained by an agency is released by that agency to another agency, all the provisions of law (including penalties) that relate to the unlawful disclosure of information apply to the officers and employees of the agency to which information is released to the same extent and in the same manner as the provisions apply to the officers and employees of the agency which originally obtained the information.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The officers and employees of the agency to which the information is released, in addition, shall be subject to the same provisions of law, including penalties, relating to the unlawful disclosure of information as if the information had been collected directly by that agency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–13, § 2</ref>, <date date="1995-05-22">May 22, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 180</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3511.</num>
<heading> Data inventory and Federal data catalogue</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Comprehensive Data Inventory.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In consultation with the Director and in accordance with the guidance established under paragraph (2), the head of each agency shall, to the maximum extent practicable, develop and maintain a comprehensive data inventory that accounts for all data assets created by, collected by, under the control or direction of, or maintained by the agency. The head of each agency shall ensure that such inventory provides a clear and comprehensive understanding of the data assets in the possession of the agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Guidance</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Director shall establish guidance for agencies to develop and maintain comprehensive data inventories under paragraph (1). Such guidance shall include the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> A requirement for the head of an agency to include in the comprehensive data inventory metadata on each data asset of the agency, including, to the maximum extent practicable, the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> A description of the data asset, including all variable names and definitions.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The name or title of the data asset.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> An indication of whether or not the agency—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<chapeau> has determined or can determine if the data asset is—</chapeau>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> an open Government data asset;</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> subject to disclosure or partial disclosure or exempt from disclosure under <ref>section 552 of title 5</ref>;</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(cc)</num>
<content> a public data asset eligible for disclosure under subsection (b); or</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(dd)</num>
<content> a data asset not subject to open format or open license requirements due to existing limitations or restrictions on government distribution of the asset; or</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> as of the date of such indication, has not made such determination.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> Any determination made under section 3582, if available.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> A description of the method by which the public may access or request access to the data asset.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> The date on which the data asset was most recently updated.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> Each agency responsible for maintaining the data asset.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> The owner of the data asset.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ix)</num>
<content> To the extent practicable, any restriction on the use of the data asset.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(x)</num>
<content> The location of the data asset.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(xi)</num>
<content> Any other metadata necessary to make the comprehensive data inventory useful to the agency and the public, or otherwise determined useful by the Director.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A requirement for the head of an agency to exclude from the comprehensive data inventory any data asset contained on a national security system, as defined in <ref>section 11103 of title 40</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Criteria for the head of an agency to use in determining which metadata required by subparagraph (A), if any, in the comprehensive data inventory may not be made publicly available, which shall include, at a minimum, a requirement to ensure all information that could not otherwise be withheld from disclosure under <ref>section 552 of title 5</ref> is made public in the comprehensive data inventory.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> A requirement for the head of each agency, in accordance with a procedure established by the Director, to submit for inclusion in the Federal data catalogue maintained under subsection (c) the comprehensive data inventory developed pursuant to subparagraph (C), including any real-time updates to such inventory, and data assets made available in accordance with subparagraph (E) or any electronic hyperlink providing access to such data assets.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<chapeau> Criteria for the head of an agency to use in determining whether a particular data asset should not be made publicly available in a manner that takes into account—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> risks and restrictions related to the disclosure of personally identifiable information, including the risk that an individual data asset in isolation does not pose a privacy or confidentiality risk but when combined with other available information may pose such a risk;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> security considerations, including the risk that information in an individual data asset in isolation does not pose a security risk but when combined with other available information may pose such a risk;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the cost and benefits to the public of converting the data into a format that could be understood and used by the public;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> whether the public dissemination of the data asset could result in legal liability;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<chapeau> whether the data asset—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> is subject to intellectual property rights, including rights under titles 17 and 35;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> contains confidential business information, that could be withheld under <ref>section 552(b)(4) of title 5</ref>; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> is restricted by contract or other binding, written agreement;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> whether the holder of a right to such data asset has been consulted;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> the expectation that all data assets that would otherwise be made available under <ref>section 552 of title 5</ref> be disclosed; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> any other considerations that the Director determines to be relevant.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Criteria for the head of an agency to use in assessing the indication of a determination under subparagraph (A)(iii) and how to prioritize any such subsequent determinations in the strategic information management plan under section 3506, in consideration of the existing resources available to the agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regular updates required</inline>.—</heading>
<content>With respect to each data asset created or identified by an agency, the head of the agency shall update the comprehensive data inventory of the agency not later than 90 days after the date of such creation or identification.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Public Data Assets</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The head of each agency shall submit public data assets, or links to public data assets available online, as open Government data assets for inclusion in the Federal data catalogue maintained under subsection (c), in accordance with the guidance established under subsection (a)(2).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Federal Data Catalogue.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator of General Services shall maintain a single public interface online as a point of entry dedicated to sharing agency data assets with the public, which shall be known as the “Federal data catalogue”. The Administrator and the Director shall ensure that agencies can submit public data assets, or links to public data assets, for publication and public availability on the interface.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Repository</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Director shall collaborate with the Office of Government Information Services and the Administrator of General Services to develop and maintain an online repository of tools, best practices, and schema standards to facilitate the adoption of open data practices across the Federal Government, which shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> include any definitions, regulations, policies, checklists, and case studies related to open data policy;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> facilitate collaboration and the adoption of best practices across the Federal Government relating to the adoption of open data practices; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> be made available on the Federal data catalogue maintained under paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Access to other data assets</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Director shall ensure the Federal data catalogue maintained under paragraph (1) provides information on how the public can access a data asset included in a comprehensive data inventory under subsection (a) that is not yet available on the Federal data catalogue, including information regarding the application process established under <ref>section 3583 of title 44</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Delegation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Director shall delegate to the Administrator of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs and the Administrator of the Office of Electronic Government the authority to jointly issue guidance required under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–13, § 2</ref>, <date date="1995-05-22">May 22, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 180</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 113–235, div. H, title I, § 1301(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-16">Dec. 16, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 2537</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–435, title II, § 202(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="2019-01-14">Jan. 14, 2019</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5538</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3512.</num>
<heading> Public protection</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no person shall be subject to any penalty for failing to comply with a collection of information that is subject to this subchapter if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the collection of information does not display a valid control number assigned by the Director in accordance with this subchapter; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the agency fails to inform the person who is to respond to the collection of information that such person is not required to respond to the collection of information unless it displays a valid control number.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The protection provided by this section may be raised in the form of a complete defense, bar, or otherwise at any time during the agency administrative process or judicial action applicable thereto.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–13, § 2</ref>, <date date="1995-05-22">May 22, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 181</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title X, § 1064(b)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–275.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3513.</num>
<heading> Director review of agency activities; reporting; agency response</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> In consultation with the Administrator of General Services, the Archivist of the United States, the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology, and the Director of the Office of Personnel Management, the Director shall periodically review selected agency information resources management activities to ascertain the efficiency and effectiveness of such activities to improve agency performance and the accomplishment of agency missions.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Each agency having an activity reviewed under subsection (a) shall, within 60 days after receipt of a report on the review, provide a written plan to the Director describing steps (including milestones) to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> be taken to address information resources management problems identified in the report; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> improve agency performance and the accomplishment of agency missions.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Comparable Treatment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Director shall treat or review a rule or order prescribed or proposed by the Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection on the same terms and conditions as apply to any rule or order prescribed or proposed by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–13, § 2</ref>, <date date="1995-05-22">May 22, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 181</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 111–203, title X, § 1100D(b)</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2111</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3514.</num>
<heading> Responsiveness to Congress</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Director shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> keep the Congress and congressional committees fully and currently informed of the major activities under this subchapter; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> submit a report on such activities to the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives annually and at such other times as the Director determines necessary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Director shall include in any such report a description of the extent to which agencies have—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> reduced information collection burdens on the public, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a summary of accomplishments and planned initiatives to reduce collection of information burdens;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a list of all violations of this subchapter and of any rules, guidelines, policies, and procedures issued pursuant to this subchapter;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a list of any increase in the collection of information burden, including the authority for each such collection; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> a list of agencies that in the preceding year did not reduce information collection burdens in accordance with section 3505(a)(1), a list of the programs and statutory responsibilities of those agencies that precluded that reduction, and recommendations to assist those agencies to reduce information collection burdens in accordance with that section;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> improved the quality and utility of statistical information;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> improved public access to Government information; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> improved program performance and the accomplishment of agency missions through information resources management.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The preparation of any report required by this section shall be based on performance results reported by the agencies and shall not increase the collection of information burden on persons outside the Federal Government.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–13, § 2</ref>, <date date="1995-05-22">May 22, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 181</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title X, § 1064(b)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–275.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3515.</num>
<heading> Administrative powers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon the request of the Director, each agency (other than an independent regulatory agency) shall, to the extent practicable, make its services, personnel, and facilities available to the Director for the performance of functions under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–13, § 2</ref>, <date date="1995-05-22">May 22, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 182</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title X, § 1064(b)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–275.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3516.</num>
<heading> Rules and regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director shall promulgate rules, regulations, or procedures necessary to exercise the authority provided by this subchapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–13, § 2</ref>, <date date="1995-05-22">May 22, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 182</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title X, § 1064(b)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–275.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3517.</num>
<heading> Consultation with other agencies and the public</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> In developing information resources management policies, plans, rules, regulations, procedures, and guidelines and in reviewing collections of information, the Director shall provide interested agencies and persons early and meaningful opportunity to comment.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Any person may request the Director to review any collection of information conducted by or for an agency to determine, if, under this subchapter, a person shall maintain, provide, or disclose the information to or for the agency. Unless the request is frivolous, the Director shall, in coordination with the agency responsible for the collection of information—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> respond to the request within 60 days after receiving the request, unless such period is extended by the Director to a specified date and the person making the request is given notice of such extension; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> take appropriate remedial action, if necessary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–13, § 2</ref>, <date date="1995-05-22">May 22, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 182</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title X, § 1064(b)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–275.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3518.</num>
<heading> Effect on existing laws and regulations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Except as otherwise provided in this subchapter, the authority of an agency under any other law to prescribe policies, rules, regulations, and procedures for Federal information resources management activities is subject to the authority of the Director under this subchapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Nothing in this subchapter shall be deemed to affect or reduce the authority of the Secretary of Commerce or the Director of the Office of Management and Budget pursuant to Reorganization Plan No. 1 of 1977 (as amended) and Executive order, relating to telecommunications and information policy, procurement and management of telecommunications and information systems, spectrum use, and related matters.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Except as provided in paragraph (2), this subchapter shall not apply to the collection of information—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> during the conduct of a Federal criminal investigation or prosecution, or during the disposition of a particular criminal matter;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> during the conduct of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a civil action to which the United States or any official or agency thereof is a party; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> an administrative action or investigation involving an agency against specific individuals or entities;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> by compulsory process pursuant to the Antitrust Civil Process Act and section 13 of the Federal Trade Commission Improvements Act of 1980; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> during the conduct of intelligence activities as defined in section 3.4(e) of Executive Order No. 12333, issued <date date="1981-12-04">December 4, 1981</date>, or successor orders, or during the conduct of cryptologic activities that are communications security activities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> This subchapter applies to the collection of information during the conduct of general investigations (other than information collected in an antitrust investigation to the extent provided in subparagraph (C) of paragraph (1)) undertaken with reference to a category of individuals or entities such as a class of licensees or an entire industry.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Nothing in this subchapter shall be interpreted as increasing or decreasing the authority conferred by sections 11331 and 11332 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002037">1</ref> of title 40 on the Secretary of Commerce or the Director of the Office of Management and Budget.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> Nothing in this subchapter shall be interpreted as increasing or decreasing the authority of the President, the Office of Management and Budget or the Director thereof, under the laws of the United States, with respect to the substantive policies and programs of departments, agencies and offices, including the substantive authority of any Federal agency to enforce the civil rights laws.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–13, § 2</ref>, <date date="1995-05-22">May 22, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 183</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. E, title LI, § 5131(e)(2)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 688</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title X, § 1073(h)(5)(C)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1907</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title X, § 1064(b)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–275; <ref>Pub. L. 107–217, § 3</ref>(<i>l</i>)(7), <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1302</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3519.</num>
<heading> Access to information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Under the conditions and procedures prescribed in <ref>section 716 of title 31</ref>, the Director and personnel in the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs shall furnish such information as the Comptroller General may require for the discharge of the responsibilities of the Comptroller General. For the purpose of obtaining such information, the Comptroller General or representatives thereof shall have access to all books, documents, papers and records, regardless of form or format, of the Office.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–13, § 2</ref>, <date date="1995-05-22">May 22, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 183</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3520.</num>
<heading> Chief Data Officers</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The head of each agency shall designate a nonpolitical appointee employee in the agency as the Chief Data Officer of the agency.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Qualifications</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Chief Data Officer of an agency shall be designated on the basis of demonstrated training and experience in data management, governance (including creation, application, and maintenance of data standards), collection, analysis, protection, use, and dissemination, including with respect to any statistical and related techniques to protect and de-identify confidential data.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Functions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Chief Data Officer of an agency shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> be responsible for lifecycle data management;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> coordinate with any official in the agency responsible for using, protecting, disseminating, and generating data to ensure that the data needs of the agency are met;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> manage data assets of the agency, including the standardization of data format, sharing of data assets, and publication of data assets in accordance with applicable law;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> in carrying out the requirements under paragraphs (3) and (5), consult with any statistical official of the agency (as designated under <ref>section 314 of title 5</ref>);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> carry out the requirements of the agency under subsections (b) through (d), (f), and (i) of section 3506, section 3507, and section 3511;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> ensure that, to the extent practicable, agency data conforms with data management best practices;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> engage agency employees, the public, and contractors in using public data assets and encourage collaborative approaches on improving data use;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> support the Performance Improvement Officer of the agency in identifying and using data to carry out the functions described in <ref>section 1124(a)(2) of title 31</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> support the Evaluation Officer of the agency in obtaining data to carry out the functions described in <ref>section 313(d) of title 5</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> review the impact of the infrastructure of the agency on data asset accessibility and coordinate with the Chief Information Officer of the agency to improve such infrastructure to reduce barriers that inhibit data asset accessibility;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> ensure that, to the extent practicable, the agency maximizes the use of data in the agency, including for the production of evidence (as defined in section 3561), cybersecurity, and the improvement of agency operations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> identify points of contact for roles and responsibilities related to open data use and implementation (as required by the Director);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> serve as the agency liaison to other agencies and the Office of Management and Budget on the best way to use existing agency data for statistical purposes (as defined in section 3561); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> comply with any regulation and guidance issued under subchapter III, including the acquisition and maintenance of any required certification and training.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Delegation of Responsibilities.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>To the extent necessary to comply with statistical laws, the Chief Data Officer of an agency shall delegate any responsibility under subsection (c) to the head of a statistical agency or unit (as defined in section 3561) within the agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consultation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>To the extent permissible under law, the individual to whom a responsibility has been delegated under paragraph (1) shall consult with the Chief Data Officer of the agency in carrying out such responsibility.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Deference</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Chief Data Officer of the agency shall defer to the individual to whom a responsibility has been delegated under paragraph (1) regarding the necessary delegation of such responsibility with respect to any data acquired, maintained, or disseminated by the agency under applicable statistical law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reports</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Chief Data Officer of an agency shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives an annual report on the compliance of the agency with the requirements of this subchapter, including information on each requirement that the agency could not carry out and, if applicable, what the agency needs to carry out such requirement.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 107–198, § 3(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2002-06-28">June 28, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 730</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–435, title II, § 202(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="2019-01-14">Jan. 14, 2019</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5541</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3520A.</num>
<heading> Chief Data Officer Council</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is established in the Office of Management and Budget a Chief Data Officer Council (in this section referred to as the “Council”).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Purpose and Functions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Council shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> establish Governmentwide best practices for the use, protection, dissemination, and generation of data;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> promote and encourage data sharing agreements between agencies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> identify ways in which agencies can improve upon the production of evidence for use in policymaking;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> consult with the public and engage with private users of Government data and other stakeholders on how to improve access to data assets of the Federal Government; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> identify and evaluate new technology solutions for improving the collection and use of data.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Membership.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Chief Data Officer of each agency shall serve as a member of the Council.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Chair</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Director shall select the Chair of the Council from among the members of the Council.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Additional members</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator of the Office of Electronic Government shall serve as a member of the Council.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Ex officio member</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Director shall appoint a representative for all Chief Information Officers and Evaluation Officers, and such representative shall serve as an ex officio member of the Council.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reports</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Council shall submit to the Director, the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate, and the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives a biennial report on the work of the Council.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Evaluation and Termination.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">GAO evaluation of council</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 4 years after date <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002038">1</ref> of the enactment of this section, the Comptroller General shall submit to Congress a report on whether the additional duties of the Council improved the use of evidence and program evaluation in the Federal Government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Termination of council</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Council shall terminate and this section shall be repealed upon the expiration of the 2-year period that begins on the date the Comptroller General submits the report under paragraph (1) to Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–435, title II, § 202(f)(1)</ref>, <date date="2019-01-14">Jan. 14, 2019</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5542</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3521.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs to carry out the provisions of this subchapter, and for no other purpose, $8,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 1996, 1997, 1998, 1999, 2000, and 2001.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–13, § 2</ref>, <date date="1995-05-22">May 22, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 184</ref>, § 3520; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title X, § 1064(b)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–275; renumbered § 3521, <ref>Pub. L. 107–198, § 3(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-06-28">June 28, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 730</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§§ 3531 to 3549.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 113–283, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-18">Dec. 18, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3073</ref>]</heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>INFORMATION SECURITY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3551.</num>
<heading> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes of this subchapter are to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provide a comprehensive framework for ensuring the effectiveness of information security controls over information resources that support Federal operations and assets;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> recognize the highly networked nature of the current Federal computing environment and provide effective governmentwide management and oversight of the related information security risks, including coordination of information security efforts throughout the civilian, national security, and law enforcement communities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> provide for development and maintenance of minimum controls required to protect Federal information and information systems;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> provide a mechanism for improved oversight of Federal agency information security programs, including through automated security tools to continuously diagnose and improve security;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> acknowledge that commercially developed information security products offer advanced, dynamic, robust, and effective information security solutions, reflecting market solutions for the protection of critical information infrastructures important to the national defense and economic security of the nation that are designed, built, and operated by the private sector; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> recognize that the selection of specific technical hardware and software information security solutions should be left to individual agencies from among commercially developed products.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 113–283, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-18">Dec. 18, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3073</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3552.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided under subsection (b), the definitions under section 3502 shall apply to this subchapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Additional Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>As used in this subchapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The term “binding operational directive” means a compulsory direction to an agency that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is for purposes of safeguarding Federal information and information systems from a known or reasonably suspected information security threat, vulnerability, or risk;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> shall be in accordance with policies, principles, standards, and guidelines issued by the Director; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> may be revised or repealed by the Director if the direction issued on behalf of the Director is not in accordance with policies and principles developed by the Director.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The term “incident” means an occurrence that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> actually or imminently jeopardizes, without lawful authority, the integrity, confidentiality, or availability of information or an information system; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> constitutes a violation or imminent threat of violation of law, security policies, security procedures, or acceptable use policies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The term “information security” means protecting information and information systems from unauthorized access, use, disclosure, disruption, modification, or destruction in order to provide—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> integrity, which means guarding against improper information modification or destruction, and includes ensuring information nonrepudiation and authenticity;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> confidentiality, which means preserving authorized restrictions on access and disclosure, including means for protecting personal privacy and proprietary information; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> availability, which means ensuring timely and reliable access to and use of information.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “information technology” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 11101 of title 40</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The term “intelligence community” has the meaning given that term in section 3(4) of the National Security Act of 1947 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3003(4)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> The term “national security system” means any information system (including any telecommunications system) used or operated by an agency or by a contractor of an agency, or other organization on behalf of an agency—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> the function, operation, or use of which—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> involves intelligence activities;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> involves cryptologic activities related to national security;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> involves command and control of military forces;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> involves equipment that is an integral part of a weapon or weapons system; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(V)</num>
<content> subject to subparagraph (B), is critical to the direct fulfillment of military or intelligence missions; or</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> is protected at all times by procedures established for information that have been specifically authorized under criteria established by an Executive order or an Act of Congress to be kept classified in the interest of national defense or foreign policy.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Subparagraph (A)(i)(V) does not include a system that is to be used for routine administrative and business applications (including payroll, finance, logistics, and personnel management applications).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Homeland Security.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 113–283, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-18">Dec. 18, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3074</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3553.</num>
<heading> Authority and functions of the Director and the Secretary</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Director</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Director shall oversee agency information security policies and practices, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> developing and overseeing the implementation of policies, principles, standards, and guidelines on information security, including through ensuring timely agency adoption of and compliance with standards promulgated under <ref>section 11331 of title 40</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> requiring agencies, consistent with the standards promulgated under such section 11331 and the requirements of this subchapter, to identify and provide information security protections commensurate with the risk and magnitude of the harm resulting from the unauthorized access, use, disclosure, disruption, modification, or destruction of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> information collected or maintained by or on behalf of an agency; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> information systems used or operated by an agency or by a contractor of an agency or other organization on behalf of an agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> ensuring that the Secretary carries out the authorities and functions under subsection (b);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> coordinating the development of standards and guidelines under section 20 of the National Institute of Standards and Technology Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 278g–3</ref>) with agencies and offices operating or exercising control of national security systems (including the National Security Agency) to assure, to the maximum extent feasible, that such standards and guidelines are complementary with standards and guidelines developed for national security systems;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> overseeing agency compliance with the requirements of this subchapter and <ref>section 1326 of title 41</ref>, including through any authorized action under <ref>section 11303 of title 40</ref>, to enforce accountability for compliance with such requirements; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> coordinating information security policies and procedures with related information resources management policies and procedures.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Secretary</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary, in consultation with the Director, shall administer the implementation of agency information security policies and practices for information systems, except for national security systems and information systems described in paragraph (2) or (3) of subsection (e), including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> assisting the Director in carrying out the authorities and functions under paragraphs (1), (2), (3), (5), and (6) of subsection (a);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> developing and overseeing the implementation of binding operational directives to agencies to implement the policies, principles, standards, and guidelines developed by the Director under subsection (a)(1) and the requirements of this subchapter, which may be revised or repealed by the Director if the operational directives issued on behalf of the Director are not in accordance with policies, principles, standards, and guidelines developed by the Director, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> requirements for reporting security incidents to the Federal information security incident center established under section 3556;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> requirements for the contents of the annual reports required to be submitted under section 3554(c)(1);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> requirements for the mitigation of exigent risks to information systems; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> other operational requirements as the Director or Secretary, in consultation with the Director, may determine necessary;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> monitoring agency implementation of information security policies and practices;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> convening meetings with senior agency officials to help ensure effective implementation of information security policies and practices;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> coordinating Government-wide efforts on information security policies and practices, including consultation with the Chief Information Officers Council established under section 3603 and the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> providing operational and technical assistance to agencies in implementing policies, principles, standards, and guidelines on information security, including implementation of standards promulgated under <ref>section 11331 of title 40</ref>, including by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> operating the Federal information security incident center established under section 3556;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> upon request by an agency, deploying, operating, and maintaining technology to assist the agency to continuously diagnose and mitigate against cyber threats and vulnerabilities, with or without reimbursement;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> compiling and analyzing data on agency information security; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> developing and conducting targeted operational evaluations, including threat and vulnerability assessments, on the information systems;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> hunting for and identifying, with or without advance notice to or authorization from agencies, threats and vulnerabilities within Federal information systems;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<chapeau> upon request by an agency, and at the Secretary’s discretion, with or without reimbursement—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> providing services, functions, and capabilities, including operation of the agency’s information security program, to assist the agency with meeting the requirements set forth in section 3554(b); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> deploying, operating, and maintaining secure technology platforms and tools, including networks and common business applications, for use by the agency to perform agency functions, including collecting, maintaining, storing, processing, disseminating, and analyzing information; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> other actions as the Director or the Secretary, in consultation with the Director, may determine necessary to carry out this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not later than March 1 of each year, the Director, in consultation with the Secretary, shall submit to Congress a report on the effectiveness of information security policies and practices during the preceding year, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a summary of the incidents described in the annual reports required to be submitted under section 3554(c)(1), including a summary of the information required under section 3554(c)(1)(A)(iii);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a description of the threshold for reporting major information security incidents;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a summary of the results of evaluations required to be performed under section 3555;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> an assessment of agency compliance with standards promulgated under <ref>section 11331 of title 40</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> an assessment of agency compliance with data breach notification policies and procedures issued by the Director.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">National Security Systems</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except for the authorities and functions described in subsection (a)(5) and subsection (c), the authorities and functions of the Director and the Secretary under this section shall not apply to national security systems.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Department of Defense and Intelligence Community Systems</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The authorities of the Director described in paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (a) shall be delegated to the Secretary of Defense in the case of systems described in paragraph (2) and to the Director of National Intelligence in the case of systems described in paragraph (3).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The systems described in this paragraph are systems that are operated by the Department of Defense, a contractor of the Department of Defense, or another entity on behalf of the Department of Defense that processes any information the unauthorized access, use, disclosure, disruption, modification, or destruction of which would have a debilitating impact on the mission of the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The systems described in this paragraph are systems that are operated by an element of the intelligence community, a contractor of an element of the intelligence community, or another entity on behalf of an element of the intelligence community that processes any information the unauthorized access, use, disclosure, disruption, modification, or destruction of which would have a debilitating impact on the mission of an element of the intelligence community.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Consideration.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In carrying out the responsibilities under subsection (b), the Secretary shall consider any applicable standards or guidelines developed by the National Institute of Standards and Technology and issued by the Secretary of Commerce under <ref>section 11331 of title 40</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Directives</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> consult with the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology regarding any binding operational directive that implements standards and guidelines developed by the National Institute of Standards and Technology; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> ensure that binding operational directives issued under subsection (b)(2) do not conflict with the standards and guidelines issued under <ref>section 11331 of title 40</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rule of construction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this subchapter shall be construed as authorizing the Secretary to direct the Secretary of Commerce in the development and promulgation of standards and guidelines under <ref>section 11331 of title 40</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exercise of Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>To ensure fiscal and policy consistency, the Secretary shall exercise the authority under this section subject to direction by the President, in coordination with the Director.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Direction to Agencies.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Authority.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to subparagraph (B), in response to a known or reasonably suspected information security threat, vulnerability, or incident that represents a substantial threat to the information security of an agency, the Secretary may issue an emergency directive to the head of an agency to take any lawful action with respect to the operation of the information system, including such systems used or operated by another entity on behalf of an agency, that collects, processes, stores, transmits, disseminates, or otherwise maintains agency information, for the purpose of protecting the information system from, or mitigating, an information security threat.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The authorities of the Secretary under this subsection shall not apply to a system described subsection (d) or to a system described in paragraph (2) or (3) of subsection (e).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Procedures for use of authority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> in coordination with the Director, and in consultation with Federal contractors as appropriate, establish procedures governing the circumstances under which a directive may be issued under this subsection, which shall include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> thresholds and other criteria;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> privacy and civil liberties protections; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> providing notice to potentially affected third parties;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> specify the reasons for the required action and the duration of the directive;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> minimize the impact of a directive under this subsection by—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> adopting the least intrusive means possible under the circumstances to secure the agency information systems; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> limiting directives to the shortest period practicable;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> notify the Director and the head of any affected agency immediately upon the issuance of a directive under this subsection;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> consult with the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology regarding any directive under this subsection that implements standards and guidelines developed by the National Institute of Standards and Technology;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> ensure that directives issued under this subsection do not conflict with the standards and guidelines issued under <ref>section 11331 of title 40</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> consider any applicable standards or guidelines developed by the National Institute of Standards and Technology issued by the Secretary of Commerce under <ref>section 11331 of title 40</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> not later than February 1 of each year, submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report regarding the specific actions the Secretary has taken pursuant to paragraph (1)(A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Imminent threats.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Notwithstanding section 3554, the Secretary may authorize the use under this subsection of the intrusion detection and prevention capabilities established under section 230(b)(1) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002039">1</ref> of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 for the purpose of ensuring the security of agency information systems, if—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Secretary determines there is an imminent threat to agency information systems;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the Secretary determines a directive under subsection (b)(2)(C) or paragraph (1)(A) is not reasonably likely to result in a timely response to the threat;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the Secretary determines the risk posed by the imminent threat outweighs any adverse consequences reasonably expected to result from the use of the intrusion detection and prevention capabilities under the control of the Secretary;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<chapeau> the Secretary provides prior notice to the Director, and the head and chief information officer (or equivalent official) of each agency to which specific actions will be taken pursuant to this paragraph, and notifies the appropriate congressional committees and authorizing committees of each such agency within 7 days of taking an action under this paragraph of—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> any action taken under this paragraph; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the reasons for and duration and nature of the action;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> the action of the Secretary is consistent with applicable law; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> the Secretary authorizes the use of the intrusion detection and prevention capabilities in accordance with the advance procedures established under subparagraph (C).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on delegation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The authority under this paragraph may not be delegated by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Advance procedures</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall, in coordination with the Director, and in consultation with the heads of Federal agencies, establish procedures governing the circumstances under which the Secretary may authorize the use of the intrusion detection and prevention capabilities under subparagraph (A). The Secretary shall submit the procedures to Congress.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary may direct or authorize lawful action or the use of the intrusion detection and prevention capabilities under this subsection only to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> protect agency information from unauthorized access, use, disclosure, disruption, modification, or destruction; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> require the remediation of or protect against identified information security risks with respect to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> information collected or maintained by or on behalf of an agency; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> that portion of an information system used or operated by an agency or by a contractor of an agency or other organization on behalf of an agency.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Report to Congress</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than February 1 of each year, the Director and the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report regarding the specific actions the Director and the Secretary have taken pursuant to subsection (a)(5), including any actions taken pursuant to <ref>section 11303(b)(5) of title 40</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rule of Construction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section shall be construed to require the Secretary to provide notice to any private entity before the Secretary issues a binding operational directive under subsection (b)(2).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(k)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appropriate Congressional Committees Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the term “appropriate congressional committees” means—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Committee on Appropriations and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Committee on Appropriations, the Committee on Homeland Security, the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(l)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Information Sharing.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, including any provision of law that would otherwise restrict or prevent the head of an agency from disclosing information to the Secretary, the Secretary in carrying out this section and title XXII of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<ref>6 U.S.C. 651</ref> et seq.) may access, use, retain, and disclose, and the head of an agency may disclose to the Secretary, information, for the purpose of protecting information and information systems from cybersecurity risks.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Paragraph (1) shall not apply to national security systems or to information systems described in paragraph (2) or (3) of subsection (e).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 113–283, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-18">Dec. 18, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3075</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 114–113, div. N, title II</ref>, §§ 224(e), 229(a), <date date="2015-12-18">Dec. 18, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 2967</ref>, 2972; <ref>Pub. L. 115–390, title II, § 204(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5192</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. E, title LXIV, § 6432</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 2200</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVII, § 1705</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4082</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3554.</num>
<heading> Federal agency responsibilities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The head of each agency shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> be responsible for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> providing information security protections commensurate with the risk and magnitude of the harm resulting from unauthorized access, use, disclosure, disruption, modification, or destruction of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> information collected or maintained by or on behalf of the agency; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> information systems used or operated by an agency or by a contractor of an agency or other organization on behalf of an agency;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> complying with the requirements of this subchapter, subchapter III of chapter 13 of title 41, and related policies, procedures, standards, and guidelines, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> information security standards promulgated under <ref>section 11331 of title 40</ref>;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> operational directives developed by the Secretary under section 3553(b);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> policies and procedures issued by the Director;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> information security standards and guidelines for national security systems issued in accordance with law and as directed by the President;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> emergency directives issued by the Secretary under section 3553(h); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> responsibilities relating to assessing and avoiding, mitigating, transferring, or accepting supply chain risks under <ref>section 1326 of title 41</ref>, and complying with exclusion and removal orders issued under section 1323 of such title; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> ensuring that information security management processes are integrated with agency strategic, operational, and budgetary planning processes;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> ensure that senior agency officials provide information security for the information and information systems that support the operations and assets under their control, including through—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> assessing the risk and magnitude of the harm that could result from the unauthorized access, use, disclosure, disruption, modification, or destruction of such information or information systems;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> determining the levels of information security appropriate to protect such information and information systems in accordance with standards promulgated under <ref>section 11331 of title 40</ref>, for information security classifications and related requirements;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> implementing policies and procedures to cost-effectively reduce risks to an acceptable level; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> periodically testing and evaluating information security controls and techniques to ensure that they are effectively implemented;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> delegate to the agency Chief Information Officer established under section 3506 (or comparable official in an agency not covered by such section) the authority to ensure compliance with the requirements imposed on the agency under this subchapter, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> designating a senior agency information security officer who shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> carry out the Chief Information Officer’s responsibilities under this section;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> possess professional qualifications, including training and experience, required to administer the functions described under this section;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> have information security duties as that official’s primary duty; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> head an office with the mission and resources to assist in ensuring agency compliance with this section;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> developing and maintaining an agencywide information security program as required by subsection (b);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> developing and maintaining information security policies, procedures, and control techniques to address all applicable requirements, including those issued under <ref>section 3553 of this title</ref> and <ref>section 11331 of title 40</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> training and overseeing personnel with significant responsibilities for information security with respect to such responsibilities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> assisting senior agency officials concerning their responsibilities under paragraph (2);</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> ensure that the agency has trained personnel sufficient to assist the agency in complying with the requirements of this subchapter and related policies, procedures, standards, and guidelines;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> ensure that the agency Chief Information Officer, in coordination with other senior agency officials, reports annually to the agency head on the effectiveness of the agency information security program, including progress of remedial actions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> ensure that senior agency officials, including chief information officers of component agencies or equivalent officials, carry out responsibilities under this subchapter as directed by the official delegated authority under paragraph (3); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> ensure that all personnel are held accountable for complying with the agency-wide information security program implemented under subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Agency Program</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each agency shall develop, document, and implement an agency-wide information security program to provide information security for the information and information systems that support the operations and assets of the agency, including those provided or managed by another agency, contractor, or other source, that includes—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> periodic assessments of the risk and magnitude of the harm that could result from the unauthorized access, use, disclosure, disruption, modification, or destruction of information and information systems that support the operations and assets of the agency, which may include using automated tools consistent with standards and guidelines promulgated under <ref>section 11331 of title 40</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> policies and procedures that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> are based on the risk assessments required by paragraph (1);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> cost-effectively reduce information security risks to an acceptable level;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> ensure that information security is addressed throughout the life cycle of each agency information system; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> ensure compliance with—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the requirements of this subchapter;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> policies and procedures as may be prescribed by the Director, and information security standards promulgated under <ref>section 11331 of title 40</ref>;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> minimally acceptable system configuration requirements, as determined by the agency; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> any other applicable requirements, including standards and guidelines for national security systems issued in accordance with law and as directed by the President;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> subordinate plans for providing adequate information security for networks, facilities, and systems or groups of information systems, as appropriate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> security awareness training to inform personnel, including contractors and other users of information systems that support the operations and assets of the agency, of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> information security risks associated with their activities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> their responsibilities in complying with agency policies and procedures designed to reduce these risks;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> periodic testing and evaluation of the effectiveness of information security policies, procedures, and practices, to be performed with a frequency depending on risk, but no less than annually, of which such testing—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall include testing of management, operational, and technical controls of every information system identified in the inventory required under section 3505(c); <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002040">1</ref></content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> may include testing relied on in an evaluation under section 3555; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> shall include using automated tools, consistent with standards and guidelines promulgated under <ref>section 11331 of title 40</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> a process for planning, implementing, evaluating, and documenting remedial action to address any deficiencies in the information security policies, procedures, and practices of the agency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<chapeau> procedures for detecting, reporting, and responding to security incidents, which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall be consistent with the standards and guidelines described in section 3556(b);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> may include using automated tools; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> shall include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> mitigating risks associated with such incidents before substantial damage is done;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> notifying and consulting with the Federal information security incident center established in section 3556; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> notifying and consulting with, as appropriate—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> law enforcement agencies and relevant Offices of Inspector General and Offices of General Counsel;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> an office designated by the President for any incident involving a national security system;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<chapeau> for a major incident, the committees of Congress described in subsection (c)(1)—</chapeau>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> not later than 7 days after the date on which there is a reasonable basis to conclude that the major incident has occurred; and</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> after the initial notification under item (aa), within a reasonable period of time after additional information relating to the incident is discovered, including the summary required under subsection (c)(1)(A)(i); and</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> any other agency or office, in accordance with law or as directed by the President; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> plans and procedures to ensure continuity of operations for information systems that support the operations and assets of the agency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Agency Reporting.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Annual report.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each agency shall submit to the Director, the Secretary, the Committee on Government Reform, the Committee on Homeland Security, and the Committee on Science of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate, the appropriate authorization and appropriations committees of Congress, and the Comptroller General a report on the adequacy and effectiveness of information security policies, procedures, and practices, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> a description of each major information security incident or related sets of incidents, including summaries of—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the threats and threat actors, vulnerabilities, and impacts relating to the incident;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the risk assessments conducted under section 3554(a)(2)(A) of the affected information systems before the date on which the incident occurred;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> the status of compliance of the affected information systems with applicable security requirements at the time of the incident; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> the detection, response, and remediation actions;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the total number of information security incidents, including a description of incidents resulting in significant compromise of information security, system impact levels, types of incident, and locations of affected systems;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> a description of each major information security incident that involved a breach of personally identifiable information, as defined by the Director, including—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the number of individuals whose information was affected by the major information security incident; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> a description of the information that was breached or exposed; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> any other information as the Director or the Secretary, in consultation with the Director, may require.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Unclassified report.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each report submitted under subparagraph (A) shall be in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Access to information</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The head of an agency shall ensure that, to the greatest extent practicable, information is included in the unclassified version of the reports submitted by the agency under subparagraph (A).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Other plans and reports</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each agency shall address the adequacy and effectiveness of information security policies, procedures, and practices in management plans and reports.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Performance Plan</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> In addition to the requirements of subsection (c), each agency, in consultation with the Director, shall include as part of the performance plan required under <ref>section 1115 of title 31</ref> a description of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the time periods; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the resources, including budget, staffing, and training,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">that are necessary to implement the program required under subsection (b).</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The description under paragraph (1) shall be based on the risk assessments required under subsection (b)(1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Public Notice and Comment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each agency shall provide the public with timely notice and opportunities for comment on proposed information security policies and procedures to the extent that such policies and procedures affect communication with the public.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 113–283, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-18">Dec. 18, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3078</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 114–113, div. N, title II, § 229(b)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-18">Dec. 18, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 2974</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–390, title II, § 204(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5193</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3555.</num>
<heading> Annual independent evaluation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Each year each agency shall have performed an independent evaluation of the information security program and practices of that agency to determine the effectiveness of such program and practices.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Each evaluation under this section shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> testing of the effectiveness of information security policies, procedures, and practices of a representative subset of the agency’s information systems;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an assessment of the effectiveness of the information security policies, procedures, and practices of the agency; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> separate presentations, as appropriate, regarding information security relating to national security systems.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Independent Auditor</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subject to subsection (c)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> for each agency with an Inspector General appointed under chapter 4 of title 5, the annual evaluation required by this section shall be performed by the Inspector General or by an independent external auditor, as determined by the Inspector General of the agency; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> for each agency to which paragraph (1) does not apply, the head of the agency shall engage an independent external auditor to perform the evaluation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">National Security Systems</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For each agency operating or exercising control of a national security system, that portion of the evaluation required by this section directly relating to a national security system shall be performed—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> only by an entity designated by the agency head; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in such a manner as to ensure appropriate protection for information associated with any information security vulnerability in such system commensurate with the risk and in accordance with all applicable laws.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Existing Evaluations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The evaluation required by this section may be based in whole or in part on an audit, evaluation, or report relating to programs or practices of the applicable agency.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Agency Reporting</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Each year, not later than such date established by the Director, the head of each agency shall submit to the Director the results of the evaluation required under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> To the extent an evaluation required under this section directly relates to a national security system, the evaluation results submitted to the Director shall contain only a summary and assessment of that portion of the evaluation directly relating to a national security system.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Protection of Information</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Agencies and evaluators shall take appropriate steps to ensure the protection of information which, if disclosed, may adversely affect information security. Such protections shall be commensurate with the risk and comply with all applicable laws and regulations.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">OMB Reports to Congress</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Director shall summarize the results of the evaluations conducted under this section in the report to Congress required under section 3553(c).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Director’s report to Congress under this subsection shall summarize information regarding information security relating to national security systems in such a manner as to ensure appropriate protection for information associated with any information security vulnerability in such system commensurate with the risk and in accordance with all applicable laws.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Evaluations and any other descriptions of information systems under the authority and control of the Director of National Intelligence or of National Foreign Intelligence Programs systems under the authority and control of the Secretary of Defense shall be made available to Congress only through the appropriate oversight committees of Congress, in accordance with applicable laws.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Comptroller General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Comptroller General shall periodically evaluate and report to Congress on—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the adequacy and effectiveness of agency information security policies and practices; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> implementation of the requirements of this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Assessment Technical Assistance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Comptroller General may provide technical assistance to an Inspector General or the head of an agency, as applicable, to assist the Inspector General or head of an agency in carrying out the duties under this section, including by testing information security controls and procedures.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Guidance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Director, in consultation with the Secretary, the Chief Information Officers Council established under section 3603, the Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency, and other interested parties as appropriate, shall ensure the development of guidance for evaluating the effectiveness of an information security program and practices.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 113–283, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-18">Dec. 18, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3082</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(b)(89)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4352</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3556.</num>
<heading> Federal information security incident center</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall ensure the operation of a central Federal information security incident center to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provide timely technical assistance to operators of agency information systems regarding security incidents, including guidance on detecting and handling information security incidents;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> compile and analyze information about incidents that threaten information security;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> inform operators of agency information systems about current and potential information security threats, and vulnerabilities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> provide, as appropriate, intelligence and other information about cyber threats, vulnerabilities, and incidents to agencies to assist in risk assessments conducted under section 3554(b); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> consult with the National Institute of Standards and Technology, agencies or offices operating or exercising control of national security systems (including the National Security Agency), and such other agencies or offices in accordance with law and as directed by the President regarding information security incidents and related matters.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">National Security Systems</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each agency operating or exercising control of a national security system shall share information about information security incidents, threats, and vulnerabilities with the Federal information security incident center to the extent consistent with standards and guidelines for national security systems, issued in accordance with law and as directed by the President.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 113–283, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-18">Dec. 18, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3084</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3557.</num>
<heading> National security systems</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The head of each agency operating or exercising control of a national security system shall be responsible for ensuring that the agency—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provides information security protections commensurate with the risk and magnitude of the harm resulting from the unauthorized access, use, disclosure, disruption, modification, or destruction of the information contained in such system;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> implements information security policies and practices as required by standards and guidelines for national security systems, issued in accordance with law and as directed by the President; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> complies with the requirements of this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 113–283, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-18">Dec. 18, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3084</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3558.</num>
<heading> Effect on existing law</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this subchapter, <ref>section 11331 of title 40</ref>, or section 20 of the National Standards <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002041">1</ref> and Technology Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 278g–3</ref>) may be construed as affecting the authority of the President, the Office of Management and Budget or the Director thereof, the National Institute of Standards and Technology, or the head of any agency, with respect to the authorized use or disclosure of information, including with regard to the protection of personal privacy under <ref>section 552a of title 5</ref>, the disclosure of information under <ref>section 552 of title 5</ref>, the management and disposition of records under chapters <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002042">2</ref> 29, 31, or 33 of title 44, the management of information resources under subchapter I of chapter 35 of this title, or the disclosure of information to the Congress or the Comptroller General of the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 113–283, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-18">Dec. 18, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3084</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3559.</num>
<heading> Federal websites required to be mobile friendly</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If, on or after the date that is 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section, an agency creates a website that is intended for use by the public or conducts a redesign of an existing legacy website that is intended for use by the public, the agency shall ensure to the greatest extent practicable that the website is mobile friendly.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Agency</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “agency” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 551 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Mobile friendly</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “mobile friendly” means, with respect to a website, that the website is configured in such a way that the website may be navigated, viewed, and accessed on a smartphone, tablet computer, or similar mobile device.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–114, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-01-10">Jan. 10, 2018</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 2278</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>CONFIDENTIAL INFORMATION PROTECTION AND STATISTICAL EFFICIENCY</heading>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part A—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">General</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3561.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this subchapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Agency</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “agency” means any entity that falls within the definition of the term “executive agency”, as defined in <ref>section 102 of title 31</ref>, or “agency”, as defined in section 3502.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Agent</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “agent” means an individual—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> who is an employee of a private organization or a researcher affiliated with an institution of higher learning (including a person granted special sworn status by the Bureau of the Census under <ref>section 23(c) of title 13</ref>), and with whom a contract or other agreement is executed, on a temporary basis, by an executive agency to perform exclusively statistical activities under the control and supervision of an officer or employee of that agency;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> who is working under the authority of a government entity with which a contract or other agreement is executed by an executive agency to perform exclusively statistical activities under the control of an officer or employee of that agency;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> who is a self-employed researcher, a consultant, a contractor, or an employee of a contractor, and with whom a contract or other agreement is executed by an executive agency to perform a statistical activity under the control of an officer or employee of that agency; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> who is a contractor or an employee of a contractor, and who is engaged by the agency to design or maintain the systems for handling or storage of data received under this subchapter; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> who agrees in writing to comply with all provisions of law that affect information acquired by that agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Business data</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “business data” means operating and financial data and information about businesses, tax-exempt organizations, and government entities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Data asset</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “data asset” has the meaning given that term in section 3502.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Director</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “Director” means the Director of the Office of Management and Budget.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Evidence</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “evidence” means information produced as a result of statistical activities conducted for a statistical purpose.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Identifiable form</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “identifiable form” means any representation of information that permits the identity of the respondent to whom the information applies to be reasonably inferred by either direct or indirect means.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Nonstatistical purpose</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “nonstatistical purpose”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> means the use of data in identifiable form for any purpose that is not a statistical purpose, including any administrative, regulatory, law enforcement, adjudicatory, or other purpose that affects the rights, privileges, or benefits of a particular identifiable respondent; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> includes the disclosure under <ref>section 552 of title 5</ref> of data that are acquired for exclusively statistical purposes under a pledge of confidentiality.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Respondent</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “respondent” means a person who, or organization that, is requested or required to supply information to an agency, is the subject of information requested or required to be supplied to an agency, or provides that information to an agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Statistical activities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “statistical activities”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> means the collection, compilation, processing, or analysis of data for the purpose of describing or making estimates concerning the whole, or relevant groups or components within, the economy, society, or the natural environment; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> includes the development of methods or resources that support those activities, such as measurement methods, models, statistical classifications, or sampling frames.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Statistical agency or unit</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “statistical agency or unit” means an agency or organizational unit of the executive branch whose activities are predominantly the collection, compilation, processing, or analysis of information for statistical purposes, as designated by the Director under section 3562.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Statistical purpose</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “statistical purpose”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> means the description, estimation, or analysis of the characteristics of groups, without identifying the individuals or organizations that comprise such groups; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> includes the development, implementation, or maintenance of methods, technical or administrative procedures, or information resources that support the purposes described in subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–435, title III, § 302(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-01-14">Jan. 14, 2019</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5544</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3562.</num>
<heading> Coordination and oversight of policies</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Director shall coordinate and oversee the confidentiality and disclosure policies established by this subchapter. The Director may promulgate rules or provide other guidance to ensure consistent interpretation of this subchapter by the affected agencies. The Director shall develop a process by which the Director designates agencies or organizational units as statistical agencies and units. The Director shall promulgate guidance to implement such process, which shall include specific criteria for such designation and methods by which the Director will ensure transparency in the process.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Agency Rules</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to subsection (c), agencies may promulgate rules to implement this subchapter. Rules governing disclosures of information that are authorized by this subchapter shall be promulgated by the agency that originally collected the information.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Review and Approval of Rules</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Director shall review any rules proposed by an agency pursuant to this subchapter for consistency with the provisions of this chapter and such rules shall be subject to the approval of the Director.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Reports.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The head of each agency shall provide to the Director such reports and other information as the Director requests.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Each Designated Statistical Agency (as defined in section 3576(e)) shall report annually to the Director, the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate on the actions it has taken to implement section 3576. The report shall include copies of each written agreement entered into pursuant to section 3576(c)(1) for the applicable year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Director shall include a summary of reports submitted to the Director under this subsection and actions taken by the Director to advance the purposes of this subchapter in the annual report to Congress on statistical programs prepared under section 3504(e)(2).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–435, title III, § 302(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-01-14">Jan. 14, 2019</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5546</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3563.</num>
<heading> Statistical agencies</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Responsibilities.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each statistical agency or unit shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> produce and disseminate relevant and timely statistical information;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> conduct credible and accurate statistical activities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> conduct objective statistical activities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> protect the trust of information providers by ensuring the confidentiality and exclusive statistical use of their responses.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Policies, best practices, and procedures</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each statistical agency or unit shall adopt policies, best practices, and appropriate procedures to implement the responsibilities described in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Support From Other Agencies</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The head of each agency shall enable, support, and facilitate statistical agencies or units in carrying out the responsibilities described in subsection (a)(1).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Director shall prescribe regulations to carry out this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Accurate</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “accurate”, when used with respect to statistical activities, means statistics that consistently match the events and trends being measured.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Confidentiality</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “confidentiality” means a quality or condition accorded to information as an obligation not to disclose that information to an unauthorized party.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Objective</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “objective”, when used with respect to statistical activities, means accurate, clear, complete, and unbiased.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Relevant</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “relevant”, when used with respect to statistical information, means processes, activities, and other such matters likely to be useful to policymakers and public and private sector data users.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–435, title III, § 302(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-01-14">Jan. 14, 2019</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5546</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3564.</num>
<heading> Effect on other laws</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Title</inline> 44, <inline class="small-caps">United States Code</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This subchapter does not diminish the authority under section 3510 of the Director to direct, and of an agency to make, disclosures that are not inconsistent with any applicable law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Title</inline> 13 <inline class="small-caps">and Title</inline> 44, <inline class="small-caps">United States Code</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This subchapter does not diminish the authority of the Bureau of the Census to provide information in accordance with sections 8, 16, 301, and 401 of title 13 and <ref>section 2108 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Title</inline> 13, <inline class="small-caps">United States Code</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This subchapter shall not be construed as authorizing the disclosure for nonstatistical purposes of demographic data or information collected by the Bureau of the Census pursuant to <ref>section 9 of title 13</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Various Energy Statutes</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Data or information acquired by the Energy Information Administration under a pledge of confidentiality and designated by the Energy Information Administration to be used for exclusively statistical purposes shall not be disclosed in identifiable form for nonstatistical purposes under—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> section 12, 20, or 59 of the Federal Energy Administration Act of 1974 (<ref>15 U.S.C. 771</ref>, 779, 790h);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> section 11 of the Energy Supply and Environmental Coordination Act of 1974 (<ref>15 U.S.C. 796</ref>); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> section 205 or 407 of the Department of Energy Organization Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 7135</ref>, 7177).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Section</inline> 201 <inline class="small-caps">of Congressional Budget Act of</inline> 1974.—</heading>
<content>This subchapter shall not be construed to limit any authorities of the Congressional Budget Office to work (consistent with laws governing the confidentiality of information the disclosure of which would be a violation of law) with databases of Designated Statistical Agencies (as defined in section 3576(e)), either separately or, for data that may be shared pursuant to section 3576(c) or other authority, jointly in order to improve the general utility of these databases for the statistical purpose of analyzing pension and health care financing issues.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Preemption of State Law</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this subchapter shall preempt applicable State law regarding the confidentiality of data collected by the States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Statutes Regarding False Statements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding section 3572, information collected by an agency for exclusively statistical purposes under a pledge of confidentiality may be provided by the collecting agency to a law enforcement agency for the prosecution of submissions to the collecting agency of false statistical information under statutes that authorize criminal penalties (such as <ref>section 221 of title 13</ref>) or civil penalties for the provision of false statistical information, unless such disclosure or use would otherwise be prohibited under Federal law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Construction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this subchapter shall be construed as restricting or diminishing any confidentiality protections or penalties for unauthorized disclosure that otherwise apply to data or information collected for statistical purposes or nonstatistical purposes, including, but not limited to, section 6103 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority of Congress</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this subchapter shall be construed to affect the authority of the Congress, including its committees, members, or agents, to obtain data or information for a statistical purpose, including for oversight of an agency’s statistical activities.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–435, title III, § 302(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-01-14">Jan. 14, 2019</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5547</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part B—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Confidential Information Protection</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3571.</num>
<heading> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress finds the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Individuals, businesses, and other organizations have varying degrees of legal protection when providing information to the agencies for strictly statistical purposes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Pledges of confidentiality by agencies provide assurances to the public that information about individuals or organizations or provided by individuals or organizations for exclusively statistical purposes will be held in confidence and will not be used against such individuals or organizations in any agency action.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Protecting the confidentiality interests of individuals or organizations who provide information under a pledge of confidentiality for Federal statistical programs serves both the interests of the public and the needs of society.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Declining trust of the public in the protection of information provided under a pledge of confidentiality to the agencies adversely affects both the accuracy and completeness of statistical analyses.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Ensuring that information provided under a pledge of confidentiality for statistical purposes receives protection is essential in continuing public cooperation in statistical programs.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–435, title III, § 302(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-01-14">Jan. 14, 2019</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5548</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3572.</num>
<heading> Confidential information protection</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Purposes</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The purposes of this section are the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> To ensure that information supplied by individuals or organizations to an agency for statistical purposes under a pledge of confidentiality is used exclusively for statistical purposes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> To ensure that individuals or organizations who supply information under a pledge of confidentiality to agencies for statistical purposes will neither have that information disclosed in identifiable form to anyone not authorized by this subchapter nor have that information used for any purpose other than a statistical purpose.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> To safeguard the confidentiality of individually identifiable information acquired under a pledge of confidentiality for statistical purposes by controlling access to, and uses made of, such information.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of Statistical Data or Information</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Data or information acquired by an agency under a pledge of confidentiality and for exclusively statistical purposes shall be used by officers, employees, or agents of the agency exclusively for statistical purposes and protected in accordance with such pledge.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Disclosure of Statistical Data or Information.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Data or information acquired by an agency under a pledge of confidentiality for exclusively statistical purposes shall not be disclosed by an agency in identifiable form, for any use other than an exclusively statistical purpose, except with the informed consent of the respondent.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A disclosure pursuant to paragraph (1) is authorized only when the head of the agency approves such disclosure and the disclosure is not prohibited by any other law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> This section does not restrict or diminish any confidentiality protections in law that otherwise apply to data or information acquired by an agency under a pledge of confidentiality for exclusively statistical purposes.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rule for Use of Data or Information for Nonstatistical Purposes</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A statistical agency or unit shall clearly distinguish any data or information it collects for nonstatistical purposes (as authorized by law) and provide notice to the public, before the data or information is collected, that the data or information could be used for nonstatistical purposes.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designation of Agents</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A statistical agency or unit may designate agents, by contract or by entering into a special agreement containing the provisions required under section 3561(2) for treatment as an agent under that section, who may perform exclusively statistical activities, subject to the limitations and penalties described in this subchapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Fines and Penalties</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Whoever, being an officer, employee, or agent of an agency acquiring information for exclusively statistical purposes, having taken and subscribed the oath of office, or having sworn to observe the limitations imposed by this section, comes into possession of such information by reason of his or her being an officer, employee, or agent and, knowing that the disclosure of the specific information is prohibited under the provisions of this subchapter, willfully discloses the information in any manner to a person or agency not entitled to receive it, shall be guilty of a class E felony and imprisoned for not more than 5 years, or fined not more than $250,000, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–435, title III, § 302(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-01-14">Jan. 14, 2019</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5548</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part C—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Statistical Efficiency</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3575.</num>
<heading> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress finds the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Federal statistics are an important source of information for public and private decision-makers such as policymakers, consumers, businesses, investors, and workers.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Federal statistical agencies should continuously seek to improve their efficiency. Statutory constraints limit the ability of these agencies to share data and thus to achieve higher efficiency for Federal statistical programs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The quality of Federal statistics depends on the willingness of businesses to respond to statistical surveys. Reducing reporting burdens will increase response rates, and therefore lead to more accurate characterizations of the economy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Enhanced sharing of business data among the Bureau of the Census, the Bureau of Economic Analysis, and the Bureau of Labor Statistics for exclusively statistical purposes will improve their ability to track more accurately the large and rapidly changing nature of United States business. In particular, the statistical agencies will be able to better ensure that businesses are consistently classified in appropriate industries, resolve data anomalies, produce statistical samples that are consistently adjusted for the entry and exit of new businesses in a timely manner, and correct faulty reporting errors quickly and efficiently.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Congress enacted the International Investment and Trade in Services Survey Act (<ref>Public Law 94–472</ref>), which allowed the Bureau of the Census, the Bureau of Economic Analysis, and the Bureau of Labor Statistics to share data on foreign-owned companies. The Act not only expanded detailed industry coverage from 135 industries to over 800 industries with no increase in the data collected from respondents but also demonstrated how data sharing can result in the creation of valuable data products.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> With part B of this subchapter, the sharing of business data among the Bureau of the Census, the Bureau of Economic Analysis, and the Bureau of Labor Statistics continues to ensure the highest level of confidentiality for respondents to statistical surveys.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–435, title III, § 302(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-01-14">Jan. 14, 2019</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5549</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3576.</num>
<heading> Designated statistical agencies</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Purposes</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The purposes of this section are the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> To authorize the sharing of business data among the Bureau of the Census, the Bureau of Economic Analysis, and the Bureau of Labor Statistics for exclusively statistical purposes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> To reduce the paperwork burdens imposed on businesses that provide requested information to the Federal Government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> To improve the comparability and accuracy of Federal economic statistics by allowing the Bureau of the Census, the Bureau of Economic Analysis, and the Bureau of Labor Statistics to update sample frames, develop consistent classifications of establishments and companies into industries, improve coverage, and reconcile significant differences in data produced by the three agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> To increase understanding of the United States economy, especially for key industry and regional statistics, to develop more accurate measures of the impact of technology on productivity growth, and to enhance the reliability of the Nation’s most important economic indicators, such as the National Income and Product Accounts.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Responsibilities of Designated Statistical Agencies</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The head of each of the Designated Statistical Agencies shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> identify opportunities to eliminate duplication and otherwise reduce reporting burden and cost imposed on the public in providing information for statistical purposes;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> enter into joint statistical projects to improve the quality and reduce the cost of statistical programs; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> protect the confidentiality of individually identifiable information acquired for statistical purposes by adhering to safeguard principles, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> emphasizing to their officers, employees, and agents the importance of protecting the confidentiality of information in cases where the identity of individual respondents can reasonably be inferred by either direct or indirect means;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> training their officers, employees, and agents in their legal obligations to protect the confidentiality of individually identifiable information and in the procedures that must be followed to provide access to such information;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> implementing appropriate measures to assure the physical and electronic security of confidential data;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> establishing a system of records that identifies individuals accessing confidential data and the project for which the data were required; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> being prepared to document their compliance with safeguard principles to other agencies authorized by law to monitor such compliance.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Sharing of Business Data Among Designated Statistical Agencies.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A Designated Statistical Agency may provide business data in an identifiable form to another Designated Statistical Agency under the terms of a written agreement among the agencies sharing the business data that specifies—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the business data to be shared;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the statistical purposes for which the business data are to be used;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the officers, employees, and agents authorized to examine the business data to be shared; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> appropriate security procedures to safeguard the confidentiality of the business data.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Responsibilities of agencies under other laws</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The provision of business data by an agency to a Designated Statistical Agency under this section shall in no way alter the responsibility of the agency providing the data under other statutes (including sections 552 and 552b of title 5) with respect to the provision or withholding of such information by the agency providing the data.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Responsibilities of officers, employees, and agents</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Examination of business data in identifiable form shall be limited to the officers, employees, and agents authorized to examine the individual reports in accordance with written agreements pursuant to this section. Officers, employees, and agents of a Designated Statistical Agency who receive data pursuant to this section shall be subject to all provisions of law, including penalties, that relate—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to the unlawful provision of the business data that would apply to the officers, employees, and agents of the agency that originally obtained the information; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to the unlawful disclosure of the business data that would apply to officers, employees, and agents of the agency that originally obtained the information.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Whenever a written agreement concerns data that respondents were required by law to report and the respondents were not informed that the data could be shared among the Designated Statistical Agencies, for exclusively statistical purposes, the terms of such agreement shall be described in a public notice issued by the agency that intends to provide the data. Such notice shall allow a minimum of 60 days for public comment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Limitations on Use of Business Data Provided by Designated Statistical Agencies.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General use</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Business data provided by a Designated Statistical Agency pursuant to this section shall be used exclusively for statistical purposes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Publication</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Publication of business data acquired by a Designated Statistical Agency shall occur in a manner whereby the data furnished by any particular respondent are not in identifiable form.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designated Statistical Agency Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the term “Designated Statistical Agency” means each of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Census Bureau of the Department of Commerce.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Bureau of Economic Analysis of the Department of Commerce.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Bureau of Labor Statistics of the Department of Labor.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–435, title III, § 302(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-01-14">Jan. 14, 2019</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5550</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part D—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Access to Data for Evidence</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3581.</num>
<heading> Presumption of accessibility for statistical agencies and units</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Accessibility of Data Assets</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The head of an agency shall, to the extent practicable, make any data asset maintained by the agency available, upon request, to any statistical agency or unit for purposes of developing evidence.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subsection (a) does not apply to any data asset that is subject to a statute that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> prohibits the sharing or intended use of such asset in a manner as to leave no discretion on the issue; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> if enacted after the date of the enactment of this section, specifically cites to this paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Director shall prescribe regulations for agencies to carry out this section. Such regulations shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> require the timely provision of data assets under subsection (a);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provide a list of statutes that exempt agencies from the requirement under subsection (a) pursuant to subsection (b)(1);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> establish clear and consistent standards, to the extent possible, for complying with <ref>section 552a of title 5</ref> (commonly known as the “Privacy Act of 1974”) and any other applicable law requiring the protection and confidentiality of individually identifiable information; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> require a transparent process for statistical agencies and units to request data assets from agencies and for agencies to respond to such requests.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rule of Construction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section may be construed as altering existing intellectual property rights or the terms of any contract or other binding, written agreement.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–435, title III, § 303(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-01-14">Jan. 14, 2019</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5554</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3582.</num>
<heading> Expanding secure access to CIPSEA data assets</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Statistical Agency Responsibilities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>To the extent practicable, each statistical agency or unit shall expand access to data assets of such agency or unit acquired or accessed under this subchapter to develop evidence while protecting such assets from inappropriate access and use, in accordance with the regulations promulgated under subsection (b).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations for Accessibility of Nonpublic Data Assets</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Director shall promulgate regulations, in accordance with applicable law, for statistical agencies and units to carry out the requirement under subsection (a). Such regulations shall include the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Standards for each statistical agency or unit to assess each data asset owned or accessed by the statistical agency or unit for purposes of categorizing the sensitivity level of each such asset and identifying the corresponding level of accessibility to each such asset. Such standards shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> common sensitivity levels and corresponding levels of accessibility that may be assigned to a data asset, including a requisite minimum and maximum number of sensitivity levels for each statistical agency or unit to use;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> criteria for determining the sensitivity level and corresponding level of accessibility of each data asset; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> criteria for determining whether a less sensitive and more accessible version of a data asset can be produced.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Standards for each statistical agency or unit to improve access to a data asset pursuant to paragraph (1) or (3) by removing or obscuring information in such a manner that the identity of the data subject is less likely to be reasonably inferred by either direct or indirect means.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A requirement for each statistical agency or unit to conduct a comprehensive risk assessment of any data asset acquired or accessed under this subchapter prior to any public release of such asset, including standards for such comprehensive risk assessment and criteria for making a determination of whether to release the data.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> Requirements for each statistical agency or unit to make any process or assessment established, produced, or conducted pursuant to this section transparent and easy to understand, including the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A requirement to make information on the assessment of the sensitivity level of each data asset conducted pursuant to paragraph (1) available on the Federal data catalogue established under section 3511(c)(1).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A requirement to make any comprehensive risk assessment, and associated determinations, conducted under paragraph (3) available on the Federal data catalogue established under section 3511(c)(1).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> A requirement to make any standard or policy established by the statistical agency or unit to carry out this section and any assessment conducted under this section easily accessible on the public website of such agency or unit.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Responsibilities of the Director</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Director shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> make public all standards and policies established under this section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> ensure that statistical agencies and units have the ability to make information public on the Federal data catalogue established under section 3511(c)(1), in accordance with requirements established pursuant to subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–435, title III, § 303(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-01-14">Jan. 14, 2019</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5554</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3583.</num>
<heading> Application to access data assets for developing evidence</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Standard Application Process</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Director shall establish a process through which agencies, the Congressional Budget Office, State, local, and Tribal governments, researchers, and other individuals, as appropriate, may apply to access the data assets accessed or acquired under this subchapter by a statistical agency or unit for purposes of developing evidence. The process shall include the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Sufficient detail to ensure that each statistical agency or unit establishes an identical process.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A common application form.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Criteria for statistical agencies and units to determine whether to grant an applicant access to a data asset.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Timeframes for prompt determinations by each statistical agency or unit.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> An appeals process for adverse decisions and noncompliance with the process established under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> Standards for transparency, including requirements to make the following information publicly available:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Each application received.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The status of each application.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The determination made for each application.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Any other information, as appropriate, to ensure full transparency of the process established under this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consultation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In establishing the process required under subsection (a), the Director shall consult with stakeholders, including the public, agencies, State and local governments, and representatives of non-governmental researchers.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Implementation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The head of each statistical agency or unit shall implement the process established under subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–435, title III, § 303(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-01-14">Jan. 14, 2019</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5555</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
</subchapter>
</chapter>