<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 1—</num>
<heading>JOINT COMMITTEE ON PRINTING</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 101.</num>
<heading> Joint Committee on Printing: membership</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Joint Committee on Printing shall consist of the chairman and four members of the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate and the chairman and four members of the Committee on House Oversight of the House of Representatives.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–620</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1238</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–4</ref>, <date date="1981-02-17">Feb. 17, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 6</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–186, title II, § 223(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1751</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 102.</num>
<heading> Joint Committee on Printing: succession; powers during recess</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The members of the Joint Committee on Printing who are reelected to the succeeding Congress shall continue as members of the committee until their successors are chosen. The President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives shall, on the last day of a Congress, appoint members of their respective Houses who have been elected to the succeeding Congress to fill vacancies which may then be about to occur on the Committee, and the appointees and members of the Committee who have been reelected shall continue until their successors are chosen.</p>
<p class="indent0">When Congress is not in session, the Joint Committee may exercise all its powers and duties as when Congress is in session.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–620</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1238</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 103.</num>
<heading> Joint Committee on Printing: remedial powers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Joint Committee on Printing may use any measures it considers necessary to remedy neglect, delay, duplication, or waste in the public printing and binding and the distribution of Government publications.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–620</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1239</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>