<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 27—</num>
<heading>ADVISORY COMMITTEE ON THE RECORDS OF CONGRESS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2701.</num>
<heading> Advisory Committee on the Records of Congress</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> There is established the Advisory Committee on the Records of Congress (hereafter in this chapter referred to as the Committee).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Committee shall be subject to the provisions of chapter 10 of title 5, except that the Committee shall be of permanent duration, notwithstanding any provision of <ref>section 1013 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–509, title IV, § 1(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1417</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(a)(287)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4337</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2702.</num>
<heading> Membership; chairman; meetings</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Committee shall consist of the eleven members including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Secretary of the Senate;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the Clerk of the House of Representatives;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the Archivist of the United States;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the Historian of the Senate; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> the Historian of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> six members of whom one shall be appointed by each of the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Speaker of the House of Representatives;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the Minority Leader of the House of Representatives;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the Majority Leader of the Senate;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the Minority Leader of the Senate;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> the Secretary of the Senate; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> the Clerk of the House of Representatives.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Each member appointed under paragraph (1)(B) shall have knowledge or expertise in United States history, archival management, publishing, library science, or use of legislative records.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Senate shall serve as Chairman during the two-year period beginning on <date date="1991-01-01">January 1, 1991</date>, and the Clerk of the House of Representatives shall serve as Chairman during the two-year period beginning on <date date="1993-01-01">January 1, 1993</date>. Thereafter, such members shall alternate serving as Chairman for a term of two years.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Members of the Committee referred to in subsection (a)(1)(A) shall serve only while holding such offices. Members appointed to the Committee under subsection (a)(1)(B) shall serve for a term of two years, and may be reappointed without limitation. The initial appointments for such terms shall begin on <date date="1991-01-01">January 1, 1991</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any vacancy on the Committee shall not affect the powers of the Committee. Any vacancy in an appointed position on the Committee shall be filled in the same manner in which the original appointment was made.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> No later than thirty days after the date on which the first session of the 102d Congress begins, the Committee shall hold its first meeting. Thereafter, the Committee shall meet semiannually or at the call of a majority of its members.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Seven members of the Committee shall constitute a quorum, but a lesser number may hold hearings.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–509, title IV, § 1(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1417</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2703.</num>
<heading> Functions of the Committee</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Committee shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> review the management and preservation of the records of Congress;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> report to and advise the Congress and the Archivist of the United States on such management and preservation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> no later than <date date="1991-12-31">December 31, 1991</date>, conduct a study and submit a report to the Congress on—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the effect any transfer of records of the National Archives and Records Administration from facilities located in Washington, D.C., to any location outside of Washington, D.C., shall have on the management and preservation of the records of Congress; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the five year plan for the management and preservation of the records of Congress; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> no later than <date date="1995-12-31">December 31, 1995</date>, conduct a study to update the report submitted under subparagraph (A)(ii), and submit a report to the Congress.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–509, title IV, § 1(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1418</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2704.</num>
<heading> Powers of the Committee</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> For purposes of carrying out the duties referred to under section 2703, the Committee or, on the authorization of the Committee, any subcommittee or member thereof, may hold such hearings, sit and act at such times and places, take such testimony, and receive such evidence as is appropriate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Committee may secure directly from any department or agency of the United States such information as the Committee may require to carry out the duties referred to under section 2703. Upon request of the Chairman of the Committee, the head of such department or agency shall furnish such information to the Committee.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–509, title IV, § 1(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1418</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2705.</num>
<heading> Compensation and travel expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A member of the Committee may not be paid compensation for service performed as a member of the Committee. However, members of the Committee shall be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, at rates authorized for employees of agencies under subchapter I of chapter 57 of title 5, United States Code, while away from their homes or regular places of business in the performance of service for the Committee.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–509, title IV, § 1(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1418</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2706.</num>
<heading> Administrative provisions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Upon request of the Committee, the head of any Federal agency is authorized to detail to the Committee, on a nonreimbursable basis, any of the personnel of such agency to assist the Committee in carrying out the duties referred to under section 2703 and such detail shall be without interruption or loss of civil service status or privilege.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> For purposes of supporting the Committee, the Archivist may obtain the services of experts and consultants in accordance with the provisions of <ref>section 3109 of title 5</ref>, United States Code, but at rates for individuals not to exceed the daily equivalent of the minimum annual rate of basic pay payable for GS–16 of the General Schedule under section 5332 of such title.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–509, title IV, § 1(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1418</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>