<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 9—</num>
<heading>CONGRESSIONAL RECORD</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 901.</num>
<heading> Congressional Record: arrangement, style, contents, and indexes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Joint Committee on Printing shall control the arrangement and style of the Congressional Record, and while providing that it shall be substantially a verbatim report of proceedings, shall take all needed action for the reduction of unnecessary bulk. It shall provide for the publication of an index of the Congressional Record semimonthly during and at the close of sessions of Congress.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–620</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1255</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 902.</num>
<heading> Congressional Record: Indexes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director of the Government Publishing Office shall prepare the semimonthly and the session index to the Congressional Record. The Joint Committee on Printing shall direct the form and manner of its publication and distribution.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–620</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1256</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–102, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="2003-10-29">Oct. 29, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1198</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–235, div. H, title I, § 1301(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-16">Dec. 16, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 2537</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 903.</num>
<heading> Congressional Record: daily and permanent forms</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The public proceedings of each House of Congress as reported by the Official Reporters, shall be printed in the Congressional Record, which shall be issued in daily form during each session and shall be revised, printed, and bound promptly, as directed by the Joint Committee on Printing, in permanent form, for distribution during and after the close of each session of Congress. The daily and the permanent Record shall bear the same date, which shall be that of the actual day’s proceedings reported. The “usual number” of the Congressional Record may not be printed.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–620</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1256</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 904.</num>
<heading> Congressional Record: maps; diagrams; illustrations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Maps, diagrams, or illustrations may not be inserted in the Record without the approval of the Joint Committee on Printing.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–620</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1256</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 905.</num>
<heading> Congressional Record: additional insertions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Joint Committee on Printing shall provide for printing in the daily Record the legislative program for the day together with a list of congressional committee meetings and hearings, and the place of meeting and subject matter. It shall cause a brief resume of congressional activities for the previous day to be incorporated in the Record, together with an index of its contents prepared under the supervision of the Secretary of the Senate and the Clerk of the House of Representatives, respectively.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–620</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1256</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 906.</num>
<heading> Congressional Record: gratuitous copies; delivery</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director of the Government Publishing Office shall furnish the Congressional Record only as follows:</p>
<p class="indent0">of the bound edition—</p>
<p class="indent1">to the Senate Service Department five copies for the Vice President and each Senator;</p>
<p class="indent1">to the Secretary and Sergeant at Arms of the Senate, each, two copies;</p>
<p class="indent1">to the Joint Committee on Printing not to exceed one hundred copies;</p>
<p class="indent1">to the House of Representatives Publications Distribution Service, three copies for each Representative and Resident Commissioner in Congress; and</p>
<p class="indent1">to the Clerk and the Sergeant at Arms of the House of Representatives, each, two copies;</p>
<p class="indent0">of the daily edition—</p>
<p class="indent1">to the Vice President, one hundred copies;</p>
<p class="indent1">to each Senator, fifty copies (which may be transferred only to public agencies and institutions);</p>
<p class="indent1">to the Secretary and Sergeant at Arms of the Senate, each, twenty-five copies;</p>
<p class="indent1">to the Secretary, for official use, not to exceed thirty-five copies; and</p>
<p class="indent1">to the Sergeant at Arms for use on the floor of the Senate, not to exceed fifty copies;</p>
<p class="indent1">to each Member of the House of Representatives, the Resident Commissioner from Puerto Rico, the Delegate from the District of Columbia, the Delegate from Guam, and the Delegate from the Virgin Islands, thirty-four copies (which may be transferred only to public agencies and institutions);</p>
<p class="indent1">to the Clerk and the Sergeant at Arms of the House of Representatives, each, twenty-five copies;</p>
<p class="indent1">to the Clerk, for official use, not to exceed fifty copies, and to the Clerk for use on the floor of the House of Representatives, not to exceed seventy-five copies;</p>
<p class="indent1">to the Vice President and each Senator, Representative, and Resident Commissioner in Congress (and not transferable) three copies of which one shall be delivered at his residence, one at his office, and one at the Capitol.</p>
<p class="indent0">In addition to the foregoing the Congressional Record shall also be furnished as follows:</p>
<p class="indent0">In unstitched form, and held in reserve by the Director of the Government Publishing Office, as many copies of the daily Record as may be required to supply a semimonthly edition, bound in paper cover together with each semimonthly index when it is issued, and then be delivered promptly as follows:</p>
<p class="indent1">to each committee and commission of Congress, one daily and one semimonthly copy;</p>
<p class="indent1">to each joint committee and joint commission in Congress, as may be designated by the Joint Committee on Printing, two copies of the daily, one semimonthly copy, and one bound copy;</p>
<p class="indent1">to the Secretary and the Sergeant at Arms of the Senate, for office use, each, six semimonthly copies;</p>
<p class="indent1">to the Clerk and the Sergeant at Arms of the House, for office use, each, six semimonthly copies;</p>
<p class="indent1">to the Joint Committee on Printing, ten semimonthly copies;</p>
<p class="indent1">to the Vice President and each Senator, Representative, and Resident Commissioner in Congress, one semimonthly copy;</p>
<p class="indent1">to the President of the United States, for the use of the Executive Office, ten copies of the daily, two semimonthly copies, and one bound copy;</p>
<p class="indent1">to the Chief Justice of the United States and each of the Associate Justices of the Supreme Court of the United States, one copy of the daily;</p>
<p class="indent1">to the offices of the marshal and clerk of the Supreme Court of the United States, each, two copies of the daily and one semimonthly copy;</p>
<p class="indent1">to each United States circuit and district judge, and to the chief judge and each associate judge of the United States Court of Federal Claims, the United States Court of International Trade, the Tax Court of the United States, the United States Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims, and the United States Court of Appeals for the Armed Forces, upon request to a member of Congress and notification by the Member to the Director of the Government Publishing Office, one copy of the daily, in addition to those authorized to be furnished to Members of Congress under the preceding provisions of this section;</p>
<p class="indent1">to the offices of the Vice President and the Speaker of the House of Representatives, each, six copies of the daily and one semimonthly copy;</p>
<p class="indent1">to the Sergeant at Arms, the Chaplain, the Postmaster, the superintendent and the foreman of the Senate Service Department and of the House of Representatives Publications Distribution Service, respectively; and to the Secretaries to the Majority and the Minority of the Senate, each, one copy of the daily;</p>
<p class="indent1">to the office of the Parliamentarian of the House of Representatives, six copies of the daily, one semimonthly copy, and two bound copies;</p>
<p class="indent1">to the offices of the Official Reporters of Debates of the Senate and House of Representatives, respectively, each, fifteen copies of the daily, one semimonthly copy, and three bound copies;</p>
<p class="indent1">to the office of the stenographers to committees of the House of Representatives, four copies of the daily and one semimonthly copy;</p>
<p class="indent1">to the office of the Congressional Record Index, ten copies of the daily and two semimonthly copies;</p>
<p class="indent1">to the offices of the superintendent of the Senate and House document rooms, each, three copies of the daily, one semimonthly copy, and one bound copy;</p>
<p class="indent1">to the offices of the superintendents of the Senate and House press galleries, each, two copies of the daily, one semimonthly copy, and one bound copy;</p>
<p class="indent1">to the offices of the Legislative Counsel of the Senate and House of Representatives, respectively, and the Architect of the Capitol, each, three copies of the daily, one semimonthly copy, and one bound copy;</p>
<p class="indent1">to the Library of Congress for official use in Washington, District of Columbia, and for international exchange, as provided by sections 1718 and 1719 of this title, not to exceed one hundred and forty-five copies of the daily, five semimonthly copies, and one hundred and fifty bound copies;</p>
<p class="indent1">to the library of the Senate, three copies of the daily, two semimonthly copies, and not to exceed fifteen bound copies;</p>
<p class="indent1">to the library of the House of Representatives, five copies of the daily, two semimonthly copies, and not to exceed twenty-eight bound copies, of which eight copies may be bound in the style and manner approved by the Joint Committee on Printing;</p>
<p class="indent1">to the library of the Supreme Court of the United States, two copies of the daily, two semimonthly copies, and not to exceed five bound copies;</p>
<p class="indent1">to the library of each United States Court of Appeals, each United States District Court, the United States Court of Federal Claims, the United States Court of International Trade, the Tax Court of the United States, the United States Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims, and the United States Court of Appeals for the Armed Forces, upon request to the Director of the Government Publishing Office, one copy of the daily, one semimonthly copy, and one bound copy;</p>
<p class="indent1">to the Director of the Government Publishing Office for official use, not to exceed seventy-five copies of the daily, ten semimonthly copies, and two bound copies;</p>
<p class="indent1">to the Director of the Botanic Garden, two copies of the daily and one semimonthly copy;</p>
<p class="indent1">to the Archivist of the United States, five copies of the daily, two semimonthly copies, and two bound copies;</p>
<p class="indent1">to the library of each executive department, independent office, and establishment of the Government in the District of Columbia, except those designated as depository libraries, and to the libraries of the municipal government of the District of Columbia, the Naval Observatory, and the Smithsonian Institution, each, two copies of the daily, one semimonthly copy, and one bound copy;</p>
<p class="indent1">to the offices of the Governors of Puerto Rico, Guam and the Virgin Islands, each, five copies in both daily and bound form;</p>
<p class="indent1">to the office of the Governor of the Canal Zone, five copies in both daily and bound form;</p>
<p class="indent1">to each ex-President and ex-Vice President of the United States, one copy of the daily;</p>
<p class="indent1">to each former Senator, Representative, and Commissioner from Puerto Rico, upon request to the Director of the Government Publishing Office, one copy of the daily;</p>
<p class="indent1">to the Governor of each State, one copy in both daily and bound form;</p>
<p class="indent1">to each separate establishment of the Armed Forces Retirement Home, to each of the National Homes for Disabled Volunteer Soldiers, and to each of the State soldiers’ homes, one copy of the daily;</p>
<p class="indent1">to the Superintendent of Documents, as many daily and bound copies as may be required for distribution to depository libraries;</p>
<p class="indent1">to the Department of State, not to exceed one hundred and fifty copies of the daily, for distribution to each United States embassy and legation abroad, and to the principal consular offices in the discretion of the Secretary of State;</p>
<p class="indent1">to each foreign legation in Washington whose government extends a like courtesy to our embassies and legations abroad, one copy of the daily, to be furnished upon requisition of and sent through the Secretary of State;</p>
<p class="indent1">to each newspaper correspondent whose name appears in the Congressional Directory, and who makes application, for his personal use and that of the papers he represents, one copy of the daily and one copy of the bound, the same to be sent to the office address of the member of the press or elsewhere as he directs; not to exceed four copies in all may be furnished to members of the same press bureau.</p>
<p class="indent0">Copies of the daily edition, unless otherwise directed by the Joint Committee on Printing, shall be supplied and delivered promptly on the day after the actual day’s proceedings as originally published. Each order for the daily Record shall begin with the current issue, if previous issues of the same session are not available. The apportionment specified for daily copies may not be transferred for the bound form and an allotment of daily copies not used by a Member during a session shall lapse when the session ends.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–620</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1256</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–276</ref>, <date date="1970-06-12">June 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 303</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–373</ref>, <date date="1972-08-10">Aug. 10, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 528</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–314, § 1(b)</ref>, <date date="1974-06-08">June 8, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 239</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–94, title IV, § 407(a)</ref>, <date date="1977-08-05">Aug. 5, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 683</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–417, title VI, § 601(11)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-10">Oct. 10, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1744</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–164, title I, § 164(2)</ref>, <date date="1982-04-02">Apr. 2, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 50</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XV, § 1533(c)(3)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1736</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–82, § 6</ref>, <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 377</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–572, title IX, § 902(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4516</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title IX, § 924(d)(1)(D)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2832</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–186, title II, § 223(7)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1751</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–368, title V, § 512(b)(1)(C)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-11">Nov. 11, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3342</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–235, div. H, title I, § 1301(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-16">Dec. 16, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 2537</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 907.</num>
<heading> Congressional Record: extracts for Members of Congress; mailing envelopes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director of the Government Publishing Office may print and deliver, upon the order of a Member of Congress and payment of the cost, extracts from the Congressional Record. The Director of the Government Publishing Office may furnish without cost to Members and the Resident Commissioner, envelopes, ready for mailing the Congressional Record or any part of it, or speeches, or reports in it, if such part, speeches, or reports are mailable as franked mail under <ref>section 3210 of title 39</ref>. Envelopes so furnished shall contain in the upper left-hand corner the following words: “United States Senate” or “House of Representatives, U.S. Part of Congressional Record.”, and in the upper right-hand corner the letters “U.S.S.” or “M.C.”, and the Director of the Government Publishing Office may, at the request of a Member or Resident Commissioner, print in addition to the foregoing, his name and State or Commonwealth, the date, and the topic or subject matter, not exceeding twelve words. He may not print any other words on envelopes, except at the personal expense of the Member or Resident Commissioner ordering the envelopes, except to affix the official title of a document. The Director of the Government Publishing Office shall deposit moneys accruing under this section in the Treasury of the United States to the credit of the appropriation made for the working capital of the Government Publishing Office for the year in which the work is done, and accounted for in his annual report to Congress.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–620</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1259</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–191, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="1973-12-18">Dec. 18, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 745</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–255, § 2(c)</ref>, <date date="1974-03-27">Mar. 27, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 52</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–235, div. H, title I, § 1301(b)</ref>, (c)(1), <date date="2014-12-16">Dec. 16, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 2537</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 908.</num>
<heading> Congressional Record: payment for printing extracts or other documents</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If a Member or Resident Commissioner fails to pay the cost of printing extracts from the Congressional Record or other documents ordered by him to be printed, the Director of the Government Publishing Office shall certify the amount due to the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives or the financial clerk of the Senate, as the case may be, who shall deduct from any salary due the delinquent the amount, or as much of it as the salary due may cover, and pay the amount so obtained to the Director of the Government Publishing Office, to be applied by him to the satisfaction of the indebtedness.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–620</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1260</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–186, title II, § 223(8)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1752</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–235, div. H, title I, § 1301(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-16">Dec. 16, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 2537</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 909.</num>
<heading> Congressional Record: exchange for Parliamentary Hansard</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Librarian of Congress may furnish a copy of the daily and bound Congressional Record to the Undersecretary of State for External Affairs of Canada in exchange for a copy of the Parliamentary Hansard, and the Director of the Government Publishing Office shall honor the requisition of the Librarian of Congress for it. The Parliamentary Hansard so received shall be the property of the Department of State.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–620</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1260</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–235, div. H, title I, § 1301(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-16">Dec. 16, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 2537</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 910.</num>
<heading> Congressional Record: subscriptions; sale of current, individual numbers, and bound sets; postage rate</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Under the direction of the Joint Committee, the Director of the Government Publishing Office may sell—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> subscriptions to the daily Record; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> current, individual numbers, and bound sets of the Congressional Record.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The price of a subscription to the daily Record and of current, individual numbers, and bound sets shall be determined by the Director of the Government Publishing Office based upon the cost of printing and distribution. Any such price shall be paid in advance. The money from any such sale shall be paid into the Treasury and accounted for in the Public Printer’s <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002004">1</ref> annual report to Congress.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Congressional Record shall be entitled to be mailed at the same rates of postage at which any newspaper or other periodical publication, with a legitimate list of paid subscribers, is entitled to be mailed.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–620</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1260</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–314, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1974-06-08">June 8, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 239</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–235, div. H, title I, § 1301(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-16">Dec. 16, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 2537</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>