<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 21—</num>
<heading>NATIONAL ARCHIVES AND RECORDS ADMINISTRATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2101.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “Presidential archival depository” means an institution operated by the United States to house and preserve the papers and books of a President or former President of the United States, together with other historical materials belonging to a President or former President of the United States, or related to his papers or to the events of his official or personal life, and may include research facilities and museum facilities in accordance with this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> “historical materials” including books, correspondence, documents, papers, pamphlets, works of art, models, pictures, photographs, plats, maps, films, motion pictures, sound recordings, and other objects or materials having historical or commemorative value;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> “Archivist” means the Archivist of the United States appointed under <ref>section 2103 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> “Administration” means the National Archives and Records Administration established under <ref>section 2102 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–620</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1287</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–497, title I, § 102(b)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2282</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–323, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-05-27">May 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 495</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2102.</num>
<heading> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There shall be an independent establishment in the executive branch of the Government to be known as the National Archives and Records Administration. The Administration shall be administered under the supervision and direction of the Archivist.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–620</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1287</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–497, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2280</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2103.</num>
<heading> Officers</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Archivist of the United States shall be appointed by the President by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. The Archivist shall be appointed without regard to political affiliations and solely on the basis of the professional qualifications required to perform the duties and responsibilities of the office of Archivist. The Archivist may be removed from office by the President. The President shall communicate the reasons for any such removal to each House of the Congress.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Archivist shall be compensated at the rate provided for level III of the Executive Schedule under <ref>section 5314 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> There shall be in the Administration a Deputy Archivist of the United States, who shall be appointed by and who shall serve at the pleasure of the Archivist. The Deputy Archivist shall be established as a career reserved position in the Senior Executive Service within the meaning of <ref>section 3132(a)(8) of title 5</ref>. The Deputy Archivist shall perform such functions as the Archivist shall designate. During any absence or disability of the Archivist, the Deputy Archivist shall act as Archivist. In the event of a vacancy in the office of the Archivist, the Deputy Archivist shall act as Archivist until an Archivist is appointed under subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 98–497, title I, § 102(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2280</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2104.</num>
<heading> Administrative provisions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Archivist shall prescribe such regulations as the Archivist deems necessary to effectuate the functions of the Archivist, and the head of each executive agency shall cause to be issued such orders and directives as such agency head deems necessary to carry out such regulations.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Except as otherwise expressly provided by law, the Archivist may delegate any of the functions of the Archivist to such officers and employees of the Administration as the Archivist may designate, and may authorize such successive redelegations of such functions as the Archivist may deem to be necessary or appropriate. A delegation of functions by the Archivist shall not relieve the Archivist of responsibility for the administration of such functions.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Archivist may organize the Administration as the Archivist finds necessary or appropriate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The Archivist is authorized to establish, maintain, alter, or discontinue such regional, local, or other field offices as the Archivist finds necessary or appropriate to perform the functions of the Archivist or the Administration.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> The Archivist shall cause a seal of office to be made for the Administration of such design as the Archivist shall approve. Judicial notice shall be taken of such seal.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> The Archivist may establish advisory committees to provide advice with respect to any function of the Archivist or the Administration. Members of any such committee shall serve without compensation but shall be entitled to transportation expenses and per diem in lieu of subsistence in accordance with <ref>section 5703 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> The Archivist shall advise and consult with interested Federal agencies with a view to obtaining their advice and assistance in carrying out the purposes of this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<content> If authorized by the Archivist, officers and employees of the Administration having investigatory functions are empowered, while engaged in the performance of their duties in conducting investigations, to administer oaths.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 98–497, title I, § 102(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2281</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2105.</num>
<heading> Personnel and services</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Archivist is authorized to select, appoint, employ, and fix the compensation of such officers and employees, pursuant to part III of title 5, as are necessary to perform the functions of the Archivist and the Administration.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding paragraph (1), the Archivist is authorized to appoint, subject to the consultation requirements set forth in paragraph (f)(2) of <ref>section 2203 of this title</ref>,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002014">1</ref> a director at each Presidential archival depository established under <ref>section 2112 of this title</ref>. The Archivist may appoint a director without regard to subchapter I and subchapter VIII of chapter 33 of title 5, United States Code, governing appointments in the competitive service and the Senior Executive Service. A director so appointed shall be responsible for the care and preservation of the Presidential records and historical materials deposited in a Presidential archival depository, shall serve at the pleasure of the Archivist and shall perform such other functions as the Archivist may specify.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Archivist is authorized to obtain the services of experts and consultants under <ref>section 3109 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding the provisions of <ref>section 973 of title 10</ref> or any other provision of law, the Archivist, in carrying out the functions of the Archivist or the Administration, is authorized to utilize in the Administration the services of officials, officers, and other personnel in other Federal agencies, including personnel of the armed services, with the consent of the head of the agency concerned.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding <ref>section 1342 of title 31</ref>, United States Code, the Archivist is authorized to accept and utilize voluntary and uncompensated services.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 98–497, title I, § 102(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2281</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–67, title VI, § 649</ref>, <date date="2001-11-12">Nov. 12, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 556</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2106.</num>
<heading> Reports to Congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Archivist shall submit to the Congress, in January of each year and at such other times as the Archivist finds appropriate, a report concerning the administration of functions of the Archivist, the Administration, the National Historical Publications and Records Commission, and the National Archives Trust Fund. Such report shall describe—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> program administration and expenditures of funds, both appropriated and nonappropriated, by the Administration, the Commission, and the Trust Fund Board;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> research projects and publications undertaken by Commission grantees, and by Trust Fund grantees, including detailed information concerning the receipt and use of all appropriated and nonappropriated funds;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> by account, the moneys, securities, and other personal property received and held by the National Archives Trust Fund Board, and of its operations, including a listing of the purposes for which funds are transferred to the National Archives and Records Administration for expenditure to other Federal agencies; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the matters specified in <ref>section 2904(c)(8) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 98–497, title I, § 102(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2282</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2107.</num>
<heading> Acceptance of records for historical preservation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>When it appears to the Archivist to be in the public interest, the Archivist may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> accept for deposit with the National Archives of the United States the records of a Federal agency, the Congress, the Architect of the Capitol, or the Supreme Court determined by the Archivist to have sufficient historical or other value to warrant their continued preservation by the United States Government;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> direct and effect the transfer of records of a Federal agency determined by the Archivist to have sufficient historical or other value to warrant their continued preservation by the United States Government to the National Archives of the United States, as soon as practicable, and at a time mutually agreed upon by the Archivist and the head of that Federal agency not later than thirty years after such records were created or received by that agency, unless the head of such agency has certified in writing to the Archivist that such records must be retained in the custody of such agency for use in the conduct of the regular business of the agency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> direct and effect, with the approval of the head of the originating Federal agency, or if the existence of the agency has been terminated, with the approval of the head of that agency’s successor in function, if any, the transfer of records, deposited or approved for deposit with the National Archives of the United States to public or educational institutions or associations; title to the records to remain vested in the United States unless otherwise authorized by Congress; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> transfer materials from private sources authorized to be received by the Archivist by <ref>section 2111 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Early Transfer of Records</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Archivist—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in consultation with the head of the originating Federal agency, is authorized to accept a copy of the records described in subsection (a)(2) that have been in existence for less than thirty years; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> may not disclose any such records until the expiration of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the thirty-year period described in paragraph (1);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any longer period established by the Archivist by order; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any shorter period agreed to by the originating Federal agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–620</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1287</ref>, § 2103; <ref>Pub. L. 94–575, § 4(a)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2727</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–416, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-05">Oct. 5, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 915</ref>; renumbered § 2107 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–497, title I</ref>, §§ 102(a)(1), 107(a)(1), <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2280</ref>, 2285; <ref>Pub. L. 113–187, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-11-26">Nov. 26, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 2007</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2108.</num>
<heading> Responsibility for custody, use, and withdrawal of records</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Archivist shall be responsible for the custody, use, and withdrawal of records transferred to him. When records, the use of which is subject to statutory limitations and restrictions, are so transferred, permissive and restrictive statutory provisions with respect to the examination and use of records applicable to the head of the agency from which the records were transferred or to employees of that agency are applicable to the Archivist and to the employees of the National Archives and Records Administration, respectively. Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, when the head of a Federal agency states, in writing, restrictions that appear to him to be necessary or desirable in the public interest with respect to the use or examination of rec­ords being considered for transfer from his custody to the Archivist, the Archivist shall, if he concurs,,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002015">1</ref> impose such restrictions on the records so transferred, and may not relax or remove such restrictions without the written concurrence of the head of the agency from which the material was transferred, or of his successor in function, if any. In the event that a Federal agency is terminated and there is no successor in function, the Archivist is authorized to relax, remove, or impose restrictions on such agency’s records when he determines that such action is in the public interest. Statutory and other restrictions referred to in this subsection shall remain in force until the records have been in existence for thirty years unless the Archivist by order, having consulted with the head of the transferring Federal agency or his successor in function, determines, with respect to specific bodies of records, that for reasons consistent with standards established in relevant statutory law, such restrictions shall remain in force for a longer period. Restriction on the use or examination of records deposited with the National Archives of the United States imposed by section 3 of the National Archives Act, approved <date date="1934-06-19">June 19, 1934</date>, shall continue in force regardless of the expiration of the tenure of office of the official who imposed them but may be removed or relaxed by the Archivist with the concurrence in writing of the head of the agency from which material was transferred or of his successor in function, if any.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> With regard to the census and survey rec­ords of the Bureau of the Census containing data identifying individuals enumerated in population censuses, any release pursuant to this section of such identifying information contained in such records shall be made by the Archivist pursuant to the specifications and agreements set forth in the exchange of correspondence on or about the date of <date date="1952-10-10">October 10, 1952</date>, between the Director of the Bureau of the Census and the Archivist of the United States, together with all amendments thereto, now or hereafter entered into between the Director of the Bureau of the Census and the Archivist of the United States. Such amendments, if any, shall be published in the Register.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–620</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1288</ref>, § 2104; <ref>Pub. L. 95–416, § 1(b)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-05">Oct. 5, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 915</ref>; renumbered § 2108 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–497, title I</ref>, §§ 102(a)(1), 107(a)(2), <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2280</ref>, 2285.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2109.</num>
<heading> Preservation, arrangement, duplication, exhibition of records</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Archivist shall provide for the preservation, arrangement, repair and rehabilitation, duplication and reproduction (including microcopy publications), description, and exhibition of records or other documentary material transferred to him as may be needful or appropriate, including the preparation and publication of inventories, indexes, catalogs, and other finding aids or guides to facilitate their use. He may also prepare guides and other finding aids to Federal records and, when approved by the National Historical Publications and Records Commission, publish such historical works and collections of sources as seem appropriate for printing or otherwise recording at the public expense.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–620</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1288</ref>, § 2105; renumbered § 2109 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–497, title I</ref>, §§ 102(a)(1), 107(a)(3), <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2280</ref>, 2285.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2110.</num>
<heading> Servicing records</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Archivist shall provide and maintain facilities he considers necessary or desirable for servicing records in his custody that are not exempt from examination by statutory or other restrictions.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–620</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1288</ref>, § 2106; renumbered § 2110 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–497, title I</ref>, §§ 102(a)(1), 107(a)(4), <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2280</ref>, 2286.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2111.</num>
<heading> Material accepted for deposit</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>When the Archivist considers it to be in the public interest the Archivist may accept for deposit—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the papers and other historical materials of a President or former President of the United States, or other official or former official of the Government, and other papers relating to and contemporary with a President or former President of the United States, subject to restrictions agreeable to the Archivist as to their use; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> recorded information (as such term is defined in <ref>section 3301(a)(2) of this title</ref>) from private sources that are appropriate for preservation by the Government as evidence of its organization, functions, policies, decisions, procedures, and transactions.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section shall not apply in the case of any Presidential records which are subject to the provisions of chapter 22 of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–620</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1288</ref>, § 2107; <ref>Pub. L. 95–591, § 2(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-04">Nov. 4, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2528</ref>; renumbered § 2111 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–497, title I</ref>, §§ 102(a)(1), 107(a)(5), <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2280</ref>, 2286; <ref>Pub. L. 113–187, § 3(b)</ref>, <date date="2014-11-26">Nov. 26, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 2008</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2112.</num>
<heading> Presidential archival depository</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> When the Archivist considers it to be in the public interest, the Archivist may—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> accept, for and in the name of the United States, land, a facility, and equipment offered as a gift to the United States for the purpose of creating a Presidential archival depository;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> take title to the land, facility, and equipment on behalf of the United States; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> maintain, operate, and protect the land, facility, and equipment as a Presidential archival depository and as part of the national archives system;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> make agreements, upon terms and conditions the Archivist considers proper, with a State, political subdivision, university, institution of higher learning, institute, or foundation to use as a Presidential archival depository land, a facility, and equipment of the State, subdivision, university, or other organization, to be made available by it without transfer of title to the United States; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> maintain, operate, and protect the depository as a part of the national archives system; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> accept, for and in the name of the United States, gifts offered for the purpose of making any physical or material change or addition to a Presidential archival depository.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Archivist shall promulgate architectural and design standards applicable to Presidential archival depositories in order to ensure that such depositories (A) preserve Presidential records subject to chapter 22 of this title and papers and other historical materials accepted for deposit under <ref>section 2111 of this title</ref> and (B) contain adequate research facilities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> Prior to accepting and taking title to any land, facility, or equipment under subparagraph (A) of paragraph (1), or prior to entering into any agreement under subparagraph (B) of such paragraph or any other agreement to accept or establish a Presidential archival depository, the Archivist shall submit a written report on the proposed Presidential archival depository to the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives. The report shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a description of the land, facility, and equipment offered as a gift or to be made available without transfer of title;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a statement specifying the estimated total cost of the proposed depository and the amount of the endowment for the depository required pursuant to subsection (g) of this section;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a statement of the terms of the proposed agreement, if any;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a general description of the types of papers, documents, or other historical materials proposed to be deposited in the depository to be created, and of the terms of the proposed deposit;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> a statement of any additional improvements and equipment associated with the development and operation of the depository, an estimate of the costs of such improvements and equipment, and a statement as to the extent to which such costs will be incurred by any Federal or State government agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> an estimate of the total annual cost to the United States of maintaining, operating, and protecting the depository; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> a certification that such facility and equipment (whether offered as a gift or made available without transfer of title) comply with standards promulgated by the Archivist pursuant to paragraph (2) of this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> Prior to accepting any gift under subparagraph (C) of paragraph (1) for the purpose of making any physical or material change or addition to a Presidential archival depository, or prior to implementing any provision of law requiring the making of such a change or addition, the Archivist shall submit a report in writing on the proposed change or addition to the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives. The report shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a description of such gift;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a statement specifying the estimated total cost of the proposed physical or material change or addition and the amount of the deposit in an endowment for the depository required pursuant to subsection (g) of this section in order to meet the cost of such change or addition;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a statement of the purpose of the proposed change or addition and a general description of any papers, documents, or historical materials proposed to be deposited in the depository as a result of such change or addition;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a statement of any additional improvements or equipment for the depository associated with such change or addition;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> an estimate of the increase in the total annual cost to the United States of maintaining, operating, and protecting the depository that will result from such change or addition; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> a certification that the depository, and the equipment therein will, after such change or addition, comply with the standards promulgated by the Archivist pursuant to paragraph (2) of this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> The Archivist may not—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> accept or take title to land, a facility, or equipment under subparagraph (A) of paragraph (1) for the purpose of creating a Presidential archival depository;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> enter into any agreement under subparagraph (B) of such paragraph or any other agreement to accept or establish a Presidential archival depository; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> accept any gift under subparagraph (C) of such paragraph for the purpose of making any physical or material change to a Presidential archival depository,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">until the expiration of a period of 60 days of continuous session of Congress beginning on the date on which the Archivist transmits the report required under paragraph (3) of this subsection with respect to such Presidential archival depository or the report required under paragraph (4) of this subsection with respect to such change or addition, as the case may be.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> When the Archivist considers it to be in the public interest, he may deposit in a Presidential archival depository papers, documents, or other historical materials accepted under <ref>section 2111 of this title</ref>, or Federal records appropriate for preservation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> When the Archivist considers it to be in the public interest, he may exercise, with respect to papers, documents, or other historical materials deposited under this section, or otherwise, in a Presidential archival depository, all the functions and responsibilities otherwise vested in him pertaining to Federal records or other documentary materials in his custody or under his control. The Archivist, in negotiating for the deposit of Presidential historical materials, shall take steps to secure to the Government, as far as possible, the right to have continuous and permanent possession of the materials. Papers, documents, or other historical materials accepted and deposited under <ref>section 2111 of this title</ref> and this section are subject to restrictions as to their availability and use stated in writing by the donors or depositors, including the restriction that they shall be kept in a Presidential archival depository. The restrictions shall be respected for the period stated, or until revoked or terminated by the donors or depositors or by persons legally qualified to act on their behalf. Subject to the restrictions, the Archivist may dispose by sale, exchange, or otherwise, of papers, documents, or other materials which the Archivist determines to have no permanent value or historical interest or to be surplus to the needs of a Presidential archival depository. Only the first two sentences of this subsection shall apply to Presidential records as defined in <ref>section 2201(2) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> When the Archivist considers it to be in the public interest, he may cooperate with and assist a university, institution of higher learning, institute, foundation, or other organization or qualified individual to further or to conduct study or research in historical materials deposited in a Presidential archival depository.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> When the Archivist considers it to be in the public interest, he may charge and collect reasonable fees for the privilege of visiting and viewing exhibit rooms or museum space, or for the occasional, non-official use of rooms and spaces (and services related to such use), in a Presidential archival depository.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> When the Archivist considers it to be in the public interest, he may provide reasonable office space in a Presidential archival depository for the personal use of a former President of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> When the Archivist considers it to be in the public interest, the Archivist may solicit and accept gifts or bequests of money or other property for the purpose of maintaining, operating, protecting, or improving a Presidential archival depository. The proceeds of gifts or bequests, together with the proceeds from fees or from sales of historical materials, copies or reproductions, catalogs, or other items, having to do with a Presidential archival depository, shall be paid into an account in the National Archives Trust Fund and shall be held, administered, and expended for the benefit and in the interest of the Presidential archival depository in connection with which they were received, and for the same purposes and objects, including custodial and administrative services for which appropriations for the maintenance, operation, protection, or improvement of Presidential archival depositories might be expended.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Archivist shall provide for the establishment in such Trust Fund of separate endowments for the maintenance of the land, facility, and equipment of each Presidential archival depository, to which shall be credited any gifts or bequests received under paragraph (1) that are offered for that purpose. Income to each such endowment shall be available to cover the cost of facility operations, but shall not be available for the performance of archival functions under this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The Archivist shall not accept or take title to any land, facility, or equipment under subparagraph (A) of subsection (a)(1), or enter into any agreement to use any land, facility, or equipment under subparagraph (B) of such subsection for the purpose of creating a Presidential archival depository, unless the Archivist determines that there is available, by gift or bequest for deposit under paragraph (2) of this subsection in an endowment with respect to such depository, an amount for the purpose of maintaining such land, facility, and equipment equal to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> the product of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the total cost of acquiring or constructing such facility and of acquiring and installing such equipment, multiplied by</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> 20 percent; plus</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> if title to the land is to be vested in the United States, the product of—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the total cost of acquiring the land upon which such facility is located, or such other measure of the value of such land as is mutually agreed upon by the Archivist and the donor, multiplied by</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> 20 percent; or</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> if title to the land is not to be vested in the United States, the product of—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the total cost to the donor of any improvements to the land upon which such facility is located (other than such facility and equipment), multiplied by</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> 20 percent; plus</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> if the Presidential archival depository will exceed 70,000 square feet in area, an amount equal to the product of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> the sum of—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the total cost described in clause (i) of subparagraph (A); plus</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the total cost described in subclause (I) or (II) of subparagraph (B)(i), as the case may be, multiplied by</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the percentage obtained by dividing the number of square feet by which such depository will exceed 70,000 square feet by 70,000.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> If a proposed physical or material change or addition to a Presidential archival depository would result in an increase in the costs of facility operations, the Archivist may not accept any gift under subparagraph (C) of paragraph (1) for the purpose of making such a change or addition, or may not implement any provision of law requiring the making of such a change or addition, unless the Archivist determines that there is available, by gift or bequest for deposit under paragraph (2) of this subsection in an endowment with respect to such depository, an amount for the purpose of maintaining the land, facility, and equipment of such depository equal to the difference between—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> the amount which, pursuant to paragraph (3) of this subsection, would have been required to have been available for deposit in such endowment with respect to such depository if such change or addition had been included in such depository on—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the date on which the Archivist took title to the land, facility, and equipment for such depository under subparagraph (A) of subsection (a)(1); or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the date on which the Archivist entered into an agreement for the creation of such depository under subparagraph (B) of such paragraph,</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">as the case may be; minus</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the amount which, pursuant to paragraph (3) of this subsection, was required to be available for deposit in such endowment with respect to such depository on the date the Archivist took such title or entered into such agreement, as the case may be.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding paragraphs (3) and (4) (to the extent that such paragraphs are inconsistent with this paragraph), this subsection shall be administered in accordance with this paragraph with respect to any Presidential archival depository created as a depository for the papers, documents, and other historical materials and Presidential records pertaining to any President who takes the oath of office as President for the first time on or after <date date="2002-07-01">July 1, 2002</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> For purposes of subparagraphs (A)(ii), (B)(i)(II), and (B)(ii)(II) of paragraph (3) the percentage of 60 percent shall apply instead of 20 percent.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> In this subparagraph, the term “base endowment amount” means the amount of the endowment required under paragraph (3).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(ii)</num>
<subclause class="indent0">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> The Archivist may give credits against the base endowment amount if the Archivist determines that the proposed Presidential archival depository will have construction features or equipment that are expected to result in quantifiable long-term savings to the Government with respect to the cost of facility operations.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent0">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> The features and equipment described under subclause (I) shall comply with the standards promulgated by the Archivist under subsection (a)(2).</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent0">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> The Archivist shall promulgate standards to be used in calculating the dollar amount of any credit to be given, and shall consult with all donors of the endowment before giving any credits. The total dollar amount of credits given under this paragraph may not exceed 20 percent of the base endowment amount.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(D)</num>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> In calculating the additional endowment amount required under paragraph (4), the Archivist shall take into account credits given under subparagraph (C), and may also give credits against the additional endowment amount required under paragraph (4), if the Archivist determines that construction features or equipment used in making or equipping the physical or material change or addition are expected to result in quantifiable long-term savings to the Government with respect to the cost of facility operations.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The features and equipment described under clause (i) shall comply with the standards promulgated by the Archivist under subsection (a)(2).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> The Archivist shall promulgate standards to be used in calculating the dollar amount of any credit to be given, and shall consult with all donors of the endowment before giving any credits. The total dollar amount of credits given under this paragraph may not exceed 20 percent of the additional endowment amount required under paragraph (4).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–620</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1289</ref>, § 2108; <ref>Pub. L. 94–575, § 4(a)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2727</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–591, § 2(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-04">Nov. 4, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2528</ref>; renumbered § 2112 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–497, title I</ref>, §§ 102(a)(1), 107(a)(6), <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2280</ref>, 2286; <ref>Pub. L. 99–323, § 3</ref>, <date date="1986-05-27">May 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 495</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–7, div. J, title V, § 513</ref>, <date date="2003-02-20">Feb. 20, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 462</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–383, § 4(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-30">Oct. 30, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2218</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–404, § 6(b)</ref>, <date date="2008-10-13">Oct. 13, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4285</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2113.</num>
<heading> Depository for agreements between States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Archivist may receive duplicate originals or authenticated copies of agreements or compacts entered into under the Constitution and laws of the United States, between States of the Union, and take necessary actions for their preservation and servicing.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–620</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1290</ref>, § 2109; renumbered § 2113 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–497, title I</ref>, §§ 102(a)(1), 107(a)(7), <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2280</ref>, 2286.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2114.</num>
<heading> Preservation of audio and visual records</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Archivist may make and preserve audio and visual records, including motion-picture films, still photographs, and sound recordings, in analog, digital, or any other form, pertaining to and illustrative of the historical development of the United States Government and its activities, and provide for preparing, editing, titling, scoring, processing, duplicating, reproducing, exhibiting, and releasing for non-profit educational purposes, motion-picture films, still photographs, and sound recordings in the Archivist’s custody.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–620</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1290</ref>, § 2110; renumbered § 2114 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–497, title I</ref>, §§ 102(a)(1), 107(a)(7), <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2280</ref>, 2286; <ref>Pub. L. 113–187, § 3(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2014-11-26">Nov. 26, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 2008</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2115.</num>
<heading> Reports; correction of violations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> In carrying out the duties and responsibilities under chapters 21, 25, 29, 31, and 33 of this title, the Archivist may obtain reports from any Federal agency on such agency’s activities under such chapters.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> When the Archivist finds that a provision of any such chapter has been or is being violated, the Archivist shall (1) inform in writing the head of the agency concerned of the violation and make recommendations for its correction; and (2) unless satisfactory corrective measures are demonstrably commenced within a reasonable time, submit a written report of the matter to the President and the Congress.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–620</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1290</ref>, § 2111; <ref>Pub. L. 94–575, § 4(b)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2727</ref>; renumbered § 2115 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–497, title I</ref>, §§ 102(a)(1), 107(a)(8), <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2280</ref>, 2286; <ref>Pub. L. 113–187, § 9(e)</ref>, <date date="2014-11-26">Nov. 26, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 2014</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2116.</num>
<heading> Legal status of reproductions; official seal; fees for copies and reproductions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> When records that are required by statute to be retained indefinitely have been reproduced by photographic, microphotographic, digital, or other processes, in accordance with standards established by the Archivist the indefinite retention by the photographic, microphotographic, digital, or other reproductions constitutes compliance with the statutory requirement for the indefinite retention of the original records. The reproductions, as well as reproductions made under regulations to carry out chapter 21, 29, 31, and 33 of this title, shall have the same legal status as the originals.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> There shall be an official seal for the National Archives of the United States which shall be judicially noticed. When a copy or reproduction, furnished under this section, is authenticated by the official seal and certified by the Archivist, the copy or reproduction shall be admitted in evidence equally with the original from which it was made.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Archivist may charge a fee set to recover the costs for making or authenticating copies or reproductions of materials transferred to the Archivist’s custody. Such fee shall be fixed by the Archivist at a level which will recover, so far as practicable, all elements of such costs, and may, in the Archivist’s discretion, include increments for the estimated replacement cost of equipment. Such fees shall be paid into, administered, and expended as a part of the National Archives Trust Fund. The Archivist may not charge for making or authenticating copies or reproductions of materials for official use by the United States Government unless appropriations available to the Archivist for this purpose are insufficient to cover the cost of performing the work.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–620</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1291</ref>, § 2112; <ref>Pub. L. 94–575, § 4(b)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2727</ref>; renumbered § 2116 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–497, title I</ref>, §§ 102(a)(1), 107(a)(9), title II, § 201, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2280</ref>, 2286, 2292; <ref>Pub. L. 113–187</ref>, §§ 3(d), 8(1), <date date="2014-11-26">Nov. 26, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 2008</ref>, 2011.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2117.</num>
<heading> Limitation on liability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">When letters and other intellectual productions (exclusive of patented material, published works under copyright protection, and unpublished works for which copyright registration has been made) come into the custody or possession of the Archivist, the United States or its agents are not liable for infringement of copyright or analogous rights arising out of use of the materials for display, inspection, research, reproduction, or other purposes.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–620</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1291</ref>, § 2113; <ref>Pub. L. 94–553, § 105(b)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-19">Oct. 19, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2599</ref>; renumbered § 2117 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–497, title I</ref>, §§ 102(a)(1), 107(a)(7), <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2280</ref>, 2286.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2118.</num>
<heading> Records of Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Senate and the Clerk of the House of Representatives, acting jointly, shall obtain at the close of each Congress all the noncurrent records of the Congress and of each congressional committee and transfer them to the National Archives and Records Administration for preservation, subject to the orders of the Senate or the House of Representatives, respectively.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–620</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1291</ref>, § 2114; renumbered § 2118 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–497, title I</ref>, §§ 102(a)(1), 107(a)(10), <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2280</ref>, 2286.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2119.</num>
<heading> Cooperative agreements</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Archivist may enter into cooperative agreements pursuant to <ref>section 6305 of title 31</ref> that involve the transfer of funds from the National Archives and Records Administration to State and local governments, other public entities, educational institutions, or private nonprofit organizations (including foundations or institutes organized to support the National Archives and Records Administration or the Presidential archival depositories operated by it) for the public purpose of carrying out programs of the National Archives and Records Administration.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not more than $25,000 may be transferred under a cooperative agreement entered into as authorized by subsection (a). Not more than a total of $75,000 may be transferred under such agreements in any fiscal year.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than December 31st of each year, the Archivist shall submit to the Committee on Government Reform of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report on the provisions, amount, and duration of each cooperative agreement entered into as authorized by subsection (a) during the preceding fiscal year.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–383, § 5(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-30">Oct. 30, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2219</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2120.</num>
<heading> Online access of founding fathers documents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Archivist may enter into a cooperative agreement to provide online access to the published volumes of the papers of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> George Washington;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Alexander Hamilton;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Thomas Jefferson;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Benjamin Franklin;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> John Adams;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> James Madison; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> other prominent historical figures, as determined appropriate by the Archivist of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–404, § 4(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-10-13">Oct. 13, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4283</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>