<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 25—</num>
<heading>NATIONAL HISTORICAL PUBLICATIONS AND RECORDS COMMISSION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2501.</num>
<heading> Creation; composition; appointment and tenure; meetings</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The National Historical Publications and Records Commission shall consist of 15 members as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the following ex officio members:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Archivist of the United States, who shall be chairman;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Librarian of Congress (or an alternate designated by the Librarian);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> one Senator, appointed by the President of the Senate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> one Representative, appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> one member of the judicial branch of the Government, appointed by the Chief Justice of the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> one representative of the Department of State to be appointed by the Secretary of State; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> one representative of the Department of Defense to be appointed by the Secretary of Defense;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> one member from each of the following organizations, appointed by the governing council or board of the respective organization:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the American Historical Association;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Organization of American Historians;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Society of American Archivists;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the American Association for State and Local History;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the Association for Documentary Editing; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the National Association for Government Archives and Records Administrators; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> two other members, outstanding in the fields of the social or physical sciences, the arts, or archival or library science, appointed by the President of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The members appointed under subsection (a) shall be appointed for not more than 2 terms of 4 years, except that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a member appointed under subsection (a)(1)(D) shall be appointed for not more than 4 terms of 2 years; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Archivist and the Librarian of Congress are permanent ex officio members.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A member may continue to serve after the expiration of a term until a successor has been appointed, but not to exceed one year.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Commission shall meet at least annually and at call of the Chairman.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Recusal</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Members of the Commission shall recuse themselves from voting on any matter that poses, or could potentially pose, a conflict of interest, including a matter that could benefit them or an entity they represent.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–620</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1293</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–546, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1972-10-25">Oct. 25, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 1155</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–536, § 1(b)</ref>, <date date="1974-12-22">Dec. 22, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1735</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–98, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="1979-11-01">Nov. 1, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 731</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–497, title I, § 107(b)(9)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2287</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–365, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-07-13">July 13, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 823</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–404, § 3(a)(1)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="2008-10-13">Oct. 13, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4282</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2502.</num>
<heading> Vacancies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A person appointed to fill a vacancy in the membership of the Commission shall be appointed only for the unexpired term of the member whom he succeeds, and his appointment shall be made in the same manner as the appointment of his predecessor.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–620</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1294</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2503.</num>
<heading> Executive director, staff, transportation expenses</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Commission may appoint, without reference to chapter 51 of title 5, an executive director. The Chairman may appoint such other employees as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Members of the Commission shall be allowed travel expenses (including per diem allowance in lieu of subsistence) in the same amount and to the same extent as persons serving intermittently in the Government service are allowed travel expenses under <ref>section 5703 of title 5</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–620</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1294</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–546, § 1(b)</ref>, <date date="1972-10-25">Oct. 25, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 1155</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–98, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1979-11-01">Nov. 1, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 731</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–365, § 3</ref>, <date date="1988-07-13">July 13, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 824</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2504.</num>
<heading> Duties; authorization of grants for historical publications and records programs; authorization for appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Commission shall make plans, estimates, and recommendations for historical works and collections of sources it considers appropriate for preserving, publishing or otherwise recording at the public expense. The Chairman of the Commission shall transmit to the President and the Congress from time to time, and at least biennially, the plans, estimates, and recommendations developed and approved by the Commission.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Commission shall cooperate with, assist and encourage appropriate Federal, State, and local agencies and nongovernmental institutions, societies, and individuals in collecting and preserving and, when it considers it desirable, in editing and publishing papers of outstanding citizens of the United States, and other documents as may be important for an understanding and appreciation of the history of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Commission may conduct institutes, training and educational programs, and recommend candidates for fellowships related to the activities of the Commission and may disseminate information about documentary sources through guides, directories, and other technical publications.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The Commission may recommend the expenditure of appropriated or donated funds for the collecting, describing, preserving, compiling and publishing (including microfilming and other forms of reproduction) of documentary sources significant to the history of the United States and for the activities described in subsection (c).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> The Archivist of the United States may, within the limits of available appropriated and donated funds, make grants to State and local agencies and to nonprofit organizations, institutions, and individuals, for those activities in subsection (d) after considering the advice and recommendations of the Commission.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Grants for Presidential Centers of Historical Excellence.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Archivist, with the recommendation of the Commission, may make grants, on a competitive basis and in accordance with this subsection, to eligible entities to promote the historical preservation of, and public access to, historical records and documents relating to any former President who does not have a Presidential archival depository currently managed and maintained by the Federal Government pursuant to section 2112 (commonly known as the “Presidential Libraries Act of 1955”).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Eligible entity</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For purposes of this subsection, an eligible entity is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an organization described under section 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and exempt from taxation under section 501(a) of that Code; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a State or local government of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Amounts received by an eligible entity under paragraph (1) shall be used to promote the historical preservation of, and public access to, historical records or historical documents relating to any former President covered under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition on use of funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Amounts received by an eligible entity under paragraph (1) may not be used for the maintenance, operating costs, or construction of any facility to house the historical records or historical documents relating to any former President covered under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Application.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An eligible entity seeking a grant under this subsection shall submit to the Commission an application at such time, in such manner, and containing or accompanied by such information as the Commission may require, including a description of the activities for which a grant under this subsection is sought.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Approval of application</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Commission shall not consider or recommend a grant application submitted under subparagraph (A) unless an eligible entity establishes that such entity—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> possesses, with respect to any former President covered under paragraph (1), historical works and collections of historical sources that the Commission considers appropriate for preserving, publishing, or otherwise recording at the public expense;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> has appropriate facilities and space for preservation of, and public access to, the historical works and collections of historical sources;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> shall ensure preservation of, and public access to, such historical works and collections of historical sources at no charge to the public;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> has educational programs that make the use of such documents part of the mission of such entity;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> has raised funds from non-Federal sources in support of the efforts of the entity to promote the historical preservation of, and public access to, such historical works and collections of historical sources in an amount equal to the amount of the grant the entity seeks under this subsection;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> shall coordinate with any relevant Federal program or activity, including programs and activities relating to Presidential archival depositories;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> shall coordinate with any relevant non-Federal program or activity, including programs and activities conducted by State and local governments and private educational historical entities; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> has a workable plan for preserving and providing public access to such historical works and collections of historical sources.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> For the purposes specified in this section, there is hereby authorized to be appropriated to the National Historical Publications and Records Commission—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> $6,000,000 for fiscal year 1989;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> $8,000,000 for fiscal year 1990;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> $10,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 1991, 1992, and 1993;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> $6,000,000 for fiscal year 1994;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> $7,000,000 for fiscal year 1995;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> $8,000,000 for fiscal year 1996;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> $10,000,000 for fiscal year 1997;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> $10,000,000 for fiscal year 1998;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> $10,000,000 for fiscal year 1999;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> $10,000,000 for fiscal year 2000;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> $10,000,000 for fiscal year 2001;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(L)</num>
<content> $10,000,000 for fiscal year 2002;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(M)</num>
<content> $10,000,000 for fiscal year 2003;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(N)</num>
<content> $10,000,000 for fiscal year 2004;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(O)</num>
<content> $10,000,000 for fiscal year 2005;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(P)</num>
<content> $10,000,000 for fiscal year 2006;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(Q)</num>
<content> $10,000,000 for fiscal year 2007;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(R)</num>
<content> $10,000,000 for fiscal year 2008; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(S)</num>
<content> $10,000,000 for fiscal year 2009.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Amounts appropriated under this subsection shall be available until expended when so provided in appropriation Acts.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–620</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1294</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–546, § 1(c)</ref>, <date date="1972-10-25">Oct. 25, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 1155</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–536, § 1(c)</ref>, <date date="1974-12-22">Dec. 22, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1735</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–98, § 1</ref>, <date date="1979-11-01">Nov. 1, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 731</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–189</ref>, <date date="1983-11-30">Nov. 30, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 1323</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–497, title I, § 107(b)(10)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2287</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–365, § 4</ref>, <date date="1988-07-13">July 13, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 824</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–262, § 1</ref>, <date date="1994-05-31">May 31, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 706</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–274, § 1</ref>, <date date="1996-10-09">Oct. 9, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3321</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–410</ref>, <date date="2000-11-01">Nov. 1, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1788</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–383, § 6</ref>, <date date="2004-10-30">Oct. 30, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2219</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–404, § 2</ref>, <date date="2008-10-13">Oct. 13, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4281</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2505.</num>
<heading> Special advisory committees; membership; reimbursement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission may establish special advisory committees to consult with and make recommendations to it, from among the leading historians, political scientists, archivists, librarians, and other specialists of the Nation. Members of special advisory committees shall be reimbursed for transportation and other expenses on the same basis as members of the Commission.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–620</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1294</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2506.</num>
<heading> Records to be kept by grantees</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Each recipient of grant assistance under <ref>section 2504 of this title</ref> shall keep such records as the Archivist of the United States prescribes, including records which fully disclose the amount and disposition by the recipient of the proceeds of the grants, the total cost of the project or undertaking in connection with which funds are given or used, and the amount of that portion of the cost of the project or undertaking supplied by other sources, and any other records as will facilitate an effective audit.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Archivist and the Comptroller General of the United States or their authorized representatives shall have access for the purposes of audit and examination to books, documents, papers, and records of the recipients that are pertinent to the grants received under <ref>section 2504 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–620</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1294</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–497, title I, § 107(b)(11)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2287</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2507.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 98–497, title I, § 107(b)(12)(A)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2287</ref>]</heading>
</section>
</chapter>