<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 23—</num>
<heading>NATIONAL ARCHIVES TRUST FUND BOARD</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2301.</num>
<heading> Establishment of Board; membership</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The National Archives Trust Fund Board shall consist of the Archivist of the United States, as Chairman, and the Secretary of the Treasury and the Chairman of the National Endowment for the Humanities. Membership on the Board is not an office within the meaning of the statutes of the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–620</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1292</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–391</ref>, <date date="1976-08-19">Aug. 19, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1192</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–379</ref>, <date date="1978-09-22">Sept. 22, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 724</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–497, title I, § 107(b)(8)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2287</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2302.</num>
<heading> Authority of the Board; seal; services; bylaws; rules; regulations; employees</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In carrying out the purposes of this chapter, the Board—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> may adopt an official seal, which shall be judicially noticed;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> may utilize on a reimbursable basis the services and personnel of the National Archives and Records Administration necessary (as determined by the Archivist) to assist the Board in the administration of the trust fund, and in the preparation and publication of special works and collections of sources and preparation, duplication, editing, and release of historical photographic materials and sound recordings, and may utilize on a reimbursable basis the services and personnel of other Federal agencies for such purposes;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> may adopt bylaws, rules, and regulations necessary for the administration of its functions under this chapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> may, subject to the laws and regulations governing appointments in the civil service, appoint and fix the compensation of such personnel as may be necessary to carry out its functions.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–620</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1292</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–497, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2293</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2303.</num>
<heading> Powers and obligations of the Board; liability of members</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided by this chapter, the Board shall have all the usual powers and obligations of a trustee with respect to property and funds administered by it, but the members of the Board are not personally liable, except for malfeasance.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–620</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1292</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–497, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2293</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2304.</num>
<heading> Compensation of members; availability of trust funds for expenses of the Board</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Compensation may not be paid to the members of the Board for their services as members. Costs incurred by the Board in carrying out its duties under this chapter, including the obligations necessarily incurred by the members of the Board in the performance of their duties and the compensation of persons employed by the Board, shall be paid by the Archivist of the United States from trust funds available to the Board for this purpose. The Board, by resolution, may authorize the transfer of funds (including the principal or interest of a gift or bequest) to the National Archives and Records Administration to be expended on an archival or records activity approved by the Board or to accomplish the purpose of a gift or bequest.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–620</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1292</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–497, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2293</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2305.</num>
<heading> Acceptance of gifts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Board may solicit and accept gifts or bequests of money, securities, or other personal property, for the benefit of or in connection with the national archival and records activities administered by the National Archives and Records Administration. Moneys that are for deposit into the trust fund shall be deposited within 10 working days of the receipt thereof.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–620</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1292</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–497, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2293</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2306.</num>
<heading> Investment of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Treasury shall receipt for moneys or securities composing trust funds given or bequeathed to the Board and shall invest, reinvest, and retain the moneys or securities as the Board from time to time determines. The Board may not engage in business or exercise a voting privilege which may be incidental to securities in such trust funds, nor may the Secretary of the Treasury make investments for the account of the Board which could not lawfully be made by a trust company in the District of Columbia, unless directly authorized by the instrument of gift or bequest under which the funds to be invested are derived, and may retain investments accepted by the Board.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–620</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1292</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2307.</num>
<heading> Trust fund account; disbursements; sales of publications and releases</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The income from trust funds held by the Board and the proceeds from the sale of securities and other personal property, as and when collected, shall be covered into the Treasury of the United States in a trust fund account to be known as the National Archives Trust Fund, subject to disbursement on the basis of certified vouchers of the Archivist of the United States (or his designee) for activities approved by the Board and in the interest of the national archival and records activities administered by the National Archives and Records Administration, including but not restricted to the preparation and publication of special works, and collections of sources and the preparation, duplication, editing, and release of historical photographic materials and sound recordings. The Archivist may sell publications and releases authorized by this section and paid for out of the income derived from trust funds at a price which will cover their cost, plus 10 percent, and moneys received from these sales shall be paid into, administered, and expended as part of the National Archives Trust Fund.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–620</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1293</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–497, title II, § 202(b)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2294</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2308.</num>
<heading> Tax exemption for gifts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Gifts and bequests received by the Board under this chapter, and the income from them are exempt from taxes.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–620</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1293</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>