<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 12—</num>
<heading>COPYRIGHT PROTECTION AND MANAGEMENT SYSTEMS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1201.</num>
<heading> Circumvention of copyright protection systems</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Violations Regarding Circumvention of Technological Measures</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> No person shall circumvent a technological measure that effectively controls access to a work protected under this title. The prohibition contained in the preceding sentence shall take effect at the end of the 2-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The prohibition contained in subparagraph (A) shall not apply to persons who are users of a copyrighted work which is in a particular class of works, if such persons are, or are likely to be in the succeeding 3-year period, adversely affected by virtue of such prohibition in their ability to make noninfringing uses of that particular class of works under this title, as determined under subparagraph (C).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> During the 2-year period described in subparagraph (A), and during each succeeding 3-year period, the Librarian of Congress, upon the recommendation of the Register of Copyrights, who shall consult with the Assistant Secretary for Communications and Information of the Department of Commerce and report and comment on his or her views in making such recommendation, shall make the determination in a rulemaking proceeding for purposes of subparagraph (B) of whether persons who are users of a copyrighted work are, or are likely to be in the succeeding 3-year period, adversely affected by the prohibition under subparagraph (A) in their ability to make noninfringing uses under this title of a particular class of copyrighted works. In conducting such rulemaking, the Librarian shall examine—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the availability for use of copyrighted works;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the availability for use of works for nonprofit archival, preservation, and educational purposes;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the impact that the prohibition on the circumvention of technological measures applied to copyrighted works has on criticism, comment, news reporting, teaching, scholarship, or research;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the effect of circumvention of technological measures on the market for or value of copyrighted works; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> such other factors as the Librarian considers appropriate.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The Librarian shall publish any class of copyrighted works for which the Librarian has determined, pursuant to the rulemaking conducted under subparagraph (C), that noninfringing uses by persons who are users of a copyrighted work are, or are likely to be, adversely affected, and the prohibition contained in subparagraph (A) shall not apply to such users with respect to such class of works for the ensuing 3-year period.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Neither the exception under subparagraph (B) from the applicability of the prohibition contained in subparagraph (A), nor any determination made in a rulemaking conducted under subparagraph (C), may be used as a defense in any action to enforce any provision of this title other than this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> No person shall manufacture, import, offer to the public, provide, or otherwise traffic in any technology, product, service, device, component, or part thereof, that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is primarily designed or produced for the purpose of circumventing a technological measure that effectively controls access to a work protected under this title;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> has only limited commercially significant purpose or use other than to circumvent a technological measure that effectively controls access to a work protected under this title; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> is marketed by that person or another acting in concert with that person with that person’s knowledge for use in circumventing a technological measure that effectively controls access to a work protected under this title.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> As used in this subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to “circumvent a technological measure” means to descramble a scrambled work, to decrypt an encrypted work, or otherwise to avoid, bypass, remove, deactivate, or impair a technological measure, without the authority of the copyright owner; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a technological measure “effectively controls access to a work” if the measure, in the ordinary course of its operation, requires the application of information, or a process or a treatment, with the authority of the copyright owner, to gain access to the work.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Additional Violations</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> No person shall manufacture, import, offer to the public, provide, or otherwise traffic in any technology, product, service, device, component, or part thereof, that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is primarily designed or produced for the purpose of circumventing protection afforded by a technological measure that effectively protects a right of a copyright owner under this title in a work or a portion thereof;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> has only limited commercially significant purpose or use other than to circumvent protection afforded by a technological measure that effectively protects a right of a copyright owner under this title in a work or a portion thereof; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> is marketed by that person or another acting in concert with that person with that person’s knowledge for use in circumventing protection afforded by a technological measure that effectively protects a right of a copyright owner under this title in a work or a portion thereof.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> As used in this subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to “circumvent protection afforded by a technological measure” means avoiding, bypassing, removing, deactivating, or otherwise impairing a technological measure; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a technological measure “effectively protects a right of a copyright owner under this title” if the measure, in the ordinary course of its operation, prevents, restricts, or otherwise limits the exercise of a right of a copyright owner under this title.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Other Rights, Etc., Not Affected</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Nothing in this section shall affect rights, remedies, limitations, or defenses to copyright infringement, including fair use, under this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Nothing in this section shall enlarge or diminish vicarious or contributory liability for copyright infringement in connection with any technology, product, service, device, component, or part thereof.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Nothing in this section shall require that the design of, or design and selection of parts and components for, a consumer electronics, telecommunications, or computing product provide for a response to any particular technological measure, so long as such part or component, or the product in which such part or component is integrated, does not otherwise fall within the prohibitions of subsection (a)(2) or (b)(1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Nothing in this section shall enlarge or diminish any rights of free speech or the press for activities using consumer electronics, telecommunications, or computing products.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exemption for Nonprofit Libraries, Archives, and Educational Institutions</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> A nonprofit library, archives, or educational institution which gains access to a commercially exploited copyrighted work solely in order to make a good faith determination of whether to acquire a copy of that work for the sole purpose of engaging in conduct permitted under this title shall not be in violation of subsection (a)(1)(A). A copy of a work to which access has been gained under this paragraph—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> may not be retained longer than necessary to make such good faith determination; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> may not be used for any other purpose.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The exemption made available under paragraph (1) shall only apply with respect to a work when an identical copy of that work is not reasonably available in another form.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> A nonprofit library, archives, or educational institution that willfully for the purpose of commercial advantage or financial gain violates paragraph (1)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall, for the first offense, be subject to the civil remedies under section 1203; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> shall, for repeated or subsequent offenses, in addition to the civil remedies under section 1203, forfeit the exemption provided under paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> This subsection may not be used as a defense to a claim under subsection (a)(2) or (b), nor may this subsection permit a nonprofit library, archives, or educational institution to manufacture, import, offer to the public, provide, or otherwise traffic in any technology, product, service, component, or part thereof, which circumvents a technological measure.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> In order for a library or archives to qualify for the exemption under this subsection, the collections of that library or archives shall be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> open to the public; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> available not only to researchers affiliated with the library or archives or with the institution of which it is a part, but also to other persons doing research in a specialized field.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Law Enforcement, Intelligence, and Other Government Activities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section does not prohibit any lawfully authorized investigative, protective, information security, or intelligence activity of an officer, agent, or employee of the United States, a State, or a political subdivision of a State, or a person acting pursuant to a contract with the United States, a State, or a political subdivision of a State. For purposes of this subsection, the term “information security” means activities carried out in order to identify and address the vulnerabilities of a government computer, computer system, or computer network.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reverse Engineering</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (a)(1)(A), a person who has lawfully obtained the right to use a copy of a computer program may circumvent a technological measure that effectively controls access to a particular portion of that program for the sole purpose of identifying and analyzing those elements of the program that are necessary to achieve interoperability of an independently created computer program with other programs, and that have not previously been readily available to the person engaging in the circumvention, to the extent any such acts of identification and analysis do not constitute infringement under this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding the provisions of subsections (a)(2) and (b), a person may develop and employ technological means to circumvent a technological measure, or to circumvent protection afforded by a technological measure, in order to enable the identification and analysis under paragraph (1), or for the purpose of enabling interoperability of an independently created computer program with other programs, if such means are necessary to achieve such interoperability, to the extent that doing so does not constitute infringement under this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The information acquired through the acts permitted under paragraph (1), and the means permitted under paragraph (2), may be made available to others if the person referred to in paragraph (1) or (2), as the case may be, provides such information or means solely for the purpose of enabling interoperability of an independently created computer program with other programs, and to the extent that doing so does not constitute infringement under this title or violate applicable law other than this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> For purposes of this subsection, the term “interoperability” means the ability of computer programs to exchange information, and of such programs mutually to use the information which has been exchanged.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Encryption Research.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For purposes of this subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the term “encryption research” means activities necessary to identify and analyze flaws and vulnerabilities of encryption technologies applied to copyrighted works, if these activities are conducted to advance the state of knowledge in the field of encryption technology or to assist in the development of encryption products; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the term “encryption technology” means the scrambling and descrambling of information using mathematical formulas or algorithms.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Permissible acts of encryption research</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (a)(1)(A), it is not a violation of that subsection for a person to circumvent a technological measure as applied to a copy, phonorecord, performance, or display of a published work in the course of an act of good faith encryption research if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the person lawfully obtained the encrypted copy, phonorecord, performance, or display of the published work;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> such act is necessary to conduct such encryption research;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the person made a good faith effort to obtain authorization before the circumvention; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> such act does not constitute infringement under this title or a violation of applicable law other than this section, including <ref>section 1030 of title 18</ref> and those provisions of title 18 amended by the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Factors in determining exemption</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In determining whether a person qualifies for the exemption under paragraph (2), the factors to be considered shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> whether the information derived from the encryption research was disseminated, and if so, whether it was disseminated in a manner reasonably calculated to advance the state of knowledge or development of encryption technology, versus whether it was disseminated in a manner that facilitates infringement under this title or a violation of applicable law other than this section, including a violation of privacy or breach of security;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> whether the person is engaged in a legitimate course of study, is employed, or is appropriately trained or experienced, in the field of encryption technology; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> whether the person provides the copyright owner of the work to which the technological measure is applied with notice of the findings and documentation of the research, and the time when such notice is provided.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of technological means for research activities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (a)(2), it is not a violation of that subsection for a person to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> develop and employ technological means to circumvent a technological measure for the sole purpose of that person performing the acts of good faith encryption research described in paragraph (2); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provide the technological means to another person with whom he or she is working collaboratively for the purpose of conducting the acts of good faith encryption research described in paragraph (2) or for the purpose of having that other person verify his or her acts of good faith encryption research described in paragraph (2).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report to congress</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this chapter, the Register of Copyrights and the Assistant Secretary for Communications and Information of the Department of Commerce shall jointly report to the Congress on the effect this subsection has had on—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> encryption research and the development of encryption technology;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the adequacy and effectiveness of technological measures designed to protect copyrighted works; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> protection of copyright owners against the unauthorized access to their encrypted copyrighted works.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">The report shall include legislative recommendations, if any.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exceptions Regarding Minors</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In applying subsection (a) to a component or part, the court may consider the necessity for its intended and actual incorporation in a technology, product, service, or device, which—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> does not itself violate the provisions of this title; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> has the sole purpose to prevent the access of minors to material on the Internet.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Protection of Personally Identifying Information.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Circumvention permitted</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (a)(1)(A), it is not a violation of that subsection for a person to circumvent a technological measure that effectively controls access to a work protected under this title, if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the technological measure, or the work it protects, contains the capability of collecting or disseminating personally identifying information reflecting the online activities of a natural person who seeks to gain access to the work protected;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the normal course of its operation, the technological measure, or the work it protects, collects or disseminates personally identifying information about the person who seeks to gain access to the work protected, without providing conspicuous notice of such collection or dissemination to such person, and without providing such person with the capability to prevent or restrict such collection or dissemination;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the act of circumvention has the sole effect of identifying and disabling the capability described in subparagraph (A), and has no other effect on the ability of any person to gain access to any work; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the act of circumvention is carried out solely for the purpose of preventing the collection or dissemination of personally identifying information about a natural person who seeks to gain access to the work protected, and is not in violation of any other law.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inapplicability to certain technological measures</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This subsection does not apply to a technological measure, or a work it protects, that does not collect or disseminate personally identifying information and that is disclosed to a user as not having or using such capability.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Security Testing.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of this subsection, the term “security testing” means accessing a computer, computer system, or computer network, solely for the purpose of good faith testing, investigating, or correcting, a security flaw or vulnerability, with the authorization of the owner or operator of such computer, computer system, or computer network.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Permissible acts of security testing</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (a)(1)(A), it is not a violation of that subsection for a person to engage in an act of security testing, if such act does not constitute infringement under this title or a violation of applicable law other than this section, including <ref>section 1030 of title 18</ref> and those provisions of title 18 amended by the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Factors in determining exemption</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In determining whether a person qualifies for the exemption under paragraph (2), the factors to be considered shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> whether the information derived from the security testing was used solely to promote the security of the owner or operator of such computer, computer system or computer network, or shared directly with the developer of such computer, computer system, or computer network; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> whether the information derived from the security testing was used or maintained in a manner that does not facilitate infringement under this title or a violation of applicable law other than this section, including a violation of privacy or breach of security.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of technological means for security testing</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (a)(2), it is not a violation of that subsection for a person to develop, produce, distribute or employ technological means for the sole purpose of performing the acts of security testing described in subsection (2),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002018">1</ref> provided such technological means does not otherwise violate section <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002019">2</ref> (a)(2).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(k)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Certain Analog Devices and Certain Technological Measures.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Certain analog devices.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> Effective 18 months after the date of the enactment of this chapter, no person shall manufacture, import, offer to the public, provide or otherwise traffic in any—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> VHS format analog video cassette recorder unless such recorder conforms to the automatic gain control copy control technology;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> 8mm format analog video cassette camcorder unless such camcorder conforms to the automatic gain control technology;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Beta format analog video cassette recorder, unless such recorder conforms to the automatic gain control copy control technology, except that this requirement shall not apply until there are 1,000 Beta format analog video cassette recorders sold in the United States in any one calendar year after the date of the enactment of this chapter;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> 8mm format analog video cassette recorder that is not an analog video cassette camcorder, unless such recorder conforms to the automatic gain control copy control technology, except that this requirement shall not apply until there are 20,000 such recorders sold in the United States in any one calendar year after the date of the enactment of this chapter; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> analog video cassette recorder that records using an NTSC format video input and that is not otherwise covered under clauses (i) through (iv), unless such device conforms to the automatic gain control copy control technology.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> Effective on the date of the enactment of this chapter, no person shall manufacture, import, offer to the public, provide or otherwise traffic in—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any VHS format analog video cassette recorder or any 8mm format analog video cassette recorder if the design of the model of such recorder has been modified after such date of enactment so that a model of recorder that previously conformed to the automatic gain control copy control technology no longer conforms to such technology; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any VHS format analog video cassette recorder, or any 8mm format analog video cassette recorder that is not an 8mm analog video cassette camcorder, if the design of the model of such recorder has been modified after such date of enactment so that a model of recorder that previously conformed to the four-line colorstripe copy control technology no longer conforms to such technology.</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">Manufacturers that have not previously manufactured or sold a VHS format analog video cassette recorder, or an 8mm format analog cassette recorder, shall be required to conform to the four-line colorstripe copy control technology in the initial model of any such recorder manufactured after the date of the enactment of this chapter, and thereafter to continue conforming to the four-line colorstripe copy control technology. For purposes of this subparagraph, an analog video cassette recorder “conforms to” the four-line colorstripe copy control technology if it records a signal that, when played back by the playback function of that recorder in the normal viewing mode, exhibits, on a reference display device, a display containing distracting visible lines through portions of the viewable picture.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Certain encoding restrictions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>No person shall apply the automatic gain control copy control technology or colorstripe copy control technology to prevent or limit consumer copying except such copying—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> of a single transmission, or specified group of transmissions, of live events or of audiovisual works for which a member of the public has exercised choice in selecting the transmissions, including the content of the transmissions or the time of receipt of such transmissions, or both, and as to which such member is charged a separate fee for each such transmission or specified group of transmissions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> from a copy of a transmission of a live event or an audiovisual work if such transmission is provided by a channel or service where payment is made by a member of the public for such channel or service in the form of a subscription fee that entitles the member of the public to receive all of the programming contained in such channel or service;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> from a physical medium containing one or more prerecorded audiovisual works; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> from a copy of a transmission described in subparagraph (A) or from a copy made from a physical medium described in subparagraph (C).</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">In the event that a transmission meets both the conditions set forth in subparagraph (A) and those set forth in subparagraph (B), the transmission shall be treated as a transmission described in subparagraph (A).</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inapplicability</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>This subsection shall not—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> require any analog video cassette camcorder to conform to the automatic gain control copy control technology with respect to any video signal received through a camera lens;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> apply to the manufacture, importation, offer for sale, provision of, or other trafficking in, any professional analog video cassette recorder; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> apply to the offer for sale or provision of, or other trafficking in, any previously owned analog video cassette recorder, if such recorder was legally manufactured and sold when new and not subsequently modified in violation of paragraph (1)(B).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For purposes of this subsection:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> An “analog video cassette recorder” means a device that records, or a device that includes a function that records, on electromagnetic tape in an analog format the electronic impulses produced by the video and audio portions of a television program, motion picture, or other form of audiovisual work.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> An “analog video cassette camcorder” means an analog video cassette recorder that contains a recording function that operates through a camera lens and through a video input that may be connected with a television or other video playback device.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> An analog video cassette recorder “conforms” to the automatic gain control copy control technology if it—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> detects one or more of the elements of such technology and does not record the motion picture or transmission protected by such technology; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> records a signal that, when played back, exhibits a meaningfully distorted or degraded display.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The term “professional analog video cassette recorder” means an analog video cassette recorder that is designed, manufactured, marketed, and intended for use by a person who regularly employs such a device for a lawful business or industrial use, including making, performing, displaying, distributing, or transmitting copies of motion pictures on a commercial scale.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The terms “VHS format”, “8mm format”, “Beta format”, “automatic gain control copy control technology”, “colorstripe copy control technology”, “four-line version of the colorstripe copy control technology”, and “NTSC” have the meanings that are commonly understood in the consumer electronics and motion picture industries as of the date of the enactment of this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Violations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any violation of paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be treated as a violation of subsection (b)(1) of this section. Any violation of paragraph (2) of this subsection shall be deemed an “act of circumvention” for the purposes of section 1203(c)(3)(A) of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 105–304, title I, § 103(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-28">Oct. 28, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2863</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(9) [title V, § 5006]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–594.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1202.</num>
<heading> Integrity of copyright management information</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">False Copyright Management Information</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>No person shall knowingly and with the intent to induce, enable, facilitate, or conceal infringement—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provide copyright management information that is false, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> distribute or import for distribution copyright management information that is false.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Removal or Alteration of Copyright Management Information</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>No person shall, without the authority of the copyright owner or the law—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> intentionally remove or alter any copyright management information,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> distribute or import for distribution copyright management information knowing that the copyright management information has been removed or altered without authority of the copyright owner or the law, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> distribute, import for distribution, or publicly perform works, copies of works, or phonorecords, knowing that copyright management information has been removed or altered without authority of the copyright owner or the law,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">knowing, or, with respect to civil remedies under section 1203, having reasonable grounds to know, that it will induce, enable, facilitate, or conceal an infringement of any right under this title.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>As used in this section, the term “copyright management information” means any of the following information conveyed in connection with copies or phonorecords of a work or performances or displays of a work, including in digital form, except that such term does not include any personally identifying information about a user of a work or of a copy, phonorecord, performance, or display of a work:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The title and other information identifying the work, including the information set forth on a notice of copyright.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The name of, and other identifying information about, the author of a work.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The name of, and other identifying information about, the copyright owner of the work, including the information set forth in a notice of copyright.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> With the exception of public performances of works by radio and television broadcast stations, the name of, and other identifying information about, a performer whose performance is fixed in a work other than an audiovisual work.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> With the exception of public performances of works by radio and television broadcast stations, in the case of an audiovisual work, the name of, and other identifying information about, a writer, performer, or director who is credited in the audiovisual work.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Terms and conditions for use of the work.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Identifying numbers or symbols referring to such information or links to such information.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Such other information as the Register of Copyrights may prescribe by regulation, except that the Register of Copyrights may not require the provision of any information concerning the user of a copyrighted work.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Law Enforcement, Intelligence, and Other Government Activities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section does not prohibit any lawfully authorized investigative, protective, information security, or intelligence activity of an officer, agent, or employee of the United States, a State, or a political subdivision of a State, or a person acting pursuant to a contract with the United States, a State, or a political subdivision of a State. For purposes of this subsection, the term “information security” means activities carried out in order to identify and address the vulnerabilities of a government computer, computer system, or computer network.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Limitations on Liability.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Analog transmissions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In the case of an analog transmission, a person who is making transmissions in its capacity as a broadcast station, or as a cable system, or someone who provides programming to such station or system, shall not be liable for a violation of subsection (b) if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> avoiding the activity that constitutes such violation is not technically feasible or would create an undue financial hardship on such person; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> such person did not intend, by engaging in such activity, to induce, enable, facilitate, or conceal infringement of a right under this title.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Digital transmissions.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> If a digital transmission standard for the placement of copyright management information for a category of works is set in a voluntary, consensus standard-setting process involving a representative cross-section of broadcast stations or cable systems and copyright owners of a category of works that are intended for public performance by such stations or systems, a person identified in paragraph (1) shall not be liable for a violation of subsection (b) with respect to the particular copyright management information addressed by such standard if—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the placement of such information by someone other than such person is not in accordance with such standard; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the activity that constitutes such violation is not intended to induce, enable, facilitate, or conceal infringement of a right under this title.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> Until a digital transmission standard has been set pursuant to subparagraph (A) with respect to the placement of copyright management information for a category of works, a person identified in paragraph (1) shall not be liable for a violation of subsection (b) with respect to such copyright management information, if the activity that constitutes such violation is not intended to induce, enable, facilitate, or conceal infringement of a right under this title, and if—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the transmission of such information by such person would result in a perceptible visual or aural degradation of the digital signal; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> the transmission of such information by such person would conflict with—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> an applicable government regulation relating to transmission of information in a digital signal;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> an applicable industry-wide standard relating to the transmission of information in a digital signal that was adopted by a voluntary consensus standards body prior to the effective date of this chapter; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> an applicable industry-wide standard relating to the transmission of information in a digital signal that was adopted in a voluntary, consensus standards-setting process open to participation by a representative cross-section of broadcast stations or cable systems and copyright owners of a category of works that are intended for public performance by such stations or systems.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>As used in this subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the term “broadcast station” has the meaning given that term in section 3 of the Communications Act of 1934 (<ref>47 U.S.C. 153</ref>); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the term “cable system” has the meaning given that term in section 602 of the Communications Act of 1934 (<ref>47 U.S.C. 522</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 105–304, title I, § 103(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-28">Oct. 28, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2872</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–44, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1999-08-05">Aug. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 222</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1203.</num>
<heading> Civil remedies</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Civil Actions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any person injured by a violation of section 1201 or 1202 may bring a civil action in an appropriate United States district court for such violation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Powers of the Court</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In an action brought under subsection (a), the court—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> may grant temporary and permanent injunctions on such terms as it deems reasonable to prevent or restrain a violation, but in no event shall impose a prior restraint on free speech or the press protected under the 1st amendment to the Constitution;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> at any time while an action is pending, may order the impounding, on such terms as it deems reasonable, of any device or product that is in the custody or control of the alleged violator and that the court has reasonable cause to believe was involved in a violation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> may award damages under subsection (c);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> in its discretion may allow the recovery of costs by or against any party other than the United States or an officer thereof;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> in its discretion may award reasonable attorney’s fees to the prevailing party; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> may, as part of a final judgment or decree finding a violation, order the remedial modification or the destruction of any device or product involved in the violation that is in the custody or control of the violator or has been impounded under paragraph (2).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Award of Damages.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Except as otherwise provided in this title, a person committing a violation of section 1201 or 1202 is liable for either—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the actual damages and any additional profits of the violator, as provided in paragraph (2), or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> statutory damages, as provided in paragraph (3).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Actual damages</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The court shall award to the complaining party the actual damages suffered by the party as a result of the violation, and any profits of the violator that are attributable to the violation and are not taken into account in computing the actual damages, if the complaining party elects such damages at any time before final judgment is entered.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Statutory damages</inline>.—</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> At any time before final judgment is entered, a complaining party may elect to recover an award of statutory damages for each violation of section 1201 in the sum of not less than $200 or more than $2,500 per act of circumvention, device, product, component, offer, or performance of service, as the court considers just.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> At any time before final judgment is entered, a complaining party may elect to recover an award of statutory damages for each violation of section 1202 in the sum of not less than $2,500 or more than $25,000.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Repeated violations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In any case in which the injured party sustains the burden of proving, and the court finds, that a person has violated section 1201 or 1202 within 3 years after a final judgment was entered against the person for another such violation, the court may increase the award of damages up to triple the amount that would otherwise be awarded, as the court considers just.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Innocent violations.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The court in its discretion may reduce or remit the total award of damages in any case in which the violator sustains the burden of proving, and the court finds, that the violator was not aware and had no reason to believe that its acts constituted a violation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Nonprofit library, archives, educational institutions, or public broadcasting entities.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this subparagraph, the term “public broadcasting entity” has the meaning given such term under section 118(f).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In the case of a nonprofit library, archives, educational institution, or public broadcasting entity, the court shall remit damages in any case in which the library, archives, educational institution, or public broadcasting entity sustains the burden of proving, and the court finds, that the library, archives, educational institution, or public broadcasting entity was not aware and had no reason to believe that its acts constituted a violation.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 105–304, title I, § 103(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-28">Oct. 28, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2874</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(9) [title V, § 5004(a)]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–593; <ref>Pub. L. 111–295, § 6(f)(3)</ref>, <date date="2010-12-09">Dec. 9, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3181</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1204.</num>
<heading> Criminal offenses and penalties</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Any person who violates section 1201 or 1202 willfully and for purposes of commercial advantage or private financial gain—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall be fined not more than $500,000 or imprisoned for not more than 5 years, or both, for the first offense; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall be fined not more than $1,000,000 or imprisoned for not more than 10 years, or both, for any subsequent offense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation for Nonprofit Library, Archives, Educational Institution, or Public Broadcasting Entity</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subsection (a) shall not apply to a nonprofit library, archives, educational institution, or public broadcasting entity (as defined under section 118(f)).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Statute of Limitations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No criminal proceeding shall be brought under this section unless such proceeding is commenced within 5 years after the cause of action arose.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 105–304, title I, § 103(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-28">Oct. 28, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2876</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(9) [title V, § 5004(b)]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–593; <ref>Pub. L. 111–295, § 6(f)(3)</ref>, <date date="2010-12-09">Dec. 9, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3181</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1205.</num>
<heading> Savings clause</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter abrogates, diminishes, or weakens the provisions of, nor provides any defense or element of mitigation in a criminal prosecution or civil action under, any Federal or State law that prevents the violation of the privacy of an individual in connection with the individual’s use of the Internet.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 105–304, title I, § 103(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-28">Oct. 28, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2876</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>