<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 11—</num>
<heading>SOUND RECORDINGS AND MUSIC VIDEOS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1101.</num>
<heading> Unauthorized fixation and trafficking in sound recordings and music videos</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Unauthorized Acts</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Anyone who, without the consent of the performer or performers involved—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> fixes the sounds or sounds and images of a live musical performance in a copy or phonorecord, or reproduces copies or phonorecords of such a performance from an unauthorized fixation,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> transmits or otherwise communicates to the public the sounds or sounds and images of a live musical performance, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> distributes or offers to distribute, sells or offers to sell, rents or offers to rent, or traffics in any copy or phonorecord fixed as described in paragraph (1), regardless of whether the fixations occurred in the United States,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be subject to the remedies provided in sections 502 through 505, to the same extent as an infringer of copyright.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “traffic” has the same meaning as in section 2320(e) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002017">1</ref> of title 18.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Applicability</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section shall apply to any act or acts that occur on or after the date of the enactment of the Uruguay Round Agreements Act.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">State Law Not Preempted</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section may be construed to annul or limit any rights or remedies under the common law or statutes of any State.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–465, title V, § 512(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4974</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 109–181, § 2(c)(3)</ref>, <date date="2006-03-16">Mar. 16, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 288</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>