<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 54—</num>
<heading>STATE SMALL BUSINESS CREDIT INITIATIVE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5701.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter, the following definitions shall apply:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appropriate committees of Congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “appropriate committees of Congress” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship, the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry, the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs, the Committee on Finance, the Committee on the Budget, and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Committee on Small Business, the Committee on Agriculture, the Committee on Financial Services, the Committee on Ways and Means, the Committee on the Budget, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appropriate Federal banking agency</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “appropriate Federal banking agency”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> has the same meaning as in <ref>section 1813(q) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> includes the National Credit Union Administration Board in the case of any credit union the deposits of which are insured in accordance with the Federal Credit Union Act [<ref>12 U.S.C. 1751</ref> et seq.].</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Enrolled loan</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “enrolled loan” means a loan made by a financial institution lender that is enrolled by a participating State in an approved State capital access program in accordance with this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal contribution</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Federal contribution” means the portion of the contribution made by a participating State to, or for the account of, an approved State program that is made with Federal funds allocated to the State by the Secretary under <ref>section 5702 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Financial institution</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “financial institution” means any insured depository institution, insured credit union, or community development financial institution, as those terms are each defined in <ref>section 4702 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Participating State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “participating State” means any State that has been approved for participation in the Program under <ref>section 5703 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Program” means the State Small Business Credit Initiative established under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Qualifying loan or swap funding facility</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “qualifying loan or swap funding facility” means a contractual arrangement between a participating State and a private financial entity under which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the participating State delivers funds to the entity as collateral;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the entity provides funding from the arrangement back to the participating State; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the full amount of resulting funding from the arrangement, less any fees and other costs of the arrangement, is contributed to, or for the account of, an approved State program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reserve fund</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “reserve fund” means a fund, established by a participating State, dedicated to a particular financial institution lender, for the purposes of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> depositing all required premium charges paid by the financial institution lender and by each borrower receiving a loan under an approved State program from that financial institution lender;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> depositing contributions made by the participating State, including State contributions made with Federal contributions; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> covering losses on enrolled loans by disbursing accumulated funds.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(10)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “State” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a State of the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Commonwealth of Northern Mariana Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the United States Virgin Islands;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> when designated by a State of the United States, a political subdivision of that State that the Secretary determines has the capacity to participate in the Program;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> under the circumstances described in <ref>section 5703(d) of this title</ref>, a municipality of a State of the United States to which the Secretary has given a special permission under <ref>section 5703(d) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> a Tribal government, or a group of Tribal governments that jointly apply for an allocation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(11)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State capital access program</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “State capital access program” means a program of a State that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> uses public resources to promote private access to credit; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> meets the eligibility criteria in <ref>section 5704(c) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(12)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State other credit support program</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “State other credit support program”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> means a program of a State that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> uses public resources to promote private access to credit;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> is not a State capital access program; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> meets the eligibility criteria in <ref>section 5705(c) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> includes, collateral support programs, loan participation programs, State-run venture capital fund programs, and credit guarantee programs.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(13)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “State program” means a State capital access program or a State other credit support program.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(14)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of the Treasury.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(15)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Business enterprise owned and controlled by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “business enterprise owned and controlled by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals” means a business that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> if privately owned, 51 percent is owned by one or more socially and economically disadvantaged individuals;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> if publicly owned, 51 percent of the stock is owned by one or more socially and economically disadvantaged individuals; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> in the case of a mutual institution, a majority of the Board of Directors, account holders, and the community which the institution services is predominantly comprised of socially and economically disadvantaged individuals.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(16)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Community development financial institution</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “community development financial institution” has the meaning given that term under <ref>section 4702 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(17)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Minority depository institution</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “minority depository institution” has the meaning given that term under section 308(b) of the Financial Institutions Reform, Recovery, and Enforcement Act of 1989.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(18)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Socially and economically disadvantaged individual</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “socially and economically disadvantaged individual” means an individual who is a socially disadvantaged individual or an economically disadvantaged individual, as such terms are defined, respectively, under <ref>section 637 of title 15</ref> and the regulations thereunder.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(19)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tribal government</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Tribal government” means the recognized governing body of any Indian or Alaska Native tribe, band, nation, pueblo, village, community, component band, or component reservation, individually identified (including parenthetically) in the list published most recently as of <date date="2021-03-11">March 11, 2021</date>, pursuant to <ref>section 5131 of title 25</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–240, title III, § 3002</ref>, <date date="2010-09-27">Sept. 27, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2568</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–2, title III, § 3301(e)</ref>, (f), <date date="2021-03-11">Mar. 11, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 71</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5702.</num>
<heading> Federal funds allocated to States</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program established; purpose</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established the State Small Business Credit Initiative, to be administered by the Secretary. Under the Program, the Secretary shall allocate Federal funds to participating States and make the allocated funds available to the participating States as provided in this section for the uses described in this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Allocation formula</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 30 days after <date date="2021-03-11">March 11, 2021</date>, the Secretary shall allocate Federal funds to participating States so that each State is eligible to receive an amount equal to what the State would receive under the 2021 allocation, as determined under paragraph (2).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> 2021 allocation formula</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">With respect to States other than Tribal governments, the Secretary shall determine the 2021 allocation by allocating Federal funds among the States in the proportion that each such State’s 2020 State employment decline bears to the aggregate of the 2020 State employment declines for all States.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Minimum allocation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary shall adjust the allocations under subparagraph (A) for each State to the extent necessary to ensure that no State receives less than 0.9 percent of the Federal funds.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002544">1</ref> 2020 State employment decline defined</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In this paragraph and with respect to a State, the term “2020 State employment decline” means the excess (if any) of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the number of individuals employed in such State determined for December 2019; over</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the number of individuals employed in such State determined for December 2020.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> <sup>1</sup> Separate allocation for Tribal governments</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">With respect to States that are Tribal governments, the Secretary shall determine the 2021 allocation by allocating $500,000,000 among the Tribal governments in the proportion the Secretary determines appropriate, including with consideration to available employment and economic data regarding each such Tribal government.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice of intent; timing of allocation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">With respect to allocations to States that are Tribal governments, the Secretary may—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> require Tribal governments that individually or jointly wish to participate in the Program to file a notice of intent with the Secretary not later than 30 days after <date date="2021-03-11">March 11, 2021</date>; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> notwithstanding paragraph (1), allocate Federal funds to participating Tribal governments not later than 60 days after <date date="2021-03-11">March 11, 2021</date>.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Employment data</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">If the Secretary determines that employment data with respect to a State is unavailable from the Bureau of Labor Statistics of the Department of Labor, the Secretary shall consider such other economic and employment data that is otherwise available for purposes of determining the employment data of such State.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability of allocated amount</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The amount allocated by the Secretary to each participating State under subsection (b) shall be made available to the State as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Allocated amount generally to be available to State in one-thirds</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> apportion the participating State’s allocated amount into thirds;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> transfer to the participating State the first ⅓ when the Secretary approves the State for participation under <ref>section 5703 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> transfer to the participating State each successive ⅓ when the State has certified to the Secretary that it has expended, transferred, or obligated 80 percent of the last transferred ⅓ for Federal contributions to, or for the account of, State programs that have delivered loans or investments to eligible businesses.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority to withhold pending audit</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary may withhold the transfer of any successive ⅓ pending results of a financial audit.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inspector General audits</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The Inspector General of the Department of the Treasury shall carry out an audit of the participating State’s use of allocated Federal funds transferred to the State.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recoupment of misused transferred funds required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The allocation agreement between the Secretary and the participating State shall provide that the Secretary shall recoup any allocated Federal funds transferred to the participating State if the results of the an audit include a finding that there was an intentional or reckless misuse of transferred funds by the State.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Penalty for misstatement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Any participating State that is found to have intentionally misstated any report issued to the Secretary under the Program shall be ineligible to receive any additional funds under the Program. Funds that had been allocated or that would otherwise have been allocated to such participating State shall be paid into the general fund of the Treasury for reduction of the public debt.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iv)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Municipalities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">In this subparagraph, the term “participating State” shall include a municipality given special permission to participate in the Program, under <ref>section 5703(d) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary may, in the Secretary’s discretion, transfer the full amount of the participating State’s allocated amount to the State in a single transfer if the participating State applies to the Secretary for approval to use the full amount of the allocation as collateral for a qualifying loan or swap funding facility.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transferred amounts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Each amount transferred to a participating State under this section shall remain available to the State until used by the State as permitted under paragraph (3).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of transferred funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Each participating State may use funds transferred to it under this section only—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> for making Federal contributions to, or for the account of, an approved State program;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> as collateral for a qualifying loan or swap funding facility;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> in the case of the first ⅓ transferred, for paying administrative costs incurred by the State in implementing an approved State program in an amount not to exceed 5 percent of that first ⅓; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> in the case of each successive ⅓ transferred, for paying administrative costs incurred by the State in implementing an approved State program in an amount not to exceed 3 percent of that successive ⅓.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination of availability of amounts not transferred</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Any portion of a participating State’s allocated amount that has not been transferred to the State under this section may be deemed by the Secretary to be no longer allocated to the State and no longer available to the State and shall be returned to the general fund of the Treasury or reallocated as described under subparagraph (B), if—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the second ⅓ of a State’s allocated amount has not been transferred to the State before the end of the end of the 3-year period beginning on the date that the Secretary approves the State for participation; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the last ⅓ of a State’s allocated amount has not been transferred to the State before the end of the end of the 6-year period beginning on the date that the Secretary approves the State for participation.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reallocation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Any amount deemed by the Secretary to be no longer allocated to a State and no longer available to such State under subparagraph (A) may be reallocated by the Secretary to other participating States. In making such a reallocation, the Secretary shall not take into account the minimum allocation requirements under subsection (b)(2)(B) or the specific allocation for Tribal governments described under subsection (b)(2)(C).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transferred amounts not assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The amounts transferred to a participating State under this section shall not be considered assistance for purposes of subtitle V of title 31.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In this section—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the term “allocated amount” means the total amount of Federal funds allocated by the Secretary under subsection (b) to the participating State; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> the term “⅓” means—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> in the case of the first ⅓ and second ⅓, an amount equal to 33 percent of a participating State’s allocated amount; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in the case of the last ⅓, an amount equal to 34 percent of a participating State’s allocated amount.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional allocations to support business enterprises owned and controlled by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Of the amounts appropriated for fiscal year 2021 to carry out the Program, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> allocate $1,500,000,000 to States from funds allocated under this section and, by regulation or other guidance, prescribe Program requirements that the funds be expended for business enterprises owned and controlled by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> allocate such amounts to States based on the needs of business enterprises owned and controlled by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals, as determined by the Secretary, in each State, and not subject to the allocation formula described under subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Incentive allocations to support business enterprises owned and controlled by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Of the amounts appropriated for fiscal year 2021 to carry out the Program, the Secretary shall set aside $1,000,000,000 for an incentive program under which the Secretary shall increase the second ⅓ and last ⅓ allocations for States that demonstrate robust support, as determined by the Secretary, for business concerns owned and controlled by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals in the deployment of prior allocation amounts.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional allocations to support very small businesses</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Of the amounts appropriated to carry out the Program, the Secretary shall allocate not less than $500,000,000 to States from funds allocated under this section to be expended for very small businesses.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Very small business defined</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In this subsection, the term “very small business”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> means a business with fewer than 10 employees; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> may include independent contractors and sole proprietors.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–240, title III, § 3003</ref>, <date date="2010-09-27">Sept. 27, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2570</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–2, title III, § 3301(a)(1)(A)</ref>, (b), (c), <date date="2021-03-11">Mar. 11, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 67</ref>, 69, 70.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5703.</num>
<heading> Approving States for participation</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any State may apply to the Secretary for approval to be a participating State under the Program and to be eligible for an allocation of Federal funds under the Program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General approval criteria</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall approve a State to be a participating State, if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a specific department, agency, or political subdivision of the State has been designated to implement a State program and participate in the Program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> all legal actions necessary to enable such designated department, agency, or political subdivision to implement a State program and participate in the Program have been accomplished;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the State has filed an application with the Secretary for approval of a State capital access program under <ref>section 5704 of this title</ref> or approval as a State other credit support program under <ref>section 5705 of this title</ref>, in each case within the time period provided in the respective section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> the State and the Secretary have executed an allocation agreement that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> conforms to the requirements of this chapter;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> ensures that the State program complies with such national standards as are established by the Secretary under <ref>section 5708(a)(2) of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> sets forth internal control, compliance, and reporting requirements as established by the Secretary, and such other terms and conditions necessary to carry out the purposes of this chapter, including an agreement by the State to allow the Secretary to audit State programs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> requires that the State program be fully positioned, within 90 days of the State’s execution of the allocation agreement with the Secretary, to act on providing the kind of credit support that the State program was established to provide; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> includes an agreement by the State to deliver to the Secretary, and update annually, a schedule describing how the State intends to apportion among its State programs the Federal funds allocated to the State.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contractual arrangements for implementation of State programs</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A State may be approved to be a participating State, and be eligible for an allocation of Federal funds under the Program, if the State has contractual arrangements for the implementation and administration of its State program with—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an existing, approved State program administered by another State; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an authorized agent of, or entity supervised by, the State, including for-profit and not-for-profit entities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special permission</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Circumstances when a municipality may apply directly</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If a State does not, within 60 days after <date date="2021-03-11">March 11, 2021</date>, file with the Secretary a notice of its intent to apply for approval by the Secretary of a State program or within 9 months after <date date="2021-03-11">March 11, 2021</date>, file with the Secretary a complete application for approval of a State program, the Secretary may grant to municipalities of that State a special permission that will allow them to apply directly to the Secretary without the State for approval to be participating municipalities.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Timing requirements applicable to municipalities applying directly</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To qualify for the special permission, a municipality of a State shall be required, within 12 months after <date date="2021-03-11">March 11, 2021</date>, to file with the Secretary a complete application for approval by the Secretary of a State program.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notices of intent and applications from more than 1 municipality</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A municipality of a State may combine with 1 or more other municipalities of that State to file a joint notice of intent to file and a joint application.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Approval criteria</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The general approval criteria in paragraphs (2) and (4) shall apply.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Allocation to municipalities</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> If more than 3</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">If more than 3 municipalities, or combination of municipalities as provided in paragraph (3), of a State apply for approval by the Secretary to be participating municipalities under this subsection, and the applications meet the approval criteria in paragraph (4), the Secretary shall allocate Federal funds to the 3 municipalities with the largest populations.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> If 3 or fewer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">If 3 or fewer municipalities, or combination of municipalities as provided in paragraph (3), of a State apply for approval by the Secretary to be participating municipalities under this subsection, and the applications meet the approval criteria in paragraph (4), the Secretary shall allocate Federal funds to each applicant municipality or combination of municipalities.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Apportionment of allocated amount among participating municipalities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the Secretary approves municipalities to be participating municipalities under this subsection, the Secretary shall apportion the full amount of the Federal funds that are allocated to that State to municipalities that are approved under this subsection in amounts proportionate to the population of those municipalities, based on the most recent available decennial census.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Approving State programs for municipalities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the Secretary approves municipalities to be participating municipalities under this subsection, the Secretary shall take into account the additional considerations in <ref>section 5705(d) of this title</ref> in making the determination under section 5704 or 5705 of this title that the State program or programs to be implemented by the participating municipalities, including a State capital access program, is eligible for Federal contributions to, or for the account of, the State program.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–240, title III, § 3004</ref>, <date date="2010-09-27">Sept. 27, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2573</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–2, title III, § 3301(a)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="2021-03-11">Mar. 11, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 69</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5704.</num>
<heading> Approving State capital access programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A participating State that establishes a new, or has an existing, State capital access program that meets the eligibility criteria in subsection (c) may apply to Secretary to have the State capital access program approved as eligible for Federal contributions to the reserve fund.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Approval</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall approve such State capital access program as eligible for Federal contributions to the reserve fund if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> within 60 days after <date date="2021-03-11">March 11, 2021</date>, the State has filed with the Secretary a notice of intent to apply for approval by the Secretary of a State capital access program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> within 9 months after <date date="2021-03-11">March 11, 2021</date>, the State has filed with the Secretary a complete application for approval by the Secretary of a capital access program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the State satisfies the requirements of subsections (a) and (b) of <ref>section 5703 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the State capital access program meets the eligibility criteria in subsection (c).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility criteria for State capital access programs</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For a State capital access program to be approved under this section, that program shall be required to be a program of the State that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provides portfolio insurance for business loans based on a separate loan-loss reserve fund for each financial institution;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> requires insurance premiums to be paid by the financial institution lenders and by the business borrowers to the reserve fund to have their loans enrolled in the reserve fund;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> provides for contributions to be made by the State to the reserve fund in amounts at least equal to the sum of the amount of the insurance premium charges paid by the borrower and the financial institution to the reserve fund for any newly enrolled loan; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> provides its portfolio insurance solely for loans that meet both the following requirements:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The borrower has 500 employees or less at the time that the loan is enrolled in the Program.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The loan amount does not exceed $5,000,000.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal contributions to approved State capital access programs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A State capital access program approved under this section will be eligible for receiving Federal contributions to the reserve fund in an amount equal to the sum of the amount of the insurance premium charges paid by the borrowers and by the financial institution to the reserve fund for loans that meet the requirements in subsection (c)(4). A participating State may use the Federal contribution to make its contribution to the reserve fund of an approved State capital access program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Minimum program requirements for State capital access programs</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall, by regulation or other guidance, prescribe Program requirements that meet the following minimum requirements:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Experience and capacity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The participating State shall determine for each financial institution that participates in the State capital access program, after consultation with the appropriate Federal banking agency or, in the case of a financial institution that is a nondepository community development financial institution, the Community Development Financial Institution Fund, that the financial institution has sufficient commercial lending experience and financial and managerial capacity to participate in the approved State capital access program. The determination by the State shall not be reviewable by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Investment authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subject to applicable State law, the participating State may invest, or cause to be invested, funds held in a reserve fund by establishing a deposit account at the financial institution lender in the name of the participating State. In the event that funds in the reserve fund are not deposited in such an account, such funds shall be invested in a form that the participating State determines is safe and liquid.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Loan terms and conditions to be determined by agreement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A loan to be filed for enrollment in an approved State capital access program may be made with such interest rate, fees, and other terms and conditions, and the loan may be enrolled in the approved State capital access program and claims may be filed and paid, as agreed upon by the financial institution lender and the borrower, consistent with applicable law.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Lender capital at-risk</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A loan to be filed for enrollment in the State capital access program shall require the financial institution lender to have a meaningful amount of its own capital resources at risk in the loan.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Premium charges minimum and maximum amounts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The insurance premium charges payable to the reserve fund by the borrower and the financial institution lender shall be prescribed by the financial institution lender, within minimum and maximum limits that require that the sum of the insurance premium charges paid in connection with a loan by the borrower and the financial institution lender may not be less than 2 percent nor more than 7 percent of the amount of the loan enrolled in the approved State capital access program.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State contributions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In enrolling a loan in an approved State capital access program, the participating State may make a contribution to the reserve fund to supplement Federal contributions made under this Program.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Loan purpose</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Particular loan purpose requirements and prohibitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In connection with the filing of a loan for enrollment in an approved State capital access program, the financial institution lender—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> shall obtain an assurance from each borrower that—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the proceeds of the loan will be used for a business purpose;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the loan will not be used to finance such business activities as the Secretary, by regulation, may proscribe as prohibited loan purposes for enrollment in an approved State capital access program; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<chapeau> the borrower is not—</chapeau>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> an executive officer, director, or principal shareholder of the financial institution lender;</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> a member of the immediate family of an executive officer, director, or principal shareholder of the financial institution lender; or</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(cc)</num>
<content> a related interest of any such executive officer, director, principal shareholder, or member of the immediate family;</content>
</item>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> shall provide assurances to the participating State that the loan has not been made in order to place under the protection of the approved State capital access program prior debt that is not covered under the approved State capital access program and that is or was owed by the borrower to the financial institution lender or to an affiliate of the financial institution lender;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> shall not allow the enrollment of a loan to a borrower that is a refinancing of a loan previously made to that borrower by the financial institution lender or an affiliate of the financial institution lender; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> may include additional restrictions on the eligibility of loans or borrowers that are not inconsistent with the provisions and purposes of this chapter, including compliance with all applicable Federal and State laws, regulations, ordinances, and Executive orders.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In this paragraph, the terms “executive officer”, “director”, “principal shareholder”, “immediate family”, and “related interest” refer to the same relationship to a financial institution lender as the relationship described in part 215 of title 12 of the Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor to such part.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Capital access for small businesses in underserved communities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">At the time that a State applies to the Secretary to have the State capital access program approved as eligible for Federal contributions, the State shall deliver to the Secretary a report stating how the State plans to use the Federal contributions to the reserve fund to provide access to capital for small businesses in low- and moderate-income, minority, and other underserved communities, including women- and minority-owned small businesses.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–240, title III, § 3005</ref>, <date date="2010-09-27">Sept. 27, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2574</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–2, title III, § 3301(a)(1)(C)</ref>, <date date="2021-03-11">Mar. 11, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 69</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5705.</num>
<heading> Approving collateral support and other innovative credit access and guarantee initiatives for small businesses and manufacturers</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A participating State that establishes a new, or has an existing, credit support program that meets the eligibility criteria in subsection (c) may apply to the Secretary to have the State other credit support program approved as eligible for Federal contributions to, or for the account of, the State program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Approval</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall approve such State other credit support program as eligible for Federal contributions to, or for the account of, the program if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Secretary determines that the State satisfies the requirements of paragraphs (1) through (3) of <ref>section 5704(b) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Secretary determines that the State other credit support program meets the eligibility criteria in subsection (c);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the Secretary determines the State other credit support program to be eligible based on the additional considerations in subsection (d); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> within 9 months after <date date="2021-03-11">March 11, 2021</date>, the State has filed with Treasury a complete application for Treasury approval.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility criteria for State other credit support programs</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For a State other credit support program to be approved under this section, that program shall be required to be a program of the State that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> can demonstrate that, at a minimum, $1 of public investment by the State program will cause and result in $1 of new private credit;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> can demonstrate a reasonable expectation that, when considered with all other State programs of the State, such State programs together have the ability to use amounts of new Federal contributions to, or for the account of, all such programs in the State to cause and result in amounts of new small business lending at least 10 times the new Federal contribution amount;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> for those State other credit support programs that provide their credit support through 1 or more financial institution lenders, requires the financial institution lenders to have a meaningful amount of their own capital resources at risk in their small business lending; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> uses Federal funds allocated under this chapter to extend credit support that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> targets an average borrower size of 500 employees or less;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> does not extend credit support to borrowers that have more than 750 employees;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> targets support towards loans with an average principal amount of $5,000,000 or less; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> does not extend credit support to loans that exceed a principal amount of $20,000,000.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional considerations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In making a determination that a State other credit support program is eligible for Federal contributions to, or for the account of, the State program, the Secretary shall take into account the following additional considerations:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The anticipated benefits to the State, its businesses, and its residents to be derived from the Federal contributions to, or for the account of, the approved State other credit support program, including the extent to which resulting small business lending will expand economic opportunities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The operational capacity, skills, and experience of the management team of the State other credit support program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The capacity of the State other credit support program to manage increases in the volume of its small business lending.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The internal accounting and administrative controls systems of the State other credit support program, and the extent to which they can provide reasonable assurance that funds of the State program are safeguarded against waste, loss, unauthorized use, or misappropriation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The soundness of the program design and implementation plan of the State other credit support program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal contributions to approved State other credit support programs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A State other credit support program approved under this section will be eligible for receiving Federal contributions to, or for the account of, the State program in an amount consistent with the schedule describing the apportionment of allocated Federal funds among State programs delivered by the State to the Secretary under the allocation agreement.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Minimum Program Requirements for State other credit support programs</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fund <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002545">1</ref> to prescribe</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall, by regulation or other guidance, prescribe Program requirements for approved State other credit support programs.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Considerations for fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In prescribing minimum Program requirements for approved State other credit support programs, the Secretary shall take into consideration, to the extent the Secretary determines applicable and appropriate, the minimum Program requirements for approved State capital access programs in <ref>section 5704(e) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–240, title III, § 3006</ref>, <date date="2010-09-27">Sept. 27, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2577</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–2, title III, § 3301(a)(1)(D)</ref>, <date date="2021-03-11">Mar. 11, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 69</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5706.</num>
<heading> Reports</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Quarterly use-of-funds report</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 30 days after the beginning of each calendar quarter, beginning after the first full calendar quarter to occur after the date the Secretary approves a State for participation, the participating State shall submit to the Secretary a report on the use of Federal funding by the participating State during the previous calendar quarter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Each report under this subsection shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> indicate the total amount of Federal funding used by the participating State; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> include a certification by the participating State that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the information provided in accordance with subparagraph (A) is accurate;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> funds continue to be available and legally committed to contributions by the State to, or for the account of, approved State programs, less any amount that has been contributed by the State to, or for the account of, approved State programs subsequent to the State being approved for participation in the Program; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the participating State is implementing its approved State program or programs in accordance with this chapter and regulations issued under <ref>section 5709 of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than March 31 of each year, beginning <date date="2022-03-31">March 31, 2022</date>, each participating State shall submit to the Secretary an annual report that shall include the following information:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The number of borrowers that received new loans originated under the approved State program or programs after the State program was approved as eligible for Federal contributions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The total amount of such new loans.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Breakdowns by industry type, loan size, annual sales, and number of employees of the borrowers that received such new loans.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The zip code of each borrower that received such a new loan.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Such other data as the Secretary, in the Secretary’s sole discretion, may require to carry out the purposes of the Program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Form</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The reports and data filed under subsections (a) and (b) shall be in such form as the Secretary, in the Secretary’s sole discretion, may require.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination of reporting requirements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The requirement to submit reports under subsections (a) and (b) shall terminate for a participating State with the submission of the completed reports due on the first March 31 to occur after 5 complete 12-month periods after the State is approved by the Secretary to be a participating State.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–240, title III, § 3007</ref>, <date date="2010-09-27">Sept. 27, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2579</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–2, title III, § 3301(a)(1)(E)</ref>, <date date="2021-03-11">Mar. 11, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 69</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5707.</num>
<heading> Remedies for State program termination or failures</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Remedies</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">If any of the events listed in paragraph (2) occur, the Secretary, in the Secretary’s discretion, may—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> reduce the amount of Federal funds allocated to the State under the Program; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> terminate any further transfers of allocated amounts that have not yet been transferred to the State.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Causal events</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The events referred to in paragraph (1) are—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> termination by a participating State of its participation in the Program;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> failure on the part of a participating State to submit complete reports under <ref>section 5706 of this title</ref> on a timely basis; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> noncompliance by the State with the terms of the allocation agreement between the Secretary and the State.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deallocated amounts to be reallocated</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If, after 13 months, any portion of the amount of Federal funds allocated to a participating State is deemed by the Secretary to be no longer allocated to the State after actions taken by the Secretary under subsection (a)(1), the Secretary shall reallocate that portion among the participating States, excluding the State whose allocated funds were deemed to be no longer allocated, as provided in <ref>section 5702(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–240, title III, § 3008</ref>, <date date="2010-09-27">Sept. 27, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2580</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5708.</num>
<heading> Implementation and administration</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General authorities and duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> consult with the Administrator of the Small Business Administration and the appropriate Federal banking agencies on the administration of the Program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> establish minimum national standards for approved State programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> provide technical assistance to States for starting State programs and generally disseminate best practices;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> manage, administer, and perform necessary program integrity functions for the Program; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> ensure adequate oversight of the approved State programs, including oversight of the cash flows, performance, and compliance of each approved State program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is hereby appropriated to the Secretary, out of funds in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, $1,500,000,000 to carry out the Program, including to pay reasonable costs of administering the Program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination of Secretary’s Program administration functions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The authorities and duties of the Secretary to implement and administer the Program shall terminate at the end of the 7-year period beginning on <date date="2021-03-11">March 11, 2021</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Expedited contracting</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">During the 1-year period beginning on <date date="2021-03-11">March 11, 2021</date>, the Secretary may enter into contracts without regard to any other provision of law regarding public contracts, for purposes of carrying out this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Technical assistance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Of the amounts appropriated for fiscal year 2021 to carry out the Program, $500,000,000 may be used by the Secretary to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> provide funds to States to carry out a technical assistance plan under which a State will provide legal, accounting, and financial advisory services, either directly or contracted with legal, accounting, and financial advisory firms, with priority given to business enterprises owned and controlled by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals, to very small businesses and business enterprises owned and controlled by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals applying for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> State programs under the Program; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> other State or Federal programs that support small businesses;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> transfer amounts to the Minority Business Development Agency, so that the Agency may use such amounts in a manner the Agency determines appropriate, including through contracting with third parties, to provide technical assistance to business enterprises owned and controlled by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals applying to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> State programs under the Program; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> other State or Federal programs that support small businesses; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> contract with legal, accounting, and financial advisory firms (with priority given to business enterprises owned and controlled by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals), to provide technical assistance to business enterprises owned and controlled by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals applying to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> State programs under the Program; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> other State or Federal programs that support small businesses.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–240, title III, § 3009</ref>, <date date="2010-09-27">Sept. 27, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2580</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–2, title III, § 3301(a)(1)(F)</ref>, (d), <date date="2021-03-11">Mar. 11, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 69</ref>, 70.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5709.</num>
<heading> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary, in consultation with the Administrator of the Small Business Administration, shall issue such regulations and other guidance as the Secretary determines necessary or appropriate to implement this chapter including to define terms, to establish compliance and reporting requirements, and such other terms and conditions necessary to carry out the purposes of this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–240, title III, § 3010</ref>, <date date="2010-09-27">Sept. 27, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2581</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5710.</num>
<heading> Oversight and audits</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inspector General oversight</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Inspector General of the Department of the Treasury shall conduct, supervise, and coordinate audits and investigations of the use of funds made available under the Program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Required certification</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Financial institutions certification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">With respect to funds received by a participating State under the Program, any financial institution that receives a loan, a loan guarantee, or other financial assistance using such funds after <date date="2021-03-11">March 11, 2021</date>, shall certify that such institution is in compliance with the requirements of section 103.121 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations, a regulation that, at a minimum, requires financial institutions, as that term is defined in section 5312(a)(2) and (c)(1)(A) of title 31, to implement reasonable procedures to verify the identity of any person seeking to open an account, to the extent reasonable and practicable, maintain records of the information used to verify the person’s identity, and determine whether the person appears on any lists of known or suspected terrorists or terrorist organizations provided to the financial institution by any government agency.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sex offense certification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">With respect to funds received by a participating State under the Program, any private entity that receives a loan, a loan guarantee, or other financial assistance using such funds after <date date="2021-03-11">March 11, 2021</date>, shall certify to the participating State that the principals of such entity have not been convicted of a sex offense against a minor (as such terms are defined in <ref>section 20911 of title 34</ref>).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition on pornography</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">None of the funds made available under this chapter may be used to pay the salary of any individual engaged in activities related to the Program who has been officially disciplined for violations of subpart G of the Standards of Ethical Conduct for Employees of the Executive Branch for viewing, downloading, or exchanging pornography, including child pornography, on a Federal Government computer or while performing official Federal Government duties.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–240, title III, § 3011</ref>, <date date="2010-09-27">Sept. 27, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2581</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–188, title IX, § 901(d)</ref>, <date date="2014-11-26">Nov. 26, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 2020</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–2, title III, § 3301(a)(1)(G)</ref>, <date date="2021-03-11">Mar. 11, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 69</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>