<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 38A—</num>
<heading>SINGLE FAMILY MORTGAGE FORECLOSURE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3751.</num>
<heading> Findings and purpose</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the disparate State laws under which mortgages are foreclosed on behalf of the Secretary covering 1- to 4-family residential properties—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> burden certain programs administered by the Secretary;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> increase the costs of collecting obligations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> generally are a detriment to the community in which the properties are located;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the long periods required to complete the foreclosure of such mortgages under certain State laws—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> lead to deterioration in the condition of the properties involved;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> necessitate substantial Federal holding expenditures;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> increase the risk of vandalism, fire loss, depreciation, damage, and waste with respect to the properties; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> adversely affect the neighborhoods in which the properties are located;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> these conditions seriously impair the ability of the Secretary to protect the Federal financial interest in the affected properties and frustrate attainment of the objectives of the underlying Federal program authority;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the availability of uniform and more expeditious procedures, with no right of redemption in the mortgagor or others, for the foreclosure of these mortgages by the Secretary will tend to ameliorate these conditions; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> providing the Secretary with a nonjudicial foreclosure procedure will reduce unnecessary litigation by removing many foreclosures from the courts if they contribute to overcrowded calendars.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purpose</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purpose of this chapter is to create a uniform Federal foreclosure remedy for single family mortgages that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> are held by the Secretary pursuant to title I or title II of the National Housing Act [<ref>12 U.S.C. 1702</ref> et seq., 1707 et seq.]; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> secure loans obligated by the Secretary under section 1452b <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002355">1</ref> of title 42.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–327, title II</ref>, <date date="1994-09-28">Sept. 28, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2316</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3752.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this chapter, the following definitions shall apply:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Bona fide purchaser</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “bona fide purchaser” means a purchaser for value in good faith and without notice of any adverse claim, and who acquires the security property free of any adverse claim.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> County</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “county” has the same meaning as in <ref>section 2 of title 1</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Mortgage</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “mortgage” means a deed of trust, mortgage, deed to secure debt, security agreement, or any other form of instrument under which any property (real, personal or mixed), or any interest in property (including leaseholds, life estates, reversionary interests, and any other estates under applicable State law), is conveyed in trust, mortgaged, encumbered, pledged, or otherwise rendered subject to a lien for the purpose of securing the payment of money or the performance of an obligation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Mortgage agreement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “mortgage agreement” means the note or debt instrument and the mortgage instrument, deed of trust instrument, trust deed, or instrument or instruments creating the mortgage, including any instrument incorporated by reference therein and any instrument or agreement amending or modifying any of the foregoing.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Mortgagor</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “mortgagor” means the obligor, grantor, or trustee named in the mortgage agreement and, unless the context otherwise indicates, includes the current owner of record of the security property whether or not such owner is personally liable on the mortgage debt.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Owner</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “owner” means any person who has an ownership interest in property and includes heirs, devises, executors, administrators, and other personal representatives, and trustees of testamentary trusts if the owner of record is deceased.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Person</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “person” includes any individual, group of individuals, association, partnership, corporation, or organization.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Record; recorded</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The terms “record” and “recorded” include “register” and “registered” in the instance of registered land.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Security property</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “security property” means the property (real, personal or mixed) or an interest in property (including leaseholds, life estates, reversionary interests, and any other estates under applicable State law), together with fixtures and other interests subject to the lien of the mortgage under applicable State law.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(10)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Single family mortgage</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “single family mortgage” means a mortgage that covers property on which there is located a 1- to 4-family residence, and that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is held by the Secretary pursuant to title I or title II of the National Housing Act [<ref>12 U.S.C. 1702</ref> et seq., 1707 et seq.]; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> secures a loan obligated by the Secretary under <ref>section 1452b of title 42</ref>, as it existed before the repeal of that section by <ref>section 12839 of title 42</ref> (except that a mortgage securing such a loan that covers property containing nonresidential space and a 1- to 4-family dwelling shall not be subject to this chapter).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(11)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “State” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the several States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the District of Columbia;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the United States Virgin Islands;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Guam;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> American Samoa;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> the Northern Mariana Islands;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> Indian tribes, as defined by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–327, title II</ref>, <date date="1994-09-28">Sept. 28, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2316</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3753.</num>
<heading> Applicability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Single family mortgages encumbering real estate located in any State may be foreclosed by the Secretary in accordance with this chapter, or pursuant to other foreclosure procedures available, at the option of the Secretary.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–327, title II</ref>, <date date="1994-09-28">Sept. 28, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2316</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3754.</num>
<heading> Designation of foreclosure commissioner</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may designate a person or persons to serve as a foreclosure commissioner or commissioners for the purpose of foreclosing upon a single family mortgage.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Power of sale</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A foreclosure commissioner designated under this section shall have a nonjudicial power of sale.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Qualifications</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The foreclosure commissioner, if a natural person, shall be a resident of the State in which the security property is located and, if not a natural person, the foreclosure commissioner must be duly authorized to transact business under laws of the State in which the security property is located. No person shall be designated as a foreclosure commissioner unless that person is responsible, financially sound, and competent to conduct a foreclosure.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Designation procedure</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Written designation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may designate a foreclosure commissioner by executing a written designation stating the name and business or residential address of the commissioner, except that if a person is designated in his or her capacity as an official or employee of a government or corporate entity, such person may be designated by his or her unique title or position instead of by name.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Substitute commissioners</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may, with or without cause, designate a substitute foreclosure commissioner to replace a previously designated foreclosure commissioner.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Number</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">More than 1 foreclosure commissioner may be designated at any time.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–327, title II</ref>, <date date="1994-09-28">Sept. 28, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2316</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3755.</num>
<heading> Prerequisites to foreclosure</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Upon breach of covenant or condition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary is authorized to foreclose a mortgage under this chapter upon the breach of a covenant or condition in the mortgage agreement.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> No other pending proceedings</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prior to commencement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">No foreclosure may be commenced under this chapter unless any previously pending judicial or nonjudicial proceeding that has been separately instituted by the Secretary to foreclose the mortgage (other than under this chapter), has been withdrawn, dismissed, or otherwise terminated.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> After commencement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">No separately instituted foreclosure proceeding on a mortgage which is the subject of a foreclosure proceeding under this chapter shall be instituted by the Secretary during the pendency of foreclosure pursuant to this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other rights unaffected</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall preclude the Secretary from—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> enforcing any right, other than foreclosure, under applicable Federal or State law, including any right to obtain a monetary judgment; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> foreclosing under this chapter if the Secretary has obtained or is seeking any other remedy available pursuant to Federal or State law, or under the mortgage agreement, including the appointment of a receiver, mortgagee-in-possession status, or relief under an assignment of rents.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–327, title II</ref>, <date date="1994-09-28">Sept. 28, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2316</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3756.</num>
<heading> Commencement of foreclosure</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Request to foreclosure commissioner</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the Secretary, as holder of a single family mortgage, determines that the prerequisites to foreclosure set forth in <ref>section 3755 of this title</ref> are satisfied, the Secretary may request the foreclosure commissioner to commence foreclosure of a single family mortgage. Upon such request, the foreclosure commissioner shall commence foreclosure of the mortgage, by commencing service of a notice of default and foreclosure sale in accordance with sections 3757 and 3758 of this title.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Designation of substitute foreclosure commissioner</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">After commencement of a foreclosure under this chapter, the Secretary may designate a substitute foreclosure commissioner at any time before the time of the foreclosure sale, and the foreclosure shall continue without prejudice, unless the substitute commissioner, in that commissioner’s sole discretion, finds that continuation of the foreclosure sale will unfairly affect the interests of the mortgagor. If the substitute commissioner makes such a finding, the substitute commissioner shall cancel the foreclosure sale, or adjourn such sale in accordance with <ref>section 3760(c) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Written notice</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Upon designation of a substitute foreclosure commissioner, a copy of the written notice of such designation described in <ref>section 3754 of this title</ref> shall be served—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> by mail, as provided in <ref>section 3758 of this title</ref> (except that the minimum time periods between mailing and the date of foreclosure sale prescribed in such section shall not apply); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in any other manner which, in the substitute commissioner’s sole discretion, is conducive to achieving timely notice of such substitution.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–327, title II</ref>, <date date="1994-09-28">Sept. 28, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2316</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3757.</num>
<heading> Notice of default and foreclosure sale</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The notice of default and foreclosure sale to be served in accordance with this chapter shall set forth—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the name and address of the foreclosure commissioner;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the date on which the notice is issued;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> the names of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Secretary;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the original mortgagee (if other than the Secretary); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the original mortgagor;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the street address or a description of the location of the security property, and a description of the security property, sufficient to identify the property to be sold;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the date of the mortgage, the office in which the mortgage is recorded, and the liber number and folio or other appropriate description of the location of recordation of the mortgage;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> identification of the failure to make payment, including the due date of the earliest installment payment remaining wholly unpaid as of the date on which the notice is issued upon which the foreclosure is based, or a description of any other default or defaults upon which foreclosure is based, and the acceleration of the secured indebtedness;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the date, time, and location of the foreclosure sale;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> a statement that the foreclosure is being conducted pursuant to this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> a description of the types of costs, if any, to be paid by the purchaser upon transfer of title;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> the amount and method of deposit to be required at the foreclosure sale (except that no deposit shall be required of the Secretary) and the time and method of payment of the balance of the foreclosure purchase price; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> any other appropriate terms of sale or information, as the Secretary may determine.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–327, title II</ref>, <date date="1994-09-28">Sept. 28, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2316</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3758.</num>
<heading> Service of notice of foreclosure sale</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The foreclosure commissioner shall serve the notice of default and foreclosure sale described in <ref>section 3757 of this title</ref> upon the following persons and in the following manner, and no additional notice shall be required to be served, notwithstanding any notice requirements of any State or local law:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Timing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not less than 21 days before the date of the foreclosure sale, the notice of default and foreclosure sale shall be filed in the manner authorized for filing a notice of an action concerning real property according to the law of the State in which the security property is located or, if none, in the manner authorized by <ref>section 3201 of title 28</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice by mail</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The notice of foreclosure sale shall be sent by certified or registered mail, postage prepaid and return receipt requested, to the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Current owner</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The current security property owner of record, as the record existed 45 days before the date originally set for the foreclosure sale (whether or not the notice describes a sale adjourned).</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Mortgagors</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">All mortgagors of record or other persons who appear on the basis of the record to be liable for part or all of the mortgage debt, as the record existed 45 days before the date originally set for the foreclosure sale (whether or not the notice describes a sale adjourned).</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Dwelling units</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">All dwelling units in the security property (whether or not the notice describes a sale adjourned).</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iv)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other lienholders</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">All persons holding liens of record upon the security property, as the record existed 45 days before the date originally set for the foreclosure sale (whether or not the notice describes a sale adjourned).</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Timing</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice under clauses (i) and (ii)</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Notice under clauses (i) and (ii) of subparagraph (A) shall be mailed not less than 21 days before the date of the foreclosure sale, and shall be mailed to the current owner and mortgagor at the last known address of the current owner and mortgagor, or, if none, to the address of the security property, or, at the discretion of the foreclosure commissioner, to any other address believed to be that of such current owner and mortgagor.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice under clause (iii)</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Notice under clause (iii) of subparagraph (A) shall be mailed not less than 21 days before the date of the foreclosure sale. If the names of the occupants of the security property are not known to the Secretary, or the security property has more than 1 dwelling, the notice shall be posted at the security property not less than 21 days before the foreclosure sale.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice under clause (iv)</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Notice under clause (iv) of subparagraph (A) shall be mailed not less than 21 days before the date of the foreclosure sale, and shall be mailed to each such lienholder’s address of record or, at the discretion of the foreclosure commissioner, to any other address believed to be that of such lienholder.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effectiveness of notice</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Notice by mail pursuant to this section or <ref>section 3756(c) of this title</ref> shall be deemed duly given upon mailing, whether or not received by the addressee and whether or not a return receipt is received or the notice is returned.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Publication</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A copy of the notice of default and foreclosure sale shall be published once a week during 3 successive calendar weeks before the date of the foreclosure sale. Such publication shall be in a newspaper or newspapers having general circulation in the county or counties in which the security property being sold is located. To the extent practicable, the newspaper or newspapers chosen shall be a newspaper or newspapers having circulation conducive to achieving notice of foreclosure by publication. A legal newspaper that is accepted as a newspaper of legal record in the county or counties in which the security property being sold is located shall be considered a newspaper having general circulation for the purposes of this paragraph.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">If there is no newspaper published at least weekly which has a general circulation in one of the counties in which the security property being sold is located, copies of the notice of default and foreclosure sale shall be posted not less than 21 days before the date of the foreclosure sale—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> at the courthouse of any county or counties in which the security property is located; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> at the place where the sale is to be held.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–327, title II</ref>, <date date="1994-09-28">Sept. 28, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2316</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3759.</num>
<heading> Presale reinstatement</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Withdrawal and cancellation</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Except as provided in sections 3756(b) and 3760(c) of this title, the foreclosure commissioner shall withdraw the security property from foreclosure and cancel the foreclosure sale only if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Secretary directs the foreclosure commissioner to do so before or at the time of the sale;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the foreclosure commissioner finds, upon application of the mortgagor not less than 3 days before the date of the sale, that the default or defaults upon which the foreclosure is based did not exist at the time of service of the notice of default and foreclosure sale; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> in the case of a foreclosure involving a monetary default, there is tendered to the foreclosure commissioner before public auction is completed the entire amount of principal and interest which would be due if payments under the mortgage had not been accelerated;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in the case of a foreclosure involving a nonmonetary default, the foreclosure commissioner, upon application of the mortgagor before the date of foreclosure sale, finds that such default is cured; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> there is tendered to the foreclosure commissioner before public auction is completed—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> all amounts due under the mortgage agreement (excluding additional amounts which would have been due if mortgage payments had been accelerated);</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> all amounts of expenditures secured by the mortgage; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> all costs of foreclosure incurred for which payment from the proceeds of foreclosure is provided in <ref>section 3761 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Discretionary noncancellation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may refuse to cancel a foreclosure sale pursuant to paragraph (1)(C) if the current mortgagor or owner of record has, on one or more previous occasions, caused a foreclosure of the mortgage, commenced pursuant to this chapter or otherwise, to be canceled by curing a default.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Opportunity of Secretary to dispute withdrawal</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Before withdrawing the security property from foreclosure under subparagraph (B) or (C) of subsection (a)(1), the foreclosure commissioner shall afford the Secretary a reasonable opportunity to demonstrate why the security property should not be so withdrawn.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect of cancellation</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Mortgage unaffected</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In any case in which a foreclosure commenced under this chapter is canceled, the mortgage shall continue in effect as though acceleration had not occurred.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Commencement of new foreclosure sale</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Cancellation of a foreclosure sale under this chapter shall have no effect on the commencement of a subsequent foreclosure proceeding under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice of cancellation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The foreclosure commissioner shall file a notice of cancellation in the same place and manner provided for filing the notice of default and foreclosure sale in <ref>section 3758 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–327, title II</ref>, <date date="1994-09-28">Sept. 28, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2316</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3760.</num>
<heading> Conduct of sale; adjournment</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Manner and time</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A foreclosure sale pursuant to this chapter shall be held at public auction and shall be scheduled to begin between the hours of 9 o’clock ante meridian and 4 o’clock post meridian local time.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Location</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The foreclosure sale shall be held at a location specified in the notice of default and foreclosure sale and such location shall be at a place where foreclosure real estate auctions are customarily held in the county or counties in which the property to be sold is located, or at a courthouse therein, or at or on the property to be sold. Sale of security property situated in two or more counties may be held in any 1 of the counties in which any part of the security property is situated.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sale of multiple properties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The foreclosure commissioner may designate the order in which multiple security properties are sold.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties of foreclosure commissioner</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conduct of sale</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The foreclosure commissioner shall conduct the foreclosure sale in accordance with the provisions of this chapter and in a manner fair to both the mortgagor and the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Written bids</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Written one-price sealed bids shall be accepted by the foreclosure commissioner from the Secretary and other persons for entry by announcement by the foreclosure commissioner at the sale.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Auctioneer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The foreclosure commissioner may serve as auctioneer, or, in accordance with regulations of the Secretary, may employ an auctioneer to be paid from the commission provided for in <ref>section 3761(5) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible participants</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary, and any other person who has submitted a written one-price bid, may bid at the foreclosure sale.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibited participants</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The foreclosure commissioner or any relative, related business entity, or employee of the foreclosure commissioner or a related business entity shall not be permitted to bid in any manner on the security property subject to foreclosure sale, except that the foreclosure commissioner or an auctioneer may be directed by the Secretary to enter a bid on the Secretary’s behalf.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adjournment or cancellation of sale</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General authority</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The foreclosure commissioner may, before or at the time of the foreclosure sale, adjourn or cancel the foreclosure sale if the commissioner determines, in the commissioner’s discretion, that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> circumstances are not conducive to a sale which is fair to the mortgagor and the Secretary; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> additional time is necessary to determine whether the security property should be withdrawn from foreclosure, as provided in <ref>section 3759 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adjournment to same or later day</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The foreclosure commissioner may adjourn a foreclosure sale to a later hour the same day by announcing or posting the new time and place of the foreclosure sale, or may adjourn the foreclosure sale for not less than 9 and not more than 31 days, in which case the commissioner shall serve a notice of default and foreclosure sale revised to recite the fact that the foreclosure sale has been adjourned to a specified date, as well as any other information the foreclosure commissioner deems appropriate. Such notice shall be served by publication and mailing in accordance with <ref>section 3758 of this title</ref>, except that publication may be made on any of 3 separate days before the revised date of foreclosure sale, and mailing may be made at any time not less than 7 days before the date to which the foreclosure sale has been adjourned.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cash deposits</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The foreclosure commissioner may require a bidder to make a cash deposit in an amount or percentage set by the foreclosure commissioner and stated in the notice of foreclosure sale before the bid is accepted. A successful bidder at the foreclosure sale who fails to comply with the terms of the sale may be required to forfeit the cash deposit or, at the election of the foreclosure commissioner after consultation with the Secretary, shall be liable to the Secretary for any costs incurred as a result of such failure.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Presumption of validity of sale</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any foreclosure sale held in accordance with this chapter shall be conclusively presumed to have been conducted in a legal, fair, and reasonable manner. The sale price shall be conclusively presumed to be reasonable and equal to the fair market value of the property.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–327, title II</ref>, <date date="1994-09-28">Sept. 28, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2316</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3761.</num>
<heading> Foreclosure costs</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The following foreclosure costs shall be paid from the sale proceeds before satisfaction of any other claim to such sale proceeds:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Advertising and postage</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Necessary advertising costs and postage incurred in giving notice pursuant to sections 3758 and 3760 of this title.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Mileage</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Mileage (determined by the most reasonable road distance) for posting notices and for the foreclosure commissioner’s or auctioneer’s attendance at the sale, as provided in <ref>section 1821 of title 28</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Title and lien search</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Reasonable and necessary costs incurred in connection with any search of title and lien records.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recordation fees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Costs incurred to record documents.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Commission</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A commission for the foreclosure commissioner (if the foreclosure commissioner is not an employee of the United States) for the conduct of the foreclosure, to the extent such a commission is authorized by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–327, title II</ref>, <date date="1994-09-28">Sept. 28, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2316</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3762.</num>
<heading> Disposition of sale proceeds</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Priority payments</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Money realized from a foreclosure sale shall be made available for obligation and expenditure in the following order:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Costs of foreclosure</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To cover the costs of the foreclosure proceeding described in <ref>section 3761 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tax liens</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To pay valid tax liens or assessments if required by the notice of default and foreclosure sale.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prior liens</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To pay any liens recorded before the recording of the mortgage which are required to be paid in conformity with the terms of sale in the notice of default and foreclosure sale.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Service charges and advances</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To pay service charges and advances for taxes, assessments, and property insurance premiums.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interest</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To pay any outstanding interest.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Principal</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To pay the principal outstanding balance secured by the mortgage (including expenditures for the necessary protection, preservation, and repair of the security property as authorized under the mortgage agreement and interest thereon if provided for in the mortgage agreement).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Late charges or fees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To pay any late charges or fees.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other payments</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other lienholders and the mortgagor</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Any surplus of proceeds from a foreclosure sale, after payment of the items described in subsection (a) shall be paid in the following order:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> First, to holders of liens recorded after the mortgage in the order of priority under Federal law or the law of the State in which the security property is located.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Second, to the appropriate mortgagor.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disputed claims</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the person to whom such surplus is to be paid cannot be located, or if the surplus available is insufficient to pay all claimants and the claimants cannot agree on the allocation of the surplus, or if any person claiming an interest in the mortgage proceeds does not agree that some or all of the sale proceeds should be paid to a claimant as provided in this section, that part of the sale proceeds in question may be deposited by the foreclosure commissioner with an appropriate official or court authorized under law to receive disputed funds in such circumstances. If a procedure for the deposit of disputed funds is not available, and the foreclosure commissioner files a bill of interpleader or is sued as a stakeholder to determine entitlement to such funds, the foreclosure commissioner’s necessary costs incurred in taking or defending such action shall be deductible from the disputed funds.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–327, title II</ref>, <date date="1994-09-28">Sept. 28, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2316</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3763.</num>
<heading> Transfer of title and possession</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Delivery of deeds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The foreclosure commissioner shall, upon delivery of a deed or deeds to the purchaser or purchasers (which shall be without warranty or covenants to the purchaser or purchasers) obtain the balance of the purchase price in accordance with the terms of sale provided in the notice of default and foreclosure sale. Notwithstanding any State law to the contrary, delivery of a deed by the foreclosure commissioner shall be a conveyance of the property, and constitute passage of title to the mortgaged property, and no judicial proceedings shall be required ancillary or supplementary to the procedures provided in this chapter to assure the validity of the conveyance or confirmation of such conveyance.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Right of possession</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A purchaser at a foreclosure sale held pursuant to this chapter shall be entitled to possession upon passage of title under subsection (a) to the mortgaged property, subject to any interest or interests not barred under <ref>section 3765 of this title</ref>. Any person remaining in possession of the mortgaged property after the passage of title shall be deemed a tenant at sufferance subject to eviction under local law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Death of purchaser</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If a purchaser dies before execution and delivery of the deed conveying the property to the purchaser, the foreclosure commissioner shall execute and deliver the deed to a representative of the decedent purchaser’s estate upon payment of the purchase price in accordance with the terms of sale. Such delivery to the representative of the purchaser’s estate shall have the same effect as if accomplished during the lifetime of the purchaser.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Bona fide purchaser</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The purchaser of property under this chapter shall be presumed to be a bona fide purchaser.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> No right of redemption</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There shall be no right of redemption, or right of possession based upon a right of redemption, in the mortgagor or others subsequent to a foreclosure completed pursuant to this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certain provisions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Section 1710(<i>l</i>) of this title and <ref>section 1452c of title 42</ref> shall not apply to mortgages foreclosed under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Taxes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">When a mortgage foreclosed pursuant to this chapter is conveyed to the Secretary, no tax shall be imposed or collected with respect to the foreclosure commissioner’s deed (including any tax customarily imposed upon the deed instrument or upon the conveyance or transfer of title to the property). Failure to collect or pay a tax of the type and under the circumstances stated in the preceding sentence shall not be grounds for refusing to record such a deed, for failing to recognize such recordation as imparting notice, or for denying the enforcement of such a deed and its provisions in any State or Federal court.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–327, title II</ref>, <date date="1994-09-28">Sept. 28, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2316</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3764.</num>
<heading> Record of foreclosure and sale</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Statements included</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">To establish a sufficient record of foreclosure and sale, the foreclosure commissioner shall include in the recitals of the deed to the purchaser, or prepare as an affidavit or addendum to the deed, a statement setting forth—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the date, time, and place of the foreclosure sale;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> that the mortgage was held by the Secretary, the date of the mortgage, the office in which the mortgage was recorded, and the liber number and folio or other appropriate description of the recordation of the mortgage;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the particulars of the foreclosure commissioner’s service of the notice of default and foreclosure sale in accordance with sections 3758 and 3760 of this title;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the date and place of filing the notice of default and foreclosure sale;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> that the foreclosure was conducted in accordance with the provisions of this chapter and with the terms of the notice of default and foreclosure sale; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the sale amount.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect of statements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The items set forth in subsection (a) shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> be prima facie evidence of the truth of such facts in any Federal or State court; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> evidence a conclusive presumption in favor of bona fide purchasers and encumbrancers for value without notice.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Encumbrancers for value include liens placed by lenders who provide the purchaser with purchase money in exchange for a security interest in the newly-conveyed property.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recordation of instruments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The deed executed by the foreclosure commissioner, the foreclosure commissioner’s affidavit (if prepared) and any other instruments submitted for recordation in relation to the foreclosure of the security property under this chapter shall be accepted for recordation by the registrar of deeds or other appropriate official of the county or counties in which the security property is located upon tendering of payment of the usual recording fees for such instruments, and without regard to the compliance of those instruments with any other local filing requirements.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–327, title II</ref>, <date date="1994-09-28">Sept. 28, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2316</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3765.</num>
<heading> Effect of sale</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A sale, made and conducted as prescribed in this chapter to a bona fide purchaser, shall bar all claims upon, or with respect to, the property sold, for each of the following persons:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice recipients</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any person to whom the notice of default and foreclosure sale was mailed as provided in this chapter, and the heir, devisee, executor, administrator, successor, or assignee claiming under any such person.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Subordinate claimants with knowledge</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any person claiming any interest in the property subordinate to that of the mortgage, if such person had actual knowledge of the foreclosure sale.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonrecorded claimants</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any person claiming any interest in the property, whose assignment, mortgage, or other conveyance was not duly recorded or filed in the proper place for recording or filing, or whose judgment or decree was not duly docketed or filed in the proper place for docketing or filing, before the date on which the notice of the foreclosure sale was first served by publication, as required by <ref>section 3758(3) of this title</ref>, and the executor, administrator, or assignee of such a person.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other persons</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any person claiming an interest in the property under a statutory lien or encumbrance created subsequent to the recording or filing of the mortgage being foreclosed, and attaching to the title or interest of any person designated in any of the foregoing paragraphs.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–327, title II</ref>, <date date="1994-09-28">Sept. 28, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2316</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3766.</num>
<heading> Computation of time</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Periods of time provided for in this chapter shall be calculated in consecutive calendar days, including the day or days on which the actions or events occur or are to occur for which the period of time is provided and including the day on which an event occurs or is to occur from which the period is to be calculated.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–327, title II</ref>, <date date="1994-09-28">Sept. 28, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2316</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3767.</num>
<heading> Severability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If any part of this chapter shall, for any reason, be adjudged by a court of competent jurisdiction to be invalid, or invalid as applied to a class of cases, such judgment shall not affect, impair, or invalidate the remainder thereof, and shall be confined in its operation to the part thereof directly involved in the controversy in which such judgment shall have been rendered.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–327, title II</ref>, <date date="1994-09-28">Sept. 28, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2316</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3768.</num>
<heading> Deficiency judgment</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Referral to Attorney General</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If after deducting the payments provided for in <ref>section 3762 of this title</ref>, the price at which the security property is sold at a foreclosure sale is less than the unpaid balance of the debt secured by the security property, resulting in a deficiency, the Secretary may refer the matter to the Attorney General who may commence an action or actions against any or all debtors to recover the deficiency, unless such an action is specifically prohibited by the mortgage.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other recoveries</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In any action instituted pursuant to this section the United States may recover—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any amount authorized by <ref>section 3011 of title 28</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the costs of the action.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any action commenced to recover a deficiency under this section must be brought not later than 6 years after the date of the last sale of the security property.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–327, title II</ref>, <date date="1994-09-28">Sept. 28, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2316</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>