<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 34—</num>
<heading>FEDERAL FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS EXAMINATION COUNCIL</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3301.</num>
<heading> Declaration of purpose</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is the purpose of this chapter to establish a Financial Institutions Examination Council which shall prescribe uniform principles and standards for the Federal examination of financial institutions by the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Federal Home Loan Bank Board, and the National Credit Union Administration and make recommendations to promote uniformity in the supervision of these financial institutions. The Council’s actions shall be designed to promote consistency in such examination and to insure progressive and vigilant supervision.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–630, title X, § 1002</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 3694</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3302.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “Federal financial institutions regulatory agencies” means the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency, the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, the Office of Thrift Supervision, and the National Credit Union Administration;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “Council” means the Financial Institutions Examination Council; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “financial institution” means a commercial bank, a savings bank, a trust company, a savings association, a building and loan association, a homestead association, a cooperative bank, or a credit union; <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002338">1</ref></content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–630, title X, § 1003</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 3694</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–73, title VII, § 744(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1989-08-09">Aug. 9, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 438</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3303.</num>
<heading> Financial Institutions Examination Council</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment; composition</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There is established the Financial Institutions Examination Council which shall consist of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Comptroller of the Currency,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Chairman of the Board of Directors of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a Governor of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System designated by the Chairman of the Board,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the Director of the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the Chairman of the National Credit Union Administration Board, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the Chairman of the State Liaison Committee.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Chairmanship</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The members of the Council shall select the first chairman of the Council. Thereafter the chairmanship shall rotate among the members of the Council.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Term of office</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The term of the Chairman of the Council shall be two years.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Designation of officers and employees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The members of the Council may, from time to time, designate other officers or employees of their respective agencies to carry out their duties on the Council.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation and expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each member of the Council shall serve without additional compensation but shall be entitled to reasonable expenses incurred in carrying out his official duties as such a member.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–630, title X, § 1004</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 3694</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–73, title VII, § 744(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1989-08-09">Aug. 9, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 438</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–351, title VII, § 714(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-13">Oct. 13, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1995</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–203, title X, § 1091</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2094</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3304.</num>
<heading> Costs and expenses of Council</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">One-fifth of the costs and expenses of the Council, including the salaries of its employees, shall be paid by each of the Federal financial institutions regulatory agencies. Annual assessments for such share shall be levied by the Council based upon its projected budget for the year, and additional assessments may be made during the year if necessary.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–630, title X, § 1005</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 3695</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3305.</num>
<heading> Functions of Council</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of principles and standards</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Council shall establish uniform principles and standards and report forms for the examination of financial institutions which shall be applied by the Federal financial institutions regulatory agencies.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Making recommendations regarding supervisory matters and adequacy of supervisory tools</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Council shall make recommendations for uniformity in other supervisory matters, such as, but not limited to, classifying loans subject to country risk, identifying financial institutions in need of special supervisory attention, and evaluating the soundness of large loans that are shared by two or more financial institutions. In addition, the Council shall make recommendations regarding the adequacy of supervisory tools for determining the impact of holding company operations on the financial institutions within the holding company and shall consider the ability of supervisory agencies to discover possible fraud or questionable and illegal payments and practices which might occur in the operation of financial institutions or their holding companies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> When a recommendation of the Council is found unacceptable by one or more of the applicable Federal financial institutions regulatory agencies, the agency or agencies shall submit to the Council, within a time period specified by the Council, a written statement of the reasons the recommendation is unacceptable.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Development of uniform reporting system</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Council shall develop uniform reporting systems for federally supervised financial institutions, their holding companies, and nonfinancial institution subsidiaries of such institutions or holding companies. The authority to develop uniform reporting systems shall not restrict or amend the requirements of section 78<i>l</i>(i) of title 15.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conducting schools for examiners and assistant examiners</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Council shall conduct schools for examiners and assistant examiners employed by the Federal financial institutions regulatory agencies. Such schools shall be open to enrollment by employees of State financial institutions supervisory agencies and employees of the Federal Housing Finance Board under conditions specified by the Council.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Affect on Federal regulatory agency research and development of new financial institutions supervisory agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to limit or discourage Federal regulatory agency research and development of new financial institutions supervisory methods and tools, nor to preclude the field testing of any innovation devised by any Federal regulatory agency.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than April 1 of each year, the Council shall prepare an annual report covering its activities during the preceding year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Flood insurance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Council shall consult with and assist the Federal entities for lending regulation, as such term is defined in <ref>section 4121(a) of title 42</ref>, in developing and coordinating uniform standards and requirements for use by regulated lending institutions under the national flood insurance program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–630, title X, § 1006</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 3695</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–320, title IV, § 431</ref>, <date date="1982-10-15">Oct. 15, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1527</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–73, title VII, § 744(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1989-08-09">Aug. 9, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 438</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–325, title V, § 530</ref>, <date date="1994-09-23">Sept. 23, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2267</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3306.</num>
<heading> State liaison</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To encourage the application of uniform examination principles and standards by State and Federal supervisory agencies, the Council shall establish a liaison committee composed of five representatives of State agencies which supervise financial institutions which shall meet at least twice a year with the Council. Members of the liaison committee shall receive a reasonable allowance for necessary expenses incurred in attending meetings. Members of the Liaison Committee shall elect a chairperson from among the members serving on the committee.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–630, title X, § 1007</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 3696</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–351, title VII, § 714(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-13">Oct. 13, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1995</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3307.</num>
<heading> Administration</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority of Chairman of Council</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Chairman of the Council is authorized to carry out and to delegate the authority to carry out the internal administration of the Council, including the appointment and supervision of employees and the distribution of business among members, employees, and administrative units.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of personnel, services, and facilities of Federal financial institutions regulatory agencies, Federal Reserve banks, and Federal Home Loan Banks</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">in <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002339">1</ref> addition to any other authority conferred upon it by this chapter, in carrying out its functions under this chapter, the Council may utilize, with their consent and to the extent practical, the personnel, services, and facilities of the Federal financial institutions regulatory agencies, Federal Reserve banks, and Federal Home Loan Banks, with or without reimbursement therefor.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation, authority, and duties of officers and employees; experts and consultants</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In addition, the Council may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> subject to the provisions of title 5 relating to the competitive service, classification, and General Schedule pay rates, appoint and fix the compensation of such officers and employees as are necessary to carry out the provisions of this chapter, and to prescribe the authority and duties of such officers and employees; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> obtain the services of such experts and consultants as are necessary to carry out the provisions of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–630, title X, § 1008</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 3696</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3308.</num>
<heading> Access to books, accounts, records, etc., by Council</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purpose of carrying out this chapter, the Council shall have access to all books, accounts, records, reports, files, memorandums, papers, things, and property belonging to or in use by Federal financial institutions regulatory agencies, including reports of examination of financial institutions or their holding companies from whatever source, together with workpapers and correspondence files related to such reports, whether or not a part of the report, and all without any deletions.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–630, title X, § 1009</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 3696</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3309.</num>
<heading> Risk management training</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Seminars</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Council shall develop and administer training seminars in risk management for its employees and the employees of insured financial institutions.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Study of risk management training program</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than end of the 1-year period beginning on <date date="1989-08-09">August 9, 1989</date>, the Council shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> conduct a study on the feasibility and appropriateness of establishing a formalized risk management training program designed to lead to the certification of Risk Management Analysts; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> report to the Congress the results of such study.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–630, title X, § 1009A</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 101–73, title XII, § 1218</ref>, <date date="1989-08-09">Aug. 9, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 546</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3310.</num>
<heading> Establishment of Appraisal Subcommittee</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There shall be within the Council a subcommittee to be known as the “Appraisal Subcommittee”, which shall consist of the designees of the heads of the Federal financial institutions regulatory agencies, the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, and the Federal Housing Finance Agency. Each such designee shall be a person who has demonstrated knowledge and competence concerning the appraisal profession. At all times at least one member of the Appraisal Subcommittee shall have demonstrated knowledge and competence through licensure, certification, or professional designation within the appraisal profession.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–630, title X, § 1011</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 101–73, title XI, § 1102</ref>, <date date="1989-08-09">Aug. 9, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 511</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 111–203, title XIV, § 1473(s)</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2199</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3311.</num>
<heading> Required review of regulations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not less frequently than once every 10 years, the Council and each appropriate Federal banking agency represented on the Council shall conduct a review of all regulations prescribed by the Council or by any such appropriate Federal banking agency, respectively, in order to identify outdated or otherwise unnecessary regulatory requirements imposed on insured depository institutions.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Process</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In conducting the review under subsection (a), the Council or the appropriate Federal banking agency shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> categorize the regulations described in subsection (a) by type (such as consumer regulations, safety and soundness regulations, or such other designations as determined by the Council, or the appropriate Federal banking agency); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> at regular intervals, provide notice and solicit public comment on a particular category or categories of regulations, requesting commentators to identify areas of the regulations that are outdated, unnecessary, or unduly burdensome.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Complete review</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Council or the appropriate Federal banking agency shall ensure that the notice and comment period described in subsection (b)(2) is conducted with respect to all regulations described in subsection (a) not less frequently than once every 10 years.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulatory response</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Council or the appropriate Federal banking agency shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> publish in the Federal Register a summary of the comments received under this section, identifying significant issues raised and providing comment on such issues; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> eliminate unnecessary regulations to the extent that such action is appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report to Congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 30 days after carrying out subsection (d)(1), the Council shall submit to the Congress a report, which shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a summary of any significant issues raised by public comments received by the Council and the appropriate Federal banking agencies under this section and the relative merits of such issues; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an analysis of whether the appropriate Federal banking agency involved is able to address the regulatory burdens associated with such issues by regulation, or whether such burdens must be addressed by legislative action.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–208, div. A, title II, § 2222</ref>, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3009–414</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>