<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 39—</num>
<heading>ALTERNATIVE MORTGAGE TRANSACTIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3801.</num>
<heading> Findings and purpose</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Congress hereby finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> increasingly volatile and dynamic changes in interest rates have seriously impared <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002356">1</ref> the ability of housing creditors to provide consumers with fixed-term, fixed-rate credit secured by interests in real property, cooperative housing, manufactured homes, and other dwellings;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> alternative mortgage transactions are essential to the provision of an adequate supply of credit secured by residential property necessary to meet the demand expected during the 1980’s; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the Comptroller of the Currency, the National Credit Union Administration, and the Director of the Office of Thrift Supervision have recognized the importance of alternative mortgage transactions and have adopted regulations authorizing federally chartered depository institutions to engage in alternative mortgage financing.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> It is the purpose of this chapter to eliminate the discriminatory impact that those regulations have upon nonfederally chartered housing creditors and provide them with parity with federally chartered institutions by authorizing all housing creditors to make, purchase, and enforce alternative mortgage transactions so long as the transactions are in conformity with the regulations issued by the Federal agencies.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–320, title VIII, § 802</ref>, <date date="1982-10-15">Oct. 15, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1545</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–73, title VII, § 744(c)</ref>, <date date="1989-08-09">Aug. 9, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 438</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3802.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “alternative mortgage transaction” means a loan or credit sale secured by an interest in residential real property, a dwelling, all stock allocated to a dwelling unit in a residential cooperative housing corporation, or a residential manufactured home (as that term is defined in <ref>section 5402(6) of title 42</ref>), in which the interest rate or finance charge may be adjusted or renegotiated, described and defined by applicable regulation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the term “housing creditor” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a depository institution, as defined in section 501(a)(2) of the Depository Institutions Deregulation and Monetary Control Act of 1980;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a lender approved by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development for participation in any mortgage insurance program under the National Housing Act [<ref>12 U.S.C. 1701</ref> et seq.];</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any person who regularly makes loans, credit sales, or advances secured by interests in properties referred to in paragraph (1); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> any transferee of any of them.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">A person is not a “housing creditor” with respect to a specific alternative mortgage transaction if, except for this chapter, in order to enter into that transaction, the person would be required to comply with licensing requirements imposed under State law, unless such person is licensed under applicable State law and such person remains, or becomes, subject to the applicable regulatory requirements and enforcement mechanisms provided by State law.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–320, title VIII, § 803</ref>, <date date="1982-10-15">Oct. 15, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1545</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–203, title X, § 1083(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2080</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3803.</num>
<heading> Alternative mortgage authority</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General authority; compliance by banks, credit unions and all other housing creditors with applicable regulations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In order to prevent discrimination against State-chartered depository institutions, and other nonfederally chartered housing creditors, with respect to making, purchasing, and enforcing alternative mortgage transactions, housing creditors may make, purchase, and enforce alternative mortgage transactions, except that this section shall apply—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> with respect to banks, only to transactions made on or before the designated transfer date, as determined under section 1062 of the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010 [<ref>12 U.S.C. 5582</ref>], in accordance with regulations governing alternative mortgage transactions as issued by the Comptroller of the Currency for national banks, to the extent that such regulations are authorized by rulemaking authority granted to the Comptroller of the Currency with regard to national banks under laws other than this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> with respect to credit unions, only to transactions made on or before the designated transfer date, as determined under section 1062 of the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010, in accordance with regulations governing alternative mortgage transactions as issued by the National Credit Union Administration Board for Federal credit unions, to the extent that such regulations are authorized by rulemaking authority granted to the National Credit Union Administration with regard to Federal credit unions under laws other than this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> with respect to all other housing creditors, including without limitation, savings and loan associations, mutual savings banks, and savings banks, only to transactions made on or before the designated transfer date, as determined under section 1062 of the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010, in accordance with regulations governing alternative mortgage transactions as issued by the Director of the Office of Thrift Supervision for federally chartered savings and loan associations, to the extent that such regulations are authorized by rulemaking authority granted to the Director of the Office of Thrift Supervision with regard to federally chartered savings and loan associations under laws other than this section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> with respect to transactions made after the designated transfer date, only in accordance with regulations governing alternative mortgage transactions, as issued by the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection for federally chartered housing creditors, in accordance with the rulemaking authority granted to the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection with regard to federally chartered housing creditors under provisions of law other than this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transactions deemed in compliance with applicable regulations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For the purpose of determining the applicability of this section, an alternative mortgage transaction shall be deemed to be made in accordance with the applicable regulation notwithstanding the housing creditor’s failure to comply with the regulation, if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the transaction is in substantial compliance with the regulation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> within sixty days of discovering any error, the housing creditor corrects such error, including making appropriate adjustments, if any, to the account.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Preemption of State law</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An alternative mortgage transaction may be made by a housing creditor in accordance with this section, notwithstanding any State constitution, law, or regulation that prohibits an alternative mortgage transaction. For purposes of this subsection, a State constitution, law, or regulation that prohibits an alternative mortgage transaction does not include any State constitution, law, or regulation that regulates mortgage transactions generally, including any restriction on prepayment penalties or late charges.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Bureau actions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> review the regulations identified by the Comptroller of the Currency and the National Credit Union Administration,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002357">1</ref> (as those rules exist on the designated transfer date), as applicable under paragraphs (1) through (3) of subsection (a);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> determine whether such regulations are fair and not deceptive and otherwise meet the objectives of the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> promulgate regulations under subsection (a)(4) after the designated transfer date.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Designated transfer date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As used in this section, the term “designated transfer date” means the date determined under section 1062 of the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010 [<ref>12 U.S.C. 5582</ref>].</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–320, title VIII, § 804</ref>, <date date="1982-10-15">Oct. 15, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1546</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–73, title VII, § 744(c)</ref>, <date date="1989-08-09">Aug. 9, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 438</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–203, title X, § 1083(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2080</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3804.</num>
<heading> Applicability of preemption provisions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The provisions of <ref>section 3803 of this title</ref> shall not apply to any alternative mortgage transaction in any State made on or after the effective date (if such effective date occurs on or after <date date="1982-10-15">October 15, 1982</date>, and prior to a date three years after <date date="1982-10-15">October 15, 1982</date>) of a State law or a certification that the voters of such State have voted in favor of any provision, constitutional or otherwise, which states explicitly and by its terms that such State does not want the preemption provided in <ref>section 3803 of this title</ref> to apply with respect to alternative mortgage transactions (or to any class or type of alternative mortgage transaction) subject to the laws of such State, except that <ref>section 3803 of this title</ref> shall continue to apply to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any alternative mortgage transaction undertaken on or after such date pursuant to an agreement to undertake such alternative mortgage transaction which was entered into on or after <date date="1982-10-15">October 15, 1982</date>, and prior to such later date (the “preemption period”); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any renewal, extension, refinancing, or other modification of an alternative mortgage transaction that was entered into during the preemption period.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> An alternative mortgage transaction shall be deemed to have been undertaken during the preemption period to which this section applies if it—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> is funded or extended in whole or in part during the preemption period, regardless of whether pursuant to a commitment or other agreement therefor made prior to that period; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> is a renewal, extension, refinancing, or other modification of an alternative mortgage transaction entered into before the preemption period and such renewal, extension, or other modification is made during such period with the written consent of any person obligated to repay such credit.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–320, title VIII, § 805</ref>, <date date="1982-10-15">Oct. 15, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1547</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–181, title I</ref> [title IV, § 472], <date date="1983-11-30">Nov. 30, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 1237</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3805.</num>
<heading> Applicability of consumer protection provisions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Section 501(c)(1) of the Depository Institutions Deregulation and Monetary Control Act of 1980 shall not apply to transactions which are subject to this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–320, title VIII, § 806</ref>, <date date="1982-10-15">Oct. 15, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1548</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3806.</num>
<heading> Adjustable rate mortgage caps</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any adjustable rate mortgage loan originated by a creditor shall include a limitation on the maximum interest rate that may apply during the term of the mortgage loan.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System shall prescribe regulations to carry out the purposes of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Enforcement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any violation of this section shall be treated as a violation of the Truth in Lending Act [<ref>15 U.S.C. 1601</ref> et seq.] and shall be subject to administrative enforcement under section 108 [<ref>15 U.S.C. 1607</ref>] or civil damages under section 130 [<ref>15 U.S.C. 1640</ref>] of such Act, or both.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For the purpose of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “creditor” means a person who regularly extends credit for personal, family, or household purposes; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “adjustable rate mortgage loan” means any consumer loan secured by a lien on a one- to four-family dwelling unit, including a condominium unit, cooperative housing unit, or mobile home, where the loan is made pursuant to an agreement under which the creditor may, from time to time, adjust the rate of interest.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall take effect upon the expiration of 120 days after <date date="1987-08-10">August 10, 1987</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–86, title XII, § 1204</ref>, <date date="1987-08-10">Aug. 10, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 662</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–550, title IX, § 952</ref>, <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 3893</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>