<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 35—</num>
<heading>RIGHT TO FINANCIAL PRIVACY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3401.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For the purpose of this chapter, the term—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “financial institution”, except as provided in <ref>section 3414 of this title</ref>, means any office of a bank, savings bank, card issuer as defined in section 1602(n) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002347">1</ref> of title 15, industrial loan company, trust company, savings association, building and loan, or homestead association (including cooperative banks), credit union, or consumer finance institution, located in any State or territory of the United States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, or the Virgin Islands;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> “financial record” means an original of, a copy of, or information known to have been derived from, any record held by a financial institution pertaining to a customer’s relationship with the financial institution;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> “Government authority” means any agency or department of the United States, or any officer, employee, or agent thereof;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> “person” means an individual or a partnership of five or fewer individuals;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> “customer” means any person or authorized representative of that person who utilized or is utilizing any service of a financial institution, or for whom a financial institution is acting or has acted as a fiduciary, in relation to an account maintained in the person’s name;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> “holding company” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any bank holding company (as defined in <ref>section 1841 of this title</ref>); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any company described in <ref>section 1843(f)(1) of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<chapeau> “supervisory agency” means with respect to any particular financial institution, holding company, or any subsidiary of a financial institution or holding company, any of the following which has statutory authority to examine the financial condition, business operations, or records or transactions of that institution, holding company, or subsidiary—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the National Credit Union Administration;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the Comptroller of the Currency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the Securities and Exchange Commission;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> the Commodity Futures Trading Commission;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> the Secretary of the Treasury, with respect to the Bank Secrecy Act (<ref>Public Law 91–508, title I</ref>) [<ref>12 U.S.C. 1951</ref> et seq.] and subchapter II of chapter 53 of title 31; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> any State banking or securities department or agency; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> “law enforcement inquiry” means a lawful investigation or official proceeding inquiring into a violation of, or failure to comply with, any criminal or civil statute or any regulation, rule, or order issued pursuant thereto.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–630, title XI, § 1101</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 3697</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–73, title VII, § 744(b)</ref>, title IX, § 941, <date date="1989-08-09">Aug. 9, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 438</ref>, 496; <ref>Pub. L. 101–647, title XXV, § 2596(c)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4908</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–102, title VII, § 727(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1999-11-12">Nov. 12, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1475</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–177, title III, § 374(b)</ref>, <date date="2003-12-13">Dec. 13, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2628</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–203, title X, § 1099(1)</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2105</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3402.</num>
<heading> Access to financial records by Government authorities prohibited; exceptions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except as provided by section 3403(c) or (d), 3413, or 3414 of this title, no Government authority may have access to or obtain copies of, or the information contained in the financial records of any customer from a financial institution unless the financial records are reasonably described and—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> such customer has authorized such disclosure in accordance with <ref>section 3404 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> such financial records are disclosed in response to an administrative subpena or summons which meets the requirements of <ref>section 3405 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> such financial records are disclosed in response to a search warrant which meets the requirements of <ref>section 3406 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> such financial records are disclosed in response to a judicial subpena which meets the requirements of <ref>section 3407 of this title</ref>; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> such financial records are disclosed in response to a formal written request which meets the requirements of <ref>section 3408 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–630, title XI, § 1102</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 3697</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3403.</num>
<heading> Confidentiality of financial records</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Release of records by financial institutions prohibited</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No financial institution, or officer, employees, or agent of a financial institution, may provide to any Government authority access to or copies of, or the information contained in, the financial records of any customer except in accordance with the provisions of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Release of records upon certification of compliance with chapter</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A financial institution shall not release the financial records of a customer until the Government authority seeking such records certifies in writing to the financial institution that it has complied with the applicable provisions of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification to Government authority of existence of relevant information in records</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall preclude any financial institution, or any officer, employee, or agent of a financial institution, from notifying a Government authority that such institution, or officer, employee, or agent has information which may be relevant to a possible violation of any statute or regulation. Such information may include only the name or other identifying information concerning any individual, corporation, or account involved in and the nature of any suspected illegal activity. Such information may be disclosed notwithstanding any constitution, law, or regulation of any State or political subdivision thereof to the contrary. Any financial institution, or officer, employee, or agent thereof, making a disclosure of information pursuant to this subsection, shall not be liable to the customer under any law or regulation of the United States or any constitution, law, or regulation of any State or political subdivision thereof, for such disclosure or for any failure to notify the customer of such disclosure.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Release of records as incident to perfection of security interest, proving a claim in bankruptcy, collecting a debt, or processing an application with regard to a Government loan, loan guarantee, etc.</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Nothing in this chapter shall preclude a financial institution, as an incident to perfecting a security interest, proving a claim in bankruptcy, or otherwise collecting on a debt owing either to the financial institution itself or in its role as a fiduciary, from providing copies of any financial record to any court or Government authority.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Nothing in this chapter shall preclude a financial institution, as an incident to processing an application for assistance to a customer in the form of a Government loan, loan guaranty, or loan insurance agreement, or as an incident to processing a default on, or administering, a Government guaranteed or insured loan, from initiating contact with an appropriate Government authority for the purpose of providing any financial record necessary to permit such authority to carry out its responsibilities under a loan, loan guaranty, or loan insurance agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–630, title XI, § 1103</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 3698</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–570, title I, § 1353(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3207–21</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title VI, § 6186(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4357</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3404.</num>
<heading> Customer authorizations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Statement furnished by customer to financial institution and Government authority; contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A customer may authorize disclosure under <ref>section 3402(1) of this title</ref> if he furnishes to the financial institution and to the Government authority seeking to obtain such disclosure a signed and dated statement which—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> authorizes such disclosure for a period not in excess of three months;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> states that the customer may revoke such authorization at any time before the financial records are disclosed;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> identifies the financial records which are authorized to be disclosed;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> specifies the purposes for which, and the Government authority to which, such records may be disclosed; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> states the customer’s rights under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization as condition of doing business prohibited</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No such authorization shall be required as a condition of doing business with any financial institution.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Right of customer to access to financial institution’s record of disclosures</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The customer has the right, unless the Government authority obtains a court order as provided in <ref>section 3409 of this title</ref>, to obtain a copy of the record which the financial institution shall keep of all instances in which the customer’s record is disclosed to a Government authority pursuant to this section, including the identity of the Government authority to which such disclosure is made.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–630, title XI, § 1104</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 3698</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–3</ref>, <date date="1979-03-07">Mar. 7, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 5</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3405.</num>
<heading> Administrative subpena and summons</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A Government authority may obtain financial records under <ref>section 3402(2) of this title</ref> pursuant to an administrative subpena or summons otherwise authorized by law only if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> there is reason to believe that the rec­ords sought are relevant to a legitimate law enforcement inquiry;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a copy of the subpena or summons has been served upon the customer or mailed to his last known address on or before the date on which the subpena or summons was served on the financial institution together with the following notice which shall state with reasonable specificity the nature of the law enforcement inquiry:<p class="indent1">“Records or information concerning your transactions held by the financial institution named in the attached subpena or summons are being sought by this (agency or department) in accordance with the Right to Financial Privacy Act of 1978 [<ref>12 U.S.C. 3401</ref> et seq.] for the following purpose: If you desire that such records or information not be made available, you must:</p>
<p class="indent2" role="listItem">“1. Fill out the accompanying motion paper and sworn statement or write one of your own, stating that you are the customer whose records are being requested by the Government and either giving the reasons you believe that the records are not relevant to the legitimate law enforcement inquiry stated in this notice or any other legal basis for objecting to the release of the rec­ords.</p>
<p class="indent2" role="listItem">“2. File the motion and statement by mailing or delivering them to the clerk of any one of the following United States district courts:</p>
<p class="indent2">                      .</p>
<p class="indent2">“3. Serve the Government authority requesting the records by mailing or delivering a copy of your motion and statement to                 .</p>
<p class="indent2">“4. Be prepared to come to court and pre­sent your position in further detail.</p>
<p class="indent2">“5. You do not need to have a lawyer, although you may wish to employ one to represent you and protect your rights.</p>

<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">If you do not follow the above procedures, upon the expiration of ten days from the date of service or fourteen days from the date of mailing of this notice, the records or information requested therein will be made available. These records may be transferred to other Government authorities for legitimate law enforcement inquiries, in which event you will be notified after the transfer.”; and</continuation>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> ten days have expired from the date of service of the notice or fourteen days have expired from the date of mailing the notice to the customer and within such time period the customer has not filed a sworn statement and motion to quash in an appropriate court, or the customer challenge provisions of <ref>section 3410 of this title</ref> have been complied with.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–630, title XI, § 1105</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 3699</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3406.</num>
<heading> Search warrants</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability of Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A Government authority may obtain financial records under <ref>section 3402(3) of this title</ref> only if it obtains a search warrant pursuant to the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Mailing of copy and notice to customer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No later than ninety days after the Government authority serves the search warrant, it shall mail to the customer’s last known address a copy of the search warrant together with the following notice:</p>
<p class="indent0">“Records or information concerning your transactions held by the financial institution named in the attached search warrant were obtained by this (agency or department) on (date) for the following purpose:    . You may have rights under the Right to Financial Privacy Act of 1978 [<ref>12 U.S.C. 3401</ref> et seq.].”.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Court-ordered delays in mailing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon application of the Government authority, a court may grant a delay in the mailing of the notice required in subsection (b), which delay shall not exceed one hundred and eighty days following the service of the warrant, if the court makes the findings required in <ref>section 3409(a) of this title</ref>. If the court so finds, it shall enter an ex parte order granting the requested delay and an order prohibiting the financial institution from disclosing that records have been obtained or that a search warrant for such records has been executed. Additional delays of up to ninety days may be granted by the court upon application, but only in accordance with this subsection. Upon expiration of the period of delay of notification of the customer, the following notice shall be mailed to the customer along with a copy of the search warrant:</p>
<p class="indent0">“Records or information concerning your transactions held by the financial institution named in the attached search warrant were obtained by this (agency or department) on (date). Notification was delayed beyond the statutory ninety-day delay period pursuant to a determination by the court that such notice would seriously jeopardize an investigation concerning         . You may have rights under the Right to Financial Privacy Act of 1978 [<ref>12 U.S.C. 3401</ref> et seq.].”.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–630, title XI, § 1106</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 3700</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3407.</num>
<heading> Judicial subpena</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A Government authority may obtain financial records under <ref>section 3402(4) of this title</ref> pursuant to judicial subpena only if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> such subpena is authorized by law and there is reason to believe that the records sought are relevant to a legitimate law enforcement inquiry;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a copy of the subpena has been served upon the customer or mailed to his last known address on or before the date on which the subpena was served on the financial institution together with the following notice which shall state with reasonable specificity the nature of the law enforcement inquiry:<p class="indent1">“Records or information concerning your transactions which are held by the financial institution named in the attached subpena are being sought by this (agency or department or authority) in accordance with the Right to Financial Privacy Act of 1978 [<ref>12 U.S.C. 3401</ref> et seq.] for the following purpose: If you desire that such records or information not be made available, you must:</p>
<p class="indent2" role="listItem">“1. Fill out the accompanying motion paper and sworn statement or write one of your own, stating that you are the customer whose records are being requested by the Government and either giving the reasons you believe that the records are not relevant to the legitimate law enforcement inquiry stated in this notice or any other legal basis for objecting to the release of the rec­ords.</p>
<p class="indent2" role="listItem">“2. File the motion and statement by mailing or delivering them to the clerk of the        Court.</p>
<p class="indent2">“3. Serve the Government authority requesting the records by mailing or delivering a copy of your motion and statement to                 .</p>
<p class="indent2">“4. Be prepared to come to court and pre­sent your position in further detail.</p>
<p class="indent2">“5. You do not need to have a lawyer, although you may wish to employ one to represent you and protect your rights.</p>

<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">If you do not follow the above procedures, upon the expiration of ten days from the date of service or fourteen days from the date of mailing of this notice, the records or information requested therein will be made available. These records may be transferred to other government authorities for legitimate law enforcement inquiries, in which event you will be notified after the transfer;” and</continuation>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> ten days have expired from the date of service or fourteen days from the date of mailing of the notice to the customer and within such time period the customer has not filed a sworn statement and motion to quash in an appropriate court, or the customer challenge provisions of <ref>section 3410 of this title</ref> have been complied with.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–630, title XI, § 1107</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 3700</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3408.</num>
<heading> Formal written request</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A Government authority may request financial records under <ref>section 3402(5) of this title</ref> pursuant to a formal written request only if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> no administrative summons or subpena authority reasonably appears to be available to that Government authority to obtain financial records for the purpose for which such records are sought;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the request is authorized by regulations promulgated by the head of the agency or department;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> there is reason to believe that the rec­ords sought are relevant to a legitimate law enforcement inquiry; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a copy of the request has been served upon the customer or mailed to his last known address on or before the date on which the request was made to the financial institution together with the following notice which shall state with reasonable specificity the nature of the law enforcement inquiry:<p class="indent1" role="listItem">“Records or information concerning your transactions held by the financial institution named in the attached request are being sought by this (agency or department) in accordance with the Right to Financial Privacy Act of 1978 [<ref>12 U.S.C. 3401</ref> et seq.] for the following purpose:</p>
<p class="indent1" role="listItem">“If you desire that such records or information not be made available, you must:</p>
<p class="indent2">“1. Fill out the accompanying motion paper and sworn statement or write one of your own, stating that you are the customer whose records are being requested by the Government and either giving the reasons you believe that the records are not relevant to the legitimate law enforcement inquiry stated in this notice or any other legal basis for objecting to the release of the rec­ords.</p>
<p class="indent2">“2. File the motion and statement by mailing or delivering them to the clerk of any one of the following United States District Courts:</p>
<p class="indent2">                      .</p>
<p class="indent2">“3. Serve the Government authority requesting the records by mailing or delivering a copy of your motion and statement to                 .</p>
<p class="indent2">“4. Be prepared to come to court and pre­sent your position in further detail.</p>
<p class="indent2">“5. You do not need to have a lawyer, although you may wish to employ one to represent you and protect your rights.</p>

<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">If you do not follow the above procedures, upon the expiration of ten days from the date of service or fourteen days from the date of mailing of this notice, the records or information requested therein may be made available. These records may be transferred to other Government authorities for legitimate law enforcement inquiries, in which event you will be notified after the transfer;” and</continuation>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> ten days have expired from the date of service or fourteen days from the date of mailing of the notice by the customer and within such time period the customer has not filed a sworn statement and an application to enjoin the Government authority in an appropriate court, or the customer challenge provisions of <ref>section 3410 of this title</ref> have been complied with.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–630, title XI, § 1108</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 3701</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3409.</num>
<heading> Delayed notice</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application by Government authority; findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Upon application of the Government authority, the customer notice required under section 3404(c), 3405(2), 3406(c), 3407(2), 3408(4), or 3412(b) of this title may be delayed by order of an appropriate court if the presiding judge or magistrate judge finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the investigation being conducted is within the lawful jurisdiction of the Government authority seeking the financial records;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> there is reason to believe that the rec­ords being sought are relevant to a legitimate law enforcement inquiry; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> there is reason to believe that such notice will result in—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> endangering life or physical safety of any person;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> flight from prosecution;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> destruction of or tampering with evidence;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> intimidation of potential witnesses; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> otherwise seriously jeopardizing an investigation or official proceeding or unduly delaying a trial or ongoing official proceeding to the same extent as the circumstances in the preceeding <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002348">1</ref> subparagraphs.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">An application for delay must be made with reasonable specificity.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grant of delay order; duration and specifications; extensions; copy of request and notice to customer</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> If the court makes the findings required in paragraphs (1), (2), and (3) of subsection (a), it shall enter an ex parte order granting the requested delay for a period not to exceed ninety days and an order prohibiting the financial institution from disclosing that records have been obtained or that a request for records has been made, except that, if the records have been sought by a Government authority exercising financial controls over foreign accounts in the United States under <ref>section 4305(b) of title 50</ref>, the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (title II, <ref>Public Law 95–223</ref>) [<ref>50 U.S.C. 1701</ref> et seq.], or <ref>section 287c of title 22</ref>, and the court finds that there is reason to believe that such notice may endanger the lives or physical safety of a customer or group of customers, or any person or group of persons associated with a customer, the court may specify that the delay be indefinite.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Extensions of the delay of notice provided in paragraph (1) of up to ninety days each may be granted by the court upon application, but only in accordance with this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Upon expiration of the period of delay of notification under paragraph (1) or (2), the customer shall be served with or mailed a copy of the process or request together with the following notice which shall state with reasonable specificity the nature of the law enforcement inquiry:<p class="indent0">“Records or information concerning your transactions which are held by the financial institution named in the attached process or request were supplied to or requested by the Government authority named in the process or request on (date). Notification was withheld pursuant to a determination by the (title of court so ordering) under the Right to Financial Privacy Act of 1978 [<ref>12 U.S.C. 3401</ref> et seq.] that such notice might (state reason).        The purpose of the investigation or official proceeding was        .”.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice requirement respecting emergency access to financial records</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">When access to financial records is obtained pursuant to <ref>section 3414(b) of this title</ref> (emergency access), the Government authority shall, unless a court has authorized delay of notice pursuant to subsections (a) and (b), as soon as practicable after such records are obtained serve upon the customer, or mail by registered or certified mail to his last known address, a copy of the request to the financial institution together with the following notice which shall state with reasonable specificity the nature of the law enforcement inquiry:</p>
<p class="indent0">“Records concerning your transactions held by the financial institution named in the attached request were obtained by (agency or department) under the Right to Financial Privacy Act of 1978 [<ref>12 U.S.C. 3401</ref> et seq.] on (date) for the following purpose:        Emergency access to such records was obtained on the grounds that (state grounds).”.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Preservation of memorandums, affidavits, or other papers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any memorandum, affidavit, or other paper filed in connection with a request for delay in notification shall be preserved by the court. Upon petition by the customer to whom such records pertain, the court may order disclosure of such papers to the petitioner unless the court makes the findings required in subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–630, title XI, § 1109</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 3702</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–650, title III, § 321</ref>, <date date="1990-12-01">Dec. 1, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 5117</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3410.</num>
<heading> Customer challenges</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Filing of motion to quash or application to enjoin; proper court; contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Within ten days of service or within fourteen days of mailing of a subpena, summons, or formal written request, a customer may file a motion to quash an administrative summons or judicial subpena, or an application to enjoin a Government authority from obtaining financial records pursuant to a formal written request, with copies served upon the Government authority. A motion to quash a judicial subpena shall be filed in the court which issued the subpena. A motion to quash an administrative summons or an application to enjoin a Government authority from obtaining records pursuant to a formal written request shall be filed in the appropriate United States district court. Such motion or application shall contain an affidavit or sworn statement—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> stating that the applicant is a customer of the financial institution from which financial records pertaining to him have been sought; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> stating the applicant’s reasons for believing that the financial records sought are not relevant to the legitimate law enforcement inquiry stated by the Government authority in its notice, or that there has not been substantial compliance with the provisions of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Service shall be made under this section upon a Government authority by delivering or mailing by registered or certified mail a copy of the papers to the person, office, or department specified in the notice which the customer has received pursuant to this chapter. For the purposes of this section, “delivery” has the meaning stated in rule 5(b) of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Filing of response; additional proceedings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the court finds that the customer has complied with subsection (a), it shall order the Government authority to file a sworn response, which may be filed in camera if the Government includes in its response the reasons which make in camera review appropriate. If the court is unable to determine the motion or application on the basis of the parties’ initial allegations and response, the court may conduct such additional proceedings as it deems appropriate. All such proceedings shall be completed and the motion or application decided within seven calendar days of the filing of the Government’s response.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Decision of court</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the court finds that the applicant is not the customer to whom the financial records sought by the Government authority pertain, or that there is a demonstrable reason to believe that the law enforcement inquiry is legitimate and a reasonable belief that the records sought are relevant to that inquiry, it shall deny the motion or application, and, in the case of an administrative summons or court order other than a search warrant, order such process enforced. If the court finds that the applicant is the customer to whom the records sought by the Government authority pertain, and that there is not a demonstrable reason to believe that the law enforcement inquiry is legitimate and a reasonable belief that the records sought are relevant to that inquiry, or that there has not been substantial compliance with the provisions of this chapter, it shall order the process quashed or shall enjoin the Government au­thority’s formal written request.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appeals</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A court ruling denying a motion or application under this section shall not be deemed a final order and no interlocutory appeal may be taken therefrom by the customer. An appeal of a ruling denying a motion or application under this section may be taken by the customer (1) within such period of time as provided by law as part of any appeal from a final order in any legal proceeding initiated against him arising out of or based upon the financial records, or (2) within thirty days after a notification that no legal proceeding is contemplated against him. The Government authority obtaining the financial records shall promptly notify a customer when a determination has been made that no legal proceeding against him is contemplated. After one hundred and eighty days from the denial of the motion or application, if the Government authority obtaining the records has not initiated such a proceeding, a supervisory official of the Government authority shall certify to the appropriate court that no such determination has been made. The court may require that such certifications be made, at reasonable intervals thereafter, until either notification to the customer has occurred or a legal proceeding is initiated as described in clause (A). <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002349">1</ref></p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sole judicial remedy available to customer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The challenge procedures of this chapter constitute the sole judicial remedy available to a customer to oppose disclosure of financial rec­ords pursuant to this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Affect on challenges by financial institutions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall enlarge or restrict any rights of a financial institution to challenge requests for records made by a Government authority under existing law. Nothing in this chapter shall entitle a customer to assert the rights of a financial institution.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–630, title XI, § 1110</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 3703</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3411.</num>
<heading> Duty of financial institutions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon receipt of a request for financial rec­ords made by a Government authority under section 3405 or 3407 of this title, the financial institution shall, unless otherwise provided by law, proceed to assemble the records requested and must be prepared to deliver the records to the Government authority upon receipt of the certificate required under <ref>section 3403(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–630, title XI, § 1111</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 3705</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3412.</num>
<heading> Use of information</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer of financial records to other agencies or departments; certification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Financial records originally obtained pursuant to this chapter shall not be transferred to another agency or department unless the transferring agency or department certifies in writing that there is reason to believe that the rec­ords are relevant to a legitimate law enforcement inquiry, or intelligence or counterintelligence activity, investigation or analysis related to international terrorism within the jurisdiction of the receiving agency or department.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Mailing of copy of certification and notice to customer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">When financial records subject to this chapter are transferred pursuant to subsection (a), the transferring agency or department shall, within fourteen days, send to the customer a copy of the certification made pursuant to subsection (a) and the following notice, which shall state the nature of the law enforcement inquiry with reasonable specificity: “Copies of, or information contained in, your financial records lawfully in possession of                    have been furnished to              pursuant to the Right of Financial Privacy Act of 1978 [<ref>12 U.S.C. 3401</ref> et seq.] for the following purpose:             . If you believe that this transfer has not been made to further a legitimate law enforcement inquiry, you may have legal rights under the Financial Privacy Act of 1978 or the Privacy Act of 1974 [<ref>5 U.S.C. 552a</ref>].”</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Court-ordered delays in mailing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding subsection (b), notice to the customer may be delayed if the transferring agency or department has obtained a court order delaying notice pursuant to section 3409(a) and (b) of this title and that order is still in effect, or if the receiving agency or department obtains a court order authorizing a delay in notice pursuant to section 3409(a) and (b) of this title. Upon the expiration of any such period of delay, the transferring agency or department shall serve to the customer the notice specified in subsection (b) and the agency or department that obtained the court order authorizing a delay in notice pursuant to section 3409(a) and (b) of this title shall serve to the customer the notice specified in <ref>section 3409(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exchanges of examination reports by supervisory agencies; transfer of financial records to defend customer action; withholding of information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter prohibits any supervisory agency from exchanging examination reports or other information with another supervisory agency. Nothing in this chapter prohibits the transfer of a customer’s financial records needed by counsel for a Government authority to defend an action brought by the customer. Nothing in this chapter shall authorize the withholding of information by any officer or employee of a supervisory agency from a duly authorized committee or subcommittee of the Congress.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exchange of records, reports, or other information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding section 3401(6) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002350">1</ref> of this title or any other provision of law, the exchange of financial records, examination reports or other information with respect to a financial institution, holding company, or any subsidiary of a depository institution or holding company, among and between the five member supervisory agencies of the Federal Financial Institutions Examination Council, the Securities and Exchange Commission, the Federal Trade Commission, the Commodity Futures Trading Commission, and the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection is permitted.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer to Attorney General or Secretary of the Treasury</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Nothing in this chapter shall apply when financial records obtained by an agency or department of the United States are disclosed or transferred to the Attorney General or the Secretary of the Treasury upon the certification by a supervisory level official of the transferring agency or department that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> there is reason to believe that the records may be relevant to a violation of Federal criminal law; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the records were obtained in the exercise of the agency’s or department’s supervisory or regulatory functions.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on use</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Records so transferred shall be used only for criminal investigative or prosecutive purposes, for civil actions under <ref>section 1833a of this title</ref>, or for forfeiture under sections <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002351">2</ref> 981 or 982 of title 18 by the Department of Justice and only for criminal investigative purposes relating to money laundering and other financial crimes by the Department of the Treasury and shall, upon completion of the investigation or prosecution (including any appeal), be returned only to the transferring agency or department. No agency or department so transferring such records shall be deemed to have waived any privilege applicable to those records under law.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–630, title XI, § 1112</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 3705</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–320, title IV, § 432(a)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-15">Oct. 15, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1527</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title VI, § 6186(b)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4357</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–73, title IX, § 944</ref>, <date date="1989-08-09">Aug. 9, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 498</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–242, title IV, § 411(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-19">Dec. 19, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 2375</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–550, title XV, § 1516</ref>, title XVI, § 1606(b), <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4059</ref>, 4087; <ref>Pub. L. 106–102, title II, § 231(b)(2)</ref>, title VII, § 727(b)(2), <date date="1999-11-12">Nov. 12, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1407</ref>, 1475; <ref>Pub. L. 107–56, title III, § 358(f)(1)</ref>, <date date="2001-10-26">Oct. 26, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 327</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–455</ref>, §§ 10, 13, <date date="2006-12-22">Dec. 22, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3381</ref>, 3382; <ref>Pub. L. 111–203, title X, § 1099(2)</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2105</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–203, § 1</ref>, <date date="2012-12-04">Dec. 4, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1484</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3413.</num>
<heading> Exceptions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disclosure of financial records not identified with particular customers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter prohibits the disclosure of any financial records or information which is not identified with or identifiable as being derived from the financial records of a particular customer.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disclosure to, or examination by, supervisory agency pursuant to exercise of supervisory, regulatory, or monetary functions with respect to financial institutions, holding companies, subsidiaries, institution-affiliated parties, or other persons</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This chapter shall not apply to the examination by or disclosure to any supervisory agency of financial records or information in the exercise of its supervisory, regulatory, or monetary functions, including conservatorship or receivership functions, with respect to any financial institution, holding company, subsidiary of a financial institution or holding company, institution-affiliated party (within the meaning of <ref>section 1813(u) of this title</ref>) with respect to a financial institution, holding company, or subsidiary, or other person participating in the conduct of the affairs thereof.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disclosure pursuant to title 26</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter prohibits the disclosure of financial records in accordance with procedures authorized by title 26.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disclosure pursuant to Federal statute or rule promulgated thereunder</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall authorize the withholding of financial records or information required to be reported in accordance with any Federal statute or rule promulgated thereunder.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disclosure pursuant to Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure or comparable rules of other courts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall apply when financial records are sought by a Government authority under the Federal Rules of Civil or Criminal Procedure or comparable rules of other courts in connection with litigation to which the Government authority and the customer are parties.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disclosure pursuant to administrative subpena issued by administrative law judge</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall apply when financial records are sought by a Government authority pursuant to an administrative subpena issued by an administrative law judge in an adjudicatory proceeding subject to <ref>section 554 of title 5</ref> and to which the Government authority and the customer are parties.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disclosure pursuant to legitimate law enforcement inquiry respecting name, address, account number, and type of account of particular customers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The notice requirements of this chapter and sections 3410 and 3412 of this title shall not apply when a Government authority by a means described in <ref>section 3402 of this title</ref> and for a legitimate law enforcement inquiry is seeking only the name, address, account number, and type of account of any customer or ascertainable group of customers associated (1) with a financial transaction or class of financial transactions, or (2) with a foreign country or subdivision thereof in the case of a Government authority exercising financial controls over foreign accounts in the United States under <ref>section 4305(b) of title 50</ref>; the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (title II, <ref>Public Law 95–223</ref>) [<ref>50 U.S.C. 1701</ref> et seq.]; or <ref>section 287c of title 22</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disclosure pursuant to lawful proceeding, investigation, etc., directed at financial institution or legal entity or consideration or administration respecting Government loans, loan guarantees, etc.</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Nothing in this chapter (except sections 3403, 3417 and 3418 of this title) shall apply when financial records are sought by a Government authority—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in connection with a lawful proceeding, investigation, examination, or inspection directed at a financial institution (whether or not such proceeding, investigation, examination, or inspection is also directed at a customer) or at a legal entity which is not a customer; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in connection with the authority’s consideration or administration of assistance to the customer in the form of a Government loan, loan guaranty, or loan insurance program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> When financial records are sought pursuant to this subsection, the Government authority shall submit to the financial institution the certificate required by <ref>section 3403(b) of this title</ref>. For access pursuant to paragraph (1)(B), no further certification shall be required for subsequent access by the certifying Government authority during the term of the loan, loan guaranty, or loan insurance agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> After the effective date of this chapter, whenever a customer applies for participation in a Government loan, loan guaranty, or loan insurance program, the Government authority administering such program shall give the customer written notice of the authority’s access rights under this subsection. No further notification shall be required for subsequent access by that authority during the term of the loan, loan guaranty, or loan insurance agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> Financial records obtained pursuant to this subsection may be used only for the purpose for which they were originally obtained, and may be transferred to another agency or department only when the transfer is to facilitate a lawful proceeding, investigation, examination, or inspection directed at a financial institution (whether or not such proceeding, investigation, examination, or inspection is also directed at a customer), or at a legal entity which is not a customer, except that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> nothing in this paragraph prohibits the use or transfer of a customer’s financial records needed by counsel representing a Government authority in a civil action arising from a Government loan, loan guaranty, or loan insurance agreement; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> nothing in this paragraph prohibits a Government authority providing assistance to a customer in the form of a loan, loan guaranty, or loan insurance agreement from using or transferring financial records necessary to process, service or foreclose a loan, or to collect on an indebtedness to the Government resulting from a customer’s default.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Notification that financial records obtained pursuant to this subsection may relate to a potential civil, criminal, or regulatory violation by a customer may be given to an agency or department with jurisdiction over that violation, and such agency or department may then seek access to the records pursuant to the provisions of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Each financial institution shall keep a notation of each disclosure made pursuant to paragraph (1)(B) of this subsection, including the date of such disclosure and the Government authority to which it was made. The customer shall be entitled to inspect this information.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disclosure pursuant to issuance of subpena or court order respecting grand jury proceeding</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter (except sections 3415 and 3420 of this title) shall apply to any subpena or court order issued in connection with proceedings before a grand jury, except that a court shall have authority to order a financial institution, on which a grand jury subpoena for customer records has been served, not to notify the customer of the existence of the subpoena or information that has been furnished to the grand jury, under the circumstances and for the period specified and pursuant to the procedures established in <ref>section 3409 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disclosure pursuant to proceeding, investigation, etc., instituted by Government Accountability Office and directed at a government authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This chapter shall not apply when financial records are sought by the Government Accountability Office pursuant to an authorized proceeding, investigation, examination or audit directed at a government authority.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(k)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disclosure necessary for proper administration of programs of certain Government authorities</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Nothing in this chapter shall apply to the disclosure by the financial institution of the name and address of any customer to the Department of the Treasury, the Social Security Administration, or the Railroad Retirement Board, where the disclosure of such information is necessary to, and such information is used solely for the purpose of, the proper administration of <ref>section 1441 of title 26</ref>, title II of the Social Security Act [<ref>42 U.S.C. 401</ref> et seq.], or the Railroad Retirement Act of 1974 [<ref>45 U.S.C. 231</ref> et seq.].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Nothing in this chapter shall apply to the disclosure by the financial institution of information contained in the financial records of any customer to any Government authority that certifies, disburses, or collects payments, where the disclosure of such information is necessary to, and such information is used solely for the purpose of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> verification of the identity of any person or proper routing and delivery of funds in connection with the issuance of a Federal payment or collection of funds by a Government authority; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the investigation or recovery of an improper Federal payment or collection of funds or an improperly negotiated Treasury check.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a request authorized by paragraph (1) or (2) (and the information contained therein) may be used by the financial institution or its agents solely for the purpose of providing information contained in the financial records of the customer to the Government authority requesting the information, and the financial institution and its agents shall be barred from redisclosure of such information. Any Government authority receiving information pursuant to paragraph (1) or (2) may not disclose or use the information, except for the purposes set forth in such paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(l)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Crimes against financial institutions by insiders</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall apply when any financial institution or supervisory agency provides any financial record of any officer, director, employee, or controlling shareholder (within the meaning of subparagraph (A) or (B) of <ref>section 1841(a)(2) of this title</ref> or subparagraph (A) or (B) of <ref>section 1730a(a)(2) of this title</ref>) of such institution, or of any major borrower from such institution who there is reason to believe may be acting in concert with any such officer, director, employee, or controlling shareholder, to the Attorney General of the United States, to a State law enforcement agency, or, in the case of a possible violation of subchapter II of chapter 53 of title 31, to the Secretary of the Treasury if there is reason to believe that such record is relevant to a possible violation by such person of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any law relating to crimes against financial institutions or supervisory agencies by directors, officers, employees, or controlling shareholders of, or by borrowers from, financial institutions; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any provision of subchapter II of chapter 53 of title 31 or of section 1956 or 1957 of title 18.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">No supervisory agency which transfers any such record under this subsection shall be deemed to have waived any privilege applicable to that record under law.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(m)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disclosure to, or examination by, employees or agents of Board of Governors of Federal Reserve System or Federal Reserve Bank</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This chapter shall not apply to the examination by or disclosure to employees or agents of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System or any Federal Reserve Bank of financial records or information in the exercise of the Federal Reserve System’s authority to extend credit to the financial institutions or others.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(n)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disclosure to, or examination by, Resolution Trust Corporation or its employees or agents</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This chapter shall not apply to the examination by or disclosure to the Resolution Trust Corporation or its employees or agents of financial records or information in the exercise of its conservatorship, receivership, or liquidation functions with respect to a financial institution.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(o)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disclosure to, or examination by, Federal Housing Finance Agency or Federal home loan banks</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This chapter shall not apply to the examination by or disclosure to the Federal Housing Finance Agency or any of the Federal home loan banks of financial records or information in the exercise of the Federal Housing Finance Agency’s authority to extend credit (either directly or through a Federal home loan bank) to financial institutions or others.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(p)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Access to information necessary for administration of certain veteran benefits laws</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Nothing in this chapter shall apply to the disclosure by the financial institution of the name and address of any customer to the Department of Veterans Affairs where the disclosure of such information is necessary to, and such information is used solely for the purposes of, the proper administration of benefits programs under laws administered by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any request authorized by paragraph (1) (and the information contained therein) may be used by the financial institution or its agents solely for the purpose of providing the customer’s name and address to the Department of Veterans Affairs and shall be barred from redisclosure by the financial institution or its agents.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(q)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disclosure pursuant to Federal contractor-issued travel charge card</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall apply to the disclosure of any financial record or information to a Government authority in conjunction with a Federal contractor-issued travel charge card issued for official Government travel.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(r)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disclosure to the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall apply to the examination by or disclosure to the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection of financial records or information in the exercise of its authority with respect to a financial institution.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–630, title XI, § 1113</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 3706</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–21, title I, § 121(c)(3)(C)</ref>, <date date="1983-04-20">Apr. 20, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 83</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 2095</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–570, title I, § 1353(b)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3207–22</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title VI, § 6186(c)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4358</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–73, title IX, § 942</ref>, <date date="1989-08-09">Aug. 9, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 497</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–647, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4791</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–242, title IV, § 411(2)</ref>–(4), <date date="1991-12-19">Dec. 19, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 2375</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–568, title VI, § 603(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4342</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–264, § 2(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-19">Oct. 19, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2351</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–271, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-07-07">July 7, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 814</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title XIV, § 14205</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1459</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title XIV, § 14205, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2221; <ref>Pub. L. 110–289, div. A, title II, § 1216(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2792</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–203, title X, § 1099(3)</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2105</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3414.</num>
<heading> Special procedures</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Access to financial records for certain intelligence and protective purposes</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Nothing in this chapter (except sections 3415, 3417, 3418, and 3421 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002352">1</ref> of this title) shall apply to the production and disclosure of financial records pursuant to requests from—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a Government authority authorized to conduct foreign counter- or foreign positive-intelligence activities for purposes of conducting such activities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Secret Service for the purpose of conducting its protective functions (<ref>18 U.S.C. 3056</ref>; <ref>18 U.S.C. 3056A</ref>, <ref>Public Law 90–331</ref>,<sup>1</sup> as amended); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a Government authority authorized to conduct investigations of, or intelligence or counterintelligence analyses related to, international terrorism for the purpose of conducting such investigations or analyses.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In the instances specified in paragraph (1), the Government authority shall submit to the financial institution the certificate required in <ref>section 3403(b) of this title</ref> signed by a supervisory official of a rank designated by the head of the Government authority and a term that specifically identifies a customer, entity, or account to be used as the basis for the production and disclosure of financial records.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> If the Government authority described in paragraph (1) or the Secret Service, as the case may be, certifies that otherwise there may result a danger to the national security of the United States, interference with a criminal, counterterrorism, or counterintelligence investigation, interference with diplomatic relations, or danger to the life or physical safety of any person, no financial institution, or officer, employee, or agent of such institution, shall disclose to any person (other than those to whom such disclosure is necessary to comply with the request or an attorney to obtain legal advice or legal assistance with respect to the request) that the Government authority or the Secret Service has sought or obtained access to a customer’s financial records.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The request shall notify the person or entity to whom the request is directed of the nondisclosure requirement under subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Any recipient disclosing to those persons necessary to comply with the request or to an attorney to obtain legal advice or legal assistance with respect to the request shall inform such persons of any applicable nondisclosure requirement. Any person who receives a disclosure under this subsection shall be subject to the same prohibitions on disclosure under subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> At the request of the authorized Government authority or the Secret Service, any person making or intending to make a disclosure under this section shall identify to the requesting official of the authorized Government authority or the Secret Service the person to whom such disclosure will be made or to whom such disclosure was made prior to the request, except that nothing in this section shall require a person to inform the requesting official of the authorized Government authority or the Secret Service of the identity of an attorney to whom disclosure was made or will be made to obtain legal advice or legal assistance with respect to the request for financial records under this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Government authority specified in paragraph (1) shall compile an annual tabulation of the occasions in which this section was used.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Financial institutions, and officers, employees, and agents thereof, shall comply with a request for a customer’s or entity’s financial records made pursuant to this subsection by the Federal Bureau of Investigation when the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation (or the Director’s designee in a position not lower than Deputy Assistant Director at Bureau headquarters or a Special Agent in Charge in a Bureau field office designated by the Director) certifies in writing to the financial institution that such records are sought for foreign counter intelligence <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002353">2</ref> purposes to protect against international terrorism or clandestine intelligence activities, provided that such an investigation of a United States person is not conducted solely upon the basis of activities protected by the first amendment to the Constitution of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Federal Bureau of Investigation may disseminate information obtained pursuant to this paragraph only as provided in guidelines approved by the Attorney General for foreign intelligence collection and foreign counterintelligence investigations conducted by the Federal Bureau of Investigation, and, with respect to dissemination to an agency of the United States, only if such information is clearly relevant to the authorized responsibilities of such agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> On the dates provided in <ref>section 3106 of title 50</ref>, the Attorney General shall fully inform the congressional intelligence committees (as defined in <ref>section 3003 of title 50</ref>) concerning all requests made pursuant to this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Emergency access to financial records</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Nothing in this chapter shall prohibit a Government authority from obtaining financial records from a financial institution if the Government authority determines that delay in obtaining access to such records would create imminent danger of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> physical injury to any person;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> serious property damage; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> flight to avoid prosecution.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In the instances specified in paragraph (1), the Government shall submit to the financial institution the certificate required in <ref>section 3403(b) of this title</ref> signed by a supervisory official of a rank designated by the head of the Government authority.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Within five days of obtaining access to financial records under this subsection, the Government authority shall file with the appropriate court a signed, sworn statement of a supervisory official of a rank designated by the head of the Government authority setting forth the grounds for the emergency access. The Government authority shall thereafter comply with the notice provisions of <ref>section 3409(c) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Government authority specified in paragraph (1) shall compile an annual tabulation of the occasions in which this section was used.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition of certain disclosure</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">If a certification is issued under subparagraph (B) and notice of the right to judicial review under subsection (d) is provided, no financial institution that receives a request under subsection (a), or officer, employee, or agent thereof, shall disclose to any person that the Federal Bureau of Investigation has sought or obtained access to information or records under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certification</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The requirements of subparagraph (A) shall apply if the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, or a designee of the Director whose rank shall be no lower than Deputy Assistant Director at Bureau headquarters or a Special Agent in Charge of a Bureau field office, certifies that the absence of a prohibition of disclosure under this subsection may result in—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a danger to the national security of the United States;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> interference with a criminal, counterterrorism, or counterintelligence investigation;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> interference with diplomatic relations; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> danger to the life or physical safety of any person.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">A financial institution that receives a request under subsection (a), or officer, employee, or agent thereof, may disclose information otherwise subject to any applicable nondisclosure requirement to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> those persons to whom disclosure is necessary in order to comply with the request;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> an attorney in order to obtain legal advice or assistance regarding the request; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> other persons as permitted by the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation or the designee of the Director.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A person to whom disclosure is made under subparagraph (A) shall be subject to the nondisclosure requirements applicable to a person to whom a request is issued under subsection (a) in the same manner as the person to whom the request is issued.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Any recipient that discloses to a person described in subparagraph (A) information otherwise subject to a nondisclosure requirement shall inform the person of the applicable nondisclosure requirement.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Identification of disclosure recipients</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">At the request of the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation or the designee of the Director, any person making or intending to make a disclosure under clause (i) or (iii) of subparagraph (A) shall identify to the Director or such designee the person to whom such disclosure will be made or to whom such disclosure was made prior to the request.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Judicial review</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A request under subsection (a) or a nondisclosure requirement imposed in connection with such request under subsection (c) shall be subject to judicial review under <ref>section 3511 of title 18</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A request under subsection (a) shall include notice of the availability of judicial review described in paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition of “financial institution”</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this section, and sections 3415 and 3417 of this title insofar as they relate to the operation of this section, the term “financial institution” has the same meaning as in subsections (a)(2) and (c)(1) of <ref>section 5312 of title 31</ref>, except that, for purposes of this section, such term shall include only such a financial institution any part of which is located inside any State or territory of the United States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, or the United States Virgin Islands.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–630, title XI, § 1114</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 3707</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–320, title IV, § 432(b)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-15">Oct. 15, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1527</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–569, title IV, § 404</ref>, <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3197</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–56, title III, § 358(f)(2)</ref>, title V, § 505(b), <date date="2001-10-26">Oct. 26, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 327</ref>, 365; <ref>Pub. L. 107–306, title VIII, § 811(b)(9)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-27">Nov. 27, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2426</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–177, title III, § 374(a)</ref>, <date date="2003-12-13">Dec. 13, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2628</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–177, title I, § 116(d)</ref>, (e), title VI, § 605(e)(1), <date date="2006-03-09">Mar. 9, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 215</ref>, 216, 255; <ref>Pub. L. 109–178, § 4(d)</ref>, <date date="2006-03-09">Mar. 9, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 280</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–23, title V</ref>, §§ 501(b), 502(b), 503(b), <date date="2015-06-02">June 2, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 282</ref>, 284, 290.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3415.</num>
<heading> Cost reimbursement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except for records obtained pursuant to section 3403(d) or 3413(a) through (h) of this title, or as otherwise provided by law, a Government authority shall pay to the financial institution assembling or providing financial records pertaining to a customer and in accordance with procedures established by this chapter a fee for reimbursement for such costs as are reasonably necessary and which have been directly incurred in searching for, reproducing, or transporting books, papers, records, or other data required or requested to be produced. The Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System shall, by regulation, establish the rates and conditions under which such payment may be made.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–630, title XI, § 1115(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 3708</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3416.</num>
<heading> Jurisdiction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An action to enforce any provision of this chapter may be brought in any appropriate United States district court without regard to the amount in controversy within three years from the date on which the violation occurs or the date of discovery of such violation, whichever is later.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–630, title XI, § 1116</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 3708</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3417.</num>
<heading> Civil penalties</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Liability of agencies or departments of United States or financial institutions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Any agency or department of the United States or financial institution obtaining or disclosing financial records or information contained therein in violation of this chapter is liable to the customer to whom such records relate in an amount equal to the sum of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> $100 without regard to the volume of records involved;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any actual damages sustained by the customer as a result of the disclosure;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> such punitive damages as the court may allow, where the violation is found to have been willful or intentional; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> in the case of any successful action to enforce liability under this section, the costs of the action together with reasonable attorney’s fees as determined by the court.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disciplinary action for willful or intentional violation of chapter by agents or employees of department or agency</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever the court determines that any agency or department of the United States has violated any provision of this chapter and the court finds that the circumstances surrounding the violation raise questions of whether an officer or employee of the department or agency acted willfully or intentionally with respect to the violation, the Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall promptly initiate a proceeding to determine whether disciplinary action is warranted against the agent or employee who was primarily responsible for the violation. The Director after investigation and consideration of the evidence submitted, shall submit his findings and recommendations to the administrative authority of the agency concerned and shall send copies of the findings and recommendations to the officer or employee or his representative. The administrative authority shall take the corrective action that the Director recommends.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Good faith defense</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any financial institution or agent or employee thereof making a disclosure of financial records pursuant to this chapter in good-faith reliance upon a certificate by any Government authority or pursuant to the provisions of section 3413(<i>l</i>) of this title shall not be liable to the customer for such disclosure under this chapter, the constitution of any State, or any law or regulation of any State or any political subdivision of any State.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exclusive judicial remedies and sanctions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The remedies and sanctions described in this chapter shall be the only authorized judicial remedies and sanctions for violations of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–630, title XI, § 1117</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 3708</ref>; 1978 Reorg. Plan No. 2, § 102, eff. <date date="1979-01-01">Jan. 1, 1979</date>, 43 F.R. 36037, <ref>92 Stat. 3783</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title VI, § 6186(d)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4358</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3418.</num>
<heading> Injunctive relief</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In addition to any other remedy contained in this chapter, injunctive relief shall be available to require that the procedures of this chapter are complied with. In the event of any successful action, costs together with reasonable attorney’s fees as determined by the court may be recovered.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–630, title XI, § 1118</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 3709</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3419.</num>
<heading> Suspension of limitations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If any individual files a motion or application under this chapter which has the effect of delaying the access of a Government authority to financial records pertaining to such individual, any applicable statute of limitations shall be deemed to be tolled for the period extending from the date such motion or application was filed until the date upon which the motion or application is decided.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–630, title XI, § 1119</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 3709</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3420.</num>
<heading> Grand jury information; notification of certain persons prohibited</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Financial records about a customer obtained from a financial institution pursuant to a subpena issued under the authority of a Federal grand jury—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall be returned and actually presented to the grand jury unless the volume of such records makes such return and actual presentation impractical in which case the grand jury shall be provided with a description of the contents of the records.; <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002354">1</ref></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall be used only for the purpose of considering whether to issue an indictment or presentment by that grand jury, or of prosecuting a crime for which that indictment or presentment is issued, or for a purpose authorized by rule 6(e) of the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure, or for a purpose authorized by <ref>section 3412(a) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> shall be destroyed or returned to the financial institution if not used for one of the purposes specified in paragraph (2); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> shall not be maintained, or a description of the contents of such records shall not be maintained by any Government authority other than in the sealed records of the grand jury, unless such record has been used in the prosecution of a crime for which the grand jury issued an indictment or presentment or for a purpose authorized by rule 6(e) of the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> No officer, director, partner, employee, or shareholder of, or agent or attorney for, a financial institution shall, directly or indirectly, notify any person named in a grand jury subpoena served on such institution in connection with an investigation relating to a possible—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> crime against any financial institution or supervisory agency or crime involving a violation of the Controlled Substance Act [<ref>21 U.S.C. 801</ref> et seq.], the Controlled Substances Import and Export Act [<ref>21 U.S.C. 951</ref> et seq.], section 1956, 1957, or 1960 of title 18, sections 5313, 5316, 5322, 5324, 5331, and 5332 of title 31, or <ref>section 6050I of title 26</ref>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> conspiracy to commit such a crime,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">about the existence or contents of such subpoena, or information that has been furnished to the grand jury in response to such subpoena.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content><ref>Section 1818 of this title</ref> and <ref>section 1786(k)(2) of this title</ref> shall apply to any violation of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–630, title XI, § 1120</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 3709</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title VI, § 6186(e)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4358</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–73, title IX, § 943</ref>, <date date="1989-08-09">Aug. 9, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 497</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–550, title XV, § 1532</ref>, <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4066</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–56, title III, § 358(f)(3)</ref>, <date date="2001-10-26">Oct. 26, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 327</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. F, title LXIII, § 6308(d)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4594</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3421.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 104–66, title III, § 3001(d)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-21">Dec. 21, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 734</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3422.</num>
<heading> Applicability to Securities and Exchange Commission</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as provided in the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 [<ref>15 U.S.C. 78a</ref> et seq.], this chapter shall apply with respect to the Securities and Exchange Commission.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–630, title XI, § 1122</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 3710</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–433, § 2</ref>, <date date="1980-10-10">Oct. 10, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1855</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3423.</num>
<heading> Immunity from suit for disclosure of financial exploitation of senior citizens</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Immunity</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In this section—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the term “Bank Secrecy Act officer” means an individual responsible for ensuring compliance with the requirements mandated by subchapter II of chapter 53 of title 31 (commonly known as the “Bank Secrecy Act”);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the term “broker-dealer” means a broker and a dealer, as those terms are defined in <ref>section 78c(a) of title 15</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> the term “covered agency” means—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a State financial regulatory agency, including a State securities or law enforcement authority and a State insurance regulator;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> each of the Federal agencies represented in the membership of the Financial Institutions Examination Council established under <ref>section 3303 of this title</ref>;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a securities association registered under section 78<i>o</i>–3 of title 15;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the Securities and Exchange Commission;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> a law enforcement agency; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> a State or local agency responsible for administering adult protective service laws;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> the term “covered financial institution” means—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a credit union;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a depository institution;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> an investment adviser;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> a broker-dealer;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> an insurance company;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> an insurance agency; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> a transfer agent;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the term “credit union” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 5301 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the term “depository institution” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 1813(c) of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<chapeau> the term “exploitation” means the fraudulent or otherwise illegal, unauthorized, or improper act or process of an individual, including a caregiver or a fiduciary, that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> uses the resources of a senior citizen for monetary or personal benefit, profit, or gain; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> results in depriving a senior citizen of rightful access to or use of benefits, resources, belongings, or assets;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> the term “insurance agency” means any business entity that sells, solicits, or negotiates insurance coverage;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the term “insurance company” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 80a–2(a) of title 15</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> the term “insurance producer” means an individual who is required under State law to be licensed in order to sell, solicit, or negotiate insurance coverage;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> the term “investment adviser” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 80b–2(a) of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(L)</num>
<chapeau> the term “investment adviser representative” means an individual who—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is employed by, or associated with, an investment adviser; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> does not perform solely clerical or ministerial acts;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(M)</num>
<content> the term “registered representative” means an individual who represents a broker-dealer in effecting or attempting to effect a purchase or sale of securities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(N)</num>
<content> the term “senior citizen” means an individual who is not younger than 65 years of age;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(O)</num>
<content> the term “State” means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, and any territory or possession of the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(P)</num>
<content> the term “State insurance regulator” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 6735 of title 15</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(Q)</num>
<content> the term “State securities or law enforcement authority” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 78x(f)(4) of title 15</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(R)</num>
<content> the term “transfer agent” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 78c(a) of title 15</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Immunity from suit</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Immunity for individuals</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">An individual who has received the training described in subsection (b) shall not be liable, including in any civil or administrative proceeding, for disclosing the suspected exploitation of a senior citizen to a covered agency if the individual, at the time of the disclosure—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> served as a supervisor or in a compliance or legal function (including as a Bank Secrecy Act officer) for, or, in the case of a registered representative, investment adviser representative, or insurance producer, was affiliated or associated with, a covered financial institution; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> made the disclosure—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> in good faith; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> with reasonable care.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Immunity for covered financial institutions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">A covered financial institution shall not be liable, including in any civil or administrative proceeding, for a disclosure made by an individual described in subparagraph (A) if—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the individual was employed by, or, in the case of a registered representative, insurance producer, or investment adviser representative, affiliated or associated with, the covered financial institution at the time of the disclosure; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> before the time of the disclosure, each individual described in subsection (b)(1) received the training described in subsection (b).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Nothing in subparagraph (A) or (B) shall be construed to limit the liability of an individual or a covered financial institution in a civil action for any act, omission, or fraud that is not a disclosure described in subparagraph (A).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Training</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A covered financial institution or a third party selected by a covered financial institution may provide the training described in paragraph (2)(A) to each officer or employee of, or registered representative, insurance producer, or investment adviser representative affiliated or associated with, the covered financial institution who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is described in subsection (a)(2)(A)(i);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> may come into contact with a senior citizen as a regular part of the professional duties of the individual; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> may review or approve the financial documents, records, or transactions of a senior citizen in connection with providing financial services to a senior citizen.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Content</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The content of the training that a covered financial institution or a third party selected by the covered financial institution may provide under paragraph (1) shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> be maintained by the covered financial institution and made available to a covered agency with examination authority over the covered financial institution, upon request, except that a covered financial institution shall not be required to maintain or make available such content with respect to any individual who is no longer employed by, or affiliated or associated with, the covered financial institution;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> instruct any individual attending the training on how to identify and report the suspected exploitation of a senior citizen internally and, as appropriate, to government officials or law enforcement authorities, including common signs that indicate the financial exploitation of a senior citizen;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> discuss the need to protect the privacy and respect the integrity of each individual customer of the covered financial institution; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> be appropriate to the job responsibilities of the individual attending the training.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Timing</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The training under paragraph (1) shall be provided—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> as soon as reasonably practicable; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> with respect to an individual who begins employment, or becomes affiliated or associated, with a covered financial institution after <date date="2018-05-24">May 24, 2018</date>, not later than 1 year after the date on which the individual becomes employed by, or affiliated or associated with, the covered financial institution in a position described in subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) of paragraph (1).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Records</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">A covered financial institution shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> maintain a record of each individual who—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> is employed by, or affiliated or associated with, the covered financial institution in a position described in subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) of paragraph (1); and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<chapeau> has completed the training under paragraph (1), regardless of whether the training was—</chapeau>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> provided by the covered financial institution or a third party selected by the covered financial institution;</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> completed before the individual was employed by, or affiliated or associated with, the covered financial institution; and</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(cc)</num>
<content> completed before, on, or after <date date="2018-05-24">May 24, 2018</date>; and</content>
</item>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> upon request, provide a record described in clause (i) to a covered agency with examination authority over the covered financial institution.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Relationship to State law</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall be construed to preempt or limit any provision of State law, except only to the extent that subsection (a) provides a greater level of protection against liability to an individual described in subsection (a)(2)(A) or to a covered financial institution described in subsection (a)(2)(B) than is provided under State law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 115–174, title III, § 303</ref>, <date date="2018-05-24">May 24, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1335</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>