<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 47—</num>
<heading>COMMUNITY DEVELOPMENT BANKING</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>COMMUNITY DEVELOPMENT BANKING AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4701.</num>
<heading> Findings and purposes</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> many of the Nation’s urban, rural, and Native American communities face critical social and economic problems arising in part from the lack of economic growth, people living in poverty, and the lack of employment and other opportunities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the restoration and maintenance of the economies of these communities will require coordinated development strategies, intensive supportive services, and increased access to equity investments and loans for development activities, including investment in businesses, housing, commercial real estate, human development, and other activities that promote the long-term economic and social viability of the community; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> community development financial institutions have proven their ability to identify and respond to community needs for equity investments, loans, and development services.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purpose</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The purpose of this subchapter is to create a Community Development Financial Institutions Fund to promote economic revitalization and community development through investment in and assistance to community development financial institutions, including enhancing the liquidity of community development financial institutions.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–325, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1994-09-23">Sept. 23, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2163</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4702.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this subchapter, the following definitions shall apply:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrator</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Administrator” means the Administrator of the Fund appointed under <ref>section 4703(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appropriate Federal banking agency</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “appropriate Federal banking agency” has the same meaning as in <ref>section 1813 of this title</ref>, and also includes the National Credit Union Administration Board with respect to insured credit unions.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Affiliate</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “affiliate” has the same meaning as in <ref>section 1841(k) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Board</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Board” means the Community Development Advisory Board established under <ref>section 4703(d) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Community development financial institution</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “community development financial institution” means a person (other than an individual) that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> has a primary mission of promoting community development;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> serves an investment area or targeted population;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> provides development services in conjunction with equity investments or loans, directly or through a subsidiary or affiliate;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> maintains, through representation on its governing board or otherwise, accountability to residents of its investment area or targeted population; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> is not an agency or instrumentality of the United States, or of any State or political subdivision of a State.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conditions for qualification of holding companies</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consolidated treatment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">A depository institution holding company may qualify as a community development financial institution only if the holding company and the subsidiaries and affiliates of the holding company collectively satisfy the requirements of subparagraph (A).</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exclusion of subsidiary or affiliate for failure to meet consolidated treatment rule</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">No subsidiary or affiliate of a depository institution holding company may qualify as a community development financial institution if the holding company and the subsidiaries and affiliates of the holding company do not collectively meet the requirements of subparagraph (A).</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conditions for subsidiaries</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">No subsidiary of an insured depository institution may qualify as a community development financial institution if the insured depository institution and its subsidiaries do not collectively meet the requirements of subparagraph (A).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Community partner</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “community partner” means a person (other than an individual) that provides loans, equity investments, or development services, including a depository institution holding company, an insured depository institution, an insured credit union, a nonprofit organization, a State or local government agency, a quasi-governmental entity, and an investment company authorized to operate pursuant to the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 [<ref>15 U.S.C. 661</ref> et seq.].</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Community partnership</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “community partnership” means an agreement between a community development financial institution and a community partner to provide development services, loans, or equity investments, to an investment area or targeted population.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Depository institution holding company</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “depository institution holding company” has the same meaning as in <ref>section 1813 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Development services</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “development services” means activities that promote community development and are integral to lending or investment activities, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> business planning;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> financial and credit counseling; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> marketing and management assistance.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(10)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Fund” means the Community Development Financial Institutions Fund established under <ref>section 4703(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(11)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Indian reservation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Indian reservation” has the same meaning as in <ref>section 1903(10) of title 25</ref>, and shall include land held by incorporated Native groups, regional corporations, and village corporations, as defined in or established pursuant to the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act [<ref>43 U.S.C. 1601</ref> et seq.], public domain Indian allotments, and former Indian reservations in the State of Oklahoma.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(12)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Indian tribe</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Indian tribe” means any Indian tribe, band, pueblo, nation, or other organized group or community, including any Alaska Native village or regional or village corporation, as defined in or established pursuant to the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act [<ref>43 U.S.C. 1601</ref> et seq.], which is recognized as eligible for the special programs and services provided by the United States to Indians because of their status as Indians.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(13)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Insured community development financial institution</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “insured community development financial institution” means any community development financial institution that is an insured depository institution or an insured credit union.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(14)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Insured credit union</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “insured credit union” has the same meaning as in <ref>section 1752(7) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(15)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Insured depository institution</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “insured depository institution” has the same meaning as in <ref>section 1813 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(16)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Investment area</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “investment area” means a geographic area (or areas) including an Indian reservation that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> meets objective criteria of economic distress developed by the Fund, which may include the percentage of low-income families or the extent of poverty, the rate of unemployment or underemployment, rural population outmigration, lag in population growth, and extent of blight and disinvestment; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> has significant unmet needs for loans or equity investments; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> encompasses or is located in an empowerment zone or enterprise community designated under <ref>section 1391 of title 26</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(17)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Low-income</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “low-income” means having an income, adjusted for family size, of not more than—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> for metropolitan areas, 80 percent of the area median income; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> for nonmetropolitan areas, the greater of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> 80 percent of the area median income; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> 80 percent of the statewide nonmetropolitan area median income.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(18)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “State” has the same meaning as in <ref>section 1813 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(19)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Subsidiary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “subsidiary” has the same meaning as in <ref>section 1813 of this title</ref>, except that a community development financial institution that is a corporation shall not be considered to be a subsidiary of any insured depository institution or depository institution holding company that controls less than 25 percent of any class of the voting shares of such corporation, and does not otherwise control in any manner the election of a majority of the directors of the corporation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(20)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Targeted population</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “targeted population” means individuals, or an identifiable group of individuals, including an Indian tribe, who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> are low-income persons; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> otherwise lack adequate access to loans or equity investments.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(21)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Training program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “training program” means the training program operated by the Fund under <ref>section 4708 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–325, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1994-09-23">Sept. 23, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2163</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4703.</num>
<heading> Establishment of national Fund for community development banking</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is established a corporation to be known as the Community Development Financial Institutions Fund that shall have the duties and responsibilities specified by this subchapter and subchapter II of this chapter. The Fund shall have succession until dissolved. The offices of the Fund shall be in Washington, D.C. The Fund shall not be affiliated with or be within any other agency or department of the Federal Government.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Wholly owned Government corporation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Fund shall be a wholly owned Government corporation in the executive branch and shall be treated in all respects as an agency of the United States, except as otherwise provided in this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Management of Fund</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment of Administrator</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The management of the Fund shall be vested in an Administrator, who shall be appointed by the President. The Administrator shall not engage in any other business or employment during service as the Administrator.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Chief financial officer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Administrator shall appoint a chief financial officer, who shall have the authority and functions of an agency Chief Financial Officer under <ref>section 902 of title 31</ref>. In the event of a vacancy in the position of the Administrator or during the absence or disability of the Administrator, the chief financial officer shall perform the duties of the position of Administrator.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other officers and employees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Administrator may appoint such other officers and employees of the Fund as the Administrator determines to be necessary or appropriate.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Expedited hiring</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">During the 2-year period beginning on <date date="1994-09-23">September 23, 1994</date>, the Administrator may—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> appoint and terminate the individuals referred to in paragraphs (2) and (3) without regard to the civil service laws and regulations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> fix the compensation of the individuals referred to in paragraph (3) without regard to the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5 relating to classification of positions and General Schedule pay rates, except that the rate of pay for such individuals may not exceed the rate payable for level V of the Executive Schedule under section 5316 of such title.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General powers</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In carrying out the functions of the Fund, the Administrator—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall have all necessary and proper authority to carry out this subchapter and subchapter II of this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall have the power to adopt, alter, and use a corporate seal for the Fund, which shall be judicially noticed;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> may adopt, amend, and repeal bylaws, rules, and regulations governing the manner in which business of the Fund may be conducted and such rules and regulations as may be necessary or appropriate to implement this subchapter and subchapter II of this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> may enter into, perform, and enforce such agreements, contracts, and transactions as may be deemed necessary or appropriate to the conduct of activities authorized under this subchapter and subchapter II of this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> may determine the character of and necessity for expenditures of the Fund and the manner in which they shall be incurred, allowed, and paid;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> may utilize or employ the services of personnel of any agency or instrumentality of the United States with the consent of the agency or instrumentality concerned on a reimbursable or nonreimbursable basis; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> may execute all instruments necessary or appropriate in the exercise of any of the functions of the Fund under this subchapter and subchapter II of this chapter and may delegate to the officers of the Fund such of the powers and responsibilities of the Administrator as the Administrator deems necessary or appropriate for the administration of the Fund.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Advisory Board</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is established an advisory board to the Fund to be known as the Community Development Advisory Board, which shall be operated in accordance with the provisions of chapter 10 of title 5, except that <ref>section 1013 of title 5</ref> does not apply to the Board.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Membership</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Board shall consist of 15 members, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Agriculture or his or her designee;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Commerce or his or her designee;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development or his or her designee;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Secretary of the Interior or his or her designee;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the Secretary of the Treasury or his or her designee;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the Administrator of the Small Business Administration or his or her designee; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<chapeau> 9 private citizens, appointed by the President, who shall be selected, to the maximum extent practicable, to provide for national geographic representation and racial, ethnic, and gender diversity, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> 2 individuals who are officers of existing community development financial institutions;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> 2 individuals who are officers of insured depository institutions;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> 2 individuals who are officers of national consumer or public interest organizations;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> 2 individuals who have expertise in community development; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> 1 individual who has personal experience and specialized expertise in the unique lending and community development issues confronted by Indian tribes on Indian reservations.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Chairperson</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The members of the Board specified in paragraph (2)(G) shall select, by majority vote, a chairperson of the Board, who shall serve for a term of 2 years.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Board function</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">It shall be the function of the Board to advise the Administrator on the policies of the Fund regarding activities under this subchapter. The Board shall not advise the Administrator on the granting or denial of any particular application.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Terms of private members</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Each member of the Board appointed under paragraph (2)(G) shall serve for a term of 4 years.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Vacancies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Any member appointed to fill a vacancy occurring prior to the expiration of the term for which the previous member was appointed shall be appointed for the remainder of such term. Members may continue to serve following the expiration of their terms until a successor is appointed.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Meetings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Board shall meet at least annually and at such other times as requested by the Administrator or the chairperson. A majority of the members of the Board shall constitute a quorum.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reimbursement for expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The members of the Board may receive reimbursement for travel, per diem, and other necessary expenses incurred in the performance of their duties, in accordance with chapter 10 of title 5.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Costs and expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Fund shall provide to the Board all necessary staff and facilities.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Government Corporation Control Act exemption</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0"><ref>Section 9107(b) of title 31</ref>, shall not apply to deposits of the Fund made pursuant to <ref>section 4707 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation of Fund and Federal liability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The liability of the Fund and the United States Government arising out of any investment in a community development financial institution in accordance with this subchapter shall be limited to the amount of the investment. The Fund shall be exempt from any assessments and other liabilities that may be imposed on controlling or principal shareholders by any Federal law or the law of any State, Territory, or the District of Columbia. Nothing in this subsection shall affect the application of any Federal tax law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition on issuance of securities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Fund may not issue stock, bonds, debentures, notes, or other securities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assisted institutions not United States instrumentalities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A community development financial institution or other organization that receives assistance pursuant to this subchapter shall not be deemed to be an agency, department, or instrumentality of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(k)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transition period</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">During the transition period, the Secretary of the Treasury may—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> assist in the establishment of the administrative functions of the Fund listed in paragraph (2); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> hire not more than 6 individuals to serve as employees of the Fund during the transition period.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Continued service</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Individuals hired in accordance with paragraph (1)(B) may continue to serve as employees of the Fund after the transition period.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrative functions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The administrative functions referred to in paragraph (1)(A) shall be limited to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> establishing accounting, information, and recordkeeping systems for the Fund; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> procuring office space, equipment, and supplies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Expedited hiring</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">During the transition period, the Secretary of the Treasury may—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> appoint and terminate the individuals referred to in paragraph (1)(B) without regard to the civil service laws and regulations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> fix the compensation of the individuals referred to in paragraph (1)(B) without regard to the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5 relating to classification of positions and General Schedule pay rates, except that the rate of pay for such individuals may not exceed the rate payable for level V of the Executive Schedule under section 5316 of such title.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certain employees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">During the transition period, employees of the Department of the Treasury may only comprise less than one-half of the total number of individuals hired in accordance with paragraph (1)(B).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transition expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Amounts previously appropriated to the Department of the Treasury may be used to pay obligations and expenses of the Fund incurred under this section, and such amounts may be reimbursed by the Fund to the Department of the Treasury from amounts appropriated to the Fund for fiscal year 1995.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> “Transition period” defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, the term “transition period” means the period beginning on <date date="1994-09-23">September 23, 1994</date>, and ending on the date on which the Administrator is appointed.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–325, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="1994-09-23">Sept. 23, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2166</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–166, § 2(w)</ref>, <date date="2012-08-10">Aug. 10, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1289</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(a)(57)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4311</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4703a.</num>
<heading> Capital investments for neighborhoods disproportionately impacted by the COVID–19 pandemic</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “bank holding company” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 1841 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “eligible institution” means any low- and moderate-income community financial institution that is eligible to participate in the Program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “Emergency Capital Investment Fund” means the Emergency Capital Investment Fund established under subsection (b);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> the term “low- and moderate-income community financial institution” means any financial institution that is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a community development financial institution; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a minority depository institution; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an insured depository institution that is not controlled by a bank holding company or savings and loan holding company that is also an eligible institution;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a bank holding company;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a savings and loan holding company; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> a federally insured credit union;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the term “minority” means any Black American, Native American, Hispanic American, Asian American, Native Alaskan, Native Hawaiian, or Pacific Islander;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> the term “minority depository institution” means an entity that is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a minority depository institution, as defined in section 308 of the Financial Institutions Reform, Recovery, and Enforcement Act of 1989 (<ref>12 U.S.C. 1463</ref> note); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> considered to be a minority depository institution by—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the appropriate Federal banking agency; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the National Credit Union Administration, in the case of an insured credit union; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> listed in the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation’s Minority Depository Institutions List published for the Third Quarter 2020.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002433">1</ref></content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the term “Program” means the Emergency Capital Investment Program established under subsection (b);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> the term “savings and loan holding company” has the meaning given the term under <ref>section 1467a(a) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> the “Secretary” means the Secretary of the Treasury.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fund established</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is established in the Treasury of the United States a fund to be known as the “Emergency Capital Investment Fund”, which shall be administered by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program authorized</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary is authorized to establish an emergency program known as the “Emergency Capital Investment Program” to support the efforts of low- and moderate-income community financial institutions to, among other things, provide loans, grants, and forbearance for small businesses, minority-owned businesses, and consumers, especially in low-income and underserved communities, including persistent poverty counties, that may be disproportionately impacted by the economic effects of the COVID–19 pandemic, by providing direct and indirect capital investments in low- and moderate-income community financial institutions consistent with this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purchases</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subject to paragraph (2), the Emergency Capital Investment Fund shall be available to the Secretary, without further appropriation or fiscal year limitation, for the costs of purchases (including commitments to purchase), and modifications of such purchases, of preferred stock and other financial instruments from eligible institutions on such terms and conditions as are determined by the Secretary in accordance with this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purchase limit</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The aggregate amount of purchases pursuant to paragraph (1) may not exceed $9,000,000,000.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Acceptance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall begin accepting applications for capital investments under the Program not later than the end of the 30-day period beginning on <date date="2020-12-27">December 27, 2020</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation with regulators</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For each eligible institution that applies to receive a capital investment under the Program, the Secretary shall consult with the appropriate Federal banking agency or the National Credit Union Administration, as applicable, to determine whether the eligible institution may receive such capital investment.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Only low- and moderate-income community financial institutions shall be eligible to participate in the Program.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional criteria</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary may establish additional criteria for participation by an institution in the Program, as the Secretary may determine appropriate in furtherance of the goals of the Program.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement to provide an emergency investment lending plan for communities that may be disproportionately impacted by the economic effects of the COVID–19 pandemic</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">At the time that an applicant submits an application to the Secretary for a capital investment under the Program, the applicant shall provide the Secretary, along with the appropriate Federal banking agency or the National Credit Union Administration, as applicable, an investment and lending plan that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> demonstrates that not less than 30 percent of the lending of the applicant over the past 2 fiscal years was made directly to low- and moderate income borrowers, to borrowers that create direct benefits for low- and moderate-income populations, to other targeted populations as defined by the Fund, or any combination thereof, as measured by the total number and dollar amount of loans;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> describes how the business strategy and operating goals of the applicant will address community development needs in communities that may be disproportionately impacted by the economic effects of COVID–19, which includes the needs of small businesses, consumers, nonprofit organizations, community development, and other projects providing direct benefits to low- and moderate-income communities, low-income individuals, and minorities within the minority, rural, and urban low-income and underserved areas served by the applicant;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> includes a plan to provide community outreach and communication, where appropriate; <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002434">2</ref></content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> includes details on how the applicant plans to expand or maintain significant lending or investment activity in low- or moderate-income minority communities, especially those that may be disproportionately impacted by COVID–19 to historically disadvantaged borrowers, and to minorities that have significant unmet capital or financial services needs.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Documentation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In the case of an applicant that is certified as a community development financial institution as of <date date="2020-12-27">December 27, 2020</date>, for purposes of subparagraph (A)(i), the Secretary may rely on documentation submitted by the applicant to the Fund as part of certification compliance reporting.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Incentives to increase lending and provide affordable credit</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Issuance and purchase of preferred stock</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">An eligible institution that the Secretary approves for participation in the Program may issue to the Secretary, and the Secretary may purchase from such institution, preferred stock that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> provides that the preferred stock will—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> be repaid not later than the end of the 10-year period beginning on the date of the capital investment under the Program; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> at the end of such 10-year period, be subject to such additional terms as the Secretary shall prescribe, which shall include a requirement that the stock shall carry the highest dividend or interest rate payable; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> provides that the term and condition described under clause (i) shall not apply if the application of that term and condition would adversely affect the capital treatment of the stock under current or successor applicable capital provisions compared to a capital instrument with identical terms other than the term and condition described under clause (i).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Alternative financial instruments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">If the Secretary determines that an institution cannot feasibly issue preferred stock as provided under subparagraph (A), such institution may issue to the Secretary, and the Secretary may purchase from such institution, a subordinated debt instrument whose terms are, to the extent possible, consistent with requirements under the Program applicable to the terms of preferred stock issued by institutions participating in the Program, with such adjustments as the Secretary determines appropriate, including by taking into account the tax treatment of payments made with respect to securities issued by such eligible institution.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements on preferred stock and other financial instrument</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Any financial instrument issued to the Secretary by a low- and moderate-income community financial institution under the Program shall provide the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> No dividends, interest or other similar required payments shall have a rate exceeding 2 percent per annum for the first 10 years.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> The annual required payment rate of dividends, interest, or other similar payments of a low- and moderate-income community financial institution shall be adjusted downward as follows, based on lending by the institution during the most recent annual period compared to lending by the institution during the annual period ending on <date date="2020-09-30">September 30, 2020</date>:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> No dividends, interest, or other similar payments shall be due within the first 24-month period after the capital investment by the Secretary.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> If the amount of lending by the institution within minority, rural, and urban low-income and underserved communities and to low- and moderate-income borrowers has increased in amount between 200 percent and 400 percent of the amount of the capital investment, the annual payment rate shall not exceed 1.25 percent per annum.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> If the amount of lending by the institution within minority, rural, and urban low-income and underserved communities and to low- and moderate-income borrowers has increased by more than 400 percent of the capital investment, the annual payment rate shall not exceed 0.5 percent per annum.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contingency of payments based on certain financial criteria</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deferral</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Any annual payments under this section shall be deferred in any quarter or payment period if any of the following is true:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The low- and moderate-income community institution fails to meet the Tier 1 capital ratio or similar ratio as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The low- and moderate-income community financial institution fails to achieve positive net income for the quarter or payment period.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> The low- and moderate-income community financial institution determines that the payment would be detrimental to the financial health of the institution and the Chief Executive Officer and Chief Financial Officer of the institution provide written notice, in a form reasonably satisfactory to the Secretary, of such determination and the basis thereof.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Testing during next payment period</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Any annual payment that is deferred under this section shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> be tested against the metrics described in subparagraph (A) at the beginning of the next payment period; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> continue to be deferred until the metrics described in that subparagraph are no longer applicable.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements in connection with failure to satisfy program goals</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any financial instrument issued to the Secretary by a low- and moderate-income community financial institution under the Program may include such additional terms and conditions as the Secretary determines may be appropriate to provide the holders with rights in the event that such institution fails to satisfy applicable requirements under the Program or to protect the interests of the Federal Government.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Restrictions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Each low- and moderate-income community financial institution may only issue financial instruments or senior preferred stock under this subsection with an aggregate principal amount (or comparable amount) that is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> not more than $250,000,000; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> not more than 7.5 percent of total assets for an institution with assets of more than $2,000,000,000;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> not more than 15 percent of total assets for an institution with assets of not less than $500,000,000 and not more than $2,000,000,000; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> not more than 22.5 percent of total assets for an institution with assets of less than $500,000,000.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Set-asides</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Of the amounts made available under subsection (c)(2), not less than $4,000,000,000 shall be made available for eligible institutions with total assets of not more than $2,000,000,000 that timely apply to receive a capital investment under the Program, of which not less than $2,000,000,000 shall be made available for eligible institutions with total assets of less than $500,000,000 that timely apply to receive a capital investment under the Program.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Holding of instruments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Holding any instrument of a low- and moderate-income community financial institution described in paragraph (1) shall not give the Secretary or any successor that owns the instrument any rights over the management of the institution in the ordinary course of business.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sale of interest</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">With respect to a capital investment made into a low- and moderate-income community financial institution under this section, the Secretary—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> prior to any sale of such capital investment to a third party, shall provide the low- and moderate-income community financial institution a right of first refusal to buy back the investment under terms that do not exceed a value as determined by an independent third party;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> shall not sell more than 25 percent of the outstanding equity interests of any institution to a single third party without the consent of such institution, which may not be unreasonably withheld; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> with the permission of the institution, may transfer or sell the interest of the Secretary in the capital investment for no consideration or for a de minimis amount to a mission aligned nonprofit affiliate of an applicant that is an insured community development financial institution.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Calculation of ownership for minority depository institutions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The calculation and determination of ownership thresholds for a depository institution to qualify as a minority depository institution shall exclude any dilutive effect of equity investments by the Federal Government, including under the Program or through the Fund.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Repayment incentives</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may establish repayment incentives that will apply to capital investments under the Program in a manner that the Secretary determines to be consistent with the purposes of the Program.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment of capital investments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall seek to establish the terms of preferred stock issued under the Program to enable such preferred stock to receive Tier 1 capital treatment.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Outreach to minority communities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall require low- and moderate-income community financial institutions receiving capital investments under the Program to provide community outreach and communication, where appropriate, describing the availability and application process of receiving loans made possible by the Program through organizations, trade associations, and individuals that represent or work within or are members of minority communities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Restrictions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than the end of the 30-day period beginning on <date date="2020-12-27">December 27, 2020</date>, the Secretary shall issue rules setting restrictions on executive compensation, share buybacks, and dividend payments for recipients of capital investments under the Program.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conflicts of interest</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In this paragraph:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Controlling interest</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The term “controlling interest” means owning, controlling, or holding not less than 20 percent, by vote or value, of the outstanding amount of any class of equity interest in an entity.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Covered entity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The term “covered entity” means an entity in which a covered individual directly or indirectly holds a controlling interest. For the purpose of determining whether an entity is a covered entity, the securities owned, controlled, or held by 2 or more individuals who are related as described in clause (iii)(II) shall be aggregated.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Covered individual</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">The term “covered individual” means—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the President, the Vice President, the head of an Executive department, or a Member of Congress; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the spouse, child, son-in-law, or daughter-in-law, as determined under applicable common law, of an individual described in subclause (i).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iv)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Executive department</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The term “Executive department” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 101 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(v)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Member of Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The term “member of Congress” means a member of the Senate or House of Representatives, a Delegate to the House of Representatives, and the Resident Commissioner from Puerto Rico.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(vi)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Equity interest</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">The term “equity interest” means—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<chapeau> a share in an entity, without regard to whether the share is—</chapeau>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> transferable; or</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> classified as stock or anything similar;</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> a capital or profit interest in a limited liability company or partnership; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> a warrant or right, other than a right to convert, to purchase, sell, or subscribe to a share or interest described in subclause (I) or (II), respectively.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, no covered entity may be eligible for any investment made under the Program.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The principal executive officer and the principal financial officer, or individuals performing similar functions, of an entity seeking to receive an investment made under the Program shall, before that investment is approved, certify to the Secretary and the appropriate Federal banking agency or the National Credit Union Administration, as applicable, that the entity is eligible to receive the investment, including that the entity is not a covered entity.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Ineligibility of certain institutions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An institution shall be ineligible to participate in the Program if such institution is designated in Troubled Condition by the appropriate Federal banking agency or the National Credit Union Administration, as applicable, or is subject to a formal enforcement action with its primary Federal regulator that addresses unsafe or unsound lending practices.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination of investment authority</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The authority to make new capital investments in low- and moderate-income community financial institutions, including commitments to purchase preferred stock or other instruments, provided under the Program shall terminate on the date that is 6 months after the date on which the national emergency concerning the novel coronavirus disease (COVID–19) outbreak declared by the President on <date date="2020-03-13">March 13, 2020</date> under the National Emergencies Act (<ref>50 U.S.C. 1601</ref> et seq.) terminates.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Nothing in this subsection may be construed to limit any other authority of the Secretary not described in paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(k)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Collection of data</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Notwithstanding the Equal Credit Opportunity Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 1691</ref> et seq.)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any low- and moderate-income community financial institution may collect data described in section 701(a)(1) of that Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 1691(a)(1)</ref>) from borrowers and applicants for credit for the sole purpose and exclusive use of monitoring compliance under the plan required under subsection (d)(4); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a low- and moderate-income community financial institution that collects the data described in paragraph (1) shall not be subject to adverse action related to that collection by the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection or any other Federal agency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(l)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deposit of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All funds received by the Secretary in connection with purchases made pursuant this section, including interest payments, dividend payments, and proceeds from the sale of any financial instrument, shall be deposited into the Fund and used to provide financial and technical assistance pursuant to <ref>section 4707 of this title</ref>, except that subsection (e) of that section shall be waived.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(m)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Direct appropriation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is appropriated, out of amounts in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, for fiscal year 2021, $9,000,000,000, to remain available until expended and to be deposited in the Emergency Capital Investment Fund, to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(n)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrative expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Funds appropriated pursuant to subsection (m) may be used for administrative expenses, including the costs of modifying such investments, and reasonable costs of administering the Program of making, holding, managing, and selling the capital investments.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(o)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrative provisions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary may take such actions as the Secretary determines necessary to carry out the authorities in this section, including the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary may use the services of any agency or instrumentality of the United States or component thereof on a reimbursable basis, and any such agency or instrumentality or component thereof is authorized to provide services as requested by the Secretary using all authorities vested in or delegated to that agency, instrumentality, or component.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary may enter into contracts, including contracts for services authorized by <ref>section 3109 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary may designate any bank, savings association, trust company, security broker or dealer, asset manager, or investment adviser as a financial agent of the Federal Government and such institution shall perform all such reasonable duties related to this section as financial agent of the Federal Government as may be required. The Secretary shall have authority to amend existing agreements with financial agents to perform reasonable duties related to this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Secretary may exercise any rights received in connection with any preferred stock or other financial instruments or assets purchased or acquired pursuant to the authorities granted under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The Secretary may manage any assets purchased under this section, including revenues and portfolio risks therefrom.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The Secretary may sell, dispose of, transfer, exchange or enter into securities loans, repurchase transactions, or other financial transactions in regard to, any preferred stock or other financial instrument or asset purchased or acquired under this section, upon terms and conditions and at a price determined by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The Secretary may manage or prohibit conflicts of interest that may arise in connection with the administration and execution of the authorities provided under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> The Secretary may establish and use vehicles to purchase, hold, and sell preferred stock or other financial instruments and issue obligations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> The Secretary may issue such regulations and other guidance as may be necessary or appropriate to define terms or carry out the authorities or purposes of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> The Secretary is authorized to use direct hiring authority to hire employees to administer this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–325, title I, § 104A</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 116–260, div. N, title V, § 522(a)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 2079</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4704.</num>
<heading> Applications for assistance</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Form and procedures</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An application for assistance under this subchapter shall be submitted in such form and in accordance with such procedures as the Fund shall establish.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Minimum requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except as provided in sections 4705 and 4712 of this title, the Fund shall require an application—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to establish that the applicant is, or will be, a community development financial institution;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> to include a comprehensive strategic plan for the organization that contains—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a business plan of not less than 5 years in duration that demonstrates that the applicant will be properly managed and will have the capacity to operate as a community development financial institution that will not be dependent upon assistance from the Fund for continued viability;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an analysis of the needs of the investment area or targeted population and a strategy for how the applicant will attempt to meet those needs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a plan to coordinate use of assistance from the Fund with existing Federal, State, local, and tribal government assistance programs, and private sector financial services;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> an explanation of how the proposed activities of the applicant are consistent with existing economic, community, and housing development plans adopted by or applicable to an investment area or targeted population; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> a description of how the applicant will coordinate with community organizations and financial institutions which will provide equity investments, loans, secondary markets, or other services to investment areas or targeted populations;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to include a detailed description of the applicant’s plans and likely sources of funds to match the amount of assistance requested from the Fund;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> in the case of an applicant that has previously received assistance under this subchapter, to demonstrate that the applicant—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> has substantially met its performance goals and otherwise carried out its responsibilities under this subchapter and the assistance agreement; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> will expand its operations into a new investment area or serve a new targeted population, offer more products or services, or increase the volume of its business;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> in the case of an applicant with a prior history of serving investment areas or targeted populations, to demonstrate that the applicant—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> has a record of success in serving investment areas or targeted populations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> will expand its operations into a new investment area or to serve a new targeted population, offer more products or services, or increase the volume of its current business; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> to include such other information as the Fund deems appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Preapplication outreach program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Fund shall provide an outreach program to identify and provide information to potential applicants and may provide technical assistance to potential applicants, but shall not assist in the preparation of any application.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–325, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1994-09-23">Sept. 23, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2170</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4705.</num>
<heading> Community partnerships</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An application for assistance may be filed jointly by a community development financial institution and a community partner to carry out a community partnership.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Fund shall require a community partnership application—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to meet the minimum requirements established for community development financial institutions under <ref>section 4704(b) of this title</ref>, except that the criteria specified in paragraphs (1) and (2)(A) of <ref>section 4704(b) of this title</ref> shall not apply to the community partner;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to describe how each coapplicant will participate in carrying out the community partnership and how the partnership will enhance activities serving the investment area or targeted population; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to demonstrate that the community partnership activities are consistent with the strategic plan submitted by the community development financial institution coapplicant.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Selection criteria</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Fund shall consider a community partnership application based on—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the community development financial institution coapplicant—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> meeting the minimum selection criteria described in <ref>section 4704 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> satisfying the selection criteria of <ref>section 4706 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the extent to which the community partner coapplicant will participate in carrying out the partnership;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the extent to which the community partnership will enhance the likelihood of success of the community development financial institution coapplicant’s strategic plan; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the extent to which service to the investment area or targeted population will be better performed by a partnership as opposed to the individual community development financial institution coapplicant.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on distribution of assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Assistance provided upon approval of an application under this section shall be distributed only to the community development financial institution coapplicant, and shall not be used to fund any activities carried out directly by the community partner or an affiliate or subsidiary thereof.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other requirements and limitations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All other requirements and limitations imposed by this subchapter on a community development financial institution assisted under this subchapter shall apply (in the manner that the Fund determines to be appropriate) to assistance provided to carry out community partnerships. The Fund may establish additional guidelines and restrictions on the use of Federal funds to carry out community partnerships.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–325, title I, § 106</ref>, <date date="1994-09-23">Sept. 23, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2171</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4706.</num>
<heading> Selection of institutions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Selection criteria</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except as provided in <ref>section 4712 of this title</ref>, the Fund shall, in its sole discretion, select community development financial institution applicants meeting the requirements of <ref>section 4704 of this title</ref> for assistance based on—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the likelihood of success of the applicant in meeting the goals of its comprehensive strategic plan;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the experience and background of the management team;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the extent of need for equity investments, loans, and development services within the investment areas or targeted populations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the extent of economic distress within the investment areas or the extent of need within the targeted populations, as those factors are measured by objective criteria;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the extent to which the applicant will concentrate its activities on serving its investment areas or targeted populations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the amount of firm commitments to meet or exceed the matching requirements and the likely success of the plan for raising the balance of the match;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the extent to which the matching funds are derived from private sources;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> the extent to which the proposed activities will expand economic opportunities within the investment areas or the targeted populations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> whether the applicant is, or will become, an insured community development financial institution;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> the extent of support from the investment areas or targeted populations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> the extent to which the applicant is, or will be, community-owned or community-governed;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> the extent to which the applicant will increase its resources through coordination with other institutions or participation in a secondary market;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> in the case of an applicant with a prior history of serving investment areas or targeted populations, the extent of success in serving them; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> other factors deemed to be appropriate by the Fund.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Geographic diversity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In selecting applicants for assistance, the Fund shall seek to fund a geographically diverse group of applicants, which shall include applicants from metropolitan, nonmetropolitan, and rural areas.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–325, title I, § 107</ref>, <date date="1994-09-23">Sept. 23, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2172</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4707.</num>
<heading> Assistance provided by Fund</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Forms of assistance</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Fund may provide—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> financial assistance through equity investments, deposits, credit union shares, loans, and grants; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> technical assistance—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> directly;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> through grants; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> by contracting with organizations that possess expertise in community development finance, without regard to whether the organizations receive or are eligible to receive assistance under this subchapter.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Equity investments</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on equity investments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Fund shall not own more than 50 percent of the equity of a community development financial institution and may not control the operations of such institution. The Fund may hold only transferable, nonvoting equity investments in the institution. Such equity investments may provide for convertibility to voting stock upon transfer by the Fund.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fund deemed not to control</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Fund shall not be deemed to control a community development financial institution by reason of any assistance provided under this subchapter for the purpose of any other applicable law to the extent that the Fund complies with subparagraph (A). Nothing in this subparagraph shall affect the application of any Federal tax law.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deposits</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Deposits made pursuant to this section in an insured community development financial institution shall not be subject to any requirement for collateral or security.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations on obligations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Direct loan obligations may be incurred by the Fund only to the extent that appropriations of budget authority to cover their cost, as defined in <ref>section 661a(5) of title 2</ref>, are made in advance.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Uses of financial assistance</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Financial assistance made available under this subchapter may be used by assisted community development financial institutions to serve investment areas or targeted populations by developing or supporting—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> commercial facilities that promote revitalization, community stability, or job creation or retention;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> businesses that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> provide jobs for low-income people or are owned by low-income people; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> enhance the availability of products and services to low-income people;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> community facilities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the provision of basic financial services;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<chapeau> housing that is principally affordable to low-income people, except that assistance used to facilitate homeownership shall only be used for services and lending products—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> that serve low-income people; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> that—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> are not provided by other lenders in the area; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> complement the services and lending products provided by other lenders that serve the investment area or targeted population; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> other businesses and activities deemed appropriate by the Fund.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">No assistance made available under this subchapter may be expended by a community development financial institution (or an organization receiving assistance under <ref>section 4712 of this title</ref>) to pay any person to influence or attempt to influence any agency, elected official, officer, or employee of a State or local government in connection with the making, award, extension, continuation, renewal, amendment, or modification of any State or local government contract, grant, loan, or cooperative agreement (as such terms are defined in <ref>section 1352 of title 31</ref>).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Uses of technical assistance</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Types of activities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Technical assistance may be used for activities that enhance the capacity of a community development financial institution, such as training of management and other personnel and development of programs and investment or loan products.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability of technical assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Fund may provide technical assistance, regardless of whether or not the recipient also receives financial assistance under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amount of assistance</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (2), the Fund may provide not more than $5,000,000 of assistance, in the aggregate, during any 3-year period to any 1 community development financial institution and its subsidiaries and affiliates.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Fund may provide not more than $3,750,000 of assistance in addition to the amount specified in paragraph (1) during the same 3-year period to an existing community development financial institution that proposes to establish a subsidiary or affiliate for the purpose of serving an investment area or targeted population outside of any State and outside of any metropolitan area presently served by the institution, if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> the subsidiary or affiliate—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> would be a community development financial institution; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> independently—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> meets the selection criteria described in <ref>section 4704 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> satisfies the selection criteria of <ref>section 4706 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> no other application for assistance to serve the investment area or targeted population has been submitted to the Administrator within a reasonable period of time preceding the date of receipt of the application at issue.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Timing of assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Assistance may be provided as described in paragraphs (1) and (2) in a lump sum or over a period of time, as determined by the Fund.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Matching requirements</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Assistance other than technical assistance shall be matched with funds from sources other than the Federal Government on the basis of not less than one dollar for each dollar provided by the Fund. Such matching funds shall be at least comparable in form and value to assistance provided by the Fund. The Fund shall provide no assistance (other than technical assistance) until a community development financial institution has secured firm commitments for the matching funds required.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In the case of an applicant with severe constraints on available sources of matching funds, the Fund may permit an applicant to comply with the matching requirements of paragraph (1) by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> reducing such matching requirement by 50 percent; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> permitting an applicant to provide matching funds in a form to be determined at the discretion of the Fund, if such applicant—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> has total assets of less than $100,000;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> serves nonmetropolitan or rural areas; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> is not requesting more than $25,000 in assistance.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not more than 25 percent of the total funds disbursed in any fiscal year by the Fund may be matched as authorized under paragraph (2).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Construction of “Federal Government funds”</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, notwithstanding section 105(a)(9) of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 [<ref>42 U.S.C. 5305(a)(9)</ref>], funds provided pursuant to such Act shall be considered to be Federal Government funds.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Terms and conditions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Soundness of unregulated institutions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Fund shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> ensure, to the maximum extent practicable, that each community development financial institution (other than an insured community development financial institution or depository institution holding company) assisted under this subchapter is financially and managerially sound and maintains appropriate internal controls;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> require such institution to submit, not less than once during each 18-month period, a statement of financial condition audited by an independent certified public accountant as part of the report required by <ref>section 4714(e)(1) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> require that all assistance granted under this section is used by the community development financial institution or community development partnership in a manner consistent with the purposes of this subchapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistance agreement</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Before providing any assistance under this subchapter, the Fund and each community development financial institution to be assisted shall enter into an agreement that requires the institution to comply with performance goals and abide by other terms and conditions pertinent to assistance received under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Performance goals</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Performance goals shall be negotiated between the Fund and each community development financial institution receiving assistance based upon the strategic plan submitted pursuant to <ref>section 4704(b)(2) of this title</ref>. Such goals may be modified with the consent of the parties, or as provided in subparagraph (C). Performance goals for insured community development financial institutions shall be determined in consultation with the appropriate Federal banking agency.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sanctions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The agreement shall provide that, in the event of fraud, mismanagement, noncompliance with this subchapter, or noncompliance with the terms of the agreement, the Fund, in its discretion, may—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> require changes to the performance goals imposed pursuant to subparagraph (B);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> require changes to the strategic plan submitted pursuant to <ref>section 4704(b)(2) of this title</ref>;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> revoke approval of the application;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> reduce or terminate assistance;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> require repayment of assistance;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> bar an applicant from reapplying for assistance from the Fund; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> take such other actions as the Fund deems appropriate.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation with tribal governments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In reviewing the performance of any assisted community development financial institution, the investment area of which includes an Indian reservation, or the targeted population of which includes an Indian tribe, the Fund shall consult with, and seek input from, any appropriate tribal government.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority to sell equity investments and loans</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Fund may, at any time, sell its equity investments and loans, but the Fund shall retain the power to enforce limitations on assistance entered into in accordance with the requirements of this subchapter until the performance goals related to the investment or loan have been met.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> No authority to limit supervision and regulation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this subchapter shall affect any authority of the appropriate Federal banking agency to supervise and regulate any institution or company.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–325, title I, § 108</ref>, <date date="1994-09-23">Sept. 23, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2172</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4708.</num>
<heading> Training</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Fund may operate a training program to increase the capacity and expertise of community development financial institutions and other members of the financial services industry to undertake community development finance activities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program activities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The training program shall provide educational programs to assist community development financial institutions and other members of the financial services industry in developing lending and investment products, underwriting and servicing loans, managing equity investments, and providing development services targeted to areas of economic distress, low-income persons, and persons who lack adequate access to loans and equity investments.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Participation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The training program shall be made available to community development financial institutions and other members of the financial services industry that serve or seek to serve areas of economic distress, low-income persons, and persons who lack adequate access to loans and equity investments.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contracting</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Fund may offer the training program described in this section directly or through a contract with other organizations. The Fund may contract to provide the training program through organizations that possess special expertise in community development, without regard to whether the organizations receive or are eligible to receive assistance under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Fund shall coordinate with other appropriate Federal departments or agencies that operate similar training programs in order to prevent duplicative efforts.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulatory fee for providing training services</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General rule</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Fund may, at the discretion of the Administrator and in accordance with this subsection, assess and collect regulatory fees solely to cover the costs of the Fund in providing training services under a training program operated in accordance with this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Persons subject to fee</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Fees may be assessed under paragraph (1) only on persons who participate in the training program.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on manner of collection</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Fees may be assessed and collected under this subsection only in such manner as may reasonably be expected to result in the collection of an aggregate amount of fees during any fiscal year which does not exceed the aggregate costs of the Fund for such year in providing training services under a training program operated in accordance with this section <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002435">1</ref></p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on amount of fee</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The amount of any fee assessed under this subsection on any person may not exceed the amount which is reasonably based on the proportion of the training services provided under a training program operated in accordance with this section which relate to such person.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–325, title I, § 109</ref>, <date date="1994-09-23">Sept. 23, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2176</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4709.</num>
<heading> Encouragement of private entities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Fund may facilitate the organization of corporations in which the Federal Government has no ownership interest. The purpose of any such entity shall be to assist community development financial institutions in a manner that is complementary to the activities of the Fund under this subchapter. Any such entity shall be managed exclusively by persons not employed by the Federal Government or any agency or instrumentality thereof, or by any State or local government or any agency or instrumentality thereof.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–325, title I, § 110</ref>, <date date="1994-09-23">Sept. 23, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2177</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4710.</num>
<heading> Collection and compilation of information</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Fund shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> collect and compile information pertinent to community development financial institutions that will assist in creating, developing, expanding, and preserving such institutions; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> make such information available to promote the purposes of this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–325, title I, § 111</ref>, <date date="1994-09-23">Sept. 23, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2177</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4711.</num>
<heading> Investment of receipts and proceeds</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of account</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any dividends on equity investments and proceeds from the disposition of investments, deposits, or credit union shares that are received by the Fund as a result of assistance provided pursuant to section 4707 or 4712 of this title, and any fees received pursuant to <ref>section 4708(f) of this title</ref> shall be deposited and accredited to an account of the Fund in the United States Treasury (hereafter in this section referred to as “the account”) established to carry out the purpose of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Investments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon request of the Administrator, the Secretary of the Treasury shall invest amounts deposited in the account in public debt securities with maturities suitable to the needs of the Fund, as determined by the Administrator, and bearing interest at rates determined by the Secretary of the Treasury, comparable to current market yields on outstanding marketable obligations of the United States of similar maturities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Amounts deposited into the account and interest earned on such amounts pursuant to this section shall be available to the Fund until expended.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–325, title I, § 112</ref>, <date date="1994-09-23">Sept. 23, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2177</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4712.</num>
<heading> Capitalization assistance to enhance liquidity</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistance</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Fund may provide assistance for the purpose of providing capital to organizations to purchase loans or otherwise enhance the liquidity of community development financial institutions, if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the primary purpose of such organizations is to promote community development; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> any assistance received is matched with funds—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> from sources other than the Federal Government;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> on the basis of not less than one dollar for each dollar provided by the Fund; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> that are comparable in form and value to the assistance provided by the Fund.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on other assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">An organization that receives assistance under this section may not receive other financial or technical assistance under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Construction of Federal Government funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, notwithstanding section 105(a)(9) of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 [<ref>42 U.S.C. 5305(a)(9)</ref>], funds provided pursuant to such Act shall be considered to be Federal Government funds.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Selection</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The selection of organizations to receive assistance under this section shall be at the discretion of the Fund and in accordance with criteria established by the Fund. In establishing such criteria, the Fund shall take into account the criteria contained in sections 4704(b) and 4706 of this title, as appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amount of assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Fund may provide a total of not more than $5,000,000 of assistance to an organization or its subsidiaries or affiliates under this section during any 3-year period. Assistance may be provided in a lump sum or over a period of time, as determined by the Fund.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Audit and report requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Organizations that receive assistance from the Fund in accordance with this section shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> submit to the Fund, not less than once in every 18-month period, financial statements audited by an independent certified public accountant, as part of the report required by paragraph (2);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> submit an annual report on its activities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> keep such records as may be necessary to disclose the manner in which any assistance under this section is used.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations on liability</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Liability of Fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The liability of the Fund and the United States Government arising out of the provision of assistance to any organization in accordance with this section shall be limited to the amount of such assistance. The Fund shall be exempt from any assessments and any other liabilities that may be imposed on controlling or principal shareholders by any Federal law or the law of any State, or territory. Nothing in this paragraph shall affect the application of Federal tax law.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Liability of Government</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">This section does not oblige the Federal Government, either directly or indirectly, to provide any funds to any organization assisted pursuant to this section, or to honor, reimburse, or otherwise guarantee any obligation or liability of such an organization. This section shall not be construed to imply that any such organization or any obligations or securities of any such organization are backed by the full faith and credit of the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of proceeds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any proceeds from the sale of loans by an organization assisted under this section shall be used by the seller for community development purposes.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–325, title I, § 113</ref>, <date date="1994-09-23">Sept. 23, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2178</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4713.</num>
<heading> Incentives for depository institution participation</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Function of Administrator</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Of any funds appropriated pursuant to the authorization in <ref>section 4718(a) of this title</ref>, the funds made available for use in carrying out this section in accordance with <ref>section 4718(a)(4) of this title</ref> shall be administered by the Administrator of the Fund, in consultation with—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Federal banking agencies (as defined in section 3 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act [<ref>12 U.S.C. 1813</ref>]) and the National Credit Union Administration;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the individuals named pursuant to clauses (ii) and (iv) of <ref>section 4703(d)(2)(G) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any other representatives of insured depository institutions or other persons as the Administrator may determine to be appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability of Bank Enterprise Act of 1991</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Subject to subsection (b) and the consultation requirement of paragraph (1)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> section 233 of the Bank Enterprise Act of 1991 [<ref>12 U.S.C. 1834a</ref>] shall be applicable to the Administrator, for purposes of this section, in the same manner and to the same extent that such section is applicable to the Community Enterprise Assessment Credit Board;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> the Administrator shall, for purposes of carrying out this section and section 233 of the Bank Enterprise Act of 1991 [<ref>12 U.S.C. 1834a</ref>]—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> have all powers and rights of the Community Enterprise Assessment Credit Board under section 233 of the Bank Enterprise Act of 1991 to administer and enforce any provision of such section 233 which is applicable to the Administrator under this section; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> shall be subject to the same duties and restrictions imposed on the Community Enterprise Assessment Credit Board; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> the Administrator shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> have all powers and rights of an appropriate Federal banking agency under section 233(b)(2) of the Bank Enterprise Act of 1991 [<ref>12 U.S.C. 1834a(b)(2)</ref>] to approve or disapprove the designation of qualified distressed communities for purposes of this section and provide information and assistance with respect to any such designation; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> shall be subject to the same duties imposed on the appropriate Federal banking agencies under such section 233(b)(2).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Awards</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Administrator shall determine the amount of assessment credits, and shall make awards of those credits.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations and guidelines</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Administrator may prescribe such regulations and issue such guidelines as the Administrator determines to be appropriate to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exceptions to applicability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding paragraphs (1) through (4) of this subsection, subsections (a)(1) and (e)(2) of section 233 of the Bank Enterprise Act of 1991 [<ref>12 U.S.C. 1834a(a)(1)</ref>, (e)(2)], and any other provision of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act [<ref>12 U.S.C. 1811</ref> et seq.] relating to the Bank Enterprise Act of 1991, do not apply to the Administrator for purposes of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Provisions relating to administration of this section</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> New lifeline accounts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In applying section 233 of the Bank Enterprise Act of 1991 [<ref>12 U.S.C. 1834a</ref>] for purposes of this section, the Administrator shall treat the provision of new lifeline accounts by an insured depository institution as an activity which is qualified to be taken into account under section 233(a)(2)(A) of such Act.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determination of assessment credit</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For the purpose of this subchapter, section 233(a)(3) of the Bank Enterprise Act of 1991 (<ref>12 U.S.C. 1834a(a)(3)</ref>) shall be applied by substituting the following text:</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">“(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amount of assessment credit</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">“The amount of an assessment credit which may be awarded to an insured depository institution to carry out the qualified activities of the institution or of the subsidiaries of the institution pursuant to this section for any semiannual period shall be equal to the sum of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>“(A)</num>
<chapeau> with respect to qualifying activities described in paragraph (2)(A), the amount which is equal to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>“(i)</num>
<content> 5 percent of the sum of the amounts determined under such subparagraph, in the case of an institution which is not a community development financial institution; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>“(ii)</num>
<content> 15 percent of the sum of the amounts determined under such subparagraph, in the case of an institution which is a community development financial institution; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>“(B)</num>
<content> with respect to qualifying activities described in paragraph (2)(C), 15 percent of the amounts determined under such subparagraph.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adjustment of percentage</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Section 233(a)(5) of the Bank Enterprise Act of 1991 [<ref>12 U.S.C. 1834a(a)(5)</ref>] shall be applied for purposes of this section by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> substituting “institutions which are community development financial institutions” for “institutions which meet the community development organization requirements under section 234 [<ref>12 U.S.C. 1834b</ref>]”; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> substituting “institutions which are not community development financial institutions” for “institutions which do not meet such requirements”.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Designation of QDC</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Section 233(b)(2) of the Bank Enterprise Act of 1991 [<ref>12 U.S.C. 1834a(b)(2)</ref>] shall be applied for purposes of this section without regard to subparagraph (A)(ii) of such section 233(b)(2).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Operation on annual basis</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Administrator may, in the Administrator’s discretion, apply section 233 of the Bank Enterprise Act of 1991 for purposes of this section by providing community enterprise assessment credits with respect to annual periods rather than semiannual periods.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Outreach</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Administrator shall ensure that information about the Bank Enterprise Act of 1991 under this section is widely disseminated to all interested parties.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Qualified activities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For the purpose of this subchapter, section 233(a)(2)(A) of the Bank Enterprise Act of 1991 shall be applied by inserting “of the increase” after “the amount”.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–325, title I, § 114</ref>, <date date="1994-09-23">Sept. 23, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2179</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4713a.</num>
<heading> Guarantees for bonds and notes issued for community or economic development purposes</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section, the following definitions shall apply:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible community development financial institution</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “eligible community development financial institution” means a community development financial institution (as described in section 1805.201 of title 12, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor thereto) certified by the Secretary that has applied to a qualified issuer for, or been granted by a qualified issuer, a loan under the Program.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible community or economic development purpose</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “eligible community or economic development purpose”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> means any purpose described in <ref>section 4707(b) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> includes the provision of community or economic development in low-income or underserved rural areas.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Guarantee</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “guarantee” means a written agreement between the Secretary and a qualified issuer (or trustee), pursuant to which the Secretary ensures repayment of the verifiable losses of principal, interest, and call premium, if any, on notes or bonds issued by a qualified issuer to finance or refinance loans to eligible community development financial institutions.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Loan</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “loan” means any credit instrument that is extended under the Program for any eligible community or economic development purpose.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Master servicer</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “master servicer” means any entity approved by the Secretary in accordance with subparagraph (B) to oversee the activities of servicers, as provided in subsection (f)(4).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Approval criteria for master servicers</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Secretary shall approve or deny any application to become a master servicer under the Program not later than 90 days after the date on which all required information is submitted to the Secretary, based on the capacity and experience of the applicant in—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> loan administration, servicing, and loan monitoring;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> managing regional or national loan intake, processing, or servicing operational systems and infrastructure;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> managing regional or national originator communication systems and infrastructure;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> developing and implementing training and other risk management strategies on a regional or national basis; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> compliance monitoring, investor relations, and reporting.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Program” means the guarantee Program for bonds and notes issued for eligible community or economic development purposes established under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program administrator</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Program administrator” means an entity designated by the issuer to perform administrative duties, as provided in subsection (f)(2).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Qualified issuer</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “qualified issuer” means a community development financial institution (or any entity designated to issue notes or bonds on behalf of such community development financial institution) that meets the qualification requirements of this paragraph.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Approval criteria for qualified issuers</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The Secretary shall approve a qualified issuer for a guarantee under the Program in accordance with the requirements of this paragraph, and such additional requirements as the Secretary may establish, by regulation.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Terms and qualifications</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">A qualified issuer shall—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> have appropriate expertise, capacity, and experience, or otherwise be qualified to make loans for eligible community or economic development purposes;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<chapeau> provide to the Secretary—</chapeau>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> an acceptable statement of the proposed sources and uses of the funds; and</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> a capital distribution plan that meets the requirements of subsection (c)(1); and</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> certify to the Secretary that the bonds or notes to be guaranteed are to be used for eligible community or economic development purposes.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Department opinion; timing</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Department opinion</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Not later than 30 days after the date of a request by a qualified issuer for approval of a guarantee under the Program, the Secretary shall provide an opinion regarding compliance by the issuer with the requirements of the Program under this section.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Timing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The Secretary shall approve or deny a guarantee under this section after consideration of the opinion provided to the Secretary under clause (i), and in no case later than 90 days after receipt of all required information by the Secretary with respect to a request for such guarantee.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of the Treasury.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(10)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Servicer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “servicer” means an entity designated by the issuer to perform various servicing duties, as provided in subsection (f)(3).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Guarantees authorized</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall guarantee payments on bonds or notes issued by any qualified issuer, if the proceeds of the bonds or notes are used in accordance with this section to make loans to eligible community development financial institutions—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> for eligible community or economic development purposes; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to refinance loans or notes issued for such purposes.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General program requirements</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A capital distribution plan meets the requirements of this subsection, if not less than 90 percent of the principal amount of guaranteed bonds or notes (other than costs of issuance fees) are used to make loans for any eligible community or economic development purpose, measured annually, beginning at the end of the 1-year period beginning on the issuance date of such guaranteed bonds or notes.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Relending account</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not more than 10 percent of the principal amount of guaranteed bonds or notes, multiplied by an amount equal to the outstanding principal balance of issued notes or bonds, minus the risk-share pool amount under subsection (d), may be held in a relending account and may be made available for new eligible community or economic development purposes.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations on unpaid principal balances</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The proceeds of guaranteed bonds or notes under the Program may not be used to pay fees (other than costs of issuance fees), and shall be held in—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> community or economic development loans;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a relending account, to the extent authorized under paragraph (2); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a risk-share pool established under subsection (d).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Repayment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If a qualified issuer fails to meet the requirements of paragraph (1) by the end of the 90-day period beginning at the end of the annual measurement period, repayment shall be made on that portion of bonds or notes necessary to bring the bonds or notes that remain outstanding after such repayment into compliance with the 90 percent requirement of paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibited uses</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary shall, by regulation—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> prohibit, as appropriate, certain uses of amounts from the guarantee of a bond or note under the Program, including the use of such funds for political activities, lobbying, outreach, counseling services, or travel expenses; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> provide that the guarantee of a bond or note under the Program may not be used for salaries or other administrative costs of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the qualified issuer; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any recipient of amounts from the guarantee of a bond or note.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Risk-share pool</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each qualified issuer shall, during the term of a guarantee provided under the Program, establish a risk-share pool, capitalized by contributions from eligible community development financial institution participants an amount equal to 3 percent of the guaranteed amount outstanding on the subject notes and bonds.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Guarantees</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A guarantee issued under the Program shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> be for the full amount of a bond or note, including the amount of principal, interest, and call premiums;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> be fully assignable and transferable to the capital market, on terms and conditions that are consistent with comparable Government-guaranteed bonds, and satisfactory to the Secretary;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> represent the full faith and credit of the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> not exceed 30 years.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual number of guarantees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary shall issue not more than 10 guarantees in any calendar year under the Program.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Guarantee amount</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary may not guarantee any amount under the Program equal to less than $100,000,000, but the total of all such guarantees in any fiscal year may not exceed $1,000,000,000.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Servicing of transactions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To maximize efficiencies and minimize cost and interest rates, loans made under this section may be serviced by qualified Program administrators, bond servicers, and a master servicer.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties of Program administrator</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The duties of a Program administrator shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> approving and qualifying eligible community development financial institution applications for participation in the Program;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> compliance monitoring;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> bond packaging in connection with the Program; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> all other duties and related services that are customarily expected of a Program administrator.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties of servicer</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The duties of a servicer shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> billing and collecting loan payments;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> initiating collection activities on past-due loans;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> transferring loan payments to the master servicing accounts;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> loan administration and servicing;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> systematic and timely reporting of loan performance through remittance and servicing reports;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> proper measurement of annual outstanding loan requirements; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> all other duties and related services that are customarily expected of servicers.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties of master servicer</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The duties of a master servicer shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> tracking the movement of funds between the accounts of the master servicer and any other servicer;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> ensuring orderly receipt of the monthly remittance and servicing reports of the servicer;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> monitoring the collection comments and foreclosure actions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> aggregating the reporting and distribution of funds to trustees and investors;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> removing and replacing a servicer, as necessary;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> loan administration and servicing;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> systematic and timely reporting of loan performance compiled from all bond servicers’ reports;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> proper distribution of funds to investors; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> all other duties and related services that are customarily expected of a master servicer.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fees</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A qualified issuer that receives a guarantee issued under this section on a bond or note shall pay a fee to the Secretary, in an amount equal to 10 basis points of the amount of the unpaid principal of the bond or note guaranteed.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A qualified issuer shall pay the fee required under this subsection on an annual basis.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of fees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Fees collected by the Secretary under this subsection shall be used to reimburse the Department of the Treasury for any administrative costs incurred by the Department in implementing the Program established under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary, such sums as are necessary to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of fees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To the extent that the amount of funds appropriated for a fiscal year under paragraph (1) are not sufficient to carry out this section, the Secretary may use the fees collected under subsection (g) for the cost of providing guarantees of bonds and notes under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Investment in guaranteed bonds ineligible for Community Reinvestment Act purposes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any investment by a financial institution in bonds or notes guaranteed under the Program shall not be taken into account in assessing the record of such institution for purposes of the Community Reinvestment Act of 1977 (<ref>12 U.S.C. 2901</ref> [et seq.]).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administration</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2010-09-27">September 27, 2010</date>, the Secretary shall promulgate regulations to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 2 years after <date date="2010-09-27">September 27, 2010</date>, the Secretary shall implement this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(k)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section is repealed, and the authority provided under this section shall terminate, on <date date="2014-09-30">September 30, 2014</date>.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002436">1</ref></p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–325, title I, § 114A</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 111–240, title I, § 1134</ref>, <date date="2010-09-27">Sept. 27, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2515</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4714.</num>
<heading> Recordkeeping</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A community development financial institution receiving assistance from the Fund shall keep such records, for such periods as may be prescribed by the Fund and necessary to disclose the manner in which any assistance under this subchapter is used and to demonstrate compliance with the requirements of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> User profile information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Fund shall require each community development financial institution or other organization receiving assistance from the Fund to compile such data, as is determined to be appropriate by the Fund, on the gender, race, ethnicity, national origin, or other pertinent information concerning individuals that utilize the services of the assisted institution to ensure that targeted populations and low-income residents of investment areas are adequately served.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Access to records</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Fund shall have access on demand, for the purpose of determining compliance with this subchapter, to any records of a community development financial institution or other organization that receives assistance from the Fund.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not less than annually, the Fund shall review the progress of each assisted community development financial institution in carrying out its strategic plan, meeting its performance goals, and satisfying the terms and conditions of its assistance agreement.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reporting</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Fund shall require each community development financial institution receiving assistance under this subchapter to submit an annual report to the Fund on its activities, its financial condition, and its success in meeting performance goals, in satisfying the terms and conditions of its assistance agreement, and in complying with other requirements of this subchapter, in such form and manner as the Fund shall specify.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability of reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Fund, after deleting or redacting any material as appropriate to protect privacy or proprietary interests, shall make such reports submitted under paragraph (1) available for public inspection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–325, title I, § 115</ref>, <date date="1994-09-23">Sept. 23, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2184</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4715.</num>
<heading> Special provisions with respect to institutions that are supervised by Federal banking agencies</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation with appropriate agencies</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Fund shall consult with and consider the views of the appropriate Federal banking agency prior to providing assistance under this subchapter to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an insured community development financial institution;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any community development financial institution that is examined by or subject to the reporting requirements of an appropriate Federal banking agency; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> any community development financial institution that has as its community partner an institution that is examined by or subject to the reporting requirements of an appropriate Federal banking agency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requests for information, reports, or records</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (4), notwithstanding any other provisions of this subchapter, prior to directly requesting information from or imposing reporting or recordkeeping requirements on an insured community development financial institution or other institution that is examined by or subject to the reporting requirements of an appropriate Federal banking agency, the Fund shall consult with the appropriate Federal banking agency to determine if the information requested is available from or may be obtained by such agency in the form, format, or detail required by the Fund.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Timing of response from appropriate Federal banking agency</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the information, reports, or records requested by the Fund pursuant to paragraph (1) are not provided by the appropriate Federal banking agency in less than 15 calendar days after the date on which the material is requested, the Fund may request the information from or impose the recordkeeping or reporting requirements directly on such institutions with notice to the appropriate Federal banking agency.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Elimination of duplicative information and reporting requirements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Fund shall use any information provided the appropriate Federal banking agency under this section to the extent practicable to eliminate duplicative requests for information and reports from, and recordkeeping by an insured community development financial institution or other institution that is examined by or subject to the reporting requirements of an appropriate Federal banking agency.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding paragraphs (1) and (2), the Fund may require an insured community development financial institution or other institution that is examined by or subject to the reporting requirements of an appropriate Federal banking agency to provide information with respect to the institution’s implementation of its strategic plan or compliance with the terms of its assistance agreement under this subchapter, after providing notice to the appropriate Federal banking agency.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exclusion for examination reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall be construed to permit the Fund to require an insured community development financial institution or other institution that is examined by or subject to the reporting requirements of an appropriate Federal banking agency, to obtain, maintain, or furnish an examination report of any appropriate Federal banking agency or records contained in or related to such a report.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sharing of information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Fund and the appropriate Federal banking agency shall promptly notify each other of material concerns about an insured community development financial institution or other institution that is examined by or subject to the reporting requirements of an appropriate Federal banking agency, and share appropriate information relating to such concerns.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disclosure prohibited</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Neither the Fund nor the appropriate Federal banking agency shall disclose confidential information obtained pursuant to this section from any party without the written consent of that party.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Privilege maintained</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Fund, the appropriate Federal banking agency, and any other party providing information under this section shall not be deemed to have waived any privilege applicable to any information or data, or any portion thereof, by providing such information or data to the other party or by permitting such data or information, or any copies or portions thereof, to be used by the other party.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall authorize the Fund or the appropriate Federal banking agency to withhold information from the Congress or prevent it from complying with a request for information from a Federal department or agency in compliance with applicable law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sanctions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Fund shall notify the appropriate Federal banking agency before imposing any sanction pursuant to the authority in <ref>section 4707(f)(2)(C) of this title</ref> on an insured community development financial institution or other institution that is examined by or subject to the reporting requirements of that agency.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Fund shall not impose a sanction referred to in paragraph (1) if the appropriate Federal banking agency, in writing, not later than 30 calendar days after receiving notice from the Fund—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> objects to the proposed sanction;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> determines that the sanction would—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> have a material adverse effect on the safety and soundness of the institution; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> impede or interfere with an enforcement action against that institution by that agency;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> proposes a comparable alternative action; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> specifically explains—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the basis for the determination under subparagraph (B) and, if appropriate, provides documentation to support the determination; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> how the alternative action suggested pursuant to subparagraph (C) would be as effective as the sanction proposed by the Fund in securing compliance with this subchapter and deterring future noncompliance.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Safety and soundness considerations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Fund and each appropriate Federal banking agency shall cooperate and respond to requests from each other and from other appropriate Federal banking agencies in a manner that ensures the safety and soundness of the insured community development financial institution or other institution that is examined by or subject to the reporting requirements of an appropriate Federal banking agency.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–325, title I, § 116</ref>, <date date="1994-09-23">Sept. 23, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2185</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4716.</num>
<heading> Studies and reports; examination and audit</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual report by Fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Fund shall conduct an annual evaluation of the activities carried out by the Fund and the community development financial institutions and other organizations assisted pursuant to this subchapter, and shall submit a report of its findings to the President and the Congress not later than 120 days after the end of each fiscal year of the Fund. The report shall include financial statements audited in accordance with subsection (f).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Optional studies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Fund may conduct such studies as the Fund determines necessary to further the purpose of this subchapter and to facilitate investment in distressed communities. The findings of any studies conducted pursuant to this subsection shall be included in the report required by subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Native American lending study</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Fund shall conduct a study on lending and investment practices on Indian reservations and other land held in trust by the United States. Such study shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> identify barriers to private financing on such lands; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> identify the impact of such barriers on access to capital and credit for Native American populations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 12 months after the date on which the Administrator is appointed, the Fund shall submit a report to the President and the Congress that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> contains the findings of the study conducted under paragraph (1);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> recommends any necessary statutory and regulatory changes to existing Federal programs; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> makes policy recommendations for community development financial institutions, insured depository institutions, secondary market institutions, and other private sector capital institutions to better serve such populations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Investment, governance, and role of Fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Thirty months after the appointment and qualification of the Administrator, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the President and the Congress a study evaluating the structure, governance, and performance of the Fund.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the conduct of the studies required under this section, the Fund shall consult, as appropriate, with the Comptroller of the Currency, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Federal Housing Finance Agency, the Farm Credit Administration, the Director of the Office of Thrift Supervision, the National Credit Union Administration Board, Indian tribal governments, community reinvestment organizations, civil rights organizations, consumer organizations, financial organizations, and such representatives of agencies or other persons, at the discretion of the Fund.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Examination and audit</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The financial statements of the Fund shall be audited in accordance with <ref>section 9105 of title 31</ref>, except that audits required by section 9105(a) of such title shall be performed annually.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–325, title I, § 117</ref>, <date date="1994-09-23">Sept. 23, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2187</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–289, div. A, title II, § 1216(b)</ref>, <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2792</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4717.</num>
<heading> Enforcement</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 180 days after the appointment and qualification of the Administrator, the Fund shall promulgate such regulations as may be necessary to carry out this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations required</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The regulations promulgated under paragraph (1) shall include regulations applicable to community development financial institutions that are not insured depository institutions to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> prevent conflicts of interest on the part of directors, officers, and employees of community development financial institutions as the Fund determines to be appropriate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> establish such standards with respect to loans by a community development financial institution to any director, officer, or employee of such institution as the Fund determines to be appropriate, including loan amount limitations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrative enforcement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The provisions of this subchapter, and regulations prescribed and agreements entered into under this subchapter, shall be enforced under section 8 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act [<ref>12 U.S.C. 1818</ref>] by the appropriate Federal banking agency, in the case of an insured community development financial institution. A violation of this subchapter, or any regulation prescribed under or any agreement entered into under this subchapter, shall be treated as a violation of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act [<ref>12 U.S.C. 1811</ref> et seq.].</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–325, title I, § 119</ref>, <date date="1994-09-23">Sept. 23, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2188</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4718.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fund authorization</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">To carry out this subchapter, there are authorized to be appropriated to the Fund, to remain available until expended—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> $60,000,000 for fiscal year 1995;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> $104,000,000 for fiscal year 1996;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> $107,000,000 for fiscal year 1997; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> $111,000,000 for fiscal year 1998;</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">or such greater sums as may be necessary to carry out this subchapter.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrative expenses</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Of amounts authorized to be appropriated to the Fund pursuant to this section, not more than $5,550,000 may be used by the Fund in each fiscal year to pay the administrative costs and expenses of the Fund. Costs associated with the training program established under <ref>section 4708 of this title</ref> and the technical assistance program established under <ref>section 4707 of this title</ref> shall not be considered to be administrative expenses for purposes of this paragraph.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Calculations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The amounts referred to in paragraphs (3) and (4) shall be calculated after subtracting the amount referred to in subparagraph (A) of this paragraph from the total amount appropriated to the Fund in accordance with paragraph (1) in any fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Capitalization assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not more than 5 percent of the amounts authorized to be appropriated under paragraph (1) may be used as provided in <ref>section 4712 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability for funding <ref>section 4713 of this title</ref></heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">33⅓ percent of the amounts appropriated to the Fund for any fiscal year pursuant to the authorization in paragraph (1) shall be available for use in carrying out <ref>section 4713 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Support of community development financial institutions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Administrator shall allocate funds authorized under this section, to the maximum extent practicable, for the support of community development financial institutions.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Community Development Credit Union Revolving Loan Fund</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated for the purposes of the Community Development Credit Union Revolving Loan Fund—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> $4,000,000 for fiscal year 1995;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> $2,000,000 for fiscal year 1996;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> $2,000,000 for fiscal year 1997; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> $2,000,000 for fiscal year 1998.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Budgetary treatment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Amounts authorized to be appropriated under this section shall be subject to discretionary spending caps, as provided in section 665 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002437">1</ref> of title 2, and therefore shall reduce by an equal amount funds made available for other discretionary spending programs.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–325, title I, § 121</ref>, <date date="1994-09-23">Sept. 23, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2189</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4719.</num>
<heading> Grants to establish loan-loss reserve funds</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes of this section are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to make financial assistance available from the Fund in order to help community development financial institutions defray the costs of operating small dollar loan programs, by providing the amounts necessary for such institutions to establish their own loan loss reserve funds to mitigate some of the losses on such small dollar loan programs; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to encourage community development financial institutions to establish and maintain small dollar loan programs that would help give consumers access to mainstream financial institutions and combat high cost small dollar lending.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grants</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Loan-loss reserve fund grants</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Fund shall make grants to community development financial institutions or to any partnership between such community development financial institutions and any other federally insured depository institution with a primary mission to serve targeted investment areas, as such areas are defined under <ref>section 4702(16) of this title</ref>, to enable such institutions or any partnership of such institutions to establish a loan-loss reserve fund in order to defray the costs of a small dollar loan program established or maintained by such institution.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Matching requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A community development financial institution or any partnership of institutions established pursuant to paragraph (1) shall provide non-Federal matching funds in an amount equal to 50 percent of the amount of any grant received under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Any grant amounts received by a community development financial institution or any partnership between or among such institutions under paragraph (1)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> may not be used by such institution to provide direct loans to consumers;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> may be used by such institution to help recapture a portion or all of a defaulted loan made under the small dollar loan program of such institution; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> may be used to designate and utilize a fiscal agent for services normally provided by such an agent.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Technical assistance grants</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Fund shall make technical assistance grants to community development financial institutions or any partnership between or among such institutions to support and maintain a small dollar loan program. Any grant amounts received under this paragraph may be used for technology, staff support, and other costs associated with establishing a small dollar loan program.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “consumer reporting agency that compiles and maintains files on consumers on a nationwide basis” has the same meaning given such term in <ref>section 1681a(p) of title 15</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the term “small dollar loan program” means a loan program wherein a community development financial institution or any partnership between or among such institutions offers loans to consumers that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> are made in amounts not exceeding $2,500;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> must be repaid in installments;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> have no pre-payment penalty;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the institution has to report payments regarding the loan to at least 1 of the consumer reporting agencies that compiles and maintains files on consumers on a nationwide basis; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> meet any other affordability requirements as may be established by the Administrator.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–325, title I, § 122</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 111–203, title XII, § 1206</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2131</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>SMALL BUSINESS CAPITAL ENHANCEMENT</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4741.</num>
<heading> Findings and purposes</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> small business concerns are a vital part of the economy, accounting for the majority of new jobs, new products, and new services created in the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> adequate access to debt capital is a critical component for small business development, productivity, expansion, and success in the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> commercial banks are the most important suppliers of debt capital to small business concerns in the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> commercial banks and other depository institutions have various incentives to minimize their risk in financing small business concerns;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> as a result of such incentives, many small business concerns with economically sound financing needs are unable to obtain access to needed debt capital;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the small business capital access programs implemented by certain States are a flexible and efficient tool to assist financial institutions in providing access to needed debt capital for many small business concerns in a manner consistent with safety and soundness regulations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> a small business capital access program would complement other programs which assist small business concerns in obtaining access to capital; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Federal policy can stimulate and accelerate efforts by States to implement small business capital access programs by providing an incentive to States, while leaving the administration of such programs to each participating State.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">By encouraging States to implement administratively efficient capital access programs that encourage commercial banks and other depository institutions to provide access to debt capital for a broad portfolio of small business concerns, and thereby promote a more efficient and effective debt market, the purposes of this subchapter are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to promote economic opportunity and growth;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to create jobs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to promote economic efficiency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to enhance productivity; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to spur innovation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–325, title II, § 251</ref>, <date date="1994-09-23">Sept. 23, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2203</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4742.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this subchapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “Fund” means the Community Development Financial Institutions Fund established under <ref>section 4703 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the term “appropriate Federal banking agency”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> has the same meaning as in <ref>section 1813 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> includes the National Credit Union Administration Board in the case of any credit union the deposits of which are insured in accordance with the Federal Credit Union Act [<ref>12 U.S.C. 1751</ref> et seq.];</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “early loan” means a loan enrolled at a time when the aggregate covered amount of loans previously enrolled under the Program by a particular participating financial institution is less than $5,000,000;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the term “enrolled loan” means a loan made by a participating financial institution that is enrolled by a participating State in accordance with this subchapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the term “financial institution” means any federally chartered or State-chartered commercial bank, savings association, savings bank, or credit union;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the term “participating financial institution” means any financial institution that has entered into a participation agreement with a participating State in accordance with <ref>section 4744 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the term “participating State” means any State that has been approved for participation in the Program in accordance with <ref>section 4743 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<chapeau> the term “passive real estate ownership” means ownership of real estate for the purpose of deriving income from speculation, trade, or rental, except that such term shall not include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the ownership of that portion of real estate being used or intended to be used for the operation of the business of the owner of the real estate (other than the business of passive ownership of real estate); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the ownership of real estate for the purpose of construction or renovation, until the completion of the construction or renovation phase;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> the term “Program” means the Small Business Capital Enhancement Program established under this subchapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<chapeau> the term “reserve fund” means a fund, established by a participating State, earmarked for a particular participating financial institution, for the purposes of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> depositing all required premium charges paid by the participating financial institution and by each borrower receiving a loan under the Program from a participating financial institution;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> depositing contributions made by the participating State; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> covering losses on enrolled loans by disbursing accumulated funds; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<chapeau> the term “State” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a State of the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the District of Columbia;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any political subdivision of a State of the United States, which subdivision has a population in excess of the population of the least populated State of the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> any other political subdivision of a State of the United States that the Fund determines has the capacity to participate in the program.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002438">1</ref></content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–325, title II, § 252</ref>, <date date="1994-09-23">Sept. 23, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2204</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4743.</num>
<heading> Approving States for participation</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any State may apply to the Fund for approval to be a participating State under the Program and to be eligible for reimbursement by the Fund pursuant to <ref>section 4747 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Approval criteria</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Fund shall approve a State to be a participating State, if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a specific department or agency of the State has been designated to implement the Program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> all legal actions necessary to enable such designated department or agency to implement the Program have been accomplished;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> funds in the amount of at least $1 for every 2 people residing in the State (as of the last decennial census for which data have been released) are available and have been legally committed to contributions by the State to reserve funds, with such funds being available without time limit and without requiring additional legal action, except that such requirements shall not be construed to limit the authority of the State to take action at a later time that results in the termination of its obligation to enroll loans and make contributions to reserve funds;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the State has prescribed a form of participation agreement to be entered into between it and each participating financial institution that is consistent with the requirements and purposes of this subchapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the State and the Fund have executed a reimbursement agreement that conforms to the requirements of this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Existing State programs</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A State that is not a participating State, but that has its own capital access program providing portfolio insurance for business loans (based on a separate loss reserve fund for each financial institution), may apply at any time to the Fund to be approved to be a participating State. The Fund shall approve such State to be a participating State, and to be eligible for reimbursements by the Fund pursuant to <ref>section 4747 of this title</ref>, if the State—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> satisfies the requirements of subsections (a) and (b); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> certifies that each affected financial institution has satisfied the requirements of <ref>section 4744 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicable terms of participation</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Status of institutions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">If a State is approved for participation under paragraph (1), each financial institution with a participation agreement in effect with the participating State shall immediately be considered a participating financial institution. Reimbursements may be made under section 4747 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002439">1</ref> of this title in connection with all contributions made to the reserve fund by the State in connection with lending that occurs on or after the date on which the Fund approves the State for participation.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date of participation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">If an amended participation agreement that conforms with <ref>section 4745 of this title</ref> is required in order to secure participation approval by the Fund, contributions subject to reimbursement under <ref>section 4747 of this title</ref> shall include only those contributions made to a reserve fund with respect to loans enrolled on or after the date that an amended participation agreement between the participating State and the participating financial institution becomes effective.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of accumulated reserve funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A State that is approved for participation in accordance with this subsection may continue to implement the program <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002440">2</ref> utilizing the reserve funds accumulated under the State program.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prior appropriations requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Fund shall not approve a State for participation in the Program until at least $50,000,000 has been appropriated to the Fund (subject to an appropriations Act), without fiscal year limitation, for the purpose of making reimbursements pursuant to <ref>section 4747 of this title</ref> and otherwise carrying out this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amendments to agreements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If a State that has been approved to be a participating State wishes to amend its form of participation agreement and continue to be a participating State, such State shall submit such amendment for review by the Fund in accordance with subsection (b)(4). Any such amendment shall become effective only after it has been approved by the Fund.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–325, title II, § 253</ref>, <date date="1994-09-23">Sept. 23, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2205</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4744.</num>
<heading> Participation agreements</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A participating State may enter into a participation agreement with any financial institution determined by the participating State, after consultation with the appropriate Federal banking agency, to have sufficient commercial lending experience and financial and managerial capacity to participate in the Program. The determination by the State shall not be reviewable by the Fund.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Participating financial institutions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon entering into the participation agreement with the participating State, the financial institution shall become a participating financial institution eligible to enroll loans under the Program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–325, title II, § 254</ref>, <date date="1994-09-23">Sept. 23, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2207</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4745.</num>
<heading> Terms of participation agreements</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The participation agreement to be entered into by a participating State and a participating financial institution shall include all provisions required by this section, and shall not include any provisions inconsistent with the provisions of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of separate reserve funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A separate reserve fund shall be established by the participating State for each participating financial institution. All funds credited to a reserve fund shall be the exclusive property of the participating State. Each reserve fund shall be an administrative account for the purposes of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> receiving all required premium charges to be paid by the borrower and participating financial institution and contributions by the participating State; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> disbursing funds, either to cover losses sustained by the participating financial institution in connection with loans made under the Program, or as contemplated by subsections (d) and (r).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Investment authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to applicable State law, the participating State may invest, or cause to be invested, funds held in a reserve fund by establishing a deposit account at the participating financial institution in the name of the participating State. In the event that funds in the reserve fund are not deposited in such an account, such funds shall be invested in a form that the participating State determines is safe and liquid.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Earned income and interest</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Interest or income earned on the funds credited to a reserve fund shall be deemed to be part of the reserve fund, except that a participating State may, as further specified in the participation agreement, provide authority for the participating State to withdraw some or all of such interest or income earned.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Loan terms and conditions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A loan to be filed for enrollment under the Program may be made with such interest rate, fees, and other terms and conditions as agreed upon by the participating financial institution and the borrower, consistent with applicable law.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Lines of credit</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If a loan to be filed for enrollment is in the form of a line of credit, the amount of the loan shall be considered to be the maximum amount that can be drawn by the borrower against the line of credit.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Enrollment process</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Filing</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A participating financial institution shall file each loan made under the Program for enrollment by completing and submitting to the participating State a form prescribed by the participating State.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Form</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The form referred to in subparagraph (A) shall include a representation by the participating financial institution that it has complied with the participation agreement in enrolling the loan with the State.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Premium charges</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Accompanying the completed form shall be the nonrefundable premium charges paid by the borrower and the participating financial institution, or evidence that such premium charges have been deposited into the deposit account containing the reserve fund, if applicable.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Submission</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The participation agreement shall require that the items required by this subsection shall be submitted to the participating State by the participating financial institutions not later than 10 calendar days after a loan is made.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Enrollment by State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Upon receipt by the participating State of the filing submitted in accordance with paragraph (1), the participating State shall promptly enroll the loan and make a matching contribution to the reserve fund in accordance with subsection (j), unless the information submitted indicates that the participating financial institution has not complied with the participation agreement in enrolling the loan.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coverage amount</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In filing a loan for enrollment under the Program, the participating financial institution may specify an amount to be covered under the Program that is less than the full amount of the loan.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Premium charges</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Minimum and maximum amounts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The premium charges payable to the reserve fund by the borrower and the participating financial institution shall be prescribed by the participating financial institution, within minimum and maximum limits set forth in the participation agreement. The participation agreement shall establish minimum and maximum limits whereby the sum of the premium charges paid in connection with a loan by the borrower and the participating financial institution is not less than 3 percent nor more than 7 percent of the amount of the loan covered under the Program.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Allocation of premium charges</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The participation agreement shall specify terms for allocating premium charges between the borrower and the participating financial institution. However, if the participating financial institution is required to pay any of the premium charges, the participation agreement shall authorize the participating financial institution to recover from the borrower the cost of the payment of the participating financial institution, in any manner on which the participating financial institution and the borrower agree.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Restrictions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Actions prohibited</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Except as provided in subsection (h) and paragraph (2) of this subsection, the participating State may not—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> impose any restrictions or requirements, relating to the interest rate, fees, collateral, or other business terms and conditions of the loan; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> condition enrollment of a loan in the Program on the review by the State of the risk or creditworthiness of a loan.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect on other law</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Nothing in this subchapter shall affect the applicability of any other law to the conduct by a participating financial institution of its business.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State contributions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In enrolling a loan under the Program, the participating State shall contribute to the reserve fund an amount, as provided for in the participation agreement, which shall not be less than the sum of the amount of premium charges paid by the borrower and the participating financial institution.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(k)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Submission of claims</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Filing</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">If a participating financial institution charges off all or part of an enrolled loan, such participating financial institution may file a claim for reimbursement with the participating State by submitting a form that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> includes the representation by the participating financial institution that it is filing the claim in accordance with the terms of the applicable participation agreement; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> contains such other information as may be required by the participating State.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Timing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any claim filed under paragraph (1) shall be filed contemporaneously with the action of the participating financial institution to charge off all or part of an enrolled loan. The participating financial institution shall determine when and how much to charge off on an enrolled loan, in a manner consistent with its usual method for making such determinations on business loans that are not enrolled loans under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(l)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Elements of claims</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A claim filed by a participating financial institution may include the amount of principal charged off, not to exceed the covered amount of the loan. Such claim may also include accrued interest and out-of-pocket expenses, if and to the extent provided for under the participation agreement.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(m)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payment of claims</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in subsection (n) and paragraph (2) of this subsection, upon receipt of a claim filed in accordance with this section and the participation agreement, the participating State shall promptly pay to the participating financial institution, from funds in the reserve fund, the full amount of the claim as submitted.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Insufficient reserve funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">If there are insufficient funds in the reserve fund to cover the entire amount of a claim of a participating financial institution, the participating State shall pay to the participating financial institution an amount equal to the current balance in the reserve fund. If the enrolled loan for which the claim has been filed—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is not an early loan, such payment shall be deemed fully to satisfy the claim, and the participating financial institution shall have no other or further right to receive any amount from the reserve fund with respect to such claim; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is an early loan, such payment shall not be deemed fully to satisfy the claim of the participating financial institution, and at such time as the remaining balance of the claim does not exceed 75 percent of the balance in the reserve fund, the participating State shall, upon the request of the participating financial institution, pay any remaining amount of the claim.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(n)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Denial of claims</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A participating State may deny a claim if a representation or warranty made by the participating financial institution to the participating State at the time that the loan was filed for enrollment or at the time that the claim was submitted was known by the participating financial institution to be false.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(o)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Subsequent recovery of claim amount</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If, subsequent to payment of a claim by the participating State, a participating financial institution recovers from a borrower any amount for which payment of the claim was made, the participating financial institution shall promptly pay to the participating State for deposit into the reserve fund the amount recovered, less any expenses incurred by the institution in collection of such amount.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(p)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Participation agreement terms</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In connection with the filing of a loan for enrollment in the Program, the participation agreement—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> shall require the participating financial institution to obtain an assurance from each borrower that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the proceeds of the loan will be used for a business purpose;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the loan will not be used to finance passive real estate ownership; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> the borrower is not—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> an executive officer, director, or principal shareholder of the participating financial institution;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> a member of the immediate family of an executive officer, director, or principal shareholder of the participating financial institution; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> a related interest of any such executive officer, director, principal shareholder, or member of the immediate family;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> shall require the participating financial institution to provide assurances to the participating State that the loan has not been made in order to place under the protection of the Program prior debt that is not covered under the Program and that is or was owed by the borrower to the participating financial institution or to an affiliate of the participating financial institution;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> may provide that if—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a participating financial institution makes a loan to a borrower that is a refinancing of a loan previously made to the borrower by the participating financial institution or an affiliate of the participating financial institution;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> such prior loan was not enrolled in the Program; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> additional or new financing is extended by the participating financial institution as part of the refinancing,</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">the participating financial institution may file the loan for enrollment, with the amount to be covered under the Program not to exceed the amount of any additional or new financing; and</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> may include additional restrictions on the eligibility of loans or borrowers that are not inconsistent with the provisions and purposes of this subchapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, the terms “executive officer”, “director”, “principal shareholder”, “immediate family”, and “related interest” refer to the same relationship to a participating financial institution as the relationship described in part 215 of title 12 of the Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor to such part.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(q)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination clause</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In each participation agreement, the participating State shall reserve for itself the ability to terminate its obligation to enroll loans under the Program. Any such termination shall be prospective only, and shall not apply to amounts of loans enrolled under the Program prior to such termination.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(r)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Allowable withdrawals from fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The participation agreement may provide that, if, for any consecutive period of not less than 24 months, the aggregate outstanding balance of all enrolled loans for a participating financial institution is continually less than the outstanding balance in the reserve fund for that participating financial institution, the participating State, in its discretion, may withdraw an amount from the reserve fund to bring the balance in the reserve fund down to the outstanding balance of all such enrolled loans.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(s)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grandfathered provision</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special treatment of premium charges</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Notwithstanding subsection (b) or (d), the participation agreement, if explicitly authorized by a statute enacted by the State before <date date="1994-09-23">September 23, 1994</date>, may allow a participating financial institution to treat the premium charges paid by the participating financial institution and the borrower into the reserve fund, and interest or income earned on funds in the reserve fund that are deemed to be attributable to such premium charges, as assets of the participating financial institution for accounting purposes, subject to withdrawal by the participating financial institution only—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> for the payment of claims approved by the participating State in accordance with this section; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> upon the participating financial institution’s withdrawal from authority to make new loans under the Program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payment of post-withdrawal claims</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">After any withdrawal of assets from the reserve fund pursuant to paragraph (1)(B), any future claims filed by the participating financial institution on loans remaining in its capital access program portfolio shall only be paid from funds remaining in the reserve fund to the extent that, in the aggregate, such claims exceed the sum of the amount of such withdrawn assets, and interest on that amount, imputed at the same rate as income would have accrued had the amount not been withdrawn.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conditions for terminating special authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the Fund determines that the inclusion in a participation agreement of the provisions authorized by this subsection is resulting in the enrollment of loans under the Program that are likely to have been made without assistance provided under this subchapter, the Fund may notify the participating State that henceforth, the Fund will only make reimbursements to the State under <ref>section 4747 of this title</ref> with respect to a loan if the participation agreement between the participating State and each participating financial institution has been amended to conform with this section, without exercise of the special authority granted by this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–325, title II, § 255</ref>, <date date="1994-09-23">Sept. 23, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2207</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4746.</num>
<heading> Reports</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reserve funds report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">On or before the last day of each calendar quarter, a participating State shall submit to the Fund a report of contributions to reserve funds made by the participating State during the previous calendar quarter. If the participating State has made contributions to one or more reserve funds during the previous quarter, the report shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> indicate the total amount of such contributions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> indicate the amount of contributions which is subject to reimbursement, which shall be equal to the total amount of contributions, unless one of the limitations contained in <ref>section 4747 of this title</ref> is applicable;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> if one of the limitations in <ref>section 4747 of this title</ref> is applicable, provide documentation of the applicability of such limitation for each loan for which the limitation applies; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> include a certification by the participating State that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the information provided in accordance with paragraphs (1), (2), and (3) is accurate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> funds in an amount meeting the minimum requirements of <ref>section 4743(b)(3) of this title</ref> continue to be available and legally committed to contributions by the State to reserve funds, less any amount that has been contributed by the State to reserve funds subsequent to the State being approved for participation in the Program;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> there has been no unapproved amendment to any participation agreement or the form of participation agreements; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the participating State is otherwise implementing the Program in accordance with this subchapter and regulations issued pursuant to <ref>section 4749 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual data</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than March 31 of each year, each participating State shall submit to the Fund annual data indicating the number of borrowers financed under the Program, the total amount of covered loans, and breakdowns by industry type, loan size, annual sales, and number of employees of the borrowers financed.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Form</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The reports and data filed pursuant to subsections (a) and (b) shall be in such form as the Fund may require.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–325, title II, § 256</ref>, <date date="1994-09-23">Sept. 23, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2212</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4747.</num>
<heading> Reimbursement by Fund</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reimbursements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 30 calendar days after receiving a report filed in compliance with <ref>section 4746 of this title</ref>, the Fund shall reimburse the participating State in an amount equal to 50 percent of the amount of contributions by the participating State to the reserve funds that are subject to reimbursement by the Fund pursuant to <ref>section 4746 of this title</ref> and this section. The Fund shall reimburse participating States, as it receives reports pursuant to <ref>section 4746(a) of this title</ref>, until available funds are expended.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Size of assisted borrower</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Fund shall not provide any reimbursement to a participating State with respect to an enrolled loan made to a borrower that has 500 or more employees at the time that the loan is enrolled in the Program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Three-year maximum</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The amount of reimbursement to be provided by the Fund to a participating State over any 3-year period in connection with loans made to any single borrower or any group of borrowers among which a common enterprise exists shall not exceed $75,000. For purposes of this subsection, “common enterprise” shall have the same meaning as in part 32 of title 12 of the Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor to that part.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Loans totaling less than $2,000,000</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In connection with a loan in which the covered amount of the loan plus the covered amount of all previous loans enrolled by a participating financial institution does not exceed $2,000,000, the amount of reimbursement by the Fund to the participating State shall not exceed the lesser of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> 75 percent of the sum of the premium charges paid to the reserve fund by the borrower and the participating financial institution; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> 5.25 percent of the covered amount of the loan.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Loans totaling more than $2,000,000</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In connection with a loan in which the sum of the covered amounts of all previous loans enrolled by the participating financial institution in the Program equals or exceeds $2,000,000, the amount of reimbursement to be provided by the Fund to the participating State shall not exceed the lesser of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> 50 percent of the sum of the premium charges paid by the borrower and the participating financial institution; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> 3.5 percent of the covered amount of the loan.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other amounts</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In connection with the enrollment of a loan that will cause the aggregate covered amount of all enrolled loans to exceed $2,000,000, the amount of reimbursement by the Fund to the participating State shall be determined—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> by applying subsection (d) to the portion of the loan, which when added to the aggregate covered amount of all previously enrolled loans equals $2,000,000; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> by applying subsection (e) to the balance of the loan.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–325, title II, § 257</ref>, <date date="1994-09-23">Sept. 23, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2212</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4748.</num>
<heading> Reimbursement to Fund</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If a participating State withdraws funds from a reserve fund pursuant to terms of the participation agreement permitted by subsection (d) or (r) of <ref>section 4745 of this title</ref>, such participating State shall, not later than 15 calendar days after such withdrawal, submit to the Fund an amount computed by multiplying the amount withdrawn by the appropriate factor, as determined under subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Factor</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The appropriate factor shall be obtained by dividing the total amount of contributions that have been made by the participating State to all reserve funds which were subject to reimbursement—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> by 2; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> by the total amount of contributions made by the participating State to all reserve funds, including if applicable, contributions that have been made by the State prior to becoming a participating State if the State continued its own capital access program in accordance with <ref>section 4743(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of reimbursements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Fund may use funds reimbursed pursuant to this section to make reimbursements under <ref>section 4747 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–325, title II, § 258</ref>, <date date="1994-09-23">Sept. 23, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2213</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4749.</num>
<heading> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Fund shall promulgate appropriate regulations to implement this subchapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–325, title II, § 259</ref>, <date date="1994-09-23">Sept. 23, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2214</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4750.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amount</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Fund $50,000,000 to carry out this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Budgetary treatment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The amount authorized to be appropriated under subsection (a) shall be subject to discretionary spending caps, as provided in section 665 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002441">1</ref> of title 2, and therefore shall reduce by an equal amount funds made available for other discretionary spending programs.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–325, title II, § 260</ref>, <date date="1994-09-23">Sept. 23, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2214</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>