<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 51—</num>
<heading>SECURE AND FAIR ENFORCEMENT FOR MORTGAGE LICENSING</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5101.</num>
<heading> Purposes and methods for establishing a mortgage licensing system and registry</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In order to increase uniformity, reduce regulatory burden, enhance consumer protection, and reduce fraud, the States, through the Conference of State Bank Supervisors and the American Association of Residential Mortgage Regulators, are hereby encouraged to establish a Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry for the residential mortgage industry that accomplishes all of the following objectives:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Provides uniform license applications and reporting requirements for State-licensed loan originators.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Provides a comprehensive licensing and supervisory database.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Aggregates and improves the flow of information to and between regulators.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Provides increased accountability and tracking of loan originators.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Streamlines the licensing process and reduces the regulatory burden.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Enhances consumer protections and supports anti-fraud measures.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Provides consumers with easily accessible information, offered at no charge, utilizing electronic media, including the Internet, regarding the employment history of, and publicly adjudicated disciplinary and enforcement actions against, loan originators.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Establishes a means by which residential mortgage loan originators would, to the greatest extent possible, be required to act in the best interests of the consumer.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> Facilitates responsible behavior in the subprime mortgage market place and provides comprehensive training and examination requirements related to subprime mortgage lending.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> Facilitates the collection and disbursement of consumer complaints on behalf of State and Federal mortgage regulators.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–289, div. A, title V, § 1502</ref>, <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2810</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5102.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this chapter, the following definitions shall apply:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Bureau</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Bureau” means the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal banking agency</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Federal banking agency” means the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency, the National Credit Union Administration, and the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Depository institution</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “depository institution” has the same meaning as in <ref>section 1813 of this title</ref>, and includes any credit union.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Loan originator</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “loan originator”—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> means an individual who—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> takes a residential mortgage loan application; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> offers or negotiates terms of a residential mortgage loan for compensation or gain;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> does not include any individual who is not otherwise described in clause (i) and who performs purely administrative or clerical tasks on behalf of a person who is described in any such clause;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> does not include a person or entity that only performs real estate brokerage activities and is licensed or registered in accordance with applicable State law, unless the person or entity is compensated by a lender, a mortgage broker, or other loan originator or by any agent of such lender, mortgage broker, or other loan originator; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> does not include a person or entity solely involved in extensions of credit relating to timeshare plans, as that term is defined in section 101(53D) of title 11.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other definitions relating to loan originator</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">For purposes of this subsection, an individual “assists a consumer in obtaining or applying to obtain a residential mortgage loan” by, among other things, advising on loan terms (including rates, fees, other costs), preparing loan packages, or collecting information on behalf of the consumer with regard to a residential mortgage loan.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrative or clerical tasks</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “administrative or clerical tasks” means the receipt, collection, and distribution of information common for the processing or underwriting of a loan in the mortgage industry and communication with a consumer to obtain information necessary for the processing or underwriting of a residential mortgage loan.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Real estate brokerage activity defined</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “real estate brokerage activity” means any activity that involves offering or providing real estate brokerage services to the public, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> acting as a real estate agent or real estate broker for a buyer, seller, lessor, or lessee of real property;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> bringing together parties interested in the sale, purchase, lease, rental, or exchange of real property;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> negotiating, on behalf of any party, any portion of a contract relating to the sale, purchase, lease, rental, or exchange of real property (other than in connection with providing financing with respect to any such transaction);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> engaging in any activity for which a person engaged in the activity is required to be registered or licensed as a real estate agent or real estate broker under any applicable law; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> offering to engage in any activity, or act in any capacity, described in clause (i), (ii), (iii), or (iv).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Loan processor or underwriter</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “loan processor or underwriter” means an individual who performs clerical or support duties at the direction of and subject to the supervision and instruction of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a State-licensed loan originator; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a registered loan originator.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Clerical or support duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">For purposes of subparagraph (A), the term “clerical or support duties” may include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the receipt, collection, distribution, and analysis of information common for the processing or underwriting of a residential mortgage loan; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> communicating with a consumer to obtain the information necessary for the processing or underwriting of a loan, to the extent that such communication does not include offering or negotiating loan rates or terms, or counseling consumers about residential mortgage loan rates or terms.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nationwide mortgage licensing system and registry</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry” means a mortgage licensing system developed and maintained by the Conference of State Bank Supervisors and the American Association of Residential Mortgage Regulators for the State licensing and registration of State-licensed loan originators and the registration of registered loan originators or any system established by the Director under <ref>section 5108 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nontraditional mortgage product</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “nontraditional mortgage product” means any mortgage product other than a 30-year fixed rate mortgage.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Registered loan originator</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “registered loan originator” means any individual who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> meets the definition of loan originator and is an employee of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a depository institution;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> a subsidiary that is—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> owned and controlled by a depository institution; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> regulated by a Federal banking agency; or</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> an institution regulated by the Farm Credit Administration; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is registered with, and maintains a unique identifier through, the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Residential mortgage loan</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “residential mortgage loan” means any loan primarily for personal, family, or household use that is secured by a mortgage, deed of trust, or other equivalent consensual security interest on a dwelling (as defined in section 1602(v) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002444">1</ref> of title 15) or residential real estate upon which is constructed or intended to be constructed a dwelling (as so defined).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(10)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Director</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Director” means the Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(11)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “State” means any State of the United States, the District of Columbia, any territory of the United States, Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, the Virgin Islands, and the Northern Mariana Islands.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(12)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State-licensed loan originator</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “State-licensed loan originator” means any individual who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is a loan originator;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> is not an employee of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a depository institution;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> a subsidiary that is—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> owned and controlled by a depository institution; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> regulated by a Federal banking agency; or</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> an institution regulated by the Farm Credit Administration; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> is licensed by a State or by the Director under <ref>section 5107 of this title</ref> and registered as a loan originator with, and maintains a unique identifier through, the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(13)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Unique identifier</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “unique identifier” means a number or other identifier that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> permanently identifies a loan originator;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> is assigned by protocols established by the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry and the Bureau to facilitate electronic tracking of loan originators and uniform identification of, and public access to, the employment history of and the publicly adjudicated disciplinary and enforcement actions against loan originators; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> shall not be used for purposes other than those set forth under this chapter.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Responsibility of States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">To the greatest extent possible and to accomplish the purpose of this chapter, States shall use unique identifiers in lieu of social security numbers.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–289, div. A, title V, § 1503</ref>, <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2811</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–203, title X, § 1100(2)</ref>–(4), <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2106</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5103.</num>
<heading> License or registration required</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subject to the existence of a licensing or registration regime, as the case may be, an individual may not engage in the business of a loan originator without first—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> obtaining, and maintaining annually—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a registration as a registered loan originator; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a license and registration as a State-licensed loan originator; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> obtaining a unique identifier.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Loan processors and underwriters</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Supervised loan processors and underwriters</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A loan processor or underwriter who does not represent to the public, through advertising or other means of communicating or providing information (including the use of business cards, stationery, brochures, signs, rate lists, or other promotional items), that such individual can or will perform any of the activities of a loan originator shall not be required to be a State-licensed loan originator.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Independent contractors</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">An independent contractor may not engage in residential mortgage loan origination activities as a loan processor or underwriter unless such independent contractor is a State-licensed loan originator.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–289, div. A, title V, § 1504</ref>, <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2814</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5104.</num>
<heading> State license and registration application and issuance</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Background checks</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In connection with an application to any State for licensing and registration as a State-licensed loan originator, the applicant shall, at a minimum, furnish to the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry information concerning the applicant’s identity, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> fingerprints for submission to the Federal Bureau of Investigation, and any governmental agency or entity authorized to receive such information for a State and national criminal history background check; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> personal history and experience, including authorization for the System to obtain—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an independent credit report obtained from a consumer reporting agency described in <ref>section 1681a(p) of title 15</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> information related to any administrative, civil or criminal findings by any governmental jurisdiction.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Issuance of license</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The minimum standards for licensing and registration as a State-licensed loan originator shall include the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The applicant has never had a loan originator license revoked in any governmental jurisdiction.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The applicant has not been convicted of, or pled guilty or nolo contendere to, a felony in a domestic, foreign, or military court—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> during the 7-year period preceding the date of the application for licensing and registration; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> at any time preceding such date of application, if such felony involved an act of fraud, dishonesty, or a breach of trust, or money laundering.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The applicant has demonstrated financial responsibility, character, and general fitness such as to command the confidence of the community and to warrant a determination that the loan originator will operate honestly, fairly, and efficiently within the purposes of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The applicant has completed the pre-licensing education requirement described in subsection (c).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The applicant has passed a written test that meets the test requirement described in subsection (d).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The applicant has met either a net worth or surety bond requirement, or paid into a State fund, as required by the State pursuant to <ref>section 5107(d)(6) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Pre-licensing education of loan originators</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Minimum educational requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In order to meet the pre-licensing education requirement referred to in subsection (b)(4), a person shall complete at least 20 hours of education approved in accordance with paragraph (2), which shall include at least—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> 3 hours of Federal law and regulations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> 3 hours of ethics, which shall include instruction on fraud, consumer protection, and fair lending issues; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> 2 hours of training related to lending standards for the nontraditional mortgage product marketplace.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Approved educational courses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of paragraph (1), pre-licensing education courses shall be reviewed, and approved by the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation and standards</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">To maintain the independence of the approval process, the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry shall not directly or indirectly offer pre-licensure educational courses for loan originators.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Standards</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In approving courses under this section, the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry shall apply reasonable standards in the review and approval of courses.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Testing of loan originators</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In order to meet the written test requirement referred to in subsection (b)(5), an individual shall pass, in accordance with the standards established under this subsection, a qualified written test developed by the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry and administered by an approved test provider.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Qualified test</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A written test shall not be treated as a qualified written test for purposes of paragraph (1) unless the test adequately measures the applicant’s knowledge and comprehension in appropriate subject areas, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> ethics;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Federal law and regulation pertaining to mortgage origination;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> State law and regulation pertaining to mortgage origination;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Federal and State law and regulation, including instruction on fraud, consumer protection, the nontraditional mortgage marketplace, and fair lending issues.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Minimum competence</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Passing score</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">An individual shall not be considered to have passed a qualified written test unless the individual achieves a test score of not less than 75 percent correct answers to questions.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initial retests</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">An individual may retake a test 3 consecutive times with each consecutive taking occurring at least 30 days after the preceding test.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Subsequent retests</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">After failing 3 consecutive tests, an individual shall wait at least 6 months before taking the test again.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Retest after lapse of license</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A State-licensed loan originator who fails to maintain a valid license for a period of 5 years or longer shall retake the test, not taking into account any time during which such individual is a registered loan originator.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Mortgage call reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each mortgage licensee shall submit to the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry reports of condition, which shall be in such form and shall contain such information as the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry may require.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–289, div. A, title V, § 1505</ref>, <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2814</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5105.</num>
<heading> Standards for State license renewal</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The minimum standards for license renewal for State-licensed loan originators shall include the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The loan originator continues to meet the minimum standards for license issuance.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The loan originator has satisfied the annual continuing education requirements described in subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Continuing education for State-licensed loan originators</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In order to meet the annual continuing education requirements referred to in subsection (a)(2), a State-licensed loan originator shall complete at least 8 hours of education approved in accordance with paragraph (2), which shall include at least—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> 3 hours of Federal law and regulations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> 2 hours of ethics, which shall include instruction on fraud, consumer protection, and fair lending issues; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> 2 hours of training related to lending standards for the nontraditional mortgage product marketplace.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Approved educational courses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of paragraph (1), continuing education courses shall be reviewed, and approved by the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Calculation of continuing education credits</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A State-licensed loan originator—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> may only receive credit for a continuing education course in the year in which the course is taken; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> may not take the same approved course in the same or successive years to meet the annual requirements for continuing education.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Instructor credit</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A State-licensed loan originator who is approved as an instructor of an approved continuing education course may receive credit for the originator’s own annual continuing education requirement at the rate of 2 hours credit for every 1 hour taught.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation and standards</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">To maintain the independence of the approval process, the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry shall not directly or indirectly offer any continuing education courses for loan originators.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Standards</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In approving courses under this section, the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry shall apply reasonable standards in the review and approval of courses.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–289, div. A, title V, § 1506</ref>, <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2816</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5106.</num>
<heading> System of registration administration by Federal agencies</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Development</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Bureau shall develop and maintain a system for registering employees of a depository institution, employees of a subsidiary that is owned and controlled by a depository institution and regulated by a Federal banking agency, or employees of an institution regulated by the Farm Credit Administration, as registered loan originators with the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry. The system shall be implemented before the end of the 1-year period beginning on <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Registration requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In connection with the registration of any loan originator under this subsection, the Bureau shall, at a minimum, furnish or cause to be furnished to the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry information concerning the identity of the employee, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> fingerprints for submission to the Federal Bureau of Investigation, and any governmental agency or entity authorized to receive such information for a State and national criminal history background check; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> personal history and experience, including authorization for the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry to obtain information related to any administrative, civil or criminal findings by any governmental jurisdiction.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Unique identifier</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Bureau,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002445">1</ref> and the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection shall coordinate with the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry to establish protocols for assigning a unique identifier to each registered loan originator that will facilitate electronic tracking and uniform identification of, and public access to, the employment history of and publicly adjudicated disciplinary and enforcement actions against loan originators.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry development</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To facilitate the transfer of information required by subsection (a)(2), the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry shall coordinate with the Bureau,<sup>1</sup> and the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection concerning the development and operation, by such System and Registry, of the registration functionality and data requirements for loan originators.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consideration of factors and procedures</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In establishing the registration procedures under subsection (a) and the protocols for assigning a unique identifier to a registered loan originator, the Bureau shall make such de minimis exceptions as may be appropriate to paragraphs (1)(A) and (2) of <ref>section 5103(a) of this title</ref>, shall make reasonable efforts to utilize existing information to minimize the burden of registering loan originators, and shall consider methods for automating the process to the greatest extent practicable consistent with the purposes of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–289, div. A, title V, § 1507</ref>, <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2817</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–203, title X, § 1100(2)</ref>, (5), <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2106</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5107.</num>
<heading> Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection backup authority to establish loan originator licensing system</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Backup licensing system</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If, by the end of the 1-year period, or the 2-year period in the case of a State whose legislature meets only biennially, beginning on <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, or at any time thereafter, the Director determines that a State does not have in place by law or regulation a system for licensing and registering loan originators that meets the requirements of sections 5104 and 5105 of this title and subsection (d) of this section, or does not participate in the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry, the Director shall provide for the establishment and maintenance of a system for the licensing and registration by the Director of loan originators operating in such State as State-licensed loan originators.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Licensing and registration requirements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The system established by the Director under subsection (a) for any State shall meet the requirements of sections 5104 and 5105 of this title for State-licensed loan originators.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Unique identifier</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director shall coordinate with the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry to establish protocols for assigning a unique identifier to each loan originator licensed by the Director as a State-licensed loan originator that will facilitate electronic tracking and uniform identification of, and public access to, the employment history of and the publicly adjudicated disciplinary and enforcement actions against loan originators.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State licensing law requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the law in effect in a State meets the requirements of this subsection if the Director determines the law satisfies the following minimum requirements:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A State loan originator supervisory authority is maintained to provide effective supervision and enforcement of such law, including the suspension, termination, or nonrenewal of a license for a violation of State or Federal law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The State loan originator supervisory authority ensures that all State-licensed loan originators operating in the State are registered with Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The State loan originator supervisory authority is required to regularly report violations of such law, as well as enforcement actions and other relevant information, to the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The State loan originator supervisory authority has a process in place for challenging information contained in the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The State loan originator supervisory authority has established a mechanism to assess civil money penalties for individuals acting as mortgage originators in their State without a valid license or registration.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The State loan originator supervisory authority has established minimum net worth or surety bonding requirements that reflect the dollar amount of loans originated by a residential mortgage loan originator, or has established a recovery fund paid into by the loan originators.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Temporary extension of period</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director may extend, by not more than 24 months, the 1-year or 2-year period, as the case may be, referred to in subsection (a) for the licensing of loan originators in any State under a State licensing law that meets the requirements of sections 5104 and 5105 of this title and subsection (d) if the Director determines that such State is making a good faith effort to establish a State licensing law that meets such requirements, license mortgage originators under such law, and register such originators with the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulation authority</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Bureau is authorized to promulgate regulations setting minimum net worth or surety bond requirements for residential mortgage loan originators and minimum requirements for recovery funds paid into by loan originators.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Considerations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In issuing regulations under paragraph (1), the Bureau shall take into account the need to provide originators adequate incentives to originate affordable and sustainable mortgage loans, as well as the need to ensure a competitive origination market that maximizes consumer access to affordable and sustainable mortgage loans.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–289, div. A, title V, § 1508</ref>, <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2818</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–203, title X, § 1100(3)</ref>, (6), <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2106</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5108.</num>
<heading> Backup authority to establish a nationwide mortgage licensing and registry system</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If at any time the Director determines that the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry is failing to meet the requirements and purposes of this chapter for a comprehensive licensing, supervisory, and tracking system for loan originators, the Director shall establish and maintain such a system to carry out the purposes of this chapter and the effective registration and regulation of loan originators.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–289, div. A, title V, § 1509</ref>, <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2819</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–203, title X, § 1100(3)</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2106</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5109.</num>
<heading> Fees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Bureau, the Farm Credit Administration, and the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry may charge reasonable fees to cover the costs of maintaining and providing access to information from the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry, to the extent that such fees are not charged to consumers for access to such system and registry.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–289, div. A, title V, § 1510</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 111–203, title X, § 1100(7)</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2107</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5110.</num>
<heading> Background checks of loan originators</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Access to records</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, in providing identification and processing functions, the Attorney General shall provide access to all criminal history information to the appropriate State officials responsible for regulating State-licensed loan originators and other financial service providers to the extent criminal history background checks are required under the laws of the State for the licensing of such loan originators or other financial service providers.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agent</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purposes of this section and in order to reduce the points of contact which the Federal Bureau of Investigation may have to maintain for purposes of subsection (a), the Conference of State Bank Supervisors or a wholly owned subsidiary may be used as a channeling agent of the States for requesting and distributing information between the Department of Justice and the appropriate State agencies .</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–289, div. A, title V, § 1511</ref>, <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2819</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–94, div. G, title LXXXVIII, § 88002</ref>, <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 1799</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5111.</num>
<heading> Confidentiality of information</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> System confidentiality</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided in this section, any requirement under Federal or State law regarding the privacy or confidentiality of any information or material provided to the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry or a system established by the Director under <ref>section 5108 of this title</ref>, and any privilege arising under Federal or State law (including the rules of any Federal or State court) with respect to such information or material, shall continue to apply to such information or material after the information or material has been disclosed to the system. Such information and material may be shared with all State and Federal regulatory officials with mortgage or financial services industry oversight authority without the loss of privilege or the loss of confidentiality protections provided by Federal and State laws.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonapplicability of certain requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Information or material that is subject to a privilege or confidentiality under subsection (a) shall not be subject to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> disclosure under any Federal or State law governing the disclosure to the public of information held by an officer or an agency of the Federal Government or the respective State; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> subpoena or discovery, or admission into evidence, in any private civil action or administrative process, unless with respect to any privilege held by the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry or the Director with respect to such information or material, the person to whom such information or material pertains waives, in whole or in part, in the discretion of such person, that privilege.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination with other law</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any State law, including any State open record law, relating to the disclosure of confidential supervisory information or any information or material described in subsection (a) that is inconsistent with subsection (a) shall be superseded by the requirements of such provision to the extent State law provides less confidentiality or a weaker privilege.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public access to information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall not apply with respect to the information or material relating to the employment history of, and publicly adjudicated disciplinary and enforcement actions against, loan originators that is included in Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry for access by the public.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–289, div. A, title V, § 1512</ref>, <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2820</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–203, title X, § 1100(3)</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2106</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–113, div. O, title VII, § 703</ref>, <date date="2015-12-18">Dec. 18, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 3025</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5112.</num>
<heading> Liability provisions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Bureau, any State official or agency, or any organization serving as the administrator of the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry or a system established by the Director under <ref>section 5108 of this title</ref>, or any officer or employee of any such entity, shall not be subject to any civil action or proceeding for monetary damages by reason of the good faith action or omission of any officer or employee of any such entity, while acting within the scope of office or employment, relating to the collection, furnishing, or dissemination of information concerning persons who—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> have applied, are applying, or are licensed or registered through the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> work in an industry with respect to which persons were licensed or registered through the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry on <date date="2018-05-24">May 24, 2018</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–289, div. A, title V, § 1513</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 111–203, title X, § 1100(8)</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2107</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–174, title I, § 106(c)</ref>, <date date="2018-05-24">May 24, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1304</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5113.</num>
<heading> Enforcement by the Bureau</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Summons authority</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Director may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> examine any books, papers, records, or other data of any loan originator operating in any State which is subject to a licensing system established by the Director under <ref>section 5107 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> summon any loan originator referred to in paragraph (1) or any person having possession, custody, or care of the reports and records relating to such loan originator, to appear before the Director or any delegate of the Director at a time and place named in the summons and to produce such books, papers, records, or other data, and to give testimony, under oath, as may be relevant or material to an investigation of such loan originator for compliance with the requirements of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Examination authority</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the Director establishes a licensing system under <ref>section 5107 of this title</ref> for any State, the Director shall appoint examiners for the purposes of administering such section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Power to examine</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any examiner appointed under paragraph (1) shall have power, on behalf of the Director, to make any examination of any loan originator operating in any State which is subject to a licensing system established by the Director under <ref>section 5107 of this title</ref> whenever the Director determines an examination of any loan originator is necessary to determine the compliance by the originator with this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report of examination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Each examiner appointed under paragraph (1) shall make a full and detailed report of examination of any loan originator examined to the Director.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administration of oaths and affirmations; evidence</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In connection with examinations of loan originators operating in any State which is subject to a licensing system established by the Director under <ref>section 5107 of this title</ref>, or with other types of investigations to determine compliance with applicable law and regulations, the Director and examiners appointed by the Director may administer oaths and affirmations and examine and take and preserve testimony under oath as to any matter in respect to the affairs of any such loan originator.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assessments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The cost of conducting any examination of any loan originator operating in any State which is subject to a licensing system established by the Director under <ref>section 5107 of this title</ref> shall be assessed by the Director against the loan originator to meet the Secretary’s <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002446">1</ref> expenses in carrying out such examination.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cease and desist proceeding</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority of Director</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the Director finds, after notice and opportunity for hearing, that any person is violating, has violated, or is about to violate any provision of this chapter, or any regulation thereunder, with respect to a State which is subject to a licensing system established by the Director under <ref>section 5107 of this title</ref>, the Director may publish such findings and enter an order requiring such person, and any other person that is, was, or would be a cause of the violation, due to an act or omission the person knew or should have known would contribute to such violation, to cease and desist from committing or causing such violation and any future violation of the same provision, rule, or regulation. Such order may, in addition to requiring a person to cease and desist from committing or causing a violation, require such person to comply, or to take steps to effect compliance, with such provision or regulation, upon such terms and conditions and within such time as the Director may specify in such order. Any such order may, as the Director deems appropriate, require future compliance or steps to effect future compliance, either permanently or for such period of time as the Director may specify, with such provision or regulation with respect to any loan originator.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Hearing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The notice instituting proceedings pursuant to paragraph (1) shall fix a hearing date not earlier than 30 days nor later than 60 days after service of the notice unless an earlier or a later date is set by the Director with the consent of any respondent so served.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Temporary order</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Whenever the Director determines that the alleged violation or threatened violation specified in the notice instituting proceedings pursuant to paragraph (1), or the continuation thereof, is likely to result in significant dissipation or conversion of assets, significant harm to consumers, or substantial harm to the public interest prior to the completion of the proceedings, the Director may enter a temporary order requiring the respondent to cease and desist from the violation or threatened violation and to take such action to prevent the violation or threatened violation and to prevent dissipation or conversion of assets, significant harm to consumers, or substantial harm to the public interest as the Director deems appropriate pending completion of such proceedings. Such an order shall be entered only after notice and opportunity for a hearing, unless the Director determines that notice and hearing prior to entry would be impracticable or contrary to the public interest. A temporary order shall become effective upon service upon the respondent and, unless set aside, limited, or suspended by the Director or a court of competent jurisdiction, shall remain effective and enforceable pending the completion of the proceedings.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review of temporary orders</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review by Director</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">At any time after the respondent has been served with a temporary cease and desist order pursuant to paragraph (3), the respondent may apply to the Director to have the order set aside, limited, or suspended. If the respondent has been served with a temporary cease and desist order entered without a prior hearing before the Director, the respondent may, within 10 days after the date on which the order was served, request a hearing on such application and the Director shall hold a hearing and render a decision on such application at the earliest possible time.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Judicial review</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Within—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> 10 days after the date the respondent was served with a temporary cease and desist order entered with a prior hearing before the Director; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> 10 days after the Director renders a decision on an application and hearing under paragraph (1), with respect to any temporary cease and desist order entered without a prior hearing before the Director,</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">the respondent may apply to the United States district court for the district in which the respondent resides or has its principal place of business, or for the District of Columbia, for an order setting aside, limiting, or suspending the effectiveness or enforcement of the order, and the court shall have jurisdiction to enter such an order. A respondent served with a temporary cease and desist order entered without a prior hearing before the Director may not apply to the court except after hearing and decision by the Director on the respondent’s application under subparagraph (A).</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> No automatic stay of temporary order</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The commencement of proceedings under subparagraph (B) shall not, unless specifically ordered by the court, operate as a stay of the Secretary’s <sup>1</sup> order.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority of the Director to prohibit persons from serving as loan originators</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In any cease and desist proceeding under paragraph (1), the Director may issue an order to prohibit, conditionally or unconditionally, and permanently or for such period of time as the Director shall determine, any person who has violated this chapter or regulations thereunder, from acting as a loan originator if the conduct of that person demonstrates unfitness to serve as a loan originator.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority of the Director to assess money penalties</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Director may impose a civil penalty on a loan originator operating in any State which is subject to a licensing system established by the Director under <ref>section 5107 of this title</ref>, if the Director finds, on the record after notice and opportunity for hearing, that such loan originator has violated or failed to comply with any requirement of this chapter or any regulation prescribed by the Director under this chapter or order issued under subsection (c).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Maximum amount of penalty</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The maximum amount of penalty for each act or omission described in paragraph (1) shall be $25,000.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–289, div. A, title V, § 1514</ref>, <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2821</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–203, title X, § 1100(3)</ref>, (9), <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2106</ref>, 2107.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5114.</num>
<heading> State examination authority</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In addition to any authority allowed under State law a State licensing agency shall have the authority to conduct investigations and examinations as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> For the purposes of investigating violations or complaints arising under this chapter, or for the purposes of examination, the State licensing agency may review, investigate, or examine any loan originator licensed or required to be licensed under this chapter, as often as necessary in order to carry out the purposes of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Each such loan originator shall make available upon request to the State licensing agency the books and records relating to the operations of such originator. The State licensing agency may have access to such books and records and interview the officers, principals, loan originators, employees, independent contractors, agents, and customers of the licensee concerning their business.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The authority of this section shall remain in effect, whether such a loan originator acts or claims to act under any licensing or registration law of such State, or claims to act without such authority.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> No person subject to investigation or examination under this section may knowingly withhold, abstract, remove, mutilate, destroy, or secrete any books, records, computer records, or other information.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–289, div. A, title V, § 1515</ref>, <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2823</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5115.</num>
<heading> Reports and recommendations to Congress</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, and annually thereafter, the Director shall submit a report to Congress on the effectiveness of the provisions of this chapter, including legislative recommendations, if any, for strengthening consumer protections, enhancing examination standards, streamlining communication between all stakeholders involved in residential mortgage loan origination and processing, and establishing performance based bonding requirements for mortgage originators or institutions that employ such brokers.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Legislative recommendations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 6 months after <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, the Director shall make recommendations to Congress on legislative reforms to the Real Estate Settlement Procedures Act of 1974 [<ref>12 U.S.C. 2601</ref> et seq.], that the Director deems appropriate to promote more transparent disclosures, allowing consumers to better shop and compare mortgage loan terms and settlement costs.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–289, div. A, title V, § 1516</ref>, <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2824</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–203, title X, § 1100(3)</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2106</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5116.</num>
<heading> Study and reports on defaults and foreclosures</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Study required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director shall conduct an extensive study of the root causes of default and foreclosure of home loans, using as much empirical data as is available.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Preliminary report to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 6 months after <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, the Director shall submit to Congress a preliminary report regarding the study required by this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Final report to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 12 months after <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, the Director shall submit to Congress a final report regarding the results of the study required by this section, which shall include any recommended legislation relating to the study, and recommendations for best practices and for a process to provide targeted assistance to populations with the highest risk of potential default or foreclosure.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–289, div. A, title V, § 1517</ref>, <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2824</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–203, title X, § 1100(3)</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2106</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5117.</num>
<heading> Employment transition of loan originators</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “application State” means a State in which a registered loan originator or a State-licensed loan originator seeks to be licensed.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State-licensed mortgage company</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “State-licensed mortgage company” means an entity that is licensed or registered under the law of any State to engage in residential mortgage loan origination and processing activities.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Temporary authority to originate loans for loan originators moving from a depository institution to a non-depository institution</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Upon becoming employed by a State-licensed mortgage company, an individual who is a registered loan originator shall be deemed to have temporary authority to act as a loan originator in an application State for the period described in paragraph (2) if the individual—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> has not had—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an application for a loan originator license denied; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a loan originator license revoked or suspended in any governmental jurisdiction;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> has not been subject to, or served with, a cease and desist order—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> in any governmental jurisdiction; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> under <ref>section 5113(c) of this title</ref>;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> has not been convicted of a misdemeanor or felony that would preclude licensure under the law of the application State;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> has submitted an application to be a State-licensed loan originator in the application State; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> was registered in the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry as a loan originator during the 1-year period preceding the date on which the information required under <ref>section 5104(a) of this title</ref> is submitted.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Period</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The period described in this paragraph shall begin on the date on which an individual described in paragraph (1) submits the information required under <ref>section 5104(a) of this title</ref> and shall end on the earliest of the date—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> on which the individual withdraws the application to be a State-licensed loan originator in the application State;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> on which the application State denies, or issues a notice of intent to deny, the application;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> on which the application State grants a State license; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> that is 120 days after the date on which the individual submits the application, if the application is listed on the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry as incomplete.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Temporary authority to originate loans for State-licensed loan originators moving interstate</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A State-licensed loan originator shall be deemed to have temporary authority to act as a loan originator in an application State for the period described in paragraph (2) if the State-licensed loan originator—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> meets the requirements of subparagraphs (A), (B), (C), and (D) of subsection (b)(1);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is employed by a State-licensed mortgage company in the application State; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> was licensed in a State that is not the application State during the 30-day period preceding the date on which the information required under <ref>section 5104(a) of this title</ref> was submitted in connection with the application submitted to the application State.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Period</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The period described in this paragraph shall begin on the date on which the State-licensed loan originator submits the information required under <ref>section 5104(a) of this title</ref> in connection with the application submitted to the application State and end on the earliest of the date—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> on which the State-licensed loan originator withdraws the application to be a State-licensed loan originator in the application State;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> on which the application State denies, or issues a notice of intent to deny, the application;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> on which the application State grants a State license; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> that is 120 days after the date on which the State-licensed loan originator submits the application, if the application is listed on the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry as incomplete.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Employer of loan originators</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any person employing an individual who is deemed to have temporary authority to act as a loan originator in an application State under this section shall be subject to the requirements of this chapter and to applicable State law to the same extent as if that individual was a State-licensed loan originator licensed by the application State.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Engaging in mortgage loan activities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any individual who is deemed to have temporary authority to act as a loan originator in an application State under this section and who engages in residential mortgage loan origination activities shall be subject to the requirements of this chapter and to applicable State law to the same extent as if that individual was a State-licensed loan originator licensed by the application State.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–289, div. A, title V, § 1518</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 115–174, title I, § 106(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-05-24">May 24, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1302</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>