<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 2—</num>
<heading>SUBMARINE CABLES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 21.</num>
<heading> Submarine cables; willful injury to; punishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any person who shall willfully and wrongfully break or injure, or attempt to break or injure, or who shall in any manner procure, counsel, aid, abet, or be accessory to such breaking or injury, or attempt to break or injure, a submarine cable in such manner as to interrupt or embarrass, in whole or in part, telegraphic communication, shall be guilty of a misdemeanor, and, on conviction thereof, shall be liable to imprisonment for a term not exceeding two years, or to a fine not exceeding $5,000, or to both fine and imprisonment, at the discretion of the court.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Feb. 29, 1888, ch. 17, § 1</ref>, <ref>25 Stat. 41</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 22.</num>
<heading> Negligent injury to submarine cables; punishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any person who by culpable negligence shall break or injure a submarine cable in such manner as to interrupt or embarrass, in whole or in part, telegraphic communication, shall be guilty of a misdemeanor, and, on conviction thereof, shall be liable to imprisonment for a term not exceeding three months, or to a fine not exceeding $500, or to both fine and imprisonment, at the discretion of the court.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Feb. 29, 1888, ch. 17, § 2</ref>, <ref>25 Stat. 41</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 23.</num>
<heading> Injury to submarine cables in efforts to save life excepted</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The provisions of sections 21 and 22 of this title shall not apply to a person who breaks or injures a cable in an effort to save the life or limb of himself or of any other person, or to save his own or any other vessel: <i>Provided</i>, That he takes reasonable precautions to avoid such breaking or injury.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Feb. 29, 1888, ch. 17, § 3</ref>, <ref>25 Stat. 41</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 24.</num>
<heading> Vessels laying cables; signals; avoidance of buoys</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The master of any vessel which, while engaged in laying or repairing submarine cables, shall fail to observe the rules concerning signals that have been or shall be adopted by the parties to the convention described in <ref>section 30 of this title</ref> with a view to preventing collisions at sea; or the master of any vessel that, perceiving, or being able to perceive the said signals displayed upon a telegraph ship engaged in repairing a cable, shall not withdraw to or keep at distance of at least one nautical mile; or the master of any vessel that seeing or being able to see buoys intended to mark the position of a cable when being laid or when out of order or broken, shall not keep at a distance of at least a quarter of a nautical mile, shall be guilty of a misdemeanor, and on conviction thereof, shall be liable to imprisonment for a term not exceeding one month, or to a fine of not exceeding $500.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Feb. 29, 1888, ch. 17, § 4</ref>, <ref>25 Stat. 41</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 25.</num>
<heading> Fishing vessels; duty to keep nets from cables</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The master of any fishing vessel who shall not keep his implements or nets at a distance of at least one nautical mile from a vessel engaged in laying or repairing a cable; or the master of any fishing vessel who shall not keep his implements or nets at a distance of at least a quarter of a nautical mile from a buoy or buoys intended to mark the position of a cable when being laid or when out of order or broken, shall be guilty of a misdemeanor, and on conviction thereof, shall be liable to imprisonment for a term not exceeding ten days, or to a fine not exceeding $250, or to both such fine and imprisonment, at the discretion of the court. Fishing vessels, on perceiving or being able to perceive the said signals displayed on a telegraph ship, shall be allowed such time as may be necessary to obey the notice thus given, not exceeding twenty-four hours, during which period no obstacle shall be placed in the way of their operations.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Feb. 29, 1888, ch. 17, § 5</ref>, <ref>25 Stat. 42</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 26.</num>
<heading> Duties of commanders of warships</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purpose of carrying into effect the convention described in <ref>section 30 of this title</ref> a person commanding a ship of war of the United States or of any foreign state for the time being bound by the convention, or a ship specially commissioned by the Government of the United States or by the government of such foreign state, may exercise and perform the duties with respect to requiring exhibition of documents evidencing the nationality of offending vessels and making reports of infractions vested in and imposed on such officer by the convention.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Feb. 29, 1888, ch. 17, § 6</ref>, <ref>25 Stat. 42</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 27.</num>
<heading> Offending vessels to show nationality</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any person having the custody of the papers necessary for the preparation of the statements provided for in article 10 of the said convention with respect to reports of infractions, by officers commanding vessels of war or vessels especially commissioned, who shall refuse to exhibit them or shall violently resist persons having authority according to article 10 of said convention to draw up statements of facts in the exercise of their functions, shall be guilty of a misdemeanor, and on conviction thereof shall be liable to imprisonment not exceeding two years, or to a fine not exceeding $5,000, or to both fine and imprisonment, at the discretion of the court.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Feb. 29, 1888, ch. 17, § 7</ref>, <ref>25 Stat. 42</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 28.</num>
<heading> Penalties not to bar suits for damages</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The penalties provided in this chapter for the breaking or injury of a submarine cable shall not be a bar to a suit for damages on account of such breaking or injury.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Feb. 29, 1888, ch. 17, § 8</ref>, <ref>25 Stat. 42</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 29.</num>
<heading> Master of offending vessel punishable</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">When an offense against this chapter shall have been committed by means of a vessel, or of any boat belonging to a vessel, the master of such vessel shall, unless some other person is shown to have been in charge of and navigating such vessel or boat, be deemed to have been in charge of and navigating the same, and be liable to be punished accordingly.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Feb. 29, 1888, ch. 17, § 9</ref>, <ref>25 Stat. 42</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 30.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Unless the context of this chapter otherwise requires, the term “vessel” shall be taken to mean every description of vessel used in navigation, in whatever way it is propelled; the term “master” shall be taken to include every person having command or charge of a vessel; and the term “person” to include a body of persons, corporate or incorporate. The term “convention” shall be taken to mean the International Convention for the Protection of Submarine Cables, made at Paris on the 14th day of May [March], 1884, and proclaimed by the President of the United States on the 22d day of May, 1885.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Feb. 29, 1888, ch. 17, § 10</ref>, <ref>25 Stat. 42</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 31.</num>
<heading> Summary trials</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The provisions of sections 391–396 of title 33 shall extend to the trial of offenses against the provisions of sections 24 and 25 of this title.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Feb. 29, 1888, ch. 17, § 11</ref>, <ref>25 Stat. 42</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 32.</num>
<heading> Application</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The provisions of this chapter shall be held to apply only to cables to which the convention for the time being applies.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Feb. 29, 1888, ch. 17, § 12</ref>, <ref>25 Stat. 42</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 33.</num>
<heading> Jurisdiction and venue of actions and offenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The district courts of the United States shall have jurisdiction over all offenses against this chapter and of all suits of a civil nature arising thereunder, whether the infraction complained of shall have been committed within the territorial waters of the United States or on board a vessel of the United States outside of said waters: <i>Provided</i>, That in case such infraction is committed outside of the territorial waters of the United States the vessel on board of which it has been committed is a vessel of the United States. From the decrees and judgments of the district courts in actions and suits arising under this chapter appeals and writs of error <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002002">1</ref> shall be allowed as now provided by law in other cases. Criminal actions and proceedings for a violation of the provisions of this chapter shall be commenced and prosecuted in the district court for the district within which the offense was committed, and when not committed within any judicial district, then in the district court for the district within which the offender may be found; and suits of a civil nature may be commenced in the district court for any district within which the defendant may be found and shall be served with process.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Feb. 29, 1888, ch. 17, § 13</ref>, <ref>25 Stat. 42</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 34.</num>
<heading> Licenses for landing or operating cables connecting United States with foreign country; necessity for</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No person shall land or operate in the United States any submarine cable directly or indirectly connecting the United States with any foreign country, or connecting one portion of the United States with any other portion thereof, unless a written license to land or operate such cable has been issued by the President of the United States. The conditions of sections 34 to 39 of this title shall not apply to cables, all of which, including both terminals, lie wholly within the continental United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 27, 1921, ch. 12, § 1</ref>, <ref>42 Stat. 8</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 35.</num>
<heading> Withholding or revoking of licenses by President; terms and conditions of licenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President may withhold or revoke such license when he shall be satisfied after due notice and hearing that such action will assist in securing rights for the landing or operation of cables in foreign countries, or in maintaining the rights or interests of the United States or of its citizens in foreign countries, or will promote the security of the United States, or may grant such license upon such terms as shall be necessary to assure just and reasonable rates and service in the operation and use of cables so licensed. The license shall not contain terms or conditions granting to the licensee exclusive rights of landing or of operation in the United States. Nothing herein contained shall be construed to limit the power and jurisdiction of the Federal Communications Commission with respect to the transmission of messages.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 27, 1921, ch. 12, § 2</ref>, <ref>42 Stat. 8</ref>; <ref>June 19, 1934, ch. 652</ref>, title VII, § 702(c), formerly title VI, § 602(c), <ref>48 Stat. 1102</ref>; renumbered <ref>Pub. L. 98–549, § 6(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2804</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 36.</num>
<heading> Preventing landing or operating of cables; injunction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President is empowered to prevent the landing of any cable about to be landed in violation of sections 34 to 39 of this title. When any such cable is about to be or is landed or is being operated without a license, any district court of the United States exercising jurisdiction in the district in which such cable is about to be or is landed, or any district court of the United States having jurisdiction of the parties, shall have jurisdiction, at the suit of the United States, to enjoin the landing or operation of such cable or to compel, by injunction, the removal thereof.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 27, 1921, ch. 12, § 3</ref>, <ref>42 Stat. 8</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 37.</num>
<heading> Violations; punishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever knowingly commits, instigates, or assists in any act forbidden by <ref>section 34 of this title</ref> shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and shall be fined not more than $5,000, or imprisoned for not more than one year, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 27, 1921, ch. 12, § 4</ref>, <ref>42 Stat. 8</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 38.</num>
<heading> “United States” defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The term “United States” as used in sections 34 to 39 of this title includes the Canal Zone and all territory continental or insular, subject to the jurisdiction of the United States of America.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 27, 1921, ch. 12, § 5</ref>, <ref>42 Stat. 8</ref>; Proc. No. 2695, eff. <date date="1946-07-04">July 4, 1946</date>, 11 F.R. 7517, <ref>60 Stat. 1352</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 39.</num>
<heading> Amendment, modification, etc., of rights granted</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No right shall accrue to any government, person, or corporation under the terms of sections 34 to 39 of this title that may not be rescinded, changed, modified, or amended by the Congress.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 27, 1921, ch. 12, § 6</ref>, <ref>42 Stat. 9</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>