<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 18—</num>
<heading>MILWAUKEE RAILROAD RESTRUCTURING</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 901.</num>
<heading> Congressional findings</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Congress hereby finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the severe operating losses and the deteriorating plant and equipment of the Milwaukee Railroad threaten to cause cessation of its operations in the near future;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a cessation of operations by the Milwaukee Railroad would have serious repercussions on the economies of the States in which such railroad principally operates (the States of Washington, Montana, Idaho, North Dakota, South Dakota, Illinois, Iowa, Missouri, Michigan, Indiana, Minnesota, and Wisconsin);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a cessation of operations of the Milwaukee Railroad would result in the loss of many thousands of jobs of railroad workers and other workers whose employment is dependent upon rail service over the lines presently operated by the Milwaukee Railroad;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> experienced railroad employees make a valuable contribution toward strengthening the railroad industry; and other railroads have the ability and willingness to employ displaced employees of the Milwaukee Railroad;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the ownership by employees or by employees and shippers of part or all of the Milwaukee Railroad may be a valuable tool in reorganization and should be given serious consideration;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> cessation of essential transportation services by the Milwaukee Railroad would endanger the public welfare;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> cessation of such services is imminent; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> there is no other practicable means of obtaining funds to meet payroll and other expenses necessary for continuation of services and reorganization of the Milwaukee Railroad.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Congress declares that emergency measures set forth in this chapter must be taken to restructure the Milwaukee Railroad and to avoid the potential unemployment and damage to the economy of the region and of the Nation which a cessation of essential services by the Milwaukee Railroad would otherwise cause.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–101, § 2</ref>, <date date="1979-11-04">Nov. 4, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 736</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 902.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “bankruptcy court” means the court having jurisdiction over the reorganization of the Milwaukee Railroad;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “Board” means the Railroad Retirement Board;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “Commission” means the Interstate Commerce Commission;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> the term “employee”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> includes any employee of the Milwaukee Railroad who worked on a line of such railroad the sale of which became effective on <date date="1979-10-01">October 1, 1979</date>; but</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> does not include any individual serving as president, vice-president, secretary, treasurer, comptroller, counsel, member of the board of directors, or any other person performing such functions;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the term “Milwaukee Railroad” means the Chicago, Milwaukee, St. Paul and Pacific Railroad Company; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the term “restructured Milwaukee Railroad” means the entity that is designated as the reorganized railroad under the reorganization plan for the Milwaukee Railroad finally certified by the Commission.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–101, § 3</ref>, <date date="1979-11-04">Nov. 4, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 736</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–254, title I, § 123</ref>, <date date="1980-05-30">May 30, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 409</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 903.</num>
<heading> Sales and transfers</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Milwaukee Railroad may negotiate and enter into agreements to sell, to another rail carrier or any other person, all or any portion of its rail properties used in railroad operations as of <date date="1979-10-15">October 15, 1979</date>. Such sale agreements may in no event become final and effective until the occurrence of an event described in <ref>section 920(b) of this title</ref>, or <date date="1980-04-01">April 1, 1980</date>, whichever first occurs. In taking action under this subsection, the Milwaukee Railroad may consult with the Secretary of Transportation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Transportation, under the authority of <ref>section 333 of title 49</ref>, may develop plans, participate in negotiations, and recommend to the trustee proposals for the sale or transfer of any rail properties of the Milwaukee Railroad which are used in rail operations as of <date date="1979-10-15">October 15, 1979</date>. In taking action under this paragraph, the Secretary shall give preference to financially responsible persons, including governmental entities, negotiating for the purchase of any lines with the intent of providing common carrier service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any sale or transfer proposal developed under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be submitted to the bankruptcy court. Such a proposal may in no event become final or effective until the occurrence of an event described in <ref>section 920(b) of this title</ref>, or <date date="1980-04-01">April 1, 1980</date>, whichever first occurs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–101, § 4</ref>, <date date="1979-11-04">Nov. 4, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 737</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 904.</num>
<heading> Court approved abandonments and sales</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Abandonment of lines of railroad under <ref>section 1170 of title 11</ref></heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Upon the occurrence of an event described in <ref>section 920(b) of this title</ref>, or on <date date="1980-04-01">April 1, 1980</date>, whichever first occurs, the bankruptcy court may authorize the abandonment of lines of the Milwaukee Railroad pursuant to <ref>section 1170 of title 11</ref>. Pending the expiration of the time for appeal of an abandonment order or the determination of any such appeal, the bankruptcy court may authorize the termination of service on a line to be abandoned, and the order authorizing such termination may not be stayed. In authorizing any abandonment pursuant to this section, the court shall require the carrier to provide a fair arrangement at least as protective of the interests of employees as that required under section 11347 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002069">1</ref> of title 49.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Prior to the date specified in paragraph (1) of this subsection, the bankruptcy court may hear and consider any request for the abandonment of lines of the Milwaukee Railroad, and may fix the time for the Commission’s report on the request, but it may take final action authorizing such abandonment only in accordance with such paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sale or transfer of lines of railroad</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Upon the occurrence of an event described in <ref>section 920(b) of this title</ref>, or on <date date="1980-04-01">April 1, 1980</date>, whichever first occurs, the bankruptcy court may authorize the sale or transfer of a line of the Milwaukee Railroad to be used in continued rail operations, subject to the approval of the Commission under paragraph (2) of this subsection. In authorizing any such sale or transfer, the court shall provide a fair arrangement at least as protective of the interest <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002070">2</ref> of employees as that required under section 11347 <sup>1</sup> of title 49.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The bankruptcy court may not authorize a sale or transfer pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection unless an appropriate application with respect to such sale or transfer is initiated with the Commission and, within such time as the court may fix, not exceeding 180 days, the Commission, with or without a hearing, as the Commission may determine, and with or without modification or condition, approves such application, or does not act on such application. Any action or order of the Commission approving, modifying, conditioning, or disapproving such application is subject to review by the court only under sections 706(2)(A), 706(2)(B), 706(2)(C), and 706(2)(D) of title 5. An application may be initiated with the Commission prior to the date specified in paragraph (1) of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Pending review of an application by the Commission pursuant to paragraph (2) of this subsection, the bankruptcy court may, on a preliminary basis, authorize the sale or transfer of lines of the Milwaukee Railroad to another rail carrier. The court may permit the purchasing carrier to operate interim service as a common carrier over the lines to be purchased, without regard to <ref>section 10901 of title 49</ref>. In operating such service, the purchasing carrier shall use employees of the Milwaukee Railroad to the extent necessary for the operation of such service. The bankruptcy court may take final action authorizing any such sale or transfer only in accordance with paragraph (1) of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect on priorities and timing of employee protection payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall be deemed to affect the priorities or timing of payment of employee protection which might have existed in the absence of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–101, § 5</ref>, <date date="1979-11-04">Nov. 4, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 737</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 905.</num>
<heading> Employee or employee-shipper ownership plan</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Submission of plan to Commission; approval; findings</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> No later than <date date="1979-12-01">December 1, 1979</date>, an association composed of representatives of national railway labor organizations, employee coalitions, and shippers (or any combination of the foregoing) may submit to the Commission a single plan for converting all or a substantial part of the Milwaukee Railroad into an employee or employee-shipper owned company and a method for implementing such plan. The plan shall include a comprehensive evaluation of the prospects for the financial self-sustainability of the Milwaukee Railroad.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Commission shall, within 30 days after the date of submission of a plan under paragraph (1) of this subsection, approve the proposed plan if it finds that such plan is feasible. The finding of the Commission with respect to the feasibility of the plan shall be made pursuant to <ref>section 554 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The Commission shall make a finding that the plan submitted under this section is feasible if it determines that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> adequate public and private financing is available to the proponents of such plan;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> such plan is fair and equitable to the estate of the Milwaukee Railroad;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> implementation of such plan will occur by <date date="1980-04-01">April 1, 1980</date>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the railroad proposed to be operated under the plan can be operated on a self-sustaining basis; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the plan contains an assessment of all operating practices, and includes agreements by labor and management to make implementing changes designed to achieve labor productivity increases (which may include changes in work rules to increase productivity) consistent with safe operations and adequate service.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">For purposes of the determinations under this paragraph, adequate financing shall include all sources of private funds, the probable value and priority of valid claims against the estate, and Federal, State, or local funds available under programs (in existence as of <date date="1980-01-01">January 1, 1980</date>) which are or will be available to the proponent and which the proponent is likely to obtain.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Submission of findings to bankruptcy court</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the Commission finds that the plan submitted under this section is feasible, it shall submit its finding to the bankruptcy court. Within 10 days after the date of such submission, the bankruptcy court shall, after a hearing, determine whether such plan is fair and equitable to the estate of the Milwaukee Railroad. The Commission’s determination with respect to that issue shall be rebutted only by clear and convincing evidence.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementation of plan</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the Commission finds that the plan is feasible and the bankruptcy court determines that the plan is fair and equitable to the estate of the Milwaukee Railroad, the proponents of such plan shall implement the plan no later than <date date="1980-04-01">April 1, 1980</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Judicial review</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as provided in this section, the findings of the Commission with respect to the plan shall not be subject to review.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Furnishing of reports and other information for preparation of plan</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The trustee of the Milwaukee Railroad shall promptly provide to the person engaged in developing the employee or employee and shipper ownership plan under this section—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> its most recent reports on the physical condition of the railroad; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> traffic, revenue, marketing, and other data necessary to determine the amount of the acquisition cost of the railroad or portion of the railroad that would be required to continue rail transportation over the railroad line.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Information provided pursuant to this subsection shall be used only for purposes of preparing a plan and shall not be disclosed to any competitor or, unless necessary in connection with the preparation of the plan, to any customer of the Milwaukee Railroad.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–101, § 6</ref>, <date date="1979-11-04">Nov. 4, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 738</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 906.</num>
<heading> Guarantee of trustee certificates</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> to (c) Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Transportation shall, under the authority of the Emergency Rail Services Act of 1970 [<ref>45 U.S.C. 661</ref> et seq.], immediately guarantee trustee certificates of the Milwaukee Railroad, on the basis of an estimate of the amount required to be provided under subsection (e) of this section, for purposes of allowing the Milwaukee Railroad, commencing <date date="1979-11-01">November 1, 1979</date>, to maintain its entire railroad system in accordance with <ref>section 920 of this title</ref>, and as required to finance operations which the Milwaukee Railroad continues for the 60-day period beginning on the date of the occurrence of an event described in <ref>section 920(b) of this title</ref> or on <date date="1980-04-01">April 1, 1980</date>, whichever first occurs. Such guarantee shall be made without regard to the findings set forth in section 3(a) of the Emergency Rail Services Act of 1970 [<ref>45 U.S.C. 662(a)</ref>], and the provisions of section 3(b)(3) [<ref>45 U.S.C. 662(b)(3)</ref>] and the last two sentences of section 3(d) of such Act [<ref>45 U.S.C. 662(d)</ref>] shall not apply to such guarantee.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amount of guarantee</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall guarantee trustee certificates of the Milwaukee Railroad pursuant to this section in an amount equal to the difference between (1) the total expenses incurred by such railroad attributable to the maintenance and the continuation of service in accordance with subsection (d) of this section, and (2) the revenues of such railroad.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Subordination of claims</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding the provisions of section 3(c) of the Emergency Rail Services Act of 1970 [<ref>45 U.S.C. 662(c)</ref>], certificates guaranteed under this chapter shall be subordinated to the claims of any creditors of the Milwaukee Railroad as of <date date="1979-11-04">November 4, 1979</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission shall immediately make available to the Secretary of Transportation the sum of $10,000,000, out of funds available for directed service under title 49. The Secretary of Transportation shall immediately make such funds available to the trustee of the Milwaukee Railroad for purposes of financing the operations of the Milwaukee Railroad, beginning <date date="1979-11-01">November 1, 1979</date>, in accordance with <ref>section 920 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cancellation of United States obligations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> All obligations to the United States or any agency or instrumentality of the United States incurred pursuant to this section by the Milwaukee Railroad or the trustee of the property of the Milwaukee Railroad shall be waived and canceled when—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Milwaukee Railroad is reorganized as an operating rail carrier; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> substantially all of the Milwaukee Railroad is purchased.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> For purposes of this subsection, substantially all of the Milwaukee Railroad shall be considered as having been purchased when (A) more than 50 percent of the rail system operated by the Milwaukee Railroad on <date date="1980-10-14">October 14, 1980</date>, has been purchased, and (B) more than 50 percent of the employees employed by the Milwaukee Railroad on <date date="1980-10-14">October 14, 1980</date>, have obtained employment with other rail carriers.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–101, § 7</ref>(less (a)–(c)), <date date="1979-11-04">Nov. 4, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 740</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–448, title VII, § 701(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-14">Oct. 14, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1961</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 907.</num>
<heading> Railroad hiring</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each person who is an employee of the Milwaukee Railroad on <date date="1979-09-30">September 30, 1979</date>, and who is separated or furloughed from his employment with such railroad (other than for cause) prior to <date date="1984-04-01">April 1, 1984</date>, as a result of a reduction of service by such railroad shall, unless found to be less qualified than other applicants, have the first right of hire by any other rail carrier that is subject to regulation by the Commission for any vacancy that is not covered by (1) an affirmative action plan, or a hiring plan designed to eliminate discrimination, that is required by Federal or State statute, regulation, or executive order, or by the order of a Federal court or agency, or (2) a permissible voluntary affirmative action plan. For purposes of this section, a rail carrier shall not be considered to be hiring new employees when it recalls any of its own furloughed employees.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–101, § 8</ref>, <date date="1979-11-04">Nov. 4, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 740</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–468, title II, § 236(a)</ref>, <date date="1983-01-14">Jan. 14, 1983</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2547</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 908.</num>
<heading> Employee protection agreements</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agreement between Milwaukee Railroad and labor organizations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Milwaukee Railroad and labor organizations representing the employees of such railroad may, not later than 20 days after <date date="1979-11-04">November 4, 1979</date>, enter into an agreement providing protection for employees of such railroad who are adversely affected as a result of a reduction in service by such railroad or a restructuring transaction carried out by such railroad. Such employee protection may include, but need not be limited to, interim employee assistance, moving expenses, employee relocation incentive compensation, and separation allowances.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Submission of matter to National Mediation Board</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the Milwaukee Railroad and the labor organizations representing the employees of such railroad are unable to enter into an employee protection agreement under subsection (a) of this section within 20 days after <date date="1979-11-04">November 4, 1979</date>, the parties shall immediately submit the matter to the National Mediation Board. The National Mediation Board shall attempt, by mediation, to bring the parties to an agreement with respect to employee protection no later than 40 days after <date date="1979-11-04">November 4, 1979</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fair and equitable agreements</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> If the National Mediation Board is unable to bring the parties to an agreement under subsection (b) of this section within 40 days after <date date="1979-11-04">November 4, 1979</date>, the Milwaukee Railroad and the labor organizations representing the employees of such railroad shall immediately enter into an employee protection agreement that is fair and equitable.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If an employee protection agreement is entered into under this subsection, any claim of an employee for benefits and allowances under such agreement shall be filed with the Board in such time and manner as the Board by regulation shall prescribe. The Board shall determine the amount for which such employee is eligible under such agreement and shall certify such amount to the Milwaukee Railroad for payment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payment of benefits and allowances</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Benefits and allowances under an employee protection agreement entered into under this section shall be paid by the Milwaukee Railroad in accordance with <ref>section 914 of this title</ref>, and claims of employees for such benefits and allowances shall be treated as administrative expenses of the estate of the Milwaukee Railroad.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–101, § 9</ref>, <date date="1979-11-04">Nov. 4, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 741</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 909.</num>
<heading> Supplementary unemployment insurance</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible employees</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Any employee of the Milwaukee Railroad—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> who (A) is employed by the restructured Milwaukee Railroad, and (B) is separated from that employment by reason of any reduction in service by such railroad prior to <date date="1984-04-01">April 1, 1984</date>; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> who (A) is separated from his employment with the Milwaukee Railroad in connection with a restructuring transaction carried out by such railroad, and obtains employment, prior to <date date="1981-04-01">April 1, 1981</date>, with another rail carrier, and (B) is separated from employment with such other carrier prior to <date date="1984-04-01">April 1, 1984</date>,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be entitled to receive monthly supplementary unemployment insurance in accordance with the provisions of this section.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Period of payment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each employee described in subsection (a) of this section shall be entitled to receive supplementary unemployment insurance during each month in which such employee is not employed, for all or a portion of such month, by the Milwaukee Railroad or another rail carrier. Each such employee shall be entitled to receive such insurance for a total of not more than 36 months, except that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the period of entitlement for assistance under this section shall not exceed the employee’s total months of service with the Milwaukee Railroad; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> no compensation shall be provided under this section after <date date="1984-04-01">April 1, 1984</date>, unless it is necessary in order to provide an employee with at least 8 months of such insurance, but after such date, such employee only shall receive such 8-month minimum if such employee is not employed continuously after such date.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amount of payment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Supplementary unemployment insurance under this section shall be payable to an employee on a monthly basis in an amount equal to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> eighty percent of such employee’s average monthly normal compensation from employment with the Milwaukee Railroad during the period beginning <date date="1977-06-01">June 1, 1977</date>, and ending on <date date="1979-11-04">November 4, 1979</date>, less</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the sum of (A) the amount of any benefits payable to such employee for such month under the Railroad Unemployment Insurance Act [<ref>45 U.S.C. 351</ref> et seq.] or under any State unemployment insurance program, and (B) the amount of any earnings of such employee for such month from employment or self-employment of any kind.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Filing of application</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An application for supplementary unemployment insurance shall be filed with the Board in such time and manner as the Board by regulation shall prescribe.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Insurance as compensation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Any supplementary unemployment insurance received by any employee pursuant to this section shall be considered to be compensation solely—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> for purposes of the Railroad Retirement Act of 1974 (<ref>45 U.S.C. 231</ref> et seq.); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> for purposes of determining the compensation received by such employee in any base year under the Railroad Unemployment Insurance Act [<ref>45 U.S.C. 351</ref> et seq.].</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Employees not covered</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The provisions of this section shall not apply to an employee in the event of his resignation, retirement, or discharge for cause from the employment of any rail carrier.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> An employee shall not be entitled to receive supplementary unemployment insurance under this section if he has failed to exhaust all seniority rights or other employment rights under applicable collective bargaining agreements.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> An employee shall not be entitled to receive supplementary unemployment insurance under this section for any month or portion of a month in which such employee is unemployed due to normal seasonal unemployment patterns in the railroad industry.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Furloughed employees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this section, any employee of the Milwaukee Railroad who is furloughed shall be considered to be separated from his employment.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–101, § 10(a)</ref>–(g), <date date="1979-11-04">Nov. 4, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 741</ref>, 742.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 910.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 97–35, title XI, § 1144(b)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 669</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 911.</num>
<heading> New career training assistance</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible employees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any employee who elects to receive a separation allowance from the Milwaukee Railroad under an employee protection agreement entered into under <ref>section 908 of this title</ref> shall be entitled to receive from the Board expenses for training in qualified institutions for new career opportunities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Commencement of training as condition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To be entitled for assistance under this section, an employee must begin his course of training within two years following the date of his separation from employment with the Milwaukee Railroad.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Filing of application; Board determination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Entitlement to expenses for assistance under this section shall be determined by the Board on the basis of an application therefor filed by an employee with the Board.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistance prohibited after <date date="1984-04-01">April 1, 1984</date></heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No assistance may be provided under this section after <date date="1984-04-01">April 1, 1984</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “expenses” means actual expenses paid for room, board, tuition, fees, or educational material in an amount not to exceed $3,000; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “qualified institution” means an educational institution accredited for payment by the Veterans’ Administration under chapter 36 of title 38, or a State-accredited institution which has been in existence for not less than two years.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–101, § 12</ref>, <date date="1979-11-04">Nov. 4, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 743</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–254, title I, § 119(f)</ref>, <date date="1980-05-30">May 30, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 408</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 912.</num>
<heading> Election</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any employee who receives any assistance under section 909 or <ref>section 911 of this title</ref> or under an employee protection agreement entered into under <ref>section 908 of this title</ref> shall be deemed to waive any employee protection benefits otherwise available to such employee under the Bankruptcy Act, subtitle IV of title 49, or any applicable contract or agreement.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–101, § 13</ref>, <date date="1979-11-04">Nov. 4, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 743</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 913.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> There is authorized to be appropriated to provide supplementary unemployment insurance under <ref>section 909 of this title</ref> not to exceed $5,000,000.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> There is authorized to be appropriated for new career training assistance under <ref>section 911 of this title</ref> not to exceed $1,500,000.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> There is authorized to be appropriated to the Board to carry out its administrative expenses under this chapter and the Rock Island Railroad Transition and Employee Assistance Act [<ref>45 U.S.C. 1001</ref> et seq.] not to exceed $750,000. Effective <date date="1980-10-01">October 1, 1980</date>, there is authorized to be appropriated to the Board an additional $1,000,000 to carry out its administrative expenses under this chapter and the Rock Island Railroad Transition and Employee Assistance Act [<ref>45 U.S.C. 1001</ref> et seq.].</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> There are authorized to be appropriated $15,000,000 for purposes of providing transaction assistance in accordance with section 825(h)(1)(A) and (B) of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> Amounts appropriated under this section are authorized to remain available until expended.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–101, § 14</ref>, <date date="1979-11-04">Nov. 4, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 743</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–254, title I, § 109</ref>, <date date="1980-05-30">May 30, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 403</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–448, title VII, § 701(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-14">Oct. 14, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1961</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–468, title II, § 234(b)</ref>, <date date="1983-01-14">Jan. 14, 1983</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2547</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 914.</num>
<heading> Obligation guarantees</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Transportation, under the authority of <ref>section 831 of this title</ref>, shall guarantee obligations of the Milwaukee Railroad for purposes of providing employee protection in accordance with the terms of the employee protection agreement entered into under <ref>section 908 of this title</ref>. Guarantees under this section shall be entered into without regard to the requirements of subsection (g) of <ref>section 831 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Obligations as administrative expense</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any obligation guaranteed pursuant to this section shall be treated as an administrative expense of the estate of the Milwaukee Railroad.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limit on aggregate unpaid principal amount</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The aggregate unpaid principal amount of obligations which may be guaranteed by the Secretary pursuant to this section shall not exceed $75,000,000.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limit on total liability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The total liability of the Milwaukee Railroad in connection with benefits and allowances provided under an employee protection agreement entered into under <ref>section 908 of this title</ref> shall not exceed $75,000,000.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Liability of United States respecting section 908 agreements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except in connection with obligations guaranteed under this section, the United States shall incur no liability to employees in connection with any employee protection agreement entered into under <ref>section 908 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability of <ref>section 22404 of title 49</ref></heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0"><ref>Section 22404 of title 49</ref> shall not apply to any obligation guaranteed under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–101, § 15</ref>, <date date="1979-11-04">Nov. 4, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 743</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–448, title VII, § 701(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-14">Oct. 14, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1959</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–58, div. B, title I, § 21301(j)(3)(E)</ref>, <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 692</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 915.</num>
<heading> Court approved abandonment and sales in pending cases</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Abandonment of lines of railroad under Bankruptcy Act</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, in any case pending under section 77 of the Bankruptcy Act on <date date="1979-11-04">November 4, 1979</date>, the court may authorize the abandonment of lines of railroad pursuant to <ref>section 1170 of title 11</ref>. Pending the expiration of the time for appeal of an abandonment order or the determination of any such appeal, the court may authorize the termination of service on a line to be abandoned, and the order authorizing such termination may not be stayed. In authorizing any abandonment pursuant to this section, the court shall require the carrier to provide a fair arrangement at least as protective of the interests of employees as that required under section 11347 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002071">1</ref> of title 49.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sale or transfer of lines of railroad under Bankruptcy Act</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, in any case pending under section 77 of the Bankruptcy Act on <date date="1979-11-04">November 4, 1979</date>, the court may authorize the sale or transfer of a line of railroad to be used in continued rail operations, subject to the approval of the Commission under paragraph (2) of this subsection, if the application with respect to such sale or transfer is filed with the Commission on or after <date date="1979-11-01">November 1, 1979</date>. In authorizing any such sale or transfer, the court shall provide a fair arrangement at least as protective of the interests of employees as that required under section 11347 <sup>1</sup> of title 49.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The court described in paragraph (1) may not authorize a sale or transfer pursuant to such paragraph unless an appropriate application with respect to such sale or transfer is initiated with the Commission and, within such time as the court may fix, not exceeding 180 days, the Commission, with or without a hearing, as the Commission may determine, and with or without modification or condition, approves such application, or does not act on such application. Any action or order of the Commission approving, modifying, conditioning, or disapproving such application is subject to review by the court only under sections 706(2)(A), 706(2)(B), 706(2)(C), and 706(2)(D) of title 5.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> If a person has made or makes an offer to acquire from a carrier subject to liquidation a rail line or lines over which no service is provided by that carrier, and that offer has been or is rejected by the trustee in bankruptcy of such carrier, such person may submit an application to the Commission seeking approval of such person’s acquisition of such line or lines. A copy of any such application shall be filed simultaneously with the court.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> The Commission shall, within 15 days after the filing of an application under subparagraph (A) of this paragraph, determine whether the applicant—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is a financially responsible person; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> has made a bona fide offer to acquire the line or lines under reasonable terms.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> If the Commission’s determination under subparagraph (B) of this paragraph is affirmative with respect to the matters referred to in clauses (i) and (ii) of such subparagraph, the applicant and the trustee in bankruptcy (hereafter in this paragraph referred to collectively as the “parties”) shall enter into negotiations with respect to terms for the acquisition of the line or lines applied for. If the parties at any time agree on such terms, a request for approval of the acquisition shall be filed with the Commission and the court. If the parties are unable to agree to such terms within 30 days after the date of the Commission’s determination under subparagraph (B) of this paragraph, either party may, within 60 days after the expiration of such 30-day period, request the Commission to prescribe terms for such acquisition, including compensation for the line or lines to be acquired. The Commission shall prescribe such terms within 60 days after any such request is made. The terms prescribed by the Commission shall be binding upon both parties, subject to court review as provided in subparagraph (D) of this paragraph, except that the applicant may withdraw its offer within 10 days after the Commission prescribes such terms.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> If more than one applicant has requested under this subparagraph that the Commission prescribe the terms of acquisition for the same or overlapping lines or portions of such lines, the Commission shall prescribe terms for such acquisition which it determines best serve the public interest.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(D)</num>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Within 15 days after the Commission prescribes terms under subparagraph (C) of this paragraph, the Commission shall transmit such terms to the court, unless the offer is withdrawn under such subparagraph. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the court shall, within 60 days after such transmittal, approve the acquisition under terms prescribed by the Commission if the compensation for the line or lines is not less than that required as a constitutional minimum.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Except as provided in this subparagraph, no action shall be taken by the court which would prejudice the acquisition which is the subject of an application under this paragraph.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The Commission shall require that any person acquiring a line or lines under this paragraph use, to the maximum extent practicable, employees or former employees of the carrier subject to liquidation in the operation of service on such line or lines.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> No person acquiring a line under this paragraph may transfer or discontinue service on such line prior to the expiration of 4 years after such acquisition.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> The Commission shall, within 45 days after <date date="1983-01-14">January 14, 1983</date>, prescribe such regulations and procedures as are necessary to carry out the provisions of this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(H)</num>
<chapeau> As used in this paragraph, the term—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> “carrier subject to liquidation” means a carrier which, on <date date="1983-01-14">January 14, 1983</date>, was the subject of a proceeding pending under section 77 of the Bankruptcy Act or under subchapter IV of chapter 11 of title 11 and which has been ordered by the court to liquidate its properties;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> “the court” means the court having bankruptcy jurisdiction over the carrier subject to liquidation; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> “financially responsible person” means a person capable of compensating the carrier subject to liquidation for the acquisition of the line or lines proposed to be acquired and able to cover expenses associated with providing service over such line or lines for a period of not less than 4 years.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Pending review of an application by the Commission pursuant to paragraph (2) of this subsection, the court described in paragraph (1) may, on a preliminary basis, authorize the sale or transfer proposed in such application. The court may permit the purchasing carrier to operate interim service over the lines to be purchased, and in operating such service it shall use employees of the carrier subject to the bankruptcy proceeding to the extent such purchasing carrier deems necessary for the operation of such service.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Judicial review</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Any action or order of the Commission approving, modifying, conditioning, or disapproving an application for the sale or transfer of rail property that is filed with the Commission before <date date="1979-11-01">November 1, 1979</date>, in connection with a case pending under section 77 of the Bankruptcy Act on <date date="1979-11-04">November 4, 1979</date>—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> is subject to review by the court only under sections 706(2)(A), 706(2)(B), 706(2)(C), and 706(2)(D) of title 5; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> may not be stayed by the Commission.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority of bankruptcy court</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The authority of the bankruptcy court to authorize abandonments, sales, and transfers of lines of the Milwaukee Railroad shall be governed by the provisions of <ref>section 904 of this title</ref>, rather than the provisions of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect on priorities and timing of employee protection payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall be deemed to affect the priorities or timing of payment of employee protection which might have existed in the absence of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–101, § 17</ref>, <date date="1979-11-04">Nov. 4, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 744</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–468, title II, § 213</ref>, <date date="1983-01-14">Jan. 14, 1983</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2544</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 916.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title III, § 328</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 952</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 917.</num>
<heading> Applicability of National Environmental Policy Act</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The provisions of the National Environmental Policy Act [<ref>42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.] shall not apply to transactions carried out pursuant to this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–101, § 19</ref>, <date date="1979-11-04">Nov. 4, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 746</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 918.</num>
<heading> Authority of Railroad Retirement Board</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Board may prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to carry out its duties under this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> In carrying out its duties under this chapter, the Board may exercise such of the powers, duties, and remedies provided in subsections (a), (b), and (d) of <ref>section 362 of this title</ref> as are not inconsistent with the provisions of this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–101, § 20</ref>, <date date="1979-11-04">Nov. 4, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 746</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 919.</num>
<heading> Publications and reports</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Within 30 days after <date date="1979-11-04">November 4, 1979</date>, the Board shall publish, and make available for distribution by the Milwaukee Railroad to all its employees, a document which describes in detail the rights of such employees under sections 907, 908, 909, 910,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002072">1</ref> and 911 of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> During the 2-year period beginning on <date date="1979-11-04">November 4, 1979</date>, the Board shall submit a report to the Congress every 6 months describing its activities under this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–101, § 21</ref>, <date date="1979-11-04">Nov. 4, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 746</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 920.</num>
<heading> Continuation of service</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Until the occurrence of an event described in subsection (b) of this section, the Milwaukee Railroad (1) shall maintain its entire railroad system, as it existed on <date date="1979-10-15">October 15, 1979</date>, (2) shall continue no less than the regular level of service provided by it as of that date, and (3) shall not embargo traffic (other than when necessitated by acts of God or safety requirements) or abandon or discontinue service over any part of its railroad system.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> The Milwaukee Railroad shall comply with the requirements of subsection (a) of this section until—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an employee or employee-shipper ownership plan is not submitted to the Interstate Commerce Commission within the time period prescribed under <ref>section 905(a) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the proposed plan is found by the Commission not to be feasible or the Commission does not act within 30 days;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the proposed plan is found by the bankruptcy court not to be fair and equitable to the estate of the Milwaukee Railroad; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the plan is not implemented within the time period prescribed under <ref>section 905(c) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–101, § 22</ref>, <date date="1979-11-04">Nov. 4, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 746</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 921.</num>
<heading> Office of Rail Public Counsel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Office of Rail Public Counsel may appear and be heard in the case in the bankruptcy court involving the reorganization of the Milwaukee Railroad, for purposes of representing affected shippers, localities, and municipalities with respect to the proposed abandonment of any line of the Milwaukee Railroad.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–101, § 25</ref>, <date date="1979-11-04">Nov. 4, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 747</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 922.</num>
<heading> Employee stock ownership plan for surviving portion of Milwaukee Railroad</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If an event described in <ref>section 920(b) of this title</ref> occurs, resulting in the survival of less than the entire Milwaukee Railroad system, then any relief provided for such surviving Milwaukee Railroad system under the Emergency Rail Services Act of 1970 [<ref>45 U.S.C. 661</ref> et seq.] or any other Federal legislation shall be conditioned upon good faith efforts by the trustee or the Milwaukee Railroad, or both, to establish an employee stock ownership plan which shall embrace the purchase or acquisition of qualifying employer securities of the Milwaukee Railroad equal in value to 25 per centum of the amount of such relief provided.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–101, § 26</ref>, <date date="1979-11-04">Nov. 4, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 747</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>