<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 19—</num>
<heading>ROCK ISLAND RAILROAD EMPLOYEE ASSISTANCE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1001.</num>
<heading> Congressional findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Congress hereby finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> uninterrupted continuation of services over Rock Island lines is dependent on adequate employee protection provisions covering Rock Island Railroad employees who are not hired by other railroads;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> for those Rock Island Railroad employees not hired by other rail carriers, there is no other practicable means of obtaining funds to meet the necessary costs of such employee protection that are assumed by the Rock Island Railroad;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a cessation of necessary operations of the Rock Island Railroad would have serious repercussions on the economies of the States in which such railroad principally operates; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> premature cessation of services over lines which are the subject of pending purchase application would result in harm to the shipping public and could imperil continuation of vital commuter service.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–254, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1980-05-30">May 30, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 399</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1002.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this chapter, the term—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “bankruptcy court” means the court having jurisdiction over the reorganization of the Rock Island Railroad;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> “Board” means the Railroad Retirement Board;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> “Commission” means the Interstate Commerce Commission;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> “employee” includes any employee of the Rock Island Railroad as of <date date="1979-08-01">August 1, 1979</date>, but does not include any individual serving as president, vice-president, secretary, treasurer, comptroller, counsel, member of the board of directors, or any other person performing such functions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the term “Rock Island Railroad” means the Chicago, Rock Island and Pacific Railroad Company, the estate of such Company in its reorganization proceeding, or the trustee appointed in such proceeding; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Transportation.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–254, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1980-05-30">May 30, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 399</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–448, title VII, § 701(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-14">Oct. 14, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1960</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1003.</num>
<heading> Service continuation</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Situations requiring directed service; time period</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Notwithstanding the provisions of <ref>Public Law 96–131</ref>, the Commission shall order directed service for a period of not to exceed 90 days over any line of the Rock Island Railroad if the Secretary finds and certifies to the Commission that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a lack of rail service exists which cannot be resolved by a grant of interim operating authority over such line and grains or foods are ready to be shipped to market; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a lack of rail service exists which cannot be resolved by a grant of interim operating authority over such line and a rail carrier, shipper, State, or other interested party has expressed in writing to the Secretary an interest in purchasing, leasing, or rehabilitating the particular rail line or facility for purposes of providing rail services, and there is a reasonable expectation that such transaction will be consummated.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability of funds</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Not more than $15,000,000 of the funds available for expenditure by the Secretary out of the Railroad Rehabilitation and Improvement Fund established under chapter 224 of title 49 may be made available by the Secretary to the Commission for purposes of providing directed service under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Funds may be made available for directed service under this section without regard to the findings of the Secretary required under chapter 224 of title 49, including section 22404 of such title, shall not apply to any directed service provided with such funds.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Continuation of compensation terms for trackage rights, joint facilities, etc.</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The terms of compensation for all trackage rights, joint facilities, and similar arrangements between other rail carriers and the trustee of the Rock Island Railroad which are in effect on or after <date date="1980-03-15">March 15, 1980</date>, on portions of the lines of the Rock Island Railroad involved in temporary emergency operations shall be continued in effect during the duration of the temporary emergency operating authority with the carrier providing temporary emergency service substituting for the trustee, except where the Rock Island Railroad has been given more favorable treatment by virtue of its bankruptcy. Such continuation shall not alter or affect the ultimate rights of other rail carriers under trackage rights, joint facilities, or similar arrangements nor prejudice the ultimate determination of any controversy or proceeding concerning rights of the parties with regard to assignment by the trustee of rights in or to the facilities or under the arrangements.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–254, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="1980-05-30">May 30, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 400</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title III, § 329(1)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 952</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–58, div. B, title I, § 21301(j)(3)(F)</ref>, <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 692</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1004.</num>
<heading> Railroad hiring</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Each person who is an employee of the Rock Island Railroad on <date date="1979-08-01">August 1, 1979</date>, and who, prior to <date date="1984-01-01">January 1, 1984</date>, is separated or furloughed (other than for cause) from his employment with such railroad, or from his employment with another rail carrier providing temporary service over lines of the Rock Island Railroad, as a result of a reduction of service by such railroad or such temporary service carrier shall, unless found to be less qualified than other applicants, have the first right of hire by any other rail carrier that is subject to regulation by the Commission for any vacancy that is not covered by (1) an affirmative action plan, or a hiring plan designed to eliminate discrimination, that is required by Federal or State statute, regulations, or Executive order, or by the order of a Federal or State court or agency, or (2) a permissible voluntary affirmative action plan. For purposes of this section, a rail carrier shall not be considered to be hiring new employees when it recalls any of its own furloughed employees.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The rights afforded to Rock Island Railroad employees by this section shall be coequal to the rights afforded to Chicago, Milwaukee, Saint Paul and Pacific Railroad Company employees by <ref>section 907 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–254, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1980-05-30">May 30, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 400</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–468, title II, § 236(b)</ref>, <date date="1983-01-14">Jan. 14, 1983</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2547</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1005.</num>
<heading> Employee protection agreement</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization; time for agreement; use of funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary and the representatives of the various classes and crafts of employees of the Rock Island Railroad shall, not later than 90 days after <date date="1983-01-14">January 14, 1983</date>, enter into an agreement providing protection for employees of the Rock Island Railroad who are adversely affected as a result of a reduction in service by such Railroad. Such agreement may provide for the use of funds described in subsection (c) of this section for the following purposes:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Subsistence allowances to employees.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Moving expenses for employees who must make a change in residence.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Retraining expenses for employees who are seeking employment in new areas.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Separation allowances for employees.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Health and welfare insurance premiums.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Such other purposes as may be agreed upon by the parties.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Failure to reach agreement; benefit schedule</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the parties are unable to reach agreement within the time period specified in subsection (a) of this section, the Secretary shall, within 30 days after the expiration of such time period, prescribe a schedule of benefits for employee protection not inconsistent with the provisions of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations on funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any agreement entered into under subsection (a) of this section, and any benefit schedule prescribed under subsection (b) of this section, shall not require the expenditure of funds in excess of amounts authorized to be appropriated under <ref>section 727(f)(1)(C) of this title</ref>, nor shall any individual employee receive benefits in excess of $20,000 under such agreement or benefit schedule. No benefits or assistance may be provided under any agreement entered into or benefit schedule prescribed under this section after <date date="1984-04-01">April 1, 1984</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administration of funds; promulgation of regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Board shall, in such manner as it shall prescribe by regulation, administer the distribution of funds under any agreement entered into or benefit schedule prescribed under this section, and shall determine the amount for which each employee is eligible under such agreement or benefit schedule. Such regulation shall include procedures to resolve by final and binding arbitration any dispute over an employee’s eligibility or claim.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–254, title I, § 106</ref>, <date date="1980-05-30">May 30, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 401</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–448, title VII, § 701(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-14">Oct. 14, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1959</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–468, title II, § 231</ref>, <date date="1983-01-14">Jan. 14, 1983</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2546</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1006.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 97–35, title XI, § 1144(b)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 669</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1007.</num>
<heading> Election</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistance received under employee protection agreement; waiver of other employee protection benefits; exception</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any employee who receives any assistance under an employee protection agreement entered into or benefit schedule prescribed under <ref>section 1005 of this title</ref> or any new career training assistance under <ref>section 1014 of this title</ref> shall be deemed to waive any employee protection benefits otherwise available to such employee under the Bankruptcy Act, subtitle IV of title 49 or any applicable contract or agreement (other than as provided in the agreement entered into in Washington, District of Columbia, on <date date="1980-03-04">March 4, 1980</date>, entitled “Labor Protective Agreement Between Railroads Parties Hereto Involved in Midwest Rail Restructuring and Employees of Such Railroads Represented by the Rail Labor Organizations Operating Through the Railway Labor Executives’ Association”).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Filing of statement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any employee of the Rock Island Railroad who is entitled to receive assistance under this chapter shall, no later than 120 days after the effective date of any agreement entered into under <ref>section 1005(a) of this title</ref> or of any benefit schedule prescribed under <ref>section 1005(b) of this title</ref>, as the case may be, file a statement with the Board indicating whether such employee elects to receive (1) assistance under this chapter; or (2) any employee protection benefits otherwise available to such employee under the Bankruptcy Act, subtitle IV of title 49, or any applicable contract or agreement.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect on priority, timing, etc., of employee protection payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">With regard to any employee who elects benefits under subsection (b)(2) of this section, nothing in this chapter shall be deemed to determine or otherwise affect the priority, status, or timing of payment of, or the liability for any claim for, employee protection which might have existed in the absence of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on assistance eligibility</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">An employee shall not be eligible to receive any assistance (other than moving expenses) under an employee protection agreement entered into or benefit schedule prescribed under <ref>section 1005 of this title</ref> or any new career training assistance under <ref>section 1014 of this title</ref>—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> during any period in which such employee is employed by any rail carrier providing temporary service over any lines of the Rock Island Railroad; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> at any time after the date such employee receives an offer of employment, in his craft and for which such employee is qualified, from a rail carrier acquiring lines of the Rock Island Railroad.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–254, title I, § 108</ref>, <date date="1980-05-30">May 30, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 402</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–448, title VII, § 701(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-14">Oct. 14, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1960</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–468, title II, § 232</ref>, <date date="1983-01-14">Jan. 14, 1983</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2547</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1008.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 97–468, title II, § 234(a)</ref>, <date date="1983-01-14">Jan. 14, 1983</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2547</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1009.</num>
<heading> Expedited proceedings</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Commission shall give all proceedings involving the Rock Island Railroad preference over all other pending proceedings related to rail carriers and make all of its decisions at the earliest practicable time.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Commission shall, within 100 days of the filing of an application (or such shorter period as the court may set) pursuant to <ref>section 915 of this title</ref>, reach a decision on all proceedings filed after <date date="1980-01-01">January 1, 1980</date>, which involve a sale, transfer or lease of any line of the Rock Island Railroad to a solvent carrier.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–254, title I, § 111</ref>, <date date="1980-05-30">May 30, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 404</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1010.</num>
<heading> Applicability of National Environmental Policy Act and <ref>section 6362(b) of title 42</ref></heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The provisions of the National Environmental Policy Act [<ref>42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.] and <ref>section 6362(b) of title 42</ref> shall not apply to transactions carried out pursuant to this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–254, title I, § 113</ref>, <date date="1980-05-30">May 30, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 405</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1011.</num>
<heading> Authority of Railroad Retirement Board</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Board may prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to carry out its duties under this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> In carrying out its duties under this chapter, the Board may exercise such of the powers, duties, and remedies provided in subsections (a), (b), and (d) of <ref>section 362 of this title</ref> as are not inconsistent with the provisions of this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–254, title I, § 114</ref>, <date date="1980-05-30">May 30, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 405</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1012.</num>
<heading> Publications and reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Within 45 days after <date date="1980-05-30">May 30, 1980</date>, the Board shall publish, and make available for distribution by the Rock Island Railroad to all eligible employees, a document which describes in detail the rights of such employees under sections 1005, 1006,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002073">1</ref> 1007, and 1014 of this title.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–254, title I, § 115</ref>, <date date="1980-05-30">May 30, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 405</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1013.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 7(b)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1379</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1014.</num>
<heading> New career training assistance</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible employees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An employee who elects to receive a separation allowance under an employee protection agreement entered into or a benefit schedule prescribed under <ref>section 1005 of this title</ref> may, if so provided under such agreement or benefit schedule, receive from the Board reasonable expenses for training in qualified institutions for new career opportunities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conditions for assistance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">To be eligible for assistance under this section, an employee—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> must first exhaust any Federal educational benefits available to such employee under any existing program; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> must begin his course of training within 2 years following the date of such employee’s separation from employment with the Rock Island Railroad.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determination of reasonable expenses by Board</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Reasonable expenses for assistance under this section shall be determined by the Board on the basis of an application therefor filed by an employee with the Board.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistance prohibited after <date date="1984-04-01">April 1, 1984</date></heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No assistance may be provided under this section after <date date="1984-04-01">April 1, 1984</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “expenses” means actual, reasonable expenses paid for room, board, tuition, fees, or educational material in an amount not to exceed $3,000; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “qualified institution” means an educational institution accredited for payment by the Veterans’ Administration under chapter 36 of title 38, or a State-accredited institution which has been in existence for not less than 2 years.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–254, title I, § 119(a)</ref>–(e), <date date="1980-05-30">May 30, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 408</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–468, title II, § 233</ref>, <date date="1983-01-14">Jan. 14, 1983</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2547</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1015.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title III, § 329(2)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 952</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1016.</num>
<heading> Temporary rail banking</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">During the 180-day period beginning on <date date="1980-05-30">May 30, 1980</date>, no rail line or facility of the Rock Island Railroad which has been approved for abandonment by the Commission or the bankruptcy court may be downgraded, scrapped, or otherwise disposed of without the approval of the Secretary under this section. In no case before abandonment has been approved and before the 180-day period has elapsed shall the Secretary approve a disposition of such portion of the rail line or related facility to any carrier or other entity not engaged in providing railroad services or not formed for the purpose of providing railroad services. The Secretary, upon application by the Rock Island Railroad, shall grant such approval unless he finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a rail carrier, shipper, State, or other interested party has expressed in writing an interest in purchasing, leasing or rehabilitating the particular rail line or facility for purposes of providing rail service; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> there is a reasonable expectation that such purchase transaction will be consummated.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–254, title I, § 121</ref>, <date date="1980-05-30">May 30, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 409</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1017.</num>
<heading> Temporary operating approval</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of tracks and facilities by other rail carriers; terms of compensation; continuation of service</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission may authorize any rail carrier willing to do so voluntarily to use the tracks and facilities of a carrier which, on <date date="1983-01-14">January 14, 1983</date>, was the subject of a proceeding pending under section 77 of the Bankruptcy Act or under subchapter IV of chapter 11 of title 11. The use of such tracks and facilities shall be under such terms of compensation as the carriers establish between themselves, or if the carriers are unable to agree, under such terms of compensation as the Commission finds to be reasonable. The Commission shall have authority to authorize continued rail service under this section over the lines of any such carrier which has been ordered by the court having jurisdiction over such a carrier to liquidate its properties until the disposition of the properties of the estate of such carrier.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of employees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In carrying out the provisions of this section, the Commission shall require, to the maximum extent practicable, the use of the employees who would normally have performed work in connection with the traffic subject to the action of the Commission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–254, title I, § 122</ref>, <date date="1980-05-30">May 30, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 409</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–130, § 5(a)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-29">Dec. 29, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1690</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–468, title II, § 214</ref>, <date date="1983-01-14">Jan. 14, 1983</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2545</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1018.</num>
<heading> Judicial review</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appeals</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any appeal from—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any decision of the bankruptcy court with respect to the constitutionality of any provision of this chapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any decision of the court having jurisdiction over the reorganization of the Milwaukee Railroad with respect to the constitutionality of the Milwaukee Railroad Restructuring Act (<ref>45 U.S.C. 901</ref> et seq.),</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be taken to the United States Court of Appeals for the Seventh Circuit.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appellate proceedings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If appeals are taken from decisions described in subsection (a) of this section involving section 1005 or 1008 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002074">1</ref> of this title or section 9 or 15 of the Milwaukee Railroad Restructuring Act [<ref>45 U.S.C. 908</ref> or 915], the court of appeals shall determine such appeals in a consolidated proceeding, sitting en banc.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Action in United States Court of Claims</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter or in the Milwaukee Railroad Restructuring Act (<ref>45 U.S.C. 901</ref> et seq.) shall limit the right of any person to commence an action in the United States Court of Claims <sup>1</sup> under <ref>section 1491 of title 28</ref> (commonly referred to as the Tucker Act).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–254, title I, § 124</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 96–448, title VII, § 701(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-14">Oct. 14, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1959</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–620, title IV, § 402(49)</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 3361</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>