<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 22—</num>
<heading>CONRAIL PRIVATIZATION</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1301.</num>
<heading> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the bankruptcy of the Penn Central and other railroads in the Northeast and Midwest resulted in a transportation emergency which required the intervention of the Federal Government;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the United States Government created the Consolidated Rail Corporation, which provides essential rail service to the Northeast and Midwest;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the future of rail service in the Northeast and Midwest is essential and must be protected through rail service obligations, consistent with the transfer of the Corporation to the private sector;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the Northeast Rail Service Act of 1981 has achieved its purpose in allowing the Corporation to become financially self-sustaining;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the Federal Government has invested over $7,000,000,000 in providing rail service to the Northeast and Midwest;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the Government, as a result of its ownership and investment of taxpayer dollars in the Corporation, controls substantial assets, including cash of approximately $1,000,000,000;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the Corporation’s viability and sound performance allow it to be sold to the American public for a substantial sum through a public offering;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> a public offering of the Corporation’s stock will preserve competitive rail service in the region, provide a reasonable return to the Government, and protect employment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> the Corporation’s employees contributed significantly to the turnaround in the Corporation’s financial performance and they should share in the Corporation’s success through a settlement of their claims for reimbursement for wages below industry standard, and a share in the common equity of the Corporation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> the requirements of section 761(e) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002090">1</ref> of this title are met by this chapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Transportation has discharged the responsibilities of the Department of Transportation under the Northeast Rail Service Act of 1981 with respect to the sale of the Corporation as a single entity.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–509, title IV, § 4002</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1893</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1302.</num>
<heading> Purposes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The purposes of this chapter are to transfer the interest of the United States in the common stock of the Corporation to the private sector in a manner that provides for the long-term viability of the Corporation, provides for the continuation by the Corporation of its rail service in the Northeast and Midwest, provides for the protection of the public interest in a sound rail transportation system, and, to the extent not inconsistent with such purposes, secures the maximum proceeds to the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–509, title IV, § 4003</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1893</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1303.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For the purposes of this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “capital expenditures” means amounts expended by the Corporation and its subsidiaries for replacement or rehabilitation of, or enhancements to, the railroad plant, property, trackage, and equipment of the Corporation and its subsidiaries, as determined in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles, and in interpreting generally accepted accounting principles, no amount spent on normal repair, maintenance, and upkeep of such railroad plant, property, trackage, and equipment in the ordinary course of business shall constitute capital expenditures;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “Commission” means the Interstate Commerce Commission;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “consolidated funded debt” means the aggregate, after eliminating intercompany items, of all funded debt of the Corporation and its consolidated subsidiaries, consolidated in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> the term “consolidated tangible net worth” means the market value of the common equity of the Corporation as of the sale date, plus or minus the change from the sale date to the date of measurement in the excess, after making appropriate deductions for any minority interest in the net worth of subsidiaries, of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the assets of the Corporation and its subsidiaries (excluding intercompany items) which, in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles, are tangible assets, after deducting adequate reserves in each case where, in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles, a reserve is proper, over</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> all liabilities of the Corporation and its subsidiaries (excluding intercompany items),</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">taking into account inventory and securities on the basis of the cost or current market value, whichever is lower, and not taking into account patents, trademarks, trade names, copyrights, licenses, goodwill, treasury stock, or any write-up in the book value of any assets;</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the term “Corporation” means the Consolidated Rail Corporation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> the term “cumulative net income” means, for any period, the net income of the Corporation and its consolidated subsidiaries as determined in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles, before provision for expenses (net of income tax effect) related to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> amounts paid by the Corporation under section 4024(e), and comparable payments made to present and former employees of the Corporation not covered by such section; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the aggregate value of any shares and cash distributed by the Corporation under section 4024(f);</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the term “debt” means (A) indebtedness, whether or not represented by bonds, debentures, notes, or other securities, for the repayment of money borrowed, (B) deferred indebtedness for the payment of the purchase price of property or assets purchased, (C) guarantees, endorsements, assumptions, and other contingent obligations in respect of, or to purchase or to otherwise acquire, indebtedness of others, and (D) indebtedness secured by any mortgage, pledge, or lien existing on property owned, subject to such mortgage, pledge, or lien, whether or not indebtedness secured thereby shall have been assumed;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> the term “funded debt” means all debt created, assumed, or guaranteed, directly or indirectly, by the Corporation and its subsidiaries which matures by its terms, or is renewable at the option of the Corporation or any such subsidiary to a date, more than 1 year after the date of the original creation, assumption, or guarantee of such debt by the Corporation or such subsidiary;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> the term “liabilities” means all items of indebtedness or liability which, in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles, would be included in determining total liabilities as shown on the liabilities side of a balance sheet as at the date as of which liabilities are to be determined;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> the term “person” means an individual, corporation, partnership, association, trust, or other entity or organization, including a government or political subdivision thereof or a governmental body;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> the term “preferred stock” means any class or series of preferred stock, and any class or series of common stock having liquidation and dividend rights and preferences superior to the common stock of the Corporation offered for sale under <ref>section 1312 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> the term “public offering” means an underwritten offering to the public of such common stock of the Corporation as the Secretary of Transportation determines to sell under <ref>section 1312 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> the term “sale date” means the date on which the initial public offering is closed;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> the term “subsidiary” means any corporation more than 50 percent of whose outstanding voting securities are directly or indirectly owned by the Corporation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<content> the term “United States share” means a share of common stock of the Corporation held by the United States Government on <date date="1986-10-21">October 21, 1986</date>, or as a result of any split required pursuant to <ref>section 1312(d) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–509, title IV, § 4004</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1894</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>CONRAIL</heading>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part A—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Sale of Conrail</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1311.</num>
<heading> Preparation for public offering</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public offering managers</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Not later than 30 days after <date date="1986-10-21">October 21, 1986</date>, the Secretary of Transportation, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury and the Chairman of the Board of Directors of the Corporation, shall retain the services of investment banking firms to serve jointly and be compensated equally as co-lead managers of the public offering (hereafter in this part referred to as the “co-lead managers”) and to establish a syndicate to underwrite the public offering. The total number of co-lead managers shall be no fewer than 4 nor greater than 6. The Secretary shall designate one co-lead manager to coordinate and administer the public offering.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In selecting the investment banking firms to serve as co-lead managers of the public offering under paragraph (1), consideration shall be given to the firm’s institutional and retail distribution capabilities, financial strength, knowledge of the railroad industry, experience in large scale public offerings, research capability, and reputation. In addition, recognition shall also be given to contributions made by particular investment banking firms before <date date="1986-10-21">October 21, 1986</date>, in demonstrating and promoting the long-term financial viability of the Corporation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payment to United States</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Not later than 30 days after <date date="1986-10-21">October 21, 1986</date>, the Corporation shall transfer to the Secretary of the Treasury $200,000,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> On or before <date date="1987-02-01">February 1, 1987</date>, or 30 days before the sale date, whichever occurs first, the Secretary of Transportation shall determine whether to require the Corporation to transfer to the Secretary of the Treasury, in addition to amounts transferred under paragraph (1), not to exceed $100,000,000, taking into account the viability of the Corporation. The Corporation shall transfer such funds as are required to be transferred under this paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Registration statement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Corporation shall prepare and cause to be filed with the Securities and Exchange Commission a registration statement with respect to the securities to be offered and sold in accordance with the securities laws and the rules and regulations thereunder in connection with the initial and any subsequent public offering.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–509, title IV, § 4011</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1895</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1312.</num>
<heading> Public offering</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Structure of public offering</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> After the registration statement referred to in <ref>section 1311(c) of this title</ref> is declared effective by the Securities and Exchange Commission, the Secretary of Transportation, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury, the Chairman of the Board of Directors of the Corporation, and the co-lead managers, shall offer the United States shares for sale in a public offering, except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Transportation, after such consultation, may elect to offer less than all of the United States shares for sale at the time of the initial sale.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Under no circumstances shall the Secretary of Transportation offer any of the United States shares for sale unless, before the sale date, the Secretary determines, after such consultation, that the estimated sum of the gross proceeds from the sale of all the United States shares will be an adequate amount. A determination by the Secretary under this paragraph shall not be reviewable.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> In making a determination under paragraph (3), the Secretary shall have the goal of obtaining at least $2,000,000,000 in aggregate gross proceeds for the United States from the public offering and any payments made under <ref>section 1311(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Subsequent sales</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the Secretary of Transportation elects to offer for sale less than all the United States shares, the Secretary shall sell the remaining United States shares in subsequent public offerings.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consent of Corporation not required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any public offering under this section may be made without the consent of the Corporation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority to require stock splits</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Transportation, in consultation with the co-lead managers and the Chairman of the Board of Directors of the Corporation, may, in connection with the initial public offering described in subsection (a), before the filing of the registration statement referred to in <ref>section 1311(c) of this title</ref>, require the Corporation to declare a stock split or reverse stock split.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Corporation shall take such action as may be necessary to comply with the Secretary’s requirements under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cancellation of other securities held by United States</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In consideration for amounts transferred to the United States under <ref>section 1311(b) of this title</ref>, the Secretary of Transportation shall, concurrent with the initial public offering described in subsection (a), deliver to the Corporation all preferred stock, 7.5 percent debentures, and contingent interest notes of the Corporation. The Corporation shall immediately cancel such debentures, preferred stock, and contingent interest notes, and any interest of the United States in such debentures, preferred stock, and contingent interest notes shall be thereby extinguished.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> For purposes of regulation by the Commission and State public utility regulation, the actions authorized by this subsection, the public offering, and the value of the consideration received therefor shall not change the value of the Corporation’s assets net of depreciation and shall not be used to alter the calculation of the Corporation’s stock or asset values, rate base, expenses, costs, returns, profits, or revenues, or otherwise affect or be the basis for a change in the regulation of any railroad service, rate, or practice provided or established by the Corporation, or any change in the financial reporting practice of the Corporation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Minority investment banking firms</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Transportation shall ensure that minority owned or controlled investment banking firms shall have an opportunity to participate to a significant degree in any public offering under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Investment banking firm requirements</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The level of any investment banking firm’s participation in the public offering shall be consistent with that firm’s financial capabilities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> No investment banking firm which was not in existence on <date date="1986-09-01">September 1, 1986</date>, shall participate in the public offering.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Government Accountability Office authority to conduct audits</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Government Accountability Office may make such audits as may be deemed appropriate by the Comptroller General of the United States of all accounts, books, records, memoranda, correspondence, and other documents and transactions of the Corporation and the co-lead managers associated with the public offering. The co-lead managers shall agree, in writing, to allow the Government Accountability Office to make such audits. The Government Accountability Office shall report the results of all such audits to the Congress.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–509, title IV, § 4012</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1896</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–271, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-07-07">July 7, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 814</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1313.</num>
<heading> Fees</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Investment banking firm fees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Transportation, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury, shall agree to pay to investment banking firms and other persons participating with such firms in the public offering the absolute minimum amount in fees necessary to carry out the public offering.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Costs of public offering</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All costs of the public offering payable by the Secretary of Transportation shall be paid from the proceeds of the public offering.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–509, title IV, § 4013</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1897</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part B—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Other Matters Relating to Sale</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1321.</num>
<heading> Rail service obligations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Obligations of Corporation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">During a period of 5 years beginning on <date date="1986-10-21">October 21, 1986</date>, the following obligations shall apply to the Corporation:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Corporation shall spend in each fiscal year the greater of (A) an amount equal to the Corporation’s depreciation for financial reporting purposes for such year or (B) $500,000,000, in capital expenditures. With respect to any fiscal year, the Corporation’s Board of Directors may reduce the required capital expenditures for such year to an amount which the Board determines is justified by prudent business and engineering practices, except that the Corporation’s capital expenditures shall not be less than $350,000,000 for its first fiscal year beginning after the sale date, a total of $700,000,000 for its first two fiscal years beginning after the sale date, a total of $1,050,000,000 for its first three fiscal years beginning after the sale date, a total of $1,400,000,000 for its first four fiscal years beginning after the sale date, and a total of $1,750,000,000 for its first five fiscal years beginning after the sale date.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 101–213, § 2(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="1989-12-11">Dec. 11, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1843</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Corporation shall continue its affirmative action program and its minority vendor program, substantially as such programs were being conducted by the Corporation as of <date date="1985-02-08">February 8, 1985</date>, subject to any provisions of applicable law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Corporation shall not permit to occur any transaction or series of transactions (other than in the ordinary course of business of the Corporation and its subsidiaries) whereby all or any substantial part of the railroad assets and business of the Corporation and its subsidiaries taken as a whole are sold, leased, transferred, or otherwise disposed of to any corporation or entity other than to a wholly owned subsidiary of the Corporation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The Corporation shall offer any line for which an abandonment certificate is issued by the Commission to a purchaser who agrees to provide interconnecting rail service. Such offer shall last for the 120-day period following the date of issuance of the abandonment certificate and the price for such abandoned line shall be equal to 75 percent of net liquidation value as determined by the Commission, pursuant to regulations that had been issued under <ref>section 748 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The Corporation and its subsidiaries shall maintain, preserve, protect, and keep their respective properties in good repair, working order, and condition, and shall not permit deferral of normal and prudent maintenance necessary to provide and maintain rail service.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compliance certificates</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Within 90 days after the close of each of its fiscal years, or at the time its financial statements have been audited, whichever occurs later, the Corporation shall deliver to the Secretary of Transportation a certificate executed by an executive officer of the Corporation. Such certificate shall certify that, as of such date, the Corporation is in compliance with all requirements (other than the requirement regarding a common stock dividend or a preferred stock dividend) set forth in this section. Such certificate shall include audited consolidated financial statements.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Within 5 days after the declaration of any common stock dividend or preferred stock dividend, the Corporation shall deliver to the Secretary of Transportation a certificate executed by an executive officer of the Corporation. Such certificate shall certify that, after giving effect to any such dividend, the Corporation shall be in compliance with any requirement regarding a common stock dividend or a preferred stock dividend set forth in this section. Such certificate shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> quarterly financial statements; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a report of the Corporation’s total capital expenditures,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">for the period with respect to which the dividend has been declared, and the fiscal year to date, and shall compare such capital expenditures to the budgeted capital expenditures and to the capital expenditures during the comparable periods of the previous fiscal year.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–509, title IV, § 4021</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1898</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–213, § 2(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="1989-12-11">Dec. 11, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1843</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1322.</num>
<heading> Ownership limitations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> During a period of 3 years beginning on the sale date, no person, directly or indirectly, may acquire or hold securities representing more than 10 percent of the total votes of all outstanding voting securities of the Corporation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> This subsection shall not apply—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to the employee stock ownership plan (or successor plans) of the Corporation,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to the Secretary of Transportation,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to a railroad as described under subsection (b),</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> to underwriting syndicates holding shares for resale, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> in the case of shares beneficially held for others, to commercial banks, broker-dealers, clearing corporations, or other nominees.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Railroads</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> During a period of 1 year beginning on the sale date, no railroad may purchase or hold, directly or indirectly, more than 10 percent of any class of stock of the Corporation. During such period, no railroad may file an application with the Commission for a merger or consolidation with the Corporation or the acquisition of control of the Corporation under section 11344 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002091">1</ref> of title 49.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> During a period of 3 years beginning on the sale date, any railroad which purchases or holds any stock of the Corporation shall vote such stock in the same proportion as all other common stock of the Corporation is voted. After the expiration of 1 year after the sale date, the preceding sentence shall not apply to any railroad with respect to which the Commission has approved an application for a merger or consolidation with the Corporation or the acquisition of control of the Corporation under section 11344 <sup>1</sup> of title 49.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> As used in this subsection, the term “railroad” means a class I railroad as determined by the Commission under the definition in effect on <date date="1986-10-21">October 21, 1986</date>, and includes any entity controlling, controlled by, or under common control with any railroad (other than the Corporation or its subsidiaries).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–509, title IV, § 4022</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1900</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1323.</num>
<heading> Board of Directors</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Board of Directors of the Corporation shall be comprised as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraph (3), with respect to the period ending <date date="1987-06-30">June 30, 1987</date>, the board shall remain as it exists on <date date="1986-10-21">October 21, 1986</date>, with any vacancies being filled by directors nominated and elected by the remainder of the members of the board.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> Except as provided in paragraph (3), with respect to the period beginning <date date="1987-07-01">July 1, 1987</date>, the board shall consist of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> 3 directors appointed by the Secretary of Transportation;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the Chief Executive Officer and the Chief Operating Officer of the Corporation; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> 8 directors appointed from among persons knowledgeable in business affairs by the special court trustees named under subparagraph (C), in consultation with the Secretary of Transportation and the Chairman of the Board of Directors of the Corporation, and recognizing the need for and importance of—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> continuity in the direction of the Corporation’s business and affairs;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> preserving the value of the investment of the United States in the Corporation;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> preserving essential rail service provided by the Corporation; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> providing for the sale of the United States shares.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Transportation and the special court trustees may appoint directors under subparagraph (A) from among existing directors of the Corporation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> If more than 50 percent of the interest of the United States in the Corporation has not been sold before <date date="1987-06-01">June 1, 1987</date>, the special court established under <ref>section 719 of this title</ref> shall, on that date, name 3 trustees from among persons knowledgeable in business affairs to make the appointments required by subparagraph (A)(iii). The Corporation shall compensate the special court trustees in an amount to be specified by the special court, not to exceed the amount paid by the Corporation to its directors for comparable services.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> No person shall be eligible to be appointed as a special court trustee under this subparagraph who, at any time during the 30 months immediately preceding such appointment, was an officer, employee, or director of the United States Railway Association, the Corporation, or the Department of Transportation.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> After the sale date, one director shall be elected by the public shareholders of the Corporation for each increment of 12.5 percent of the interest of the United States in the Corporation that has been sold through public offering.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> With respect to the period ending <date date="1987-06-30">June 30, 1987</date>—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> the first director elected under this paragraph shall replace the member of the board who became a director most recently from among—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> directors appointed by the United States Railway Association, or elected under paragraph (1) to replace such a director, and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> directors appointed by the Secretary of Transportation, or elected under paragraph (1) to replace such a director;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the second director elected under this paragraph shall replace the member of the Board who became a director most recently from among directors described in clause (i)(I) or (II), whichever group the first director replaced under this subparagraph was not a member of; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> subsequent directors elected under this paragraph shall replace members alternately from the groups described in clause (i)(I) and (II).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> With respect to the period beginning <date date="1987-07-01">July 1, 1987</date>, directors elected under this paragraph shall replace directors appointed by the special court trustees under paragraph (2)(A)(iii), in the order designated by the special court trustees in a list to be issued at the time of such original appointments.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> With respect to the period beginning on the first date more than 50 percent of the interest of the United States in the Corporation has been sold through public offering and ending when 100 percent of such interest has been sold—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> all remaining members of the board referred to in paragraph (2)(A)(iii), and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> with respect to the period ending <date date="1987-06-30">June 30, 1987</date>, all remaining members of the board, except 3 members appointed by the Secretary of Transportation and the Chief Executive Officer and the Chief Operating Officer of the Corporation,</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">shall be replaced by directors elected by the public shareholders of the Corporation.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> After 100 percent of the interest of the United States in the Corporation has been sold, any remaining directors appointed by the Secretary of Transportation, the United States Railway Association, or the special court trustees referred to under paragraph (2)(A)(iii), shall be replaced by directors elected by the public shareholders of the Corporation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to prohibit any director referred to in this section from being elected as a director by the public shareholders of the Corporation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> No director appointed or elected under this section shall be a special court trustee or an employee of the United States, except as elected by the public shareholders of the Corporation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> No director appointed or elected under this section shall be an employee of the Corporation, except as provided in paragraph (2)(A)(ii) or as elected by the public shareholders of the Corporation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–509, title IV, § 4023</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1901</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1324.</num>
<heading> Certain enforcement relief</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Enforcement actions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Transportation, with respect to any provision of section 1321 or 1322 of this title, and any person who suffers direct and substantial economic injury as a result of an alleged violation by the Corporation, with respect to the provisions of section 1321(a)(1) and (2) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002092">1</ref> of this title, and <ref>section 1322 of this title</ref>, may bring an action to require compliance with such provision.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special court</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any action brought under this subchapter shall be brought before the special court established under <ref>section 719 of this title</ref>. Such special court may limit the enforcement of a restriction under <ref>section 1321 of this title</ref>, if the effect of such restriction would be to substantially impair the continued viability of the Corporation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–509, title IV, § 4025</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1905</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part C—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Miscellaneous Provisions</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1341.</num>
<heading> Abolition of United States Railway Association</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Abolition and termination</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Effective <date date="1987-04-01">April 1, 1987</date>, the United States Railway Association is abolished.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> On <date date="1987-01-01">January 1, 1987</date>, all powers, duties, rights, and obligations of such association relating to the Corporation under the Regional Rail Reorganization Act of 1973 (<ref>45 U.S.C. 701</ref> et seq.) shall be transferred to the Secretary of Transportation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The sole function of the United States Railway Association after <date date="1987-01-01">January 1, 1987</date>, shall be the termination of its affairs and the liquidation of its assets.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer of securities and responsibilities</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Any securities of the Corporation held by the United States Railway Association shall, upon <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002093">1</ref> <date date="1986-10-21">October 21, 1986</date>, be transferred to the Secretary of Transportation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If, on the date the United States Railway Association is abolished under subsection (a), such association shall not have completed the termination of its affairs and the liquidation of its assets, the duty of completing such winding up of its affairs and liquidation shall be transferred to the Secretary of Transportation, who for such purposes shall succeed to all remaining powers, duties, rights, and obligations of such association.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Financing agreement</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> On <date date="1987-01-01">January 1, 1987</date>, the Amended and Restated Financing Agreement, dated <date date="1979-05-10">May 10, 1979</date>, between the United States Railway Association and the Corporation, together with any and all rights and obligations of or on behalf of any person with respect to such agreement, shall terminate and be of no further force or effect, except for those provisions specifying terms and conditions for payments made to the United States with respect to debentures, preferred stock, and contingent interest notes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Effective as of the sale date, those provisions of the Financing Agreement referred to in paragraph (1) shall terminate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–509, title IV, § 4031</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1906</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1342.</num>
<heading> Exemption from liability</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No person referred to in section 726(f)(8)(C)(i), (ii), or (iii) of this title shall be liable, for money damages or otherwise, to any party if, with respect to the subject matter of the action, suit, or proceeding, such person was fulfilling a duty, in connection with any action taken under this subchapter, which such person in good faith reasonably believed to be required by law or vested in such person.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall not apply to claims arising out of the Securities Act of 1933 [<ref>15 U.S.C. 77a</ref> et seq.], the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 [<ref>15 U.S.C. 78a</ref> et seq.], or the Constitution or laws of any State, territory, or possession of the United States relating to transactions in securities, which claims are in connection with a public offering under <ref>section 1312 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–509, title IV, § 4034</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1909</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1343.</num>
<heading> Charter amendment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Within 60 days after <date date="1986-10-21">October 21, 1986</date>, the Corporation shall amend its Articles of Incorporation to contain the following provision, which provision shall not be subject to amendment or repeal:</p>
<p class="indent0">“It shall be a fundamental purpose of the Corporation to maintain continued rail service in its service area.”.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–509, title IV, § 4035</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1909</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1344.</num>
<heading> Status of Conrail after sale</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Corporation shall be a rail carrier as defined in <ref>section 10102 of title 49</ref>, notwithstanding this subchapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–509, title IV, § 4036</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1909</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title III, § 332</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 953</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1345.</num>
<heading> Effect on contracts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this subchapter shall affect any obligation of the Corporation to carry out its transportation contracts and equipment leases, equipment trusts, and conditional sales agreements, in accordance with their terms.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–509, title IV, § 4037</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1909</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1346.</num>
<heading> Resolution of certain issues</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Employee issues</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Section 4024 completely and finally—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> extinguishes all employee rights, and any obligation of the United States, under section 761(e) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002094">1</ref> of this title as in effect immediately before <date date="1986-10-21">October 21, 1986</date>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> resolves any and all claims against the Corporation or any other person arising under the Definitive Agreement referred to in section 4024(d)(1) or any other agreement containing similar terms and conditions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> resolves all claims to pay entitlements arising out of the pay increase deferrals by present and former employees of the Corporation under the Agreement of <date date="1981-05-05">May 5, 1981</date>, between Conrail and Certain Labor Organizations for Labor Contributions to Self-Sufficiency for Conrail;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> resolves all issues raised by notices served by representatives of such employees under <ref>section 156 of this title</ref> proposing repayment of or compensation for such deferrals; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> resolves all claims against the Railway Labor Executives’ Association or the Corporation by any adviser, consultant, or other person who has provided services to such association in connection with any matter referred to in this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Corporation actions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Corporation shall not be considered to be in breach, default, or violation of any agreement to which it is a party, notwithstanding any provision of such agreement, because of any provision of this subchapter or any action the Corporation is required to take under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Right to sue withdrawn</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The United States hereby withdraws any stated or implied consent for the United States, or any agent or officer of the United States, to be sued by any person for any legal, equitable, or other relief with respect to any claim arising out of, or resulting from, acts or omissions under this subchapter, except actions brought to require the Secretary of Transportation to perform duties or acts required under part A of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–509, title IV, § 4038</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1909</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1347.</num>
<heading> Tax treatment of Conrail public sale</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment as new corporation</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For periods after the public sale, for purposes of title 26, Conrail shall be treated as a new corporation which purchased all of its assets as of the beginning of the day after the date of the public sale for an amount equal to the deemed purchase price.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Allocation among assets</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The deemed purchase price shall be allocated among the assets of Conrail in accordance with the temporary regulations prescribed under <ref>section 338 of title 26</ref> (as such regulations were in effect on <date date="1986-10-21">October 21, 1986</date>). The Secretary shall establish specific guidelines for carrying out the preceding sentence so that the basis of each asset will be clearly ascertainable. For purposes of applying the regulations referred to in the first sentence, accounts receivable and materials and supplies shall be treated as cash equivalents.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deemed purchase price</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, the deemed purchase price is an amount equal to the gross amount received pursuant to the public sale, multiplied by a fraction—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the numerator of which is 100 percent, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the denominator of which is the percentage (by value) of the stock of Conrail sold in the public sale.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">The amount determined under the preceding sentence shall be adjusted under regulations prescribed by the Secretary for liabilities of Conrail and other relevant items.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> No income from cancellation of debt or preferred stock</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No amount shall be included in the gross income of any person by reason of any cancellation of any obligation (or preferred stock) of Conrail in connection with the public sale.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disallowance of certain deductions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No deduction shall be allowed to Conrail for any amount which is paid after the date of the public sale to employees of Conrail for services performed on or before the date of the public sale.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Waiver of certain employee stock ownership plan provisions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of determining whether the employee stock ownership plans of Conrail meet the qualifications of sections 401 and 501 of title 26—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the limits of section 415 of such title (relating to limitations on benefits and contributions under qualified plans) shall not apply with respect to interests in stock transferred pursuant to this Act or a law heretofore enacted, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the 2-year waiting period for withdrawals shall not apply to withdrawals of amounts (or shares) in participants accounts in connection with the public sale.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conrail</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Conrail” means the Consolidated Rail Corporation. Such term includes any corporation which was a subsidiary of Conrail immediately before the public sale.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public sale</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “public sale” means the sale of stock in Conrail pursuant to a public offering under the Conrail Privatization Act [<ref>45 U.S.C. 1301</ref> et seq.]. If there is more than 1 public offering under such Act, such term means the sale pursuant to the initial public offering under such Act.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of the Treasury or his delegate.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–509, title VIII, § 8021</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1954</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 2095</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
</subchapter>
</chapter>