<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 11—</num>
<heading>RAILROAD UNEMPLOYMENT INSURANCE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 351.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For the purposes of this chapter, except when used in amending the provisions of other Acts—</chapeau>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The term “employer” means any carrier (as defined in subsection (b) of this section), and any company which is directly or indirectly owned or controlled by one or more such carriers or under common control therewith, and which operates any equipment or facility or performs any service (except trucking service, casual service, and the casual operation of equipment or facilities) in connection with the transportation of passengers or property by railroad, or the receipt, delivery, elevation, transfer in transit, refrigeration or icing, storage, or handling of property transported by railroad, and any receiver, trustee, or other individual or body, judicial or otherwise, when in the possession of the property or operating all or any part of the business of any such employer: <i>Provided, however</i>, That the term “employer” shall not include any street, interurban, or suburban electric railway, unless such railway is operating as a part of a general steam-railroad system of transportation, but shall not exclude any part of the general steam-railroad system of transportation now or hereafter operated by any other motive power. The Surface Transportation Board is hereby authorized and directed upon request of the Railroad Retirement Board, or upon complaint of any party interested, to determine after hearing whether any line operated by electric power falls within the terms of this proviso. The term “employer” shall also include railroad associations, traffic associations, tariff bureaus, demurrage bureaus, weighing and inspection bureaus, collection agencies, and other associations, bureaus, agencies, or organizations controlled and maintained wholly or principally by two or more employers as hereinbefore defined and engaged in the performance of services in connection with or incidental to railroad transportation; and railway labor organizations, national in scope, which have been or may be organized in accordance with the provisions of the Railway Labor Act [<ref>45 U.S.C. 151</ref> et seq.], and their State and National legislative committees and their general committees and their insurance departments and their local lodges and divisions, established pursuant to the constitution and bylaws of such organizations. The term “employer” shall not include any company by reason of its being engaged in the mining of coal, the supplying of coal to an employer where delivery is not beyond the mine tipple, and the operation of equipment or facilities therefor, or in any of such activities.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The term “carrier” means a railroad subject to the jurisdiction of the Surface Transportation Board under part A of subtitle IV of title 49.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The term “company” includes corporations, associations, and joint-stock companies.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The term “employee” (except when used in phrases establishing a different meaning) means any individual who is or has been (i) in the service of one or more employers for compensation, or (ii) an employee representative. The term “employee” shall include an employee of a local lodge or division defined as an employer in subsection (a) only if he was in the service of a carrier on or after <date date="1935-08-29">August 29, 1935</date>. The term “employee” includes an officer of an employer.<p class="indent0">The term “employee” shall not include any individual while such individual is engaged in the physical operations consisting of the mining of coal, the preparation of coal, the handling (other than movement by rail with standard railroad locomotives) of coal not beyond the mine tipple, or the loading of coal at the tipple.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> An individual is in the service of an employer whether his service is rendered within or without the United States if (i) he is subject to the continuing authority of the employer to supervise and direct the manner of rendition of his service, or he is rendering professional or technical services and is integrated into the staff of the employer, or he is rendering, on the property used in the employer’s operations, other personal services the rendition of which is integrated into the employer’s operations, and (ii) he renders such service for compensation: <i>Provided, however</i>, That an individual shall be deemed to be in the service of an employer, other than a local lodge or division or a general committee of a railway-labor-organization employer, not conducting the principal part of its business in the United States only when he is rendering service to it in the United States; and an individual shall be deemed to be in the service of such a local lodge or division only if (1) all, or substantially all, the individuals constituting its membership are employees of an employer conducting the principal part of its business in the United States; or (2) the headquarters of such local lodge or division is located in the United States; and an individual shall be deemed to be in the service of such a general committee only if (1) he is representing a local lodge or division described in clauses (1) or (2) immediately above; or (2) all, or substantially all, the individuals represented by it are employees of an employer conducting the principal part of its business in the United States; or (3) he acts in the capacity of a general chairman or an assistant general chairman of a general committee which represents individuals rendering service in the United States to an employer, but in such case if his office or headquarters is not located in the United States and the individuals represented by such general committee are employees of an employer not conducting the principal part of its business in the United States, only such proportion of the remuneration for such service shall be regarded as compensation as the proportion which the mileage in the United States under the jurisdiction of such general committee bears to the total mileage under its jurisdiction, unless such mileage formula is inapplicable, in which case the Board may prescribe such other formula as it finds to be equitable, and if the application of such mileage formula, or such other formula as the Board may prescribe, would result in the compensation of the individual being less than 10 per centum of his remuneration for such service no part of such remuneration shall be regarded as compensation: <i>Provided further</i>, That an individual not a citizen or resident of the United States shall not be deemed to be in the service of an employer when rendering service outside the United States to an employer who is required under the laws applicable in the place where the service is rendered to employ therein, in whole or in part, citizens or residents thereof.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> The term “employee representative” means any officer or official representative of a railway labor organization other than a labor organization included in the term employer as defined in subsection (a) who before or after <date date="1935-08-29">August 29, 1935</date>, was in the service of an employer as defined in said subsection and who is duly authorized and designated to represent employees in accordance with the Railway Labor Act [<ref>45 U.S.C. 151</ref> et seq.], and any individual who is regularly assigned to or regularly employed by such officer or official representative in connection with the duties of his office.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> The term “employment” means service performed as an employee. For the purposes of determining eligibility for and the amount of benefits and the amount of contributions due pursuant to this chapter, employment after <date date="1940-06-30">June 30, 1940</date>, in the service of a local lodge or division of a railway-labor-organization employer or as an employee representative shall be disregarded. For purposes of determining eligibility for and the amount of benefits and the amount of contributions due pursuant to this chapter, employment as a delegate to a national or international convention of a railway labor organization defined as an “employer”, in subsection (a) of this section, shall be disregarded if the individual having such employment has not previously rendered service, other than as such a delegate, which may be included in his “years of service” for purposes of the Railroad Retirement Act [<ref>45 U.S.C. 231</ref> et seq.].</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<content> The term “registration period” means, with respect to any employee, the period which begins with the first day for which such employee registers at an employment office in accordance with such regulations as the Board may prescribe, and ends with whichever is the earlier of (i) the thirteenth day thereafter, or (ii) the day immediately preceding the day for which he next registers at a different employment office; and thereafter each period which begins with the first day for which he next registers at an employment office after the end of his last preceding registration period which began with a day for which he registered at an employment office and ends with whichever is the earlier of (i) the thirteenth day thereafter, or (ii) the day immediately preceding the day for which he next registers at a different employment office.<p class="indent0">The term “registration period” means also, with respect to any employee, the period which begins with the first day with respect to which a statement of sickness for a “period of continuing sickness” (as defined in <ref>section 352(a) of this title</ref>) is filed in his behalf in accordance with such regulations as the Board may prescribe, or the first such day after the end of a registration period which will have begun with a day with respect to which a statement of sickness for a “period of continuing sickness” (as defined in <ref>section 352(a) of this title</ref>) was filed in his behalf, and ends with whichever is the earlier of (i) the thirteenth day thereafter, or (ii) the day immediately preceding the day with respect to which a statement of sickness for a new “period of continuing sickness” (as defined in <ref>section 352(a) of this title</ref>) is filed in his behalf.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “compensation” means any form of money remuneration, including pay for time lost but excluding tips, paid for services rendered as an employee to one or more employers, or as an employee representative, except that in computing the compensation paid to any employee, no part of any month’s compensation in excess of the monthly compensation base (as defined in subdivision (2)) for any month shall be recognized. Solely for the purpose of determining the compensation received by an employee in a base year, the term “compensation” shall include any separation allowance or subsistence allowance paid under any benefit schedule provided under section 701 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002025">1</ref> of title VII of the Regional Rail Reorganization Act of 1973 [<ref>45 U.S.C. 797</ref>] and any termination allowance paid under section 702 of that Act [<ref>45 U.S.C. 797a</ref>], but does not include any other benefits payable under that title [<ref>45 U.S.C. 797</ref> et seq.]. The total amount of any subsistence allowance payable under a benefit schedule provided pursuant to section 701 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002025">1</ref> of the Regional Rail Reorganization Act of 1973 shall be considered as being compensation in the month in which the employee first timely filed a claim for such an allowance. Such term does not include remuneration for service which is performed by a nonresident alien individual for the period he is temporarily present in the United States as a nonimmigrant under subparagraph (F) or (J) of <ref>section 1101(a)(15) of title 8</ref> and which is performed to carry out the purpose specified in subparagraph (F) or (J) as the case may be. A payment made by an employer to an individual through the employer’s pay roll shall be presumed, in the absence of evidence to the contrary, to be compensation for service rendered by such individual as an employee of the employer in the period with respect to which the payment is made. An employee shall be deemed to be paid, “for time lost” the amount he is paid by an employer with respect to an identifiable period of absence from the active service of the employer, including absence on account of personal injury, and the amount he is paid by the employer for loss of earnings resulting from his displacement to a less remunerative position or occupation. If a payment is made by an employer with respect to a personal injury and includes pay for time lost, the total payment shall be deemed to be paid for time lost unless, at the time of payment, a part of such payment is specifically apportioned to factors other than time lost, in which event only such part of the payment as is not so apportioned shall be deemed to be paid for time lost. Compensation earned in any calendar month before 1947 shall be deemed paid in such month regardless of whether or when payment will have been in fact made, and compensation earned in any calendar year after 1946 but paid after the end of such calendar year shall be deemed to be compensation paid in the calendar year in which it will have been earned if it is so reported by the employer before February 1 of the next succeeding calendar year or, if the employee establishes, subject to the provisions of <ref>section 356 of this title</ref>, the period during which such compensation will have been earned.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Monthly Compensation Base.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For purposes of subdivision (1), the term “monthly compensation base” means the amount—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> of $400 for calendar months before <date date="1984-01-01">January 1, 1984</date>;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> of $600 for calendar months after <date date="1983-12-31">December 31, 1983</date> and before <date date="1989-01-01">January 1, 1989</date>; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> computed under subparagraph (B) for months after <date date="1988-12-31">December 31, 1988</date>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Computation.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The amount of the monthly compensation base for each calendar year beginning after <date date="1988-12-31">December 31, 1988</date>, is the greater of—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> $600; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the amount, as rounded under clause (iii) if applicable, computed under the formula:<table width="50%" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><colgroup><col/><col/><col/><col/><col/><col/><col/></colgroup><thead><tr class="header"><td/></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p> </p></td><td><p> </p></td><td><p> </p></td><td><p>A−37,800</p></td><td/><td/></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>B=600</p></td><td><p>A</p></td><td><p>1+</p></td><td><p>————</p></td><td><p></p></td><td/></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p> </p></td><td><p> </p></td><td><p> </p></td><td><p>56,700</p></td><td/><td/></tr></tbody></table>
</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Meaning of symbols</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For the purposes of the formula in clause (i)—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> “B” is the dollar amount of the monthly compensation base; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> “A” is the amount of the applicable base with respect to tier 1 taxes, for the calendar year for which the monthly compensation base is being computed, as determined under <ref>section 3231(e)(2) of title 26</ref>.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rounding rule</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the monthly compensation base computed under this formula is not a multiple of $5, it shall be rounded to the nearest multiple of $5, with such rounding being upward in the event the amount computed is equidistant between two multiples of $5.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<content> The term “remuneration” means pay for services for hire, including pay for time lost, and tips, but pay for time lost shall be deemed earned on the day on which such time is lost. The term “remuneration” includes also earned income other than for services for hire if the accrual thereof in whole or in part is ascertainable with respect to a particular day or particular days. The term “remuneration” does not include any money payments received pursuant to any nongovernmental plan for unemployment insurance, maternity insurance, or sickness insurance.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(k)</num>
<content> Subject to the provisions of <ref>section 354 of this title</ref> (1) a day of unemployment, with respect to any employee, means a calendar day on which he is able to work and is available for work and with respect to which (i) no remuneration is payable or accrues to him, and (ii) he has, in accordance with such regulations as the Board may prescribe, registered at an employment office; and (2) a “day of sickness”, with respect to any employee, means a calendar day on which because of any physical, mental, psychological, or nervous injury, illness, sickness, or disease he is not able to work, or, with respect to a female employee, a calendar day on which, because of pregnancy, miscarriage, or the birth of a child, (i) she is unable to work or (ii) working would be injurious to her health, and with respect to which (i) no remuneration is payable or accrues to him, and (ii) in accordance with such regulations as the Board may prescribe, a statement of sickness is filed within such reasonable period, not in excess of ten days, as the Board may prescribe: <i>Provided, however</i>, That “subsidiary remuneration”, as hereinafter defined in this subsection, shall not be considered remuneration for the purpose of this subsection except with respect to an employee whose base-year compensation, exclusive of earnings from the position or occupation in which he earned such subsidiary remuneration, is less than an amount that is equal to 2.5 times the monthly compensation base for months in such base year as computed under subsection (i) of this section: <i>Provided further</i>, That remuneration for a working day which includes a part of each of two consecutive calendar days shall be deemed to have been earned on the first of such two days, and any individual who takes work for such working day shall not by reason thereof be deemed not available for work on the second of such calendar days: <i>Provided further</i>, That any calendar day on which no remuneration is payable to or accrues to an employee solely because of the application to him of mileage or work restrictions agreed upon in schedule agreements between employers and employees or solely because he is standing by for or laying over between regularly assigned trips or tours of duty shall not be considered either a day of unemployment or a day of sickness.<p class="indent0">For the purpose of this subsection, the term “subsidiary remuneration” means, with respect to any employee, remuneration not in excess of an average of $15 a day for the period with respect to which such remuneration is payable or accrues, if the work from which the remuneration is derived (i) requires substantially less than full time as determined by generally prevailing standards, and (ii) is susceptible of performance at such times and under such circumstances as not to be inconsistent with the holding of normal full-time employment in another occupation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(l)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “benefits” (except in phrases clearly designating other payments) means the money payments payable to an employee as provided in this chapter, with respect to his unemployment or sickness.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “statement of sickness” means a statement with respect to days of sickness of an employee, executed in such manner and form by an individual duly authorized pursuant to <ref>section 362(i) of this title</ref> to execute such statements, and filed as the Board may prescribe by regulations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(m)</num>
<content> The term “benefit year” means the twelve-month period beginning July 1 of any year and ending June 30 of the next year, except that a registration period beginning in June and ending in July shall be deemed to be in the benefit year ending in such month of June.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(n)</num>
<content> The term “base year” means the completed calendar year immediately preceding the beginning of the benefit year.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(o)</num>
<content> The term “employment office” means a free employment office operated by the Board, or designated as such by the Board pursuant to <ref>section 362(i) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(p)</num>
<content> The term “account” means the railroad unemployment insurance account established pursuant to <ref>section 360 of this title</ref> in the unemployment trust fund.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(q)</num>
<content> The term “fund” means the railroad unemployment insurance administration fund, established pursuant to <ref>section 361 of this title</ref> in the unemployment trust fund.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(r)</num>
<content> The term “Board” means the Railroad Retirement Board.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(s)</num>
<content> The term “United States”, when used in a geographical sense, means the States and the District of Columbia.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(t)</num>
<content> The term “State” means any of the States or the District of Columbia.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(u)</num>
<content> Any reference in this chapter to any other Act of Congress, including such reference in amendments to other Acts, includes a reference to such other Act as amended from time to time.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1938, ch. 680, § 1</ref>, <ref>52 Stat. 1094</ref>; <ref>June 20, 1939, ch. 227</ref>, §§ 1–6, 20, <ref>53 Stat. 845</ref>, 848; <ref>Aug. 13, 1940, ch. 664</ref>, §§ 1, 3, <ref>54 Stat. 785</ref>, 786; <ref>Oct. 10, 1940, ch. 842</ref>, §§ 2–8, <ref>54 Stat. 1094</ref>, 1095; <ref>Apr. 8, 1942, ch. 227, § 15</ref>, <ref>56 Stat. 210</ref>; <ref>July 31, 1946, ch. 709</ref>, §§ 1, 2, 301–304, <ref>60 Stat. 722</ref>, 735, 736; <ref>Oct. 30, 1951, ch. 632, § 26</ref>, <ref>65 Stat. 691</ref>; <ref>Aug. 31, 1954, ch. 1164</ref>, pt. III, §§ 301–303, <ref>68 Stat. 1041</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–927</ref>, pt. II, § 201, <date date="1958-09-06">Sept. 6, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1782</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–28</ref>, pt. III, § 301, <date date="1959-05-19">May 19, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 30</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–700, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1966-10-30">Oct. 30, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1087</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–257, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1968-02-15">Feb. 15, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 23</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–624, § 3</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1316</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–92, title I, § 1(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1975-08-09">Aug. 9, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 461</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–76, title IV</ref>, §§ 402(b), 403(b), 411(a)(1), title V, § 503(b), <date date="1983-08-12">Aug. 12, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 434</ref>, 436, 441; <ref>Pub. L. 100–647, title VII</ref>, §§ 7101(a), (b), 7203(a), <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3757</ref>, 3758, 3776; <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title III, § 324(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 950</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 352.</num>
<heading> Benefits</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Days for which benefits payable; determination of amount</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Payment of Unemployment Benefits.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Generally</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as otherwise provided in this subparagraph, benefits shall be payable to any qualified employee for each day of unemployment in excess of 4 during any registration period within a period of continuing unemployment.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Waiting period for first registration period</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Benefits shall be payable to any qualified employee for each day of unemployment in excess of 7 during that employee’s first registration period in a period of continuing unemployment if such period of continuing unemployment is the employee’s initial period of continuing unemployment commencing in the benefit year.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Strikes.—</inline>
</heading>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Initial 14-day waiting period</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the Board finds that a qualified employee has a period of continuing unemployment that includes days of unemployment due to a stoppage of work because of a strike in the establishment, premises, or enterprise at which such employee was last employed, no benefits shall be payable for such employee’s first 14 days of unemployment due to such stoppage of work.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(II)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Subsequent days of unemployment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For subsequent days of unemployment due to the same stoppage of work, benefits shall be payable as provided in clause (i) of this subparagraph.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(III)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Subsequent periods of continuing unemployment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If such period of continuing unemployment ends by reason of clause (v) but the stoppage of work continues, the waiting period established in clause (ii) shall apply to the employee’s first registration period in a new period of continuing unemployment based upon the same stoppage of work.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iv)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition of period of continuing unemployment</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Except as limited by clause (v), for the purposes of this subparagraph, the term “period of continuing unemployment” means—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> a single registration period that includes more than 4 days of unemployment;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> a series of consecutive registration periods, each of which includes more than 4 days of unemployment; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> a series of successive registration periods, each of which includes more than 4 days of unemployment, if each succeeding registration period begins within 15 days after the last day of the immediately preceding registration period.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(v)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Special rule regarding end of period</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of applying clause (ii), a period of continuing unemployment ends when an employee exhausts rights to unemployment benefits under subsection (c) of this section.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(vi)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limit on amount of benefits</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No benefits shall be payable to an otherwise eligible employee for any day of unemployment in a registration period where the total amount of the remuneration (as defined in <ref>section 351(j) of this title</ref>) payable or accruing to him for days within such registration period exceeds the amount of the base year monthly compensation base. For purposes of the preceding sentence, an employee’s remuneration shall be deemed to include the gross amount of any remuneration that would have become payable to that employee but did not become payable because that employee was not ready or willing to perform suitable work available to that employee on any day within such registration period.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Payment of Sickness Benefits.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Generally</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as otherwise provided in this subparagraph, benefits shall be payable to any qualified employee for each day of sickness after the 4th consecutive day of sickness in a period of continuing sickness but excluding 4 days of sickness in any registration period in such period of continuing sickness.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Waiting period for first registration period</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Benefits shall be payable to any qualified employee for each day of sickness in excess of 7 during that employee’s first registration period in a period of continuing sickness if such period of continuing sickness is the employee’s initial period of continuing sickness commencing in the benefit year. For the purposes of this clause, the first registration period in a period of continuing sickness is that registration period that first begins with 4 consecutive days of sickness and includes more than 4 days of sickness.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition of period of continuing sickness</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For the purposes of this subparagraph, a period of continuing sickness means—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> a period of consecutive days of sickness, whether from 1 or more causes; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> a period of successive days of sickness due to a single cause without interruption of more than 90 consecutive days which are not days of sickness.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iv)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Special rule regarding end of period</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of applying clause (ii), a period of continuing sickness ends when an employee exhausts rights to sickness benefits under subsection (c) of this section.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The daily benefit rate with respect to any such employee for such day of unemployment or sickness shall be in an amount equal to 60 per centum of the daily rate of compensation for the employee’s last employment in which he engaged for an employer in the base year, but not less than $12.70: <i>Provided, however</i>, That for registration periods beginning after <date date="1975-06-30">June 30, 1975</date>, but before <date date="1976-07-01">July 1, 1976</date>, such amount shall not exceed $24 per day of such unemployment or sickness, that for registration periods beginning after <date date="1976-06-30">June 30, 1976</date>, but before <date date="1988-07-01">July 1, 1988</date>, such amount shall not exceed $25 per day of such unemployment or sickness, that for registration periods beginning after <date date="1988-06-30">June 30, 1988</date>, but before <date date="1989-07-01">July 1, 1989</date>, such amount shall not exceed $30 per day of unemployment or sickness, and that for registration periods beginning after <date date="1989-06-30">June 30, 1989</date>, such amount shall not exceed the maximum daily benefit rate provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection. The daily rate of compensation referred to in this paragraph shall be determined by the Board on the basis of information furnished to the Board by the employee, his employer, or both.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The maximum daily benefit rate computed by the Board under <ref>section 362(r)(2) of this title</ref> shall be the product of the monthly compensation base, as computed under <ref>section 351(i)(2) of this title</ref> for the base year immediately preceding the beginning of the benefit year, multiplied by 5 percent. If the maximum daily benefit rate so computed is not a multiple of $1, it shall be rounded down to the nearest multiple of $1.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> In computing benefits to be paid, days of unemployment shall not be combined with days of sickness in the same registration period.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding paragraph (3), subsection (c)(1)(B), and any other limitation on total benefits in this chapter, for registration periods beginning on or after <date date="2020-04-01">April 1, 2020</date>, but on or before <date date="2020-07-31">July 31, 2020</date>, and for registration periods beginning after <date date="2020-12-26">December 26, 2020</date>, but on or before <date date="2021-09-06">September 6, 2021</date>, a recovery benefit shall be payable to a qualified employee with respect to any registration period in which the employee received unemployment benefits under paragraph (1)(A), and in any registration period in which the employee did not receive unemployment benefits due to the limitation in subsection (c)(1)(B) or due to reaching the maximum number of days of benefits in the benefit year beginning <date date="2019-07-01">July 1, 2019</date>, or <date date="2020-07-01">July 1, 2020</date>, or <date date="2021-07-01">July 1, 2021</date>, under subsection (c)(1)(A). No recovery benefits shall be payable under this section upon the exhaustion of the funds appropriated under subparagraph (B) for payment of benefits under this subparagraph. For registration periods beginning on or after <date date="2020-04-01">April 1, 2020</date>, but on or before <date date="2020-07-31">July 31, 2020</date>, the recovery benefit payable under this subparagraph shall be in the amount of $1,200. For registration periods beginning after <date date="2020-12-26">December 26, 2020</date>, but on or before <date date="2021-09-06">September 6, 2021</date>, the recovery benefit payable under this subparagraph shall be in the amount of $600.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Out of any funds in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, there are appropriated $425,000,000 to cover the cost of recovery benefits provided under subparagraph (A), to remain available until expended.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Time of payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The benefits provided for in this section shall be paid to an employee at such reasonable intervals as the Board may prescribe.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Maximum number of days for benefits</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Normal benefits</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Generally</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The maximum number of days of unemployment within a benefit year for which benefits may be paid to an employee shall be 130, and the maximum number of days of sickness within a benefit year for which benefits may be paid to an employee shall be 130.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The total amount of benefits that may be paid to an employee for days of unemployment within a benefit year shall in no case exceed the employee’s compensation in the base year; and the total amount of benefits that may be paid to an employee for days of sickness within a benefit year shall in no case exceed the employee’s compensation in the base year, except that notwithstanding <ref>section 351(i) of this title</ref>, in determining the employee’s compensation in the base year for the purpose of this sentence, any money remuneration paid to the employee for services rendered as an employee shall be taken into account that is not in excess of an amount that bears the same ratio to $775 as the monthly compensation base for that year as computed under <ref>section 351(i) of this title</ref> bears to $600.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Extended benefits</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Generally</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">With respect to an employee who has 10 or more years of service as defined in <ref>section 231(f) of this title</ref>, who did not voluntarily retire and (in a case involving exhaustion of rights to normal benefits for days of unemployment) did not voluntarily leave work without good cause, and who had current rights to normal benefits for days of unemployment or days of sickness in a benefit year but has exhausted such rights, the benefit year in which such rights are exhausted shall be deemed not to be ended until the last day of the extended benefit period determined under this paragraph, and extended unemployment benefits or extended sickness benefits (depending on the type of normal benefit rights exhausted) may be paid for not more than 65 days of unemployment or 65 days of sickness within such extended benefit period.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Beginning date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">An employee’s extended benefit period shall begin on the employee’s first day of unemployment or first day of sickness, as the case may be, following the day on which the employee exhausts the employee’s then current rights to normal benefits for days of unemployment or days of sickness and shall continue for 7 consecutive 14-day periods, each of which shall constitute a registration period, but no such extended benefit period shall extend beyond the beginning of the first registration period in a benefit year in which the employee is again qualified for benefits in accordance with <ref>section 353 of this title</ref> on the basis of compensation earned after the first of such consecutive 14-day periods has begun.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination when employee reaches age of 65</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Notwithstanding any other provision of this paragraph, an extended benefit period for sickness benefits shall terminate on the day next preceding the date on which the employee attains age 65, except that it may continue for the purpose of paying benefits for days of unemployment.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Temporary increase in extended unemployment benefits</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Employees with 10 or more years of service</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">Subject to clause (iii), in the case of an employee who has 10 or more years of service (as so defined), with respect to extended unemployment benefits—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> subparagraph (A) shall be applied by substituting “330 days of unemployment” for “65 days of unemployment”; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> subparagraph (B) shall be applied by inserting “(or, in the case of unemployment benefits, 33 consecutive 14-day periods, except that no extended benefit period shall end before 20 consecutive 14-day periods after the date of enactment of the Continued Assistance for Unemployed Workers Act of 2020 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002026">1</ref> have elapsed)” after “7 consecutive 14-day periods”.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Employees with less than 10 years of service</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">Subject to clause (iii), in the case of an employee who has less than 10 years of service (as so defined), with respect to extended unemployment benefits, this paragraph shall apply to such an employee in the same manner as this paragraph would apply to an employee described in clause (i) if such clause had not been enacted and if—</chapeau>
<level class="indent4">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> subparagraph (A) were applied by substituting “265 days of unemployment” for “65 days of unemployment”; and</content>
</level>
<level class="indent4">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> subparagraph (B) were applied by inserting “(or, in the case of unemployment benefits, 27 consecutive 14-day periods, except that no extended benefit period shall end before 20 consecutive 14-day periods after the date of enactment of the Continued Assistance for Unemployed Workers Act of 2020 <sup>1</sup> have elapsed)” after “7 consecutive 14-day periods”.</content>
</level>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The provisions of clauses (i) and (ii) shall apply to an employee who received normal benefits for days of unemployment under this chapter during the period beginning <date date="2019-07-01">July 1, 2019</date>, and ending on <date date="2022-06-30">June 30, 2022</date>, except that the provisions of clauses (i) and (ii) shall not apply to any employee with respect to any registration period beginning after <date date="2021-09-06">September 6, 2021</date>..<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002027">2</ref> Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, no benefits shall be payable under this subparagraph and clauses (i) and (ii) shall no longer be applicable upon the exhaustion of the funds appropriated under clause (v) for payment of benefits under this subparagraph.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iv)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment of certain calendar days</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">No calendar day occurring during the period beginning on the first date with respect to which the employee has exhausted all rights to extended unemployment benefits under this paragraph as in effect on the day before the date of enactment of the Continued Assistance for Unemployed Workers Act of 2020 <sup>1</sup> and ending with the date of such enactment may be treated as a day of unemployment for purposes of the payment of extended unemployment benefits under this paragraph.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(v)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appropriation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Out of any funds in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, there are appropriated $20,000,000 to cover the cost of additional extended unemployment benefits provided under this subparagraph, to remain available until expended. In addition to the amount appropriated by the preceding sentence, out of any funds in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, there are appropriated $175,000,000 to cover the cost of additional extended unemployment benefits provided under this subparagraph, to remain available until expended. In addition to the amount appropriated by the preceding two sentences, out of any funds in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, there are appropriated $2,000,000 to cover the cost of additional extended unemployment benefits provided under this subparagraph, to remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Accelerated benefits</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General rule</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">With respect to an employee who has 10 or more years of service as defined in <ref>section 231(f) of this title</ref>, who did not voluntarily retire, and (in a case involving unemployment benefits) did not voluntarily leave work without good cause, who has 14 or more consecutive days of unemployment, or 14 or more consecutive days of sickness, and who is not a qualified employee with respect to the general benefit year current when such unemployment or sickness commences but is or becomes a qualified employee for the next succeeding general benefit year, such succeeding general benefit year shall, in that employee’s case, begin on the first day of the month in which such unemployment or sickness commences.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In the case of a succeeding benefit year beginning in accordance with subparagraph (A) by reason of sickness, such sentence shall not operate to permit the payment of benefits in the period provided for in such sentence for any day of sickness beginning with the date on which the employee attains age 65, and continuing through the day preceding the first day of the next succeeding general benefit year.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determination of age</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">For the purposes of this subsection, the Board may rely on evidence of age available in its records and files at the time determinations of age are made.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Overpayment of benefits; recovery; liability of officers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the Board finds that at any time more than the correct amount of benefits has been paid to any individual under this chapter or a payment has been made to an individual not entitled thereto (including payments made prior to <date date="1940-07-01">July 1, 1940</date>), recovery by adjustments in subsequent payments to which such individual is entitled under this chapter or any other Act administered by the Board may, except as otherwise provided in this subsection, be made under regulations prescribed by the Board. If such individual dies before recovery is completed, recovery may be made by set-off or adjustments, under regulations prescribed by the Board, in subsequent payments due, under this chapter or any other Act administered by the Board, to the estate, designee, next of kin, legal representative, or surviving spouse of such individual, with respect to the employment of such individual.</p>
<p class="indent0">Adjustments under this subsection may be made either by deductions from subsequent payments or, with respect to payments which are to be made during a lifetime or lifetimes, by subtracting the total amount of benefits paid in excess of the proper amount from the actuarial value, as determined by the Board, of such payments to be made during a lifetime or lifetimes and recertifying such payments on the basis of the reduced actuarial value. In the latter case, recovery shall be deemed to have been completed upon such recertification.</p>
<p class="indent0">There shall be no recovery in any case in which more than the correct amount of benefits has been paid to an individual or payment has been made to an individual not entitled thereto (including payments made prior to <date date="1940-07-01">July 1, 1940</date>) who, in the judgment of the Board, is without fault when, in the judgment of the Board, recovery would be contrary to the purpose of this chapter or would be against equity or good conscience.</p>
<p class="indent0">No certifying or disbursing officer shall be held liable for any amount certified or paid by him in good faith to any person where the recovery of such amount is waived under the third paragraph of this subsection or has been begun but cannot be completed under the first paragraph of this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assignment, taxation, garnishment, attachment, etc., of benefits</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other law of the United States, or of any State, Territory, or the District of Columbia, no benefits shall be assignable or be subject to any tax or to garnishment, attachment, or other legal process under any circumstances whatsoever, nor shall the payment thereof be anticipated.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect of payment of benefits for remunerable period; payment of surplus remuneration to Board</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If (i) benefits are paid to any employee with respect to unemployment or sickness in any registration period, and it is later determined that remuneration is payable to such employee with respect to any period which includes days in such registration period which had been determined to be days of unemployment or sickness, and (ii) the person or company from which such remuneration is payable has, before payment thereof, notice of the payment of benefits upon the basis of days of unemployment or sickness included in such period, the remuneration so payable shall not be reduced by reason of such benefits but the remuneration so payable, to the extent to which benefits were paid upon the basis of days which had been determined to be days of unemployment or sickness and which are included in the period for which such remuneration is payable, shall be held to be a special fund in trust for the Board. The amount of such special fund shall be paid to the Board and in the collection thereof the Board shall have the same authority, and the same penalties shall apply, as are provided in <ref>section 358 of this title</ref> with respect to contributions. The proceeds of such special fund shall be credited to the account. Such benefits, to the extent that they are represented in such a special fund which has been collected by the Board, shall be disregarded for the purposes of subsection (c) of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payment of accrued benefits upon death</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Benefits accrued to an individual but not yet paid at death shall, upon certification by the Board, be paid, without necessity of filing further claims therefor, to the same individual or individuals to whom any accrued annuities under <ref>section 231e(a)(1) of this title</ref> are paid. In the event that no such accrued annuities are paid, and if application for such accrued benefits is filed prior to the expiration of two years after the death of the individual to whom such benefits accrued, such accrued benefits shall be paid, upon certification by the Board, to the individual or individuals who would be entitled thereto under <ref>section 231e(a)(1) of this title</ref> if such accrued benefits were accrued annuities. If there is no individual to whom all or any part of such accrued benefits can be paid in accordance with the foregoing provisions, such benefits or part thereof shall escheat to the credit of the account.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1938, ch. 680, § 2</ref>, <ref>52 Stat. 1096</ref>; <ref>June 20, 1939, ch. 227</ref>, §§ 7–9, 21, <ref>53 Stat. 845</ref>, 848; <ref>Oct. 10, 1940, ch. 842</ref>, §§ 9–12, <ref>54 Stat. 1095</ref>, 1096; <ref>July 31, 1946, ch. 709</ref>, §§ 305–307, <ref>60 Stat. 736</ref>, 737; <ref>May 15, 1952, ch. 290, § 1</ref>, <ref>66 Stat. 73</ref>; <ref>Aug. 31, 1954, ch. 1164</ref>, pt. III, § 304, <ref>68 Stat. 1041</ref>; <ref>Aug. 12, 1955, ch. 869, § 4</ref>, <ref>69 Stat. 716</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–28</ref>, pt. III, §§ 302, 303(a), <date date="1959-05-19">May 19, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 30</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–700, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="1966-10-30">Oct. 30, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1087</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–257, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="1968-02-15">Feb. 15, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 23</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–445, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="1974-10-16">Oct. 16, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1359</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–92, title I, § 1(c)</ref>–(e), <date date="1975-08-09">Aug. 9, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 461</ref>, 462; <ref>Pub. L. 98–76, title IV, § 412(a)</ref>, <date date="1983-08-12">Aug. 12, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 436</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–647, title VII</ref>, §§ 7101(c), 7201(a), <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3758</ref>, 3774; <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title III, § 324(3)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 950</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–251</ref>, §§ 2–5(b), <date date="1996-10-09">Oct. 9, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3161–3165</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–5, div. B, title II, § 2006(a)</ref>, <date date="2009-02-17">Feb. 17, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 445</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–92, § 9(a)</ref>, <date date="2009-11-06">Nov. 6, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2988</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–312, title V, § 505(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-12-17">Dec. 17, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3308</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–78, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-23">Dec. 23, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1283</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–96, title II, § 2124(a)</ref>, <date date="2012-02-22">Feb. 22, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 167</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–240, title V, § 504(a)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 2344</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–136, div. A, title II</ref>, §§ 2113, 2114(a), <date date="2020-03-27">Mar. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 334</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–260, div. N, title II</ref>, §§ 232(a), 233(a), <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 1957</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–2, title II</ref>, §§ 2901(a), 2902(a), <date date="2021-03-11">Mar. 11, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 49</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 353.</num>
<heading> Qualifying condition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An employee shall be a “qualified employee” if the Board finds that his compensation with respect to the base year will have been not less than 2.5 times the monthly compensation base for months in such base year as computed under <ref>section 351(i) of this title</ref>, and, if such employee has had no compensation prior to such year, that he will have had compensation with respect to each of not less than five months in such year.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1938, ch. 680, § 3</ref>, <ref>52 Stat. 1097</ref>; <ref>June 20, 1939, ch. 227, § 10</ref>, <ref>53 Stat. 845</ref>; <ref>Oct. 10, 1940, ch. 842, § 13</ref>, <ref>54 Stat. 1097</ref>; <ref>July 31, 1946, ch. 709, § 308</ref>, <ref>60 Stat. 737</ref>; <ref>May 15, 1952, ch. 290, § 2</ref>, <ref>66 Stat. 73</ref>; <ref>Aug. 31, 1954, ch. 1164</ref>, pt. III, § 303, <ref>68 Stat. 1041</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–28</ref>, pt. III, § 304, <date date="1959-05-19">May 19, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 31</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–133, title III, § 301(a)</ref>, <date date="1963-10-05">Oct. 5, 1963</date>, <ref>77 Stat. 222</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–257, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="1968-02-15">Feb. 15, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 24</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–92, title I, § 1(f)</ref>, <date date="1975-08-09">Aug. 9, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 463</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–76, title IV, § 411(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1983-08-12">Aug. 12, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 436</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–647, title VII, § 7202(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3776</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 354.</num>
<heading> Disqualifying conditions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a–1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Day of unemployment or day of sickness</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There shall not be considered as a day of unemployment, or as a day of sickness, with respect to any employee—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any of the seventy-five days beginning with the first day of any registration period with respect to which the Board finds that he knowingly made or aided in making or caused to be made any false or fraudulent statement or claim for the purpose of causing benefits to be paid;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any day in any period with respect to which the Board finds that he is receiving or will have received annuity payments under the Railroad Retirement Act of 1974 [<ref>45 U.S.C. 231</ref> et seq.], or insurance benefits under title II of the Social Security Act [<ref>42 U.S.C. 401</ref> et seq.], or unemployment, maternity, or sickness benefits under an unemployment, maternity, or sickness compensation law other than this chapter, or any other social-insurance payments under any law: <i>Provided</i>, That if an employee receives or is held entitled to receive any such payments, other than unemployment, maternity, or sickness payments, with respect to any period which include days of unemployment or sickness in a registration period, after benefits under this chapter for such registration period will have been paid, the amount by which such benefits under this chapter will have been increased by including such days as days of unemployment or as days of sickness shall be recoverable by the Board: <i>Provided further</i>, That, if that part of any such payment or payments, other than unemployment, maternity, or sickness payments, which is apportionable to such days of unemployment or days of sickness is less in amount than the benefits under this chapter which, but for this paragraph, would be payable and not recoverable with respect to such days of unemployment or days of sickness, the preceding provisions of this paragraph shall not apply but such benefits under this chapter for such days of unemployment or days of sickness shall be diminished or recoverable in the amount of such part of such other payment or payments;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> if he is paid a separation allowance, any of the days in the period beginning with the day following his separation from service and continuing for that number of consecutive fourteen-day periods which is equal, or most nearly equal, to the amount of the separation allowance divided (i) by ten times his last daily rate of compensation prior to his separation if he normally works five days a week, (ii) by twelve times such rate if he normally works six days a week, and (iii) by fourteen times such rate if he normally works seven days a week; <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002028">1</ref></content>
</clause>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a–2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Day of unemployment</heading>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<level class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> subject to the provisions of subdivision (B) hereof, any of the days in the period beginning with the day with respect to which the Board finds that he left work voluntarily, and continuing until he has been paid compensation of not less than $1,500 with respect to time after the beginning of such period and before 1989 or, if any part of such compensation is paid in a calendar year after 1988, not less than an amount that is equal to 2.5 times the monthly compensation base for months in such calendar year, as computed under <ref>section 351(i) of this title</ref>;</content>
</level>
<level class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> if the Board finds that he left work voluntarily with good cause, the provisions of subdivision (A) shall not apply, with respect to him, to any day in a registration period if such period does not include any day which is in a period for which he could receive benefits under an unemployment compensation law other than this chapter, and he so certifies. Such certification shall, in the absence of evidence to the contrary, be accepted subject to the penalty provisions of <ref>section 359(a) of this title</ref>;</content>
</level>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any of the thirty days beginning with the day with respect to which the Board finds that he failed, without good cause, to accept suitable work available on such day and offered to him, or to comply with instructions from the Board requiring him to apply for suitable work or to report, in person or by mail as the Board may require, to an employment office;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> subject to the provisions of subsection (b) of this section, any day with respect to which the Board finds that his unemployment was due to a stoppage of work because of a strike in the establishment, premises, or enterprise at which he was last employed, and the Board finds that such strike was commenced in violation of the provisions of the Railway Labor Act [<ref>45 U.S.C. 151</ref> et seq.] or in violation of the established rules and practices of a bona fide labor organization of which he was a member.</content>
</clause>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Participation, interest, or financial assistance in labor dispute</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The disqualification provided in subsection (a–2)(iii) of this section shall not apply if the Board finds that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the employee is not participating in or financing or directly interested in the strike which causes the stoppage of work: <i>Provided</i>, That payment of regular union dues shall not be construed to constitute financing a strike or direct interest in a strike within the meaning of this and the following paragraphs; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> he does not belong to a grade or class of workers of which, immediately before the commencement of the stoppage, there were members employed in the establishment, premises, or enterprise at which the stoppage occurs, any of whom are participating in or financing or directly interested in the dispute: <i>Provided</i>, That if separate types of work are commonly conducted in separate departments of a single enterprise, each such department shall, for the purposes of this subsection, be deemed to be a separate establishment, enterprise, or other premises.</content>
</clause>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Unsuitable work</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">No work shall be deemed suitable for the purposes of subsection (a–2)(ii) of this section, and benefits shall not be denied under this chapter to any otherwise qualified employee for refusing to accept work if—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the position offered is vacant due directly to a strike, lockout, or other labor dispute;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the remuneration, hours, or other conditions of work offered are substantially less favorable to the employee than those prevailing for similar work in the locality, or the rate of remuneration is less than the union wage rate, if any, for similar work in the locality;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> as a condition of being employed he would be required to join a company union or to resign from or refrain from joining any bona fide labor organization;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> acceptance of the work would require him to engage in activities in violation of law or which, by reason of their being in violation of reasonable requirements of the constitution, bylaws, or similar regulations of a bona fide labor organization of which he is a member, would subject him to expulsion from such labor organization; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> acceptance of the work would subject him to loss of substantial seniority rights under any collective bargaining agreement between a railway labor organization, organized in accordance with the provisions of the Railway Labor Act [<ref>45 U.S.C. 151</ref> et seq.], and any other employer.</content>
</clause>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Factors in determination of suitable work</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In determining, within the limitations of subsection (c) of this section, whether or not any work is suitable for an employee for the purposes of subsection (a–2)(ii) of this section, the Board shall consider, in addition to such other factors as it deems relevant, (i) the current practices recognized by management and labor with respect to such work; (ii) the degree of risk involved to such employee’s health, safety, and morals; (iii) his physical fitness and prior training; (iv) his experience and prior earnings; (v) his length of unemployment and prospects for securing work in his customary occupation; and (vi) the distance of the available work from his residence and from his most recent work.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Voluntarily leaving unsuitable work</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purposes of subsection (a–2)(i) of this section, no voluntary leaving of work shall be deemed to have been without good cause if the Board finds that such work would not have been suitable for the purposes of subsection (a–2)(ii) of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1938, ch. 680, § 4</ref>, <ref>52 Stat. 1098</ref>; <ref>June 20, 1939, ch. 227, § 11</ref>, <ref>53 Stat. 846</ref>; <ref>Oct. 10, 1940, ch. 842</ref>, §§ 14–18, <ref>54 Stat. 1097</ref>, 1098; <ref>July 31, 1946, ch. 709</ref>, §§ 309, 310, <ref>60 Stat. 737</ref>, 738; <ref>Oct. 30, 1951, ch. 632, § 27</ref>, <ref>65 Stat. 691</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–927</ref>, pt. II, § 202, <date date="1958-09-06">Sept. 6, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1782</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–28</ref>, pt. III, § 305, <date date="1959-05-19">May 19, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 31</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–133, title III, § 302(a)</ref>, <date date="1963-10-05">Oct. 5, 1963</date>, <ref>77 Stat. 222</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–257, title II, § 204</ref>, <date date="1968-02-15">Feb. 15, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 24</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–445, title IV, § 402</ref>, <date date="1974-10-16">Oct. 16, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1359</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–76, title IV, § 411(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1983-08-12">Aug. 12, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 436</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–647, title VII, § 7101(d)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3758</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 355.</num>
<heading> Claims for benefits</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Publication of Board’s regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Claims for benefits and appeals from determinations with respect thereto shall be made in accordance with such regulations as the Board shall prescribe. Each employer shall post and maintain, in places readily accessible to employees in his service, such printed statements concerning such regulations as the Board supplies to him for such purpose, and shall keep available to his employees copies of such printed statements. Such printed statements shall be supplied by the Board to each employer without cost to him.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Findings, hearings, investigations, etc., by Board</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Board is authorized and directed to make findings of fact with respect to any claim for benefits and to make decisions as to the right of any claimant to benefits. The Board is further authorized to hold such hearings, to conduct such investigations and other proceedings, and to establish, by regulations or otherwise, such procedures as it may deem necessary or proper for the determination of a right to benefits. When a claim for benefits is filed with the Board, the Board shall provide notice of such claim to the claimant’s base-year employer or employers and afford such employer or employers an opportunity to submit information relevant to the claim before making an initial determination on the claim. When the Board initially determines to pay benefits to a claimant under this chapter, the Board shall provide notice of such determination to the claimant’s base-year employer or employers.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Hearing and review of decisions on claims</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Each qualified employee whose claim for benefits has been denied in whole or in part upon an initial determination with respect thereto upon a basis other than one which is reviewable pursuant to one of the succeeding paragraphs of this subsection, shall be granted an opportunity for a fair hearing thereon before a referee or such other reviewing body as the Board may establish or assign thereto. In any such case the Board or the person or reviewing body so established or assigned shall, by publication or otherwise, notify all parties properly interested of their right to participate in the hearing and of the time and place of the hearing.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any claimant whose claim for benefits has been denied in an initial determination with respect thereto upon the basis of his not being a qualified employee, and any claimant who contends that under an initial determination of his claim he has been awarded benefits at less than the proper rate, may appeal to the Board for the review of such determination. Thereupon the Board shall review the determination and for such review may designate one of its officers or employees to receive evidence and to report to the Board thereon together with recommendations. In any such case the Board or the person so designated shall, by publication or otherwise, notify all parties properly interested of their right to participate in the proceeding and, if a hearing is to be held, of the time and place of the hearing. At the request of any party properly interested the Board shall provide for a hearing, and may provide for a hearing on its own motion. The Board shall prescribe regulations governing the appeals provided for in this paragraph and for decisions upon such appeal.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Any base-year employer of a claimant whose claim for benefits has been granted in whole or in part, either in an initial determination with respect thereto or in a determination after a hearing pursuant to paragraph (1), and who contends that the determination is erroneous for a reason or reasons other than a reason that is reviewable under paragraph (4), may appeal to the Board for review of such determination. Despite such an appeal, the benefits awarded shall be paid to such claimant, subject to recovery by the Board if and to the extent found on the appeal to have been erroneously awarded. The Board shall take such action as is appropriate to recover the amount of such benefits including if feasible adjustment in subsequent payments pursuant to the first two paragraphs of <ref>section 352(d) of this title</ref>. Upon an appeal, the Board shall review the determination appealed from and for such review may designate one of its officers or employees to receive evidence and report to the Board thereof together with recommendations. In any such case the Board or the person so designated shall, by publication or otherwise, notify all parties properly interested of their right to participate in the proceeding and, if a hearing is to be held, of the time and place of the hearing. At the request of any party properly interested the Board shall provide for a hearing, and may provide for a hearing on its own motion. The Board shall prescribe regulations governing the appeals provided for in this paragraph and for decisions upon such appeal.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> In any case in which benefits are awarded to a claimant in whole or in part upon the basis of pay earned in the service of a person or company found by the Board to be an employer as defined in this chapter but which denies that it is such an employer, such benefits awarded on such basis shall be paid to such claimant subject to a right of recovery of such benefits. The Board shall thereupon designate one of its officers or employees to receive evidence and to report to the Board on whether such benefits should be repaid. The Board may also designate one of its officers or employees to receive evidence and report to the Board whether or not any person or company is entitled to a refund of contributions or should be required to pay contributions under this chapter, regardless of whether or not any claims for benefits will have been filed upon the basis of service in the employ of such person or company, and shall follow such procedure if contributions are assessed and payment is refused or payment is made and a refund claimed upon the basis that such person or company is or will not have been liable for such contributions. In any such case the Board or the person so designated shall, by publication or otherwise, notify all parties properly interested of their right to participate in the proceeding and, if a hearing is to be held, of the time and place of the hearing. At the request of any party properly interested the Board shall provide for a hearing, and may provide for a hearing on its own motion. The Board shall prescribe regulations governing the proceedings provided for in this paragraph and for decisions upon such proceedings.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Final decision of the Board in the cases provided for in the preceding three paragraphs shall be communicated to the claimant and to the other interested parties within fifteen days after it is made. Any properly interested party notified, as hereinabove provided, of his right to participate in the proceedings may obtain a review of any such decision by which he claims to be aggrieved or the determination of any issue therein in the manner provided in subsection (f) of this section with respect to the review of the Board’s decisions upon claims for benefits and subject to all provisions of law applicable to the review of such decisions. Subject only to such review, the decision of the Board upon all issues determined in such decision shall be final and conclusive for all purposes and shall conclusively establish all rights and obligations, arising under this chapter, of every party notified as hereinabove provided of his right to participate in the proceedings.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> For purposes of this subsection and subsections (d) and (f), any base-year employer of the claimant is a properly interested party.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Any issue determinable pursuant to this subsection and subsection (f) of this section shall not be determined in any manner other than pursuant to this subsection and subsection (f).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Decisions of reviewing bodies; review and finality</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Board shall prescribe regulations governing the filing of cases with and the decision of cases by reviewing bodies, and the review of such decisions. The Board may provide for intermediate reviews of such decisions by such bodies as the Board may establish or assign thereto. The Board may (i) on its own motion review a decision of an intermediate reviewing body on the basis of the evidence previously submitted in such case, and may direct the taking of additional evidence, or (ii) permit such parties as it finds properly interested in the proceedings to take appeals to the Board. Unless a review or an appeal is had pursuant to this subsection, the decision of an intermediate reviewing body shall, subject to such regulations as the Board may prescribe, be deemed to be the final decision of the Board.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application of rules of evidence in law and equity; notice of findings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In any proceeding other than a court proceeding, the rules of evidence prevailing in courts of law or equity shall not be controlling, but a full and complete record shall be kept of all proceedings and testimony, and the Board’s final determination, together with its findings of fact and conclusions of law in connection therewith, shall be communicated to the parties within fifteen days after the date of such final determination.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review of final decision of Board by Courts of Appeals; costs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any claimant, or any railway labor organization organized in accordance with the provisions of the Railway Labor Act [<ref>45 U.S.C. 151</ref> et seq.], of which claimant is a member, or any base-year employer of the claimant, or any other party aggrieved by a final decision under subsection (c) of this section, may, only after all administrative remedies within the Board will have been availed of and exhausted, obtain a review of any final decision of the Board by filing a petition for review within ninety days after the mailing of notice of such decision to the claimant or other party, or within such further time as the Board may allow, in the United States court of appeals for the circuit in which the claimant or other party resides or will have had his principal place of business or principal executive office, or in the United States Court of Appeals for the Seventh Circuit or in the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia. A copy of such petition, together with initial process, shall forth-with be served upon the Board or any officer designated by it for such purpose. A copy of such petition also shall forthwith be served upon any other properly interested party, and such party shall be a party to the review proceeding. Service may be made upon the Board by registered mail addressed to the Chairman. Within thirty days after receipt of service, or within such additional time as the court may allow, the Board shall file with the court in which such petition has been filed the record upon which the findings and decision complained of are based, as provided in <ref>section 2112 of title 28</ref>. Upon the filing of such petition the court shall have exclusive jurisdiction of the proceeding and of the question determined therein. It shall have power to enter a decree affirming, modifying, or reversing the decision of the Board, with or without remanding the cause for rehearing. The findings of the Board as to the facts, if supported by evidence and in the absence of fraud, shall be conclusive. No additional evidence shall be received by the court but the court may order additional evidence to be taken before the Board, and the Board may, after hearing such additional evidence, modify its findings of fact and conclusions and file such additional or modified findings and conclusions with the court, and the Board shall file with the court the additional record. The judgment and decree of the court shall be final, subject to review as in equity cases.</p>
<p class="indent0">An applicant for review of a final decision of the Board concerning a claim for benefits shall not be liable for costs, including costs of serv­ice, or costs of printing records, except that costs may be assessed by the court against such applicant if the court determines that the proceedings for such review have been instituted or continued without reasonable ground.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Finality of Board decisions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Findings of fact and conclusions of law of the Board in the determination of any claim for benefits or refund, the determination of any other matter pursuant to subsection (c) of this section, and the determination of the Board that the unexpended funds in the account are available for the payment of any claim for benefits or refund under this chapter, shall be, except as provided in subsection (f) of this section, binding and conclusive for all purposes and upon all persons, including the Comptroller General and any other administrative or accounting officer, employee, or agent of the United States, and shall not be subject to review in any manner other than that set forth in subsection (f) of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Benefits payable prior to final decision of Board</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as may be otherwise prescribed by regulations of the Board, benefits payable with respect to any period prior to the date of a final decision of the Board with respect to a claim therefor, shall be paid only after such final decision.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fees for presenting claims; penalties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No claimant or other properly interested person claiming benefits shall be charged fees of any kind by the Board, its employees or representatives, with respect to such claim. Any such claimant or other properly interested person may be represented by counsel or other duly authorized agent, in any proceeding before the Board or its representatives or a court, but no such counsel or agent for a claimant shall either charge or receive for such services more than an amount approved by the Board or by the court before whom the proceedings of the Board are reviewed. Any person who violates any provision of this subsection shall be punished by a fine of not more than $10,000 or by imprisonment not exceeding one year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1938, ch. 680, § 5</ref>, <ref>52 Stat. 1099</ref>; <ref>Oct. 10, 1940, ch. 842</ref>, §§ 19, 20, <ref>54 Stat. 1098</ref>; <ref>July 31, 1946, ch. 709</ref>, §§ 311–316, <ref>60 Stat. 738</ref>; <ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, §§ 1, 32(a), <ref>62 Stat. 870</ref>, 991; <ref>May 24, 1949, ch. 139, § 127</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 107</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–791, § 23</ref>, <date date="1958-08-28">Aug. 28, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 948</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–35, title XI, § 1128(a)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 641</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–620, title IV, § 402(47)</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 3360</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–647, title VII, § 7104(a)</ref>–(c), <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3771</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 355a.</num>
<heading> Acceptance of claims for benefits</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever there is duly tendered to the Board, by any person, any claim for unemployment compensation pursuant to the Railroad Unemployment Insurance Act [<ref>45 U.S.C. 351</ref> et seq.], such claim shall be accepted by the Board without delay and appropriate administrative action for the allowance or disallowance of such claim shall be taken by the Board at the earliest practicable time.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 29, 1956, ch. 477</ref>, title V, § 501, <ref>70 Stat. 437</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 356.</num>
<heading> Returns of compensation; conclusiveness; failure to make</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Employers shall file with the Board, in such manner and at such times as the Board by regulations may prescribe, returns of compensation of employees, and, if the Board shall so require, shall distribute to employees annual statements of compensation: <i>Provided</i>, That no returns shall be required of employers which would duplicate information contained in similar returns required under any other Act of Congress administered by the Board. The Board’s record of the compensation so returned shall, for the purpose of determining eligibility for and the amount of benefits, be conclusive as to the amount of compensation paid to an employee during the period covered by the return, and the fact that the Board’s records show that no return was made of the compensation claimed to have been paid to an employee during a particular period shall, for the purposes of determining eligibility for and the amount of benefits, be taken as conclusive that no compensation was paid to such employee during that period, unless the error in the amount of compensation in the one case, or failure to make or record return of the compensation in the other case, is called to the attention of the Board within eighteen months after the date on which the last return covering any portion of the calendar year which includes such period is required to have been made.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1938, ch. 680, § 6</ref>, <ref>52 Stat. 1101</ref>; <ref>June 20, 1939, ch. 227, § 12</ref>, <ref>53 Stat. 847</ref>; <ref>Oct. 10, 1940, ch. 842, § 21</ref>, <ref>54 Stat. 1099</ref>; <ref>July 31, 1946, ch. 709, § 317</ref>, <ref>60 Stat. 739</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–700, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="1966-10-30">Oct. 30, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1087</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 357.</num>
<heading> Free transportation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It shall not be unlawful for carriers to furnish free transportation to employees qualified for benefits or serving waiting periods under this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1938, ch. 680, § 7</ref>, <ref>52 Stat. 1102</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 358.</num>
<heading> Contributions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Employer contribution</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General rule</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contribution rate generally</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Every employer shall pay a contribution, with respect to having employees in his service, equal to the percentage determined under subparagraph (B), (C), or (D), whichever is applicable, of so much of the compensation paid in any calendar month by such employer to any employee as is not in excess of the monthly compensation base for that month as computed under <ref>section 351(i) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Multiple employer limitation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">If compensation is paid to an employee by more than one employer in any calendar month—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the contributions required by this subsection shall not apply to any amount of the aggregate compensation paid to such employee by all such employers in such calendar month which is in excess of such monthly compensation base; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> each employer (other than a subordinate unit of a national-railway-labor-organization employer) shall be liable for that portion of the contribution with respect to such compensation paid by all such employers which the compensation paid by him to such employee bears to the total compensation paid in such month by all such employers to such employee.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent3 firstIndent-1"> In the event that the compensation paid by such employers to the employee in such month is less than such monthly compensation base, each subordinate unit of a national-railway-labor-organization employer shall be liable for such portion of any additional contribution as the compensation paid by such employer to such employee in such month bears to the total compensation paid by all such employers to such employee in such month.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transitional rule</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> 1st, 2d, and 3d calendar years</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Except as provided in clause (vi), with respect to compensation paid in calendar years 1988, 1989, and 1990, the contribution rate shall be 8 percent.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> 4th calendar year</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">With respect to compensation paid in calendar year 1991, the contribution rate shall be the smaller of—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the maximum contribution limit computed under paragraph (20); or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the percentage computed pursuant to the following formula:<table width="50%" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><colgroup><col/><col/><col/><col/></colgroup><thead><tr class="header"><td/></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p> </p></td><td><p>2A+B</p></td><td/></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>R=</p></td><td><p>———</p></td><td/></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p> </p></td><td><p>3</p></td><td/></tr></tbody></table>
</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> 5th calendar year</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">With respect to compensation paid in calendar year 1992, the contribution rate shall be the smaller of—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the maximum contribution limit computed under paragraph (20); or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the percentage computed pursuant to the following formula:<table width="50%" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><colgroup><col/><col/><col/><col/></colgroup><thead><tr class="header"><td/></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p> </p></td><td><p>A+2C</p></td><td/></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>R=</p></td><td><p>———</p></td><td/></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p> </p></td><td><p>3</p></td><td/></tr></tbody></table>
</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iv)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Meaning of symbols</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">For purposes of the formulas in clauses (ii) and (iii)—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> “R” is the applicable contribution rate expressed as a percentage for months in the calendar year;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> “A” is the contribution rate determined under clause (i);</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> “B” is the percentage rate for the employer, as determined under subparagraph (C), for calendar year 1991; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> “C” is the percentage rate for the employer, as determined under subparagraph (C), for calendar year 1992.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(v)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rule for certain computations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">For purposes of computing B and C in such formulas—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the percentage rate computed under subparagraph (C), if more than the maximum contribution limit computed under paragraph (20) shall not be reduced to that limit; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> any computations which under subparagraph (C) are to be made on the basis of a 4-quarter or a 12-quarter period ending on a given June 30 shall be made on the basis of a period beginning on <date date="1990-01-01">January 1, 1990</date>, and ending on that June 30, and the amount so computed shall be increased to an amount that bears the same ratio to the amount so computed as 4 or 12, as appropriate, bears to the number of calendar quarters in the period on which the computation was based.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(vi)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special transition rule for public commuter railroads</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">With respect to each of calendar years 1989 and 1990, the contribution of the National Railroad Passenger Corporation and an employer which on <date date="1988-11-10">November 10, 1988</date>, is a publicly funded and publicly operated carrier providing rail commuter service shall be equal to the amount of benefits attributable to such carrier, plus an amount equal to 0.65 percent of the total compensation paid by that employer in that year on which that employer’s contribution would be based under clause (i) if such employer’s contribution were determined under that clause.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Experience-rated contributions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">With respect to compensation paid in a calendar year that begins after <date date="1992-12-31">December 31, 1992</date>, the contribution rate for each employer shall be determined as follows:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Step 1</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Compute the employer’s benefit ratio as of the preceding June 30 to 4 decimal points in accordance with paragraph (2).</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Step 2</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Subtract the employer’s reserve ratio as of the preceding June 30 as computed to 4 decimal points in accordance with paragraph (4).</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Step 3</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Subtract the pooled credit ratio for the calendar year, if any, as computed to 4 decimal points in accordance with paragraph (12).</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iv)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Step 4</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Multiply by 100 the total arrived at under the steps set forth in clauses (i) through (iii) so as to obtain a percentage rate, which shall be rounded to the nearest 100th of 1 percent. If the total arrived at under such steps is 0 or less than 0, the percentage rate as so computed shall be 0.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(v)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Step 5</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Add 0.65 to the percentage rate arrived at under clause (iv), representing the portion of the employer’s contribution which is to be deposited to the credit of the fund under subsection (i).</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(vi)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Step 6</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Add the surcharge rate for the calendar year, if any, as computed under paragraph (14).</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(vii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Step 7</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Add the pooled charge ratio for the calendar year, if any, as computed to 4 decimal points under paragraph (13) and multiplied by 100.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(viii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Step 8</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Reduce the precentage <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002029">1</ref> rate computed in accordance with the preceding steps to the maximum contribution limit computed under paragraph (20), if such rate is higher than such limit. The rate computed in accordance with the preceding steps, after any reduction under this clause, is the contribution rate.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> New-employer contribution rates</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Notwithstanding subparagraphs (B) and (C), the contribution rate applicable to a new employer who does not become subject to this chapter until after <date date="1989-12-31">December 31, 1989</date>, shall be determined as follows:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> 1st calendar year</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">With respect to compensation paid in calendar months before the end of the first full calendar year in which the employer is subject to this chapter, the contribution rate shall be the average contribution rate paid by all employers during the 3 calendar years preceding the calendar year before the calendar year in which the compensation is paid. The average contribution rate shall be determined—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> by dividing the aggregate contributions paid by all employers under this subsection in those 3 calendar years by the aggregate compensation with respect to which such contributions were paid; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> by multiplying the resulting ratio as computed to 4 decimal points by 100.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> 2d calendar year</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">With respect to compensation paid in calendar months in the next calendar year, the contribution rate shall be the smaller of—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the maximum contribution limit computed under paragraph (20); or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the percentage rate computed pursuant to the following formula:<table width="50%" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><colgroup><col/><col/><col/><col/><col/><col/></colgroup><thead><tr class="header"><td/></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p> </p></td><td><p> </p></td><td><p>2(A2)+B</p></td><td/><td/></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>R=</p></td><td><p>A</p></td><td><p>————</p></td><td><p></p></td><td/></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p> </p></td><td><p> </p></td><td><p>3</p></td><td/><td/></tr></tbody></table>
</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> 3d calendar year</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">With respect to compensation paid in calendar months in the third full calendar year in which the employer is subject to the coverage of this chapter, the contribution rate shall be the smaller of—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the maximum contribution limit computed under paragraph (20); or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the percentage rate computed pursuant to the following formula:<table width="50%" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><colgroup><col/><col/><col/><col/></colgroup><thead><tr class="header"><td/></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p> </p></td><td><p>A3+2C</p></td><td/></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>R=</p></td><td><p>———</p></td><td/></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p> </p></td><td><p>3</p></td><td/></tr></tbody></table>
</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iv)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Subsequent calendar years</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">With respect to all calendar months in calendar years subsequent to that calendar year, the contribution rate shall be determined under subparagraph (C).</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(v)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Meaning of symbols</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">For purposes of the formulas in clauses (ii) and (iii)—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> “R” is the applicable contribution rate expressed as a percentage for months in the calendar year;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> “A1” is the contribution rate determined under clause (i) for such employer’s first full calendar year;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> “A2” is the contribution rate which would have been determined under clause (i) if the employer’s second calendar year had been its first full calendar year;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> “A3” is the contribution rate which would have been determined under clause (i) if the employer’s third calendar year had been such employer’s first full calendar year;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(V)</num>
<content> “B” is the contribution rate for the employer as determined under subparagraph (C) for the employer’s second full calendar year; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(VI)</num>
<content> “C” is the contribution rate for the employer as determined under subparagraph (C) for the employer’s third full calendar year.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(vi)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rule for certain computations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">For purposes of computing B and C in such formulas—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the percentage rate computed under subparagraph (C), shall not be reduced under clause (viii) of that subparagraph; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> any computations which under subparagraph (C) are to be made on the basis of a 4-quarter or 12-quarter period ending on a given June 30 shall be made on the basis of a period commencing with the first day of the first calendar quarter that begins after the date on which the employer first commenced paying compensation subject to this chapter and ending on that June 30, and the amount so computed shall be increased to an amount that bears the same ratio to the amount so computed as 4 or 12, as appropriate, bears to the number of calendar quarters in the period on which the computation was based.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Benefit ratio</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">An employer’s benefit ratio as of any given June 30 shall be determined by dividing all benefits charged to the employer under paragraph (15) during the 12 calendar quarters ending on such June 30 by the employer’s 3-year compensation base as of such June 30 as computed under paragraph (3).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> 3-year compensation base</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">An employer’s 3-year compensation base as of any given June 30 is the aggregate compensation with respect to which contributions were paid by the employer under this subsection in the 12 calendar quarters ending on such June 30.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reserve ratio</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">An employer’s reserve ratio as of any given June 30 shall be computed by dividing the employer’s reserve balance as of such June 30, as computed under paragraph (6), by that employer’s 1-year compensation base as of such June 30, as computed under paragraph (5). The employer’s reserve ratio may be either a positive or a negative figure, depending upon whether the employer’s reserve balance is a positive or negative figure.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> 1-year compensation base</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">An employer’s 1-year compensation base as of any given June 30 is the aggregate compensation with respect to which contributions were paid by the employer under this subsection in the 4 calendar quarters ending on such June 30.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reserve balance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">An employer’s reserve balance as of any given June 30 shall be determined by subtracting the employer’s cumulative benefit balance as of such June 30, computed under paragraph (7), from the employer’s net cumulative contribution balance as of such June 30, computed under paragraph (8). An employer’s reserve balance may be either positive or negative, depending upon whether or not that employer’s net cumulative contribution balance exceeds the employer’s cumulative benefit balance.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cumulative benefit balance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">An employer’s cumulative benefit balance as of any given June 30 shall be determined by adding—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the net amount of the benefits charged to the employer under paragraph (15) on or after <date date="1990-01-01">January 1, 1990</date>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the cumulative amount of the employer’s unallocated charges for the same period, if any, as computed under paragraph (9).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Net cumulative contribution balance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">An employer’s net cumulative contribution balance as of any given June 30 shall be determined as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Step 1</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Compute the sum of</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> all contributions paid by the employer pursuant to this subsection;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> that portion of the tax imposed under <ref>section 3321(a) of title 26</ref> that is attributable to the surtax rate under section 516(b) of the Railroad Unemployment Insurance and Retirement Improvement Act of 1988; <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002030">2</ref> and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> any taxes paid by the employer pursuant to <ref>section 3321(a) of title 26</ref> (after the outstanding balance of loans made under <ref>section 360(d) of this title</ref> before <date date="1985-10-01">October 1, 1985</date>, plus interest, have been paid);</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">on or after <date date="1990-01-01">January 1, 1990</date>.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Step 2</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Subtract an amount equal to the amount of such contributions deposited to the credit of the fund under subsection (i).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Step 3</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Add an amount equal to the aggregate amount by which such contributions were reduced in prior calendar years as a result of pooled credits, if any, under paragraph (1)(C)(iii).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Unallocated charge</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">An employer’s unallocated charge as of any given June 30 is the amount that as of such June 30 bears the same ratio to the system unallocated charge balance, computed under paragraph (10), as the employer’s 1-year compensation base, computed under paragraph (5), bears to the system compensation base computed under paragraph (11).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(10)</num>
<heading class="bold"> System unallocated charge balance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The system unallocated charge balance as of any given June 30 shall be determined as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Step 1</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Compute the aggregate amount of all interest paid by the account on loans from the Railroad Retirement Account after <date date="1985-09-30">September 30, 1985</date>, pursuant to <ref>section 360(d) of this title</ref>, during the 4 calendar quarters ending on that June 30.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Step 2</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Add the aggregate amount of any additions to the system unallocated charge balance specified in paragraphs (15) and (16), during that period.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Step 3</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Add the aggregate amount of any other expenditures by the account during that period not chargeable to any individual employer under paragraph (15) or to the fund under <ref>section 361 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Step 4</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Subtract the aggregate amount of all income to the account, under <ref>section 360(a)(iv) of this title</ref> or <ref>section 360(a)(vii) of this title</ref>, during that period.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(E)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Step 5</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Subtract the aggregate amount of all transfers to the account, pursuant to <ref>section 361(d) of this title</ref>, during that period.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(F)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Step 6</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Subtract the aggregate amount of all other income and receipts of the account, during that period, which are not assigned to individual employer balances.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(G)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Step 7</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Subtract the net cumulative contribution balance of each employer whose balance has been cancelled pursuant to paragraph (16), during that period, calculated as of the date of such cancellation.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(11)</num>
<heading class="bold"> System compensation base</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The system compensation base as of any given June 30 shall be determined by adding together the amounts of the 1-year compensation bases of all employers and employee representatives subject to this chapter, computed in accordance with paragraph (5), as of such June 30.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(12)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Pooled credit ratio</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The pooled credit ratio, if any, for a calendar year shall be determined as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Step 1</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Compute the balance to the credit of the account as of the close of business on the preceding June 30, including any amounts in the account attributable to loans made under <ref>section 360(d) of this title</ref> before <date date="1985-10-01">October 1, 1985</date>, but disregarding the obligation to repay such loans and interest thereon. In determining such balance as of June 30 of any year, so much of the balance to the credit of the railroad unemployment insurance administration fund as of the close of business on such date as is in excess of $6,000,000 shall be deemed to be part of the balance to the credit of such account. There will be a pooled credit ratio for the calendar year only if that balance is in excess of the greater of $250,000,000 or of the amount that bears the same ratio to $250,000,000 as the system compensation base as of that June 30 bears to the system compensation base as of <date date="1991-06-30">June 30, 1991</date>, as computed in accordance with paragraph (11).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Step 2</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">If there is such an excess amount, divide that excess amount by the system compensation base as of the June 30 preceding the calendar year. The result is the pooled credit ratio for the calendar year.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(13)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Pooled charge ratio</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The pooled charge ratio, if any, for a calendar year shall be determined as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Step 1</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">With respect to each employer whose contribution rate for that calendar year as computed through step 6 under paragraph (1)(C) was greater than the maximum contribution limit computed under paragraph (20), multiply the employer’s 1-year compensation base as of the preceding June 30, as computed in accordance with paragraph (5), by the difference between—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the percentage rate determined under subparagraph (B), (C), or (D) of paragraph (1) before the reduction to the maximum contribution limit; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the maximum contribution limit.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Step 2</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Add the amounts arrived at under step 1 so as to obtain an aggregate amount for all such employers.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Step 3</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">For each employer whose contribution rate as computed through step 3 under paragraph (1)(C) was less than 0, the percentage rate by which such employer’s rate was raised in order to bring that rate to 0 shall be multiplied by that employer’s 1-year compensation base as of the preceding June 30. Subtract the total of the amounts computed under the preceding sentence for all employers from the amount arrived at in step 2.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Step 4</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Divide the aggregate amount arrived at under step 3 by the system compensation base as of the preceding June 30 as computed under paragraph (11) minus the one-year compensation base of those employers whose rates computed through step 6 of paragraph (1)(C) exceeded the maximum contribution rate computed under paragraph (20). The result is the pooled charge ratio for the calendar year.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(14)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Surcharge rate</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The surcharge rate for a calendar year, if any, shall be determined as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Step 1</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Compute the balance to the credit of the account as of the close of business on the preceding June 30, including any amounts in the account attributable to loans made under <ref>section 360(d) of this title</ref> before <date date="1985-10-01">October 1, 1985</date>, but disregarding the obligation to repay such loans and interest thereon. In determining such balance as of June 30 of any year, so much of the balance to the credit of the railroad unemployment insurance administration fund as of the close of business on such date as is in excess of $6,000,000 shall be deemed to be part of the balance to the credit of such account. There will be a surcharge rate for the calendar year only if that balance is less than the greater of $100,000,000 or of the amount that bears the same ratio to $100,000,000 as the system compensation base as of that June 30 bears to the system compensation base as of <date date="1991-06-30">June 30, 1991</date>, as computed in accordance with paragraph (11).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Step 2</heading>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> If the balance to the credit of the account is less than the greater of the amounts referred to in the 2nd sentence of step 1 but is equal to or more than the greater of $50,000,000 or of the amount that bears the same ratio to $50,000,000 as the system compensation base as of that June 30 bears to the system compensation base as of <date date="1991-06-30">June 30, 1991</date>, then the surcharge rate for the calendar year shall be 1.5 percent.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> If the balance to the credit of the account is less than the greater of the amounts referred to in the clause (i), but greater than or equal to zero, then the surcharge rate for the calendar year shall be 2.5 percent.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> If the balance to the credit of the account is less than zero, the surcharge rate for the calendar year shall be 3.5 percent.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(15)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Chargeable benefits</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Beginning <date date="1990-01-01">January 1, 1990</date>, all benefits paid to an employee for days of unemployment or days of sickness shall be charged to that employee’s base year employer by adding amounts equal to the amounts of such benefits to the employer’s cumulative benefit balance except that benefits paid by reason of strikes or work stoppages growing out of labor disputes shall not be added to the employer’s cumulative benefit balance but instead shall be added to the system unallocated charge balance.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adjustments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A sum equal to each amount realized in recovery for overpayment, erroneous payment, or reimbursement of benefits and credited to the account pursuant to section 360(a)(v) or 360(a)(viii) of this title shall be subtracted from the cumulative benefit balances of the employers of the employees to whom such an amount was paid as a benefit in the proportion to the amount by which each such employer’s cumulative benefit balance was increased as a result of the payment of the benefit.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Multiple employers</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">All benefits paid to an employee who had more than 1 base-year employer shall be charged to the cumulative benefit balances of the employee’s base year employers—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> in reverse chronological order of the employee’s employment with each such employer in the base year if the employer at the time of the claim was the last base year employer, and the amount charged to each employer shall not exceed the compensation paid by that employer to the employee in the base year; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> in all other cases, in the same ratio as the compensation paid to such employee by the employer bears to the total of such compensation paid to such employees by all such employers in the base year.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rule for employer with cancelled balances</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">All benefits chargeable under this subparagraph to an employer for which the Board has cancelled balances under paragraph (16) shall be added to the system unallocated charge balance.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(16)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Defunct employer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Whenever the Board determines, pursuant to such regulations as the Board may prescribe, that an employer has permanently ceased to pay compensation with respect to which contributions are payable pursuant to this subsection, the Board shall, effective on the date of the Board’s determination, transfer the employer’s net cumulative contribution balance as a subtraction from, and cumulative benefit balance as an addition to, the system unallocated charge balance and cancel all other accumulations of the employer.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(17)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Individual employer record</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">As of <date date="1990-01-01">January 1, 1990</date>, the Board shall commence maintaining an individual employer record with respect to each employer, and the records necessary to determine pooled charges, pooled credits and unallocated charge balances for the system. Whenever a new employer begins paying compensation with respect to which contributions are payable pursuant to this subsection, the Board shall establish and maintain an individual employer record for such employer.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">As used in this paragraph, the term “individual employer record” means a record of an individual employer’s benefit ratio, reserve ratio, 1-year compensation base, 3-year compensation base, unallocated charge, reserve balance, net cumulative contribution balance, and cumulative benefit balance.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(18)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Joint employer records</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Pursuant to regulations prescribed by the Board, the Board may allow 2 or more employers, upon application, to establish and maintain, or to discontinue, a joint individual employer record for such employers as though such joint record constituted a single employer’s individual employer record.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(19)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Mergers, consolidations, or other changes in employer identity</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> With other employers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In the event of a merger, consolidation, unification, or reorganization in which an employer combines with another employer and the combination entails no partitioning of the property of the employer, the individual employer records of the 2 employers shall be combined into a joint individual employer record if the parties request such joint treatment pursuant to paragraph (18) or if the Board otherwise determines, pursuant to regulations prescribed by the Board, that such joint treatment is desirable.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> With nonemployers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In the event of a merger, consolidation, unification, or reorganization in which an employer combines with another entity that is not an employer, the employer’s individual employer record shall attach to the combined entity.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sale of assets</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In the event property of an employer is sold or transferred to another employer or other entity, or is partitioned among 2 or more employers or entities, the cumulative benefit balance, net cumulative contribution balance, 1-year compensation base, and 3-year compensation base of the employer shall be prorated among the employers which receive the property, including any entities which become employers by virtue of such transfer or partition, in such equitable manner as the Board by regulation shall prescribe.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reincorporation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The cumulative benefit balance, net cumulative contribution balance, 1-year compensation base, and 3-year compensation base of an employer that reincorporates or otherwise alters its corporate identity in a transaction not involving a merger, consolidation, or unification shall attach to the reincorporated or altered entity.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(E)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Abandonment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">If an employer abandons property or discontinues service but continues to operate as an employer, the employer’s individual employer record shall continue to be calculated as provided in this subsection without retroactive adjustment.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(20)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Maximum contribution limit</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The maximum contribution limit with respect to a calendar year is 12 percent, unless a 3.5 percent surcharge under paragraph (14) is in effect with respect to that calendar year. If such a surcharge is in effect the maximum contribution limit with respect to that calendar year is 12.5 percent.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(21)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rules for certain computations under paragraph (1)(C)</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> Any computation that is to be made under paragraph (1)(C) on the basis of a 12-quarter period ending on a given June 30 shall be made on the basis of a period—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> beginning on the later of—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content><date date="1990-01-01">January 1, 1990</date>;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the first day of the first calendar quarter that begins after the date on which the employer first began to pay compensation subject to this chapter; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> July 1 of the third calendar year preceding that June 30; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> ending on that June 30.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The amount computed under subparagraph (A) shall be increased to an amount that bears the same ratio to the amount so computed as 12 bears to the number of calendar quarters on which the computation is based.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Employee representative contribution</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each employee representative shall pay a contribution with respect to so much of the compensation paid to him for services performed as an employee representative as is not in excess of the monthly compensation base computed in accordance with <ref>section 351(i) of this title</ref>, at a rate which shall be determined under subsection (a) in the same manner and with the same effect as if the employee organization by which such employee representative is employed were an employer as defined in this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Board proclamation of balance</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than <date date="1990-10-15">October 15, 1990</date>, and October 15 of each year thereafter the Board shall proclaim—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the balance to the credit of the account as of the preceding June 30 for purposes of paragraphs (12) and (14) of subsection (a);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the balance of any advances to the account under <ref>section 360(d) of this title</ref> after <date date="1985-09-30">September 30, 1985</date>, that has not been repaid with interest as provided in such section as of September 30 of that year;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the system compensation base as of that June 30 as computed in accordance with paragraph (11) of that subsection;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the system unallocated charge balance as of that June 30, as computed in accordance with paragraph (10) of that subsection; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the pooled credit ratio, the pooled charge ratio, and the surcharge rate, if any, as determined under paragraph (12), (13), or (14) of that subsection and applicable in the following calendar year.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Publication of notice</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">As soon as is practicable after such proclamation, the Board shall publish notice in the Federal Register of the amounts so determined and proclaimed.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notifications by Board</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Not later than the last day of any calendar quarter that begins after <date date="1990-03-31">March 31, 1990</date>, the Board shall notify each employer and employee representative of its net cumulative contribution balance and cumulative benefit balance as of the end of the preceding calendar quarter, as computed in accordance with paragraphs (7) and (8) of subsection (a) as of the last day of such preceding calendar quarter rather than as of a given June 30 if such last day is not a June 30.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Not later than <date date="1990-10-15">October 15, 1990</date>, and October 15 of each year thereafter, the Board shall notify each employer and employee representative of its benefit ratio, reserve ratio, 1-year compensation base, 3-year compensation base, unallocated charge, and reserve balance as of the preceding June 30 as computed in accordance with paragraphs (2), (3), (4), (5), (6), and (9) of subsection (a), and of the contribution rate applicable to the employer or employee representative in the following calendar year as computed under paragraphs (1)(B), (C), or (D) of that subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Information to verify accuracy to be made available</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, upon request by an employer or employee representative, the Board shall make available to such employer or employee representative any information available to the Board which may be necessary to verify the accuracy of a contribution rate determined by the Board to be applicable to such employer or employee representative, or of any component of that contribution rate including the accuracy of the employer’s individual employer record, upon payment by such employer or employee representative to the Board of the cost incurred by the Board in making such information available. The amounts so paid to the Board shall be credited to and deposited in the fund.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fractional parts of a cent</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the payment of any contribution under this chapter, a fractional part of a cent shall be disregarded unless it amounts to one-half cent or more, in which case it shall be increased to one cent.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adjustments for improper payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If more or less than the correct amount of the contribution required by this section is paid with respect to any compensation, then, under regulations prescribed under this chapter by the Board, proper adjustments with respect to the contribution shall be made, without interest, in connection with subsequent contribution payments made under this chapter by the same employer or employee representative.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Refunding overpayment; collecting underpayment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If more or less than the correct amount of the contribution required by this section is paid with respect to any compensation and the overpayment or underpayment of the contribution cannot be adjusted under subsection (d) of this section, the amount of the overpayment shall be refunded from the account, or the amount of the underpayment shall be collected, in such manner and at such times (subject to the statute of limitations properly applicable thereto) as may be prescribed by regulations of the Board.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Collection and deposit of contributions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The contributions required by this chapter shall be collected by the Board and shall be deposited by it with the Secretary of the Treasury of the United States, such part thereof as equals 0.65 per centum of the total compensation on which such contributions are based to be deposited to the credit of the fund and the balance to be deposited to the credit of the account.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Time for payment; failure to pay promptly</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The contributions required by this chapter shall be collected and paid quarterly or at such other times and in such manner and under such conditions not inconsistent with this chapter as may be prescribed by regulations of the Board, and shall not be deducted, in whole or in part, from the compensation of employees in the employer’s employ. If a contribution required by this chapter is not paid when due, there shall be added to the amount payable (except in the case of adjustments made in accordance with the provisions of this chapter) interest at the rate of 1 per centum per month or fraction of a month from the date the contribution became due until paid. Any interest collected pursuant to this subsection shall be credited to the account.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(k)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application of other laws; authority of Board</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All provisions of law, including penalties, applicable with respect to any tax imposed by the provisions of the Railroad Retirement Tax Act [<ref>26 U.S.C. 3201</ref> et seq.], insofar as applicable and not inconsistent with the provisions of this chapter, shall be applicable with respect to the contributions required by this chapter: <i>Provided</i>, That all authority and functions conferred by or pursuant to such provisions upon any officer or employee of the United States, except the authority to institute and prosecute, and the function of instituting and prosecuting, criminal proceedings, shall, with respect to such contributions, be vested in and exercised by the Board or such officers and employees of the Board as it may designate therefor. The remedies available under the first sentence of this subsection for an employer or employee representative who contests the amount of contributions payable by him shall also apply with respect to a contention that the contribution rate determined by the Board under subsection (a) or (b) to be applicable to such employer or employee representative is inaccurate or otherwise improper.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1938, ch. 680, § 8</ref>, <ref>52 Stat. 1102</ref>; <ref>July 31, 1946, ch. 709, § 318</ref>, <ref>60 Stat. 739</ref>; <ref>June 23, 1948, ch. 608</ref>, §§ 4, 5(a), 6, <ref>62 Stat. 577</ref>, 578; <ref>Aug. 31, 1954, ch. 1164</ref>, pt. III, §§ 305, 306, <ref>68 Stat. 1042</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–927</ref>, pt. II, § 203, <date date="1958-09-06">Sept. 6, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1782</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–28</ref>, pt. III, §§ 306, 307, <date date="1959-05-19">May 19, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 32</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–133, title III</ref>, §§ 303(a), 304, <date date="1963-10-05">Oct. 5, 1963</date>, <ref>77 Stat. 222</ref>, 223; <ref>Pub. L. 89–700, title II, § 204</ref>, title III, § 301(i), (ii), <date date="1966-10-30">Oct. 30, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1087</ref>, 1088; <ref>Pub. L. 94–92, title I, § 1(g)</ref>, (h), <date date="1975-08-09">Aug. 9, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 463</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–35, title XI, § 1128(b)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 641</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–76, title V, § 503(a)</ref>, <date date="1983-08-12">Aug. 12, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 440</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–647, title VII</ref>, §§ 7102(a)–(d), 7103(a), <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3759–3770</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–322, § 8(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-07-06">July 6, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 297</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 359.</num>
<heading> Penalties</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Failure to make report or furnish information; false or fraudulent statement or claim</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any officer or agent of an employer, or any employee representative, or any employee acting in his own behalf, or any person whether or not of the character hereinbefore defined, who shall willfully fail or refuse to make any report or furnish any information required by the Board in the administration of this chapter, or who shall knowingly make or aid in making or cause to be made any false or fraudulent statement or report when a statement or report is required to be made for the purposes of this chapter, or who shall knowingly make or aid in making or cause to be made any false or fraudulent statement or claim for the purpose of causing benefits or other payment to be made or not to be made under this chapter, shall be punished by a fine of not more than $10,000 or by imprisonment not exceeding one year, or both.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agreement by employee to bear employer’s contribution</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any agreement by an employee to pay all or any portion of the contribution required of his employer under this chapter shall be void, and it shall be unlawful for any employer, or officer or agent of an employer, to make, require, or permit any employee to bear all or any portion of such contribution. Any employer, or officer or agent of an employer, who violates any provision of this subsection shall be punished for each such violation by a fine of not more than $10,000 or by imprisonment not exceeding one year, or both.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Punishments not specifically provided</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any person who violates any provision of this chapter, the punishment for which is not otherwise provided, shall be punished for each such violation by a fine of not more than $1,000 or by imprisonment not exceeding one year, or both.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payment and disposition of fines or penalties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All fines and penalties imposed by a court pursuant to this chapter shall be paid to the court and be remitted from time to time by order of the judge to the Treasury of the United States to be credited to the account.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1938, ch. 680, § 9</ref>, <ref>52 Stat. 1103</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 360.</num>
<heading> Railroad unemployment insurance account</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Funds constituting account; availability for benefits or refunds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Treasury shall maintain in the unemployment trust fund established pursuant to <ref>section 1104 of title 42</ref> an account to be known as the railroad unemployment insurance account. This account shall consist of (i) such part of all contributions collected pursuant to <ref>section 358 of this title</ref> as is in excess of 0.65 per centum of the total compensation on which such contributions are based, together with all interest collected pursuant to section 358(g) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002031">1</ref> of this title; (ii) all amounts transferred or paid into the account pursuant to section 363 or <ref>section 364 of this title</ref>; (iii) all additional amounts appropriated to the account in accordance with any provision of this chapter or with any provision of law now or hereafter adopted; (iv) a proportionate part of the earnings of the unemployment trust fund, computed in accordance with the provisions of <ref>section 1104(e) of title 42</ref>; (v) all amounts realized in recoveries for overpayments or erroneous payments of benefits; (vi) all amounts transferred thereto pursuant to <ref>section 361 of this title</ref>; (vii) all fines or penalties collected pursuant to the provisions of this chapter; and (viii) all amounts credited thereto pursuant to section 352(f) or <ref>section 362(g) of this title</ref>. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, all moneys credited to the account shall be mingled and undivided, and are permanently appropriated to the Board to be continuously available to the Board without further appropriation, for the payment of benefits and refunds under this chapter, and no part thereof shall lapse at any time, or be carried to the surplus fund or any other fund.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payment of benefits or refunds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All moneys in the account shall be used solely for the payment of the benefits and refunds provided for by this chapter. The Board shall, from time to time, certify to the Secretary of the Treasury the name and address of each person or company entitled to receive benefits or a refund payment under this chapter, the amount of such payment, and the time at which it shall be made. Prior to audit or settlement by the Government Accountability Office, the Secretary of the Treasury, through the Fiscal Service of the Treasury Department, shall make payments from the account directly to such person or company of the amount of benefits or refund so certified by the Board: <i>Provided, however</i>, That if the Board shall so request, the Secretary of the Treasury, through the Fiscal Service of the Treasury Department, shall transmit benefits payments to the Board for distribution by it through employment offices or in such other manner as the Board deems proper.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual report to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Board shall include in its annual report to Congress a statement with respect to the status and operation of the account.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer and retransfer of funds; interest</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever the Board finds at any time that the balance in the railroad unemployment insurance account will be insufficient to pay the benefits and refunds which it estimates are due, or will become due, under this chapter, it shall request the Secretary of the Treasury to transfer from the Railroad Retirement Account to the credit of the railroad unemployment insurance account such moneys as the Board estimates would be necessary for the payment of such benefits and refunds, and the Secretary shall make such transfer. Whenever the Board finds that the balance in the railroad unemployment insurance account, without regard to the amounts transferred pursuant to the next preceding sentence, is sufficient to pay such benefits and refunds, it shall request the Secretary of the Treasury to retransfer from the railroad unemployment insurance account to the credit of the Railroad Retirement Account such moneys as in its judgment are not needed for the payment of such benefits and refunds, plus interest at a rate for each fiscal year equal to the average rate of interest borne by all special obligations held by the Railroad Retirement Account on the last day of the preceding fiscal year, rounded to the nearest multiple of one-eighth of 1 per centum, and the Secretary shall make such retransfer. In determining the balance in the railroad unemployment insurance account as of September 30 of any year pursuant to <ref>section 358(a) of this title</ref>, any moneys transferred from the Railroad Retirement Account to the credit of the railroad unemployment insurance account which have not been retransferred as of such date from the latter account to the credit of the former, plus the interest accrued thereon to that date, shall be disregarded.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1938, ch. 680, § 10</ref> (less (e)–(g)), <ref>52 Stat. 1104</ref>; <ref>June 20, 1939, ch. 227, § 13</ref>, <ref>53 Stat. 848</ref>; 1940 Reorg. Plan No. III, § 1(a)(1), eff. <date date="1940-06-30">June 30, 1940</date>, 5 F.R. 2107, <ref>54 Stat. 1231</ref>; <ref>June 23, 1948, ch. 608, § 7</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 578</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–28</ref>, pt. III, § 308(a), <date date="1959-05-19">May 19, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 32</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–133, title III, § 305</ref>, <date date="1963-10-05">Oct. 5, 1963</date>, <ref>77 Stat. 223</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–700, title II, § 205</ref>, <date date="1966-10-30">Oct. 30, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1087</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–257, title II, § 205</ref>, <date date="1968-02-15">Feb. 15, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 24</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–445, title IV, § 403</ref>, <date date="1974-10-16">Oct. 16, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1359</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–92, title I, § 1(i)</ref>, <date date="1975-08-09">Aug. 9, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 464</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–76, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="1983-08-12">Aug. 12, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 432</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–107, § 4</ref>, <date date="1985-09-30">Sept. 30, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 479</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–155, § 2(c)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-14">Nov. 14, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 814</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–181, § 3</ref>, <date date="1985-12-13">Dec. 13, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 1172</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–189, § 3</ref>, <date date="1985-12-18">Dec. 18, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 1184</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–272, title XIII, § 13302</ref>, <date date="1986-04-07">Apr. 7, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 327</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–647, title VII, § 7103(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3770</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–271, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-07-07">July 7, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 814</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 361.</num>
<heading> Railroad unemployment insurance administration fund</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Maintenance of account; amounts constituting fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Treasury shall maintain in the unemployment trust fund established pursuant to section 904 of the Social Security Act [<ref>42 U.S.C. 1104</ref>] an account to be known as the railroad unemployment insurance administration fund. This unemployment insurance administration fund shall consist of (i) such part of all contributions collected pursuant to <ref>section 358 of this title</ref> as equals 0.65 per centum of the total compensation on which such contributions are based; (ii) all amounts advanced to the fund by the Secretary of the Treasury pursuant to this section; (iii) all amounts appropriated by subsection (b) of this section; and (iv) such additional amounts as Congress may appropriate for expenses necessary or incidental to administering this chapter. Such additional amounts are authorized to be appropriated.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations; advance of sums; repayment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In addition to the other moneys herein provided for expenses necessary or incidental to administering this chapter, there is appropriated to the fund such amount as the Secretary of the Treasury and the Board shall jointly estimate to have been collected or to be collectible with respect to the calendar years 1936, 1937, 1938, and 1939, from employers subject to this chapter, under title IX of the Social Security Act, less such amount as the Secretary of the Treasury and the Board shall jointly estimate will be appropriated or has been appropriated to States or Territories pursuant to the Act of Congress approved <date date="1937-08-24">August 24, 1937</date> (Public, Numbered 353, Seventy-fifth Congress), as proceeds of taxes paid by employers pursuant to title IX of the Social Security Act.</p>
<p class="indent0">Until the amount appropriated by this subsection is credited to the fund, the Secretary of the Treasury is directed to advance to the credit of the fund such sums, but not more than $2,000,000, as the Board requests for the purpose of financing the costs of administering this chapter. Such advance shall be repaid from the fund at such time after the amount appropriated by this subsection is credited to the fund as the Board by agreement with the Secretary of the Treasury may determine, but not later than <date date="1940-01-01">January 1, 1940</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability for administrative expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, all moneys at any time credited to the fund are permanently appropriated to the Board to be continuously available to the Board without further appropriation for any expenses necessary or incidental to administering this chapter, including personal services in the District of Columbia and elsewhere; travel expenses, including expenses of attendance at meetings when authorized by the Board; actual transportation expenses and not to exceed $10 per diem to cover subsistence and other expenses while in attendance at and en route to and from the place to which he is invited, to any person other than an employee of the Federal Government who may, from time to time, be invited to the city of Washington or elsewhere for conference or advisory purposes in furthering the work of the Board; when found by the Board to be in the interest of the Government, not exceeding 3 per centum, in any fiscal year, of the amounts credited during such year to the fund, for engaging persons or organizations, by contract or otherwise, for any special technical or professional services, determined necessary by the Board, including but not restricted to accounting, actuarial, statistical, and reporting services, without regard to <ref>section 6101 of title 41</ref> and the provisions of other laws applicable to the employment and compensation of officers and employees of the United States; services; advertising, postage, telephone, telegraph, teletype, and other communication services and tolls; supplies; reproducing, photographing, and all other equipment, office appliances, and laborsaving devices, including devices for internal communication and conveyance; purchase and exchange, operation, maintenance and repair of motor-propelled passenger-carrying vehicles to be used only for official purposes in the District of Columbia and in the field; printing and binding; purchase and exchange of law books, books of reference, and directories; periodicals, newspapers and press clippings, in such amounts as the Board deems necessary, without regard to the provisions of section 192 of the Revised Statutes; manuscripts and special reports; membership fees or dues in organizations which issue publications to members only, or to members at a lower price than to others, payment for which may be made in advance; rentals, including garages, in the District of Columbia or elsewhere; alterations and repairs; if found by the Board to be necessary to expedite the certification to the Board by the Director of the Office of Personnel Management of persons eligible to be employed by the Board, and to the extent that the Board finds such expedition necessary, meeting the expenses of the Director of the Office of Personnel Management in holding examinations for testing the fitness of applicants for admission to the classified service for employment by the Board pursuant to the second paragraph of section 362(<i>l</i>) of this title, but not to exceed the additional expenses found by the Board to have been incurred by reason of the holding of such examinations; and miscellaneous items, including those for public instruction and information deemed necessary by the Board: <i>Provided</i>, That <ref>section 6101 of title 41</ref> shall not be construed to apply to any purchase or procurement of supplies or services by the Board from moneys in the fund when the aggregate amount involved does not exceed $300. Determinations of the Board whether the fund or an appropriation for the administration of the Railroad Retirement Act of 1974 [<ref>45 U.S.C. 231</ref> et seq.] is properly chargeable with the authorized expenses, or parts thereof, incurred in the administration of such Act, or of this chapter, shall be binding and conclusive for all purposes and upon all persons, including the Comptroller General and any other administrative or accounting officer, employee, or agent of the United States and shall not be subject to review in any manner.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer of excess to insurance account</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">So much of the balance in the fund as of September 30 of each year as is in excess of $6,000,000 shall as of such date be transferred from the fund and credited to the account.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1938, ch. 680, § 11</ref>, <ref>52 Stat. 1105</ref>; <ref>June 20, 1939, ch. 227</ref>, §§ 14, 15, <ref>53 Stat. 848</ref>; <ref>Oct. 10, 1940, ch. 842, § 22</ref>, <ref>54 Stat. 1099</ref>; <ref>June 23, 1948, ch. 608, § 8</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 578</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–927</ref>, pt. II, § 205, <date date="1958-09-06">Sept. 6, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1783</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–700, title II, § 205</ref>, <date date="1966-10-30">Oct. 30, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1087</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–445, title IV, § 404</ref>, <date date="1974-10-16">Oct. 16, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1359</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–92, title I, § 1(j)</ref>, <date date="1975-08-09">Aug. 9, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 464</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–273, § 2(22)</ref>, <date date="1976-04-21">Apr. 21, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 376</ref>; 1978 Reorg. Plan No. 2, § 102, eff. <date date="1979-01-01">Jan. 1, 1979</date>, 43 F.R. 36037, <ref>92 Stat. 3783</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–647, title VII, § 7103(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3770</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 362.</num>
<heading> Duties and powers of Board</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Witnesses; subpenas, service, fees, etc.</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purpose of any investigation or other proceeding relative to the determination of any right to benefits, or relative to any other matter within its jurisdiction under this chapter, the Board shall have the power to issue subpenas requiring the attendance and testimony of witnesses and the production of any evidence, documentary or otherwise, that relates to any matter under investigation or in question, before the Board or any member, employee, or representative thereof. Any member of the Board or any of its employees or representatives designated by it may administer oaths and affirmations, examine witnesses, and receive evidence. Such attendance of witnesses and production of evidence may be required from any place in the United States or any Territory or possession thereof at any designated place of hearing. All subpenas may be served and returned by anyone authorized by the Board in the same manner as is now provided by law for the service and return by United States marshals of subpenas in suits in equity. Such service may also be made by registered mail or by certified mail and in such case the return post-office receipt shall be proof of service. Witnesses summoned in accordance with this subsection shall be paid the same fees and mileage as are paid witnesses in the district courts of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Enforcement of subpenas by courts; contempts; service of orders, writs, or processes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In case of contumacy by, or refusal to obey a subpena lawfully issued to, any person, the Board may invoke the aid of the district court of the United States or the United States courts of any Territory or possession, where such person is found or resides or is otherwise subject to service of process, or the United States District Court for the District of Columbia if the investigation or proceeding is being carried on in the District of Columbia, or the United States District Court for the Northern District of Illinois, if the investigation or proceeding is being carried on in the Northern District of Illinois, in requiring the attendance and testimony of witnesses and the production of evidence. Any such court shall issue an order requiring such person to appear before the Board or its specified employee or representative at the place specified in the subpena of the Board, whether within or without the judicial district of the court, there to produce evidence, if so ordered, or there to give testimony concerning the matter under investigation or in question; and any failure to obey such order of the court may be punished by said court as a contempt thereof. All orders, writs, and processes in any such proceeding may be served in the judicial district of the district court issuing such order, writ, or process, except that the orders, writs, and processes of the United States District Court for the District of Columbia or of the United States District Court for the Northern District of Illinois in such proceedings may run and be served anywhere in the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 91–452, title II, § 239</ref>, <date date="1970-10-15">Oct. 15, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 930</ref></heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Information as confidential</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Information obtained by the Board in connection with the administration of this chapter shall not be revealed or open to inspection nor be published in any manner revealing an employee’s identity: <i>Provided, however</i>, That (i) the Board may arrange for the exchange of any information with governmental agencies engaged in functions related to the administration of this chapter; (ii) the Board may disclose such information in cases in which the Board finds that such disclosure is clearly in furtherance of the interest of the employee or his estate; (iii) any claimant of benefits under this chapter shall, upon his request, be supplied with information from the Board’s records pertaining to his claim; and (iv) the Board shall disclose to any base-year employer of a claimant for benefits any information, including information as to the claimant’s identity, that is necessary or appropriate to notify such employer of the claim for benefits or to full and fair participation by such employer in an appeal, hearing, or other proceeding relative to the claim pursuant to <ref>section 355 of this title</ref>. Subject to the provisions of this section, the Board may furnish such information to any person or organization upon payment by such person or organization to the Board of the cost incurred by the Board by reason thereof; and the amounts so paid to the Board shall be credited to the railroad unemployment insurance administration fund established pursuant to <ref>section 361(a) of this title</ref>;</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certification of claims; authorization of employee to make payments; bond</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Board shall provide for the certification of claims for benefits and refunds and may arrange total or partial settlements at such times and in such manner as may appear to the Board to be expedient. The Board shall designate and authorize one or more of its employees to sign vouchers for the payment of benefits and refunds under this chapter. Each such employee shall give bond, in form and amount fixed by the Board, conditioned upon the faithful performance of his duties. The premiums due on such bonds shall be paid from the fund and deemed to be a part of the expenses of administering this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cooperation with other agencies administering unemployment or sickness compensation laws; agreements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Board may cooperate with or enter into agreement with the appropriate agencies charged with the administration of State, Territorial, Federal, or foreign unemployment-compensation or sickness laws or employment offices, with respect to investigations, the exchange of information and services, the establishment, maintenance, and use of free employment service facilities, and such other matters as the Board deems expedient in connection with the administration of this chapter, and may compensate any such agency for services or facilities supplied to the Board in connection with the administration of this chapter. The Board may enter also into agreements with any such agency, pursuant to which any unemployment or sickness benefits provided for by this chapter or any other unemployment-compensation or sickness law, may be paid through a single agency to persons who have, during the period on the basis of which eligibility for and duration of benefits is determined under the law administered by such agency or under this chapter, or both, performed services covered by one or more of such laws, or performed services which constitute employment as defined in this chapter: <i>Provided</i>, That the Board finds that any such agreement is fair and reasonable as to all affected interests.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Benefits also subject to a State law; mutual reimbursement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In determining whether an employee has qualified for benefits in accordance with <ref>section 353 of this title</ref>, and in determining the amount of benefits to be paid to such employee in accordance with section 352(a) and (c) of this title, the Board is authorized to consider as employment (and compensation therefor) services for hire other than employment (and remuneration therefor) if such services for hire are subject to an unemployment or sickness compensation law of any State, provided that such State has agreed to reimburse the United States such portion of the benefits to be paid upon such basis to such employee as the Board deems equitable. Any amounts collected pursuant to this paragraph shall be credited to the account.</p>
<p class="indent0">If a State, in determining whether an employee is eligible for unemployment or sickness benefits under an unemployment or sickness compensation law of such State, and in determining the amount of unemployment or sickness benefits to be paid to such employee pursuant to such unemployment or sickness compensation law, considers as services for hire (and remuneration therefor) included within the provisions of such unemployment or sickness compensation law, employment (and compensation therefor), the Board is authorized to reimburse such State such portion of such unemployment or sickness benefits as the Board deems equitable; such reimbursements shall be paid from the account, and are included within the meaning of the word “benefits” as used in this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistance from employers and labor organizations; compensation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Board may enter into agreements or arrangements with employers, organizations of employers, and railway-labor organizations which are duly organized in accordance with the provisions of the Railway Labor Act [<ref>45 U.S.C. 151</ref> et seq.], for securing the performance of services or the use of facilities in connection with the administration of this chapter, and may compensate any such employer or organization therefor upon such reasonable basis as the Board shall prescribe, but not to exceed the additional expense incurred by such employer or organization by reason of the performance of such services or making available the use of such facilities pursuant to such agreements or arrangements. Such employers and organizations, and persons employed by either of them, shall not be subject to <ref>section 209 of title 18</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Free employment offices; registration of unemployed; statements of sickness; reemployment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Board may establish, maintain, and operate free employment offices, and may designate as free employment offices facilities maintained by (i) a railway labor organization which is duly authorized and designated to represent employees in accordance with the Railway Labor Act [<ref>45 U.S.C. 151</ref> et seq.], or (ii) any other labor organization which has been or may be organized in accordance with the provisions of the Railway Labor Act, or (iii) one or more employers, or (iv) an organization of employers, or (v) a group of such employers and labor organizations, or (vi) a State, Territorial, foreign, or the Federal Government. The Board may also enter into agreements or arrangements with one or more employers or railway labor organizations organized in accordance with the provisions of the Railway Labor Act, pursuant to which notice of the availability of work and the rights of employees with respect to such work under agreements between such employers and railway labor organizations may be filed with employment offices and pursuant to which employees registered with employment offices may be referred to such work.</p>
<p class="indent0">The Board shall prescribe a procedure for registration of unemployed employees at employment offices. Such procedure for registration shall be prescribed with a view to such registration affording substantial evidence of the days of unemployment of the employees who register. The Board may, when such registration is made personally by an employee, accept such registration as initial proof of unemployment sufficient to certify for payment a claim for benefits.</p>
<p class="indent0">The Board shall provide a form or forms for statements of sickness and a procedure for the execution and filing thereof. Such forms and procedure shall be designated with a view to having such statements provide substantial evidence of the days of sickness of the employee. Such statements may be executed by any doctor (authorized to practice in the State or foreign jurisdiction in which he practices his profession) or any officer or supervisory employee of a hospital, clinic, group health association, or other similar organization, who is qualified under such regulations as the Board may prescribe to execute such statements. The Board shall issue regulations for the qualification of such persons to execute such statements. When so executed by any such person, or, in the discretion of the Board, by others designated by the Board individually or by groups, they may be accepted as initial proof of days of sickness sufficient to certify for payment a claim for benefits.</p>
<p class="indent0">The regulations of the Board concerning registration at employment offices by unemployed persons may provide for group registration and reporting, through employers, and need not be uniform with respect to different classes of employees.</p>
<p class="indent0">The operation of any employment facility operated by the Board shall be directed primarily toward the reemployment of employees who have theretofore been substantially employed by employers.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Advisory councils; members’ remuneration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Board may appoint national or local advisory councils composed of equal numbers of representatives of employers, representatives of employees, and persons representing the general public, for the purpose of discussing problems in connection with the administration of this chapter and aiding the Board in formulating policies. The members of such councils shall serve without remuneration, but shall be reimbursed for any necessary traveling and subsistence expenses or on a per diem basis in lieu of subsistence expenses.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(k)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reduction of unemployment; training and reemployment of unemployed employees, etc.</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Board, with the advice and aid of any advisory council appointed by it, shall take appropriate steps to reduce and prevent unemployment and loss of earnings; to encourage and assist in the adoption of practical methods of vocational training, retraining, and vocational guidance; to promote the reemployment of unemployed employees; and to these ends to carry on and publish the results of investigations and research studies.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(l)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Necessary and incidental powers; employees of Board, employment, remuneration, civil-service laws, registration of unemployed, and detail</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In addition to the powers and duties expressly provided, the Board shall have and exercise all the powers and duties necessary to administer or incidental to administering this chapter, and in connection therewith shall have such of the powers, duties, and remedies provided in subdivisions (5), (6), and (9) of section 7(b) of the Railroad Retirement Act of 1974 [<ref>45 U.S.C. 231f(b)</ref>] with respect to the administration of the Railroad Retirement Act of 1974 [<ref>45 U.S.C. 231</ref> et seq.], as are not inconsistent with the express provisions of this chapter. A person in the employ of the Board under section 205 of the Act of Congress approved <date date="1937-06-24">June 24, 1937</date> (<ref>50 Stat. 307</ref>), shall acquire a competitive classified civil-service status if, after recommendation by the Board to the Director of the Office of Personnel Management, he shall pass such noncompetitive tests of fitness as the Director of the Office of Personnel Management may prescribe. A person in the employ of the Board on <date date="1939-06-30">June 30, 1939</date>, and on <date date="1940-06-30">June 30, 1940</date>, and who has had experience in railroad service, shall acquire a competitive classified civil-service status if, after recommendation by the Board to the Director of the Office of Personnel Management, he shall pass such noncompetitive tests of fitness for the position for which the Board recommends him as the Director of the Office of Personnel Management may prescribe.</p>
<p class="indent0">The Board may employ such persons and provide for their remuneration and expenses, as may be necessary for the proper administration of this chapter. Such persons shall be employed and their remuneration prescribed in accordance with the civil-service laws and chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5: <i>Provided</i>, That all positions to which such persons are appointed, except one administrative assistant to each member of the Board, shall be in and under the competitive civil service and shall not be removed or excepted therefrom: <i>Provided</i>, That in the employment of such persons the Board shall give preference, as between applicants attaining the same grades, to persons who have had experience in railroad service, and notwithstanding any other provisions of law, rules, or regulations, no other preference shall be given or recognized: <i>And provided further</i>, That certification by the Director of the Office of Personnel Management of persons for appointment to any positions at minimum salaries of $4,600 per annum, or less, shall, if the Board so requests, be upon the basis of competitive examinations, written, oral, or both, as the Board may request: <i>And provided further</i>, That, for the purpose of registering unemployed employees who reside in areas in which no employer facilities are located, or in which no employer will make facilities available for the registration of such employees, the Board may, without regard to civil-service laws and chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5, appoint persons to accept, in such areas, registration of such employees and perform services incidental thereto and may compensate such persons on a piece-rate basis to be determined by the Board. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Board may detail employees from stations outside the District of Columbia to other stations outside the District of Columbia or to service in the District of Columbia, and may detail employees in the District of Columbia to service outside the District of Columbia: <i>Provided</i>, That all details hereunder shall be made by specific order and in no case for a period of time exceeding one hundred and twenty days. Details so made may, on expiration, be renewed from time to time by order of the Board, in each particular case, for periods not exceeding one hundred and twenty days.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(m)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Delegation of powers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Board is authorized to delegate to any member, officer, or employee of the Board any of the powers conferred upon the Board by this chapter, excluding only the power to prescribe rules and regulations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(n)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sickness benefits; examinations; information and reports; contracts and expenses for examinations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any employee claiming, entitled to, or receiving sickness benefits under this chapter may be required to take such examination, physical, medical, mental, or otherwise, in such manner and at such times and by such qualified individuals, including medical officers or employees of the United States or a State, as the Board may prescribe. The place or places of examination shall be reasonably convenient for the employee. No sickness benefits shall be payable under this chapter with respect to any period during which the employee unreasonably refuses to take or willfully obstructs an examination as prescribed by the Board.</p>
<p class="indent0">Any doctor who renders any attendance, treatment, attention, or care, or performs any examination with respect to a sickness of an employee, upon which a claim or right to benefits under this chapter is based, shall furnish the Board, in such manner and form and at such times as the Board by regulations may prescribe, information and reports relative thereto and to the condition of the employee. An application for sickness benefits under this chapter shall contain a waiver of any doctor-patient privilege that the employee may have with respect to any sickness period upon which such application is based: <i>Provided</i>, That such information shall not be disclosed by the Board except in a proceeding relating to any claim for benefits by the employee under this chapter.</p>
<p class="indent0">The Board may enter into agreements or arrangements with doctors, hospitals, clinics, or other persons for securing the examination, physical, medical, mental, or otherwise, of employees claiming, entitled to, or receiving sickness benefits under this chapter and the performance of services or the use of facilities in connection with the execution of statements of sickness. The Board may compensate any such doctors, hospitals, clinics, or other persons upon such reasonable basis as the Board shall prescribe. Such doctors, hospitals, clinics, or other persons and persons employed by any of them shall not be subject to <ref>section 209 of title 18</ref>. In the event that the Board pays for the physical or mental examination of an employee or for the execution of a statement of sickness and such employee’s claim for benefits is based upon such examination or statement, the Board shall deduct from any sickness benefits payable to the employee pursuant to such claim such amount as, in the judgment of the Board, is a fair and reasonable charge for such examination or execution of such statement.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(o)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Liability of third party for sickness; reimbursement of Board</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Benefits payable to an employee with respect to days of sickness shall be payable regardless of the liability of any person to pay damages for such infirmity. The Board shall be entitled to reimbursement from any sum or damages paid or payable to such employee or other person through suit, compromise, settlement, judgment, or otherwise on account of any liability (other than a liability under a health, sickness, accident, or similar insurance policy) based upon such infirmity, to the extent that it will have paid or will pay benefits for days of sickness resulting from such infirmity. Upon notice to the person against whom such right or claim exists or is asserted, the Board shall have a lien upon such right or claim, any judgment obtained thereunder, and any sum or damages paid under such right or claim, to the extent of the amount to which the Board is entitled by way of reimbursement.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(p)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disqualification to execute statements of sickness or receive fees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Board may, after hearing, disqualify any person from executing statements of sickness who, the Board finds, (i) will have solicited, or will have employed another to solicit, for himself or for another the execution of any such statement, or (ii) will have made false or misleading statements to the Board, to any employer, or to any employee, in connection with the awarding of any benefits under this chapter, or (iii) will have failed to submit medical reports and records required by the Board under this chapter, or will have failed to submit any other reports, records, or information required by the Board in connection with the administration of this chapter or any other Act heretofore or hereafter administered by the Board, or (iv) will have engaged in any malpractice or other professional misconduct. No fees or charges of any kind shall accrue to any such person from the Board after his disqualification.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(q)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Investigations and research with respect to accidents and disabilities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Board shall engage in and conduct research projects, investigations, and studies with respect to the cause, care, and prevention of, and benefits for, accidents and disabilities and other subjects deemed by the Board to be related thereto, and shall recommend legislation deemed advisable in the light of such research projects, investigations, and studies.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(r)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duty of Board to make certain computations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation base</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">On or before <date date="1988-12-01">December 1, 1988</date>, and on or before December 1 of each year thereafter, the Board shall compute—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in accordance with <ref>section 351(i) of this title</ref>, the monthly compensation base which shall be applicable with respect to months in the next succeeding calendar year; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the amounts described in <ref>section 351(k) of this title</ref>, <ref>section 352(c) of this title</ref>, <ref>section 353 of this title</ref>, and section 354(a–2)(i)(A) of this title that are related to changes in the monthly compensation base.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Maximum daily benefit rate</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">On or before <date date="1989-06-01">June 1, 1989</date>, and on or before June 1 of each year thereafter, the Board shall compute in accordance with <ref>section 352(a)(3) of this title</ref> the maximum daily benefit rate which shall be applicable with respect to days of unemployment and days of sickness in registration periods beginning after June 30 of that year.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice in Federal Register and to employers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 10 days after each computation made under this subsection, the Board shall publish notice in the Federal Register and shall notify each employer and employee representative of the amount so computed.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1938, ch. 680, § 12</ref>, <ref>52 Stat. 1107</ref>; <ref>June 20, 1939, ch. 227, § 16</ref>, <ref>53 Stat. 848</ref>; <ref>Oct. 10, 1940, ch. 842</ref>, §§ 23, 24, <ref>54 Stat. 1099</ref>; <ref>July 31, 1946, ch. 709</ref>, §§ 319–323, <ref>60 Stat. 739</ref>, 740; <ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, §§ 1, 32(b), <ref>62 Stat. 878</ref>, 895, 991; <ref>May 24, 1949, ch. 139, § 127</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 107</ref>; <ref>Oct. 28, 1949, ch. 782</ref>, title II, § 202(29), title XI, § 1106(a), <ref>63 Stat. 956</ref>, 972; <ref>Aug. 12, 1955, ch. 869, § 6</ref>, <ref>69 Stat. 716</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–927</ref>, pt. II, § 206, <date date="1958-09-06">Sept. 6, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1783</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–507, § 1(37)</ref>, <date date="1960-06-11">June 11, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 202</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–700, title II, § 206</ref>, <date date="1966-10-30">Oct. 30, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1087</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–257, title II, § 206</ref>, <date date="1968-02-15">Feb. 15, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 25</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–452, title II, § 239</ref>, <date date="1970-10-15">Oct. 15, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 930</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–445, title IV, § 405</ref>, <date date="1974-10-16">Oct. 16, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1359</ref>; 1978 Reorg. Plan No. 2, § 102, eff. <date date="1979-01-01">Jan. 1, 1979</date>, 43 F.R. 36037, <ref>92 Stat. 3783</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–647, title VII</ref>, §§ 7101(e), 7104(d), (e), <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3758</ref>, 3772.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 363.</num>
<heading> Exclusiveness of provisions; transfers from State unemployment compensation accounts to railroad unemployment insurance account</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect on State unemployment compensation laws</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">By enactment of this chapter the Congress makes exclusive provision for the payment of unemployment benefits for unemployment occurring after <date date="1939-06-30">June 30, 1939</date>, and for the payment of sickness benefits for sickness periods after <date date="1947-06-30">June 30, 1947</date>, based upon employment (as defined in this chapter). No employee shall have or assert any right to unemployment benefits under an unemployment compensation law of any State with respect to unemployment occurring after <date date="1939-06-30">June 30, 1939</date>, or to sickness benefits under a sickness law of any State with respect to sickness periods occurring after <date date="1947-06-30">June 30, 1947</date>, based upon employment (as defined in this chapter). The Congress finds and declares that by virtue of the enactment of this chapter, the application of State unemployment compensation laws after <date date="1939-06-30">June 30, 1939</date> or of State sickness laws after <date date="1947-06-30">June 30, 1947</date>, to such employment, except pursuant to <ref>section 362(g) of this title</ref>, would constitute an undue burden upon, and an undue interference with the effective regulation of, interstate commerce. In furtherance of such determination, after <date date="1939-06-30">June 30, 1939</date>, the term “person” as used in <ref>section 1106 of title 42</ref> shall not be construed to include any employer (as defined in this chapter) or any person in its employ: <i>Provided</i>, That no provision of this chapter shall be construed to affect the payment of unemployment benefits with respect to any period prior to <date date="1939-07-01">July 1, 1939</date>, under an unemployment compensation law of any State based upon employment performed prior to <date date="1939-07-01">July 1, 1939</date>, and prior to such date employment as defined in this chapter shall not constitute “Service with respect to which unemployment compensation is payable under an [or “service under any”] unemployment compensation system [or “plan”] established by an Act of Congress” [or “a law of the United States”] or “employment in interstate commerce, of an individual who is covered by an unemployment compensation system established directly by an Act of Congress,” or any term of similar import, used in any unemployment compensation law of any State.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determination of “preliminary amount” for States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Social Security Board is directed to determine for each State, after agreement with the Railroad Retirement Board, and after consultation with such State; the total (hereinafter referred to as the “preliminary amount”) of (i) the amount remaining as the balances of reserve accounts of employers as of <date date="1939-06-30">June 30, 1939</date>, if the unemployment compensation law of such State provides for a type of fund known as “Reserve Accounts,” plus (ii) if the unemployment compensation law of such State provides for a type of fund known as “Pooled Fund” or “Pooled Account,” that proportion of the balance of such fund or account of such State as of <date date="1939-06-30">June 30, 1939</date>, as the amount of taxes or contributions collected from employers and their employees prior to <date date="1939-07-01">July 1, 1939</date>, pursuant to its unemployment compensation law and credited to such fund or account bears to all such taxes or contributions theretofore collected from all persons subject to its unemployment compensation law and credited to such fund or account; and the additional amounts (hereinafter referred to as the “liquidating amount”) of taxes or contributions collected from employers and their employees from <date date="1939-07-01">July 1, 1939</date> to <date date="1939-12-31">December 31, 1939</date>, pursuant to its unemployment compensation law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Withholding amounts from certification to States; transfers to railroad unemployment compensation account</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Social Security Board shall withhold from certification to the Secretary of the Treasury for payment the amounts determined by it pursuant to <ref>section 502(a) of title 42</ref> to be necessary for the proper administration of each State’s unemployment-compensation law, until an amount equal to its “preliminary amount” plus interest from <date date="1939-07-01">July 1, 1939</date>, at 2½ per centum per annum on such portion thereof as has not been used as the measure for withholding certification for payment, has been so withheld from certification pursuant to this paragraph: <i>Provided, however</i>, That if a State shall, prior to whichever is the later of (i) thirty days after the close of the first regular session of its legislature which begins after the approval of this chapter, and (ii) <date date="1939-07-01">July 1, 1939</date>, authorize and direct the Secretary of the Treasury to transfer from its account in the unemployment trust fund to the railroad unemployment insurance account in the unemployment trust fund an amount equal to its “preliminary amount”, no amount shall be withheld from certification for payment to such State pursuant to this paragraph.</p>
<p class="indent0">The Social Security Board shall withhold from certification to the Secretary of the Treasury for payment the amounts determined by it pursuant to <ref>section 502(a) of title 42</ref> to be necessary for the proper administration of each State’s unemployment compensation law, until an amount equal to its “liquidating amount” plus interest from <date date="1940-01-01">January 1, 1940</date>, at 2½ per centum per annum on such portion thereof as has not been used as the measure for withholding certification for payment has been so withheld from certification pursuant to this paragraph: <i>Provided, however</i>, That if a State shall, prior to whichever is the later of (i) thirty days after the close of the first regular session of its legislature which begins after the approval of this chapter, and (ii) <date date="1940-01-01">January 1, 1940</date>, authorize and direct the Secretary of the Treasury to transfer from its account in the unemployment trust fund to the railroad unemployment insurance account in the unemployment trust fund an amount equal to its “liquidating amount”, no amount shall be withheld from certification for payment to such State pursuant to this paragraph.</p>
<p class="indent0">The withholdings from certification directed in each of the foregoing paragraphs of this subsection shall begin with respect to each State when the Social Security Board finds that such State is unable to avail itself of the condition set forth in the proviso contained in such paragraph: <i>Provided, however</i>, That if the Social Security Board finds with respect to any State that such State (1) is unable to avail itself of such conditions solely by reason of prohibitions contained in the constitution of such State, as determined by a decision of the highest court of such State declaring invalid in whole or in part the action of the legislature of the State purporting to provide for transfers from the State’s account in the Unemployment Trust Fund to the railroad unemployment insurance account, and (2) for similar reasons is unable to use amounts withdrawn from its account in the Unemployment Trust Fund for the payment of expenses incurred in the administration of its State unemployment compensation law, the Social Security Board shall not begin to withhold from certification to the Secretary of the Treasury for payment to such State the amounts determined by it pursuant to <ref>section 502 of title 42</ref> and to certify to the Secretary of the Treasury for payment into the railroad unemployment insurance account the amount so withheld from such State until <date date="1944-07-01">July 1, 1944</date>, or until a date one hundred and eighty days after the adjournment of the first session of the legislature of such State beginning after <date date="1942-07-01">July 1, 1942</date>, whichever date is the earlier, and then only if the Social Security Board finds that such State had not prior thereto effectively authorized and directed the Secretary of the Treasury to transfer from such State’s account in the Unemployment Trust Fund to the railroad unemployment insurance account amounts equal to such State’s “preliminary amount” and “liquidating amount” less such parts thereof, if any, as the State may have, within the periods set forth in the provisos contained in the first two paragraphs of this subsection, effectively authorized and directed the Secretary of the Treasury so to transfer, plus interest on such difference, if any, with respect to each amount, at 2½ per centum per annum from the date the State’s “preliminary amount” or “liquidating amount”, as the case may be, is determined by the Social Security Board; and with respect to any such State the amount withheld shall equal the State’s “preliminary amount” and “liquidating amount” less such parts thereof, if any, as the State may have, within the periods set forth in the provisos contained in the first two paragraphs of this subsection effectively authorized and directed the Secretary of the Treasury to transfer, plus interest from <date date="1939-07-01">July 1, 1939</date>, at 2½ per centum per annum on so much of the “preliminary amount” and “liquidating amount”, as the case may be, as has not been so transferred or has not been used as the measure for withholding. An enactment of any State legislature providing for the transfer (from the State’s account in the Unemployment Trust Fund to the railroad unemployment insurance account) of all interest earned upon contributions which are collected with respect to employment occurring after such enactment by such State pursuant to its unemployment compensation law and credited to its account in the Unemployment Trust Fund (until the total of such transfers equals the amounts which otherwise would be required to be withheld from certification under this subsection), shall be deemed an effective authorization and direction to the Secretary of the Treasury as required by this subsection; and for purposes of computing the interest to be so transferred, amounts withdrawn by such State from its account in the Unemployment Trust Fund after the date of such State enactment shall be considered to be first charged against the amounts credited to such State’s account prior to the date of such State enactment: <i>Provided, however</i>, That if at any time after such enactment the provision for transfer therein contained for any reason fails to be operative to effect the transfers of interest as therein prescribed, and such State has not otherwise made an effective authorization and direction to the Secretary of the Treasury as required by this subsection, the Social Security Board shall immediately after such failure or, on the date otherwise provided in this subsection for the beginning of withholdings from certification, whichever is later, begin to make the withholdings from certification provided for in this subsection in the same manner and to the same extent as if such enactment by such State had not been enacted, except that the amounts of the certifications withheld shall be reduced by the total amount, if any, which has been transferred from interest pursuant to such enactment.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfers and withdrawals, effect upon social security provisions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The transfers described in the provisos contained in the several paragraphs of subsection (d) of this section shall not be deemed to constitute a breach of the conditions set forth in sections 503(a)(5) and 1103(a)(4) of title 42; nor shall the withdrawal by a State from its account in the unemployment trust fund of amounts, but not to exceed the total amount the Social Security Board shall have withheld from certification with respect to such State pursuant to subsection (d) of this section, be deemed to constitute a breach of the conditions set forth in sections 503(a)(5) and 1103(a)(4) of title 42, provided the moneys so withdrawn are expended solely for expenses which the Social Security Board determines to be necessary for the proper administration of such State’s unemployment compensation law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payments to railroad unemployment insurance account; transfers from unemployment trust fund of States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Social Security Board is authorized and directed to certify to the Secretary of the Treasury for payment, and the Secretary shall pay, into the railroad unemployment insurance account, such amounts as the Social Security Board withholds from certification pursuant to subsection (d) of this section and the appropriations authorized in <ref>section 501 of title 42</ref> shall be available for payments authorized by this subsection. The Secretary shall transfer from the account of a State in the unemployment trust fund to the railroad unemployment insurance account in the unemployment trust fund such amounts as the State authorizes and directs him so to transfer pursuant to subsection (d) of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1938, ch. 680, § 13(b)</ref>–(f), <ref>52 Stat. 1110</ref>; <ref>June 20, 1939, ch. 227, § 17</ref>, <ref>53 Stat. 848</ref>; <ref>July 2, 1940, ch. 530</ref>, <ref>54 Stat. 741</ref>; <ref>June 30, 1942, ch. 463</ref>, <ref>56 Stat. 465</ref>; <ref>July 31, 1946, ch. 709, § 324</ref>, <ref>60 Stat. 741</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–257, title II, § 207</ref>, <date date="1968-02-15">Feb. 15, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 25</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 363a.</num>
<heading> Refunds of State unemployment contributions by employees; amount; application period; definitions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, in any case where an employee amount (as hereinafter defined) was paid from a State unemployment fund to the Unemployment Trust Fund, an aggregate amount equal thereto shall be paid from the Unemployment Trust Fund, as refunds, to employees who paid into the State fund the contributions upon which such payment into the Unemployment Trust Fund was based, except that in case any such employee is deceased, payment shall be made to his estate; and the payment so made in the case of any employee shall be in proportion to the contributions paid by such employee into the State fund: <i>Provided</i>, That payment in any such case shall be made only if application therefor is made to the Railroad Retirement Board within two years after <date date="1946-08-02">August 2, 1946</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> As used in this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “employee amount” means any amount paid from a State unemployment fund to the Unemployment Trust Fund which would not have been required to be paid, under the provisions of <ref>section 363(c) of this title</ref>, if said section had not required payment of amounts based on contributions collected from employees.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “Unemployment Trust Fund” means the fund established by <ref>section 1104 of title 42</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “employees” has the same meaning as in the Railroad Unemployment Insurance Act [<ref>45 U.S.C. 351</ref> et seq.].</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 2, 1946, ch. 743</ref>, <ref>60 Stat. 806</ref>; <ref>Aug. 6, 1947, ch. 509</ref>, <ref>61 Stat. 793</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 364.</num>
<heading> District of Columbia account, transfer of funds to railroad unemployment insurance account</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Treasury is authorized and directed to transfer from the account of the District of Columbia in the unemployment trust fund to the railroad unemployment insurance account in the unemployment trust fund, an amount equal to the “preliminary amount” and an amount equal to the “liquidating amount”, whenever such amounts, respectively, have been determined, with respect to the District of Columbia, pursuant to <ref>section 363 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1938, ch. 680, § 14(b)</ref>, <ref>52 Stat. 1113</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 365.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 366.</num>
<heading> Separability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If any provision of this chapter or the application there of to any person or circumstance is held invalid, the application of such provision to other persons or circumstances, and the remainder of this chapter shall not be affected thereby.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1938, ch. 680, § 16</ref>, <ref>52 Stat. 1113</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 366a.</num>
<heading> Effect of Internal Revenue Code</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The provisions of the Railroad Unemployment Insurance Act, as herein amended, shall be in full force and effect notwithstanding the enactment of the Internal Revenue Code.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 20, 1939, ch. 227, § 22</ref>, <ref>53 Stat. 848</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 367.</num>
<heading> Short title</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This chapter may be cited as the “Railroad Unemployment Insurance Act”.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1938, ch. 680, § 17</ref>, <ref>52 Stat. 1113</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 368.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 104–251, § 5(c)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-09">Oct. 9, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3165</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 369.</num>
<heading> Annual report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On or before July 1 of 1989, and of each calendar year thereafter, the Railroad Retirement Board shall submit to the Congress a report on the financial status of the railroad unemployment insurance system under various economic and employment assumptions. Such report shall include any recommendation for financing changes which might be advisable, including any adjustment the Railroad Retirement Board recommends regarding the rates of employer contributions.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–647, title VII, § 7105</ref>, <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3772</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>