<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 15—</num>
<heading>PENSION FOR NON-SERVICE-CONNECTED DISABILITY OR DEATH OR FOR SERVICE</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>GENERAL</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1501.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For the purposes of this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “Indian Wars” means the campaigns, engagements, and expeditions of the United States military forces against Indian tribes or nations, service in which has been recognized heretofore as pensionable service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “World War I” includes, in the case of any veteran, any period of service performed by such veteran after <date date="1918-11-11">November 11, 1918</date>, and before <date date="1921-07-02">July 2, 1921</date>, if such veteran served in the active military, naval, or air service after <date date="1917-04-05">April 5, 1917</date>, and before <date date="1918-11-12">November 12, 1918</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “Civil War veteran” includes a person who served in the military or naval forces of the Confederate States of America during the Civil War, and the term “active military or naval service” includes active service in those forces.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “period of war” means the Mexican border period, World War I, World War II, the Korean conflict, the Vietnam era, the Persian Gulf War, and the period beginning on the date of any future declaration of war by the Congress and ending on the date prescribed by Presidential proclamation or concurrent resolution of the Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–857</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1134</ref>, § 501; <ref>Pub. L. 94–169, title I, § 106(1)</ref>, <date date="1975-12-23">Dec. 23, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 1017</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–588, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1978-11-04">Nov. 4, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2497</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–25, title III, § 333(a)</ref>, <date date="1991-04-06">Apr. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 88</ref>; renumbered § 1501, <ref>Pub. L. 102–83, § 5(a)</ref>, <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 406</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1502.</num>
<heading> Determinations with respect to disability</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> For the purposes of this chapter, a person shall be considered to be permanently and totally disabled if such person is any of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A patient in a nursing home for long-term care because of disability.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Disabled, as determined by the Commissioner of Social Security for purposes of any benefits administered by the Commissioner.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Unemployable as a result of disability reasonably certain to continue throughout the life of the person.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> Suffering from—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any disability which is sufficient to render it impossible for the average person to follow a substantially gainful occupation, but only if it is reasonably certain that such disability will continue throughout the life of the person; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any disease or disorder determined by the Secretary to be of such a nature or extent as to justify a determination that persons suffering therefrom are permanently and totally disabled.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> For the purposes of this chapter, a person shall be considered to be in need of regular aid and attendance if such person is (1) a patient in a nursing home or (2) blind, or so nearly blind or significantly disabled as to need or require the regular aid and attendance of another person.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> For the purposes of this chapter, the requirement of “permanently housebound” will be considered to have been met when the veteran is substantially confined to such veteran’s house (ward or clinical areas, if institutionalized) or immediate premises due to a disability or disabilities which it is reasonably certain will remain throughout such veteran’s lifetime.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–857</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1134</ref>, § 502; <ref>Pub. L. 88–664, § 6(b)</ref>, <date date="1964-10-13">Oct. 13, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 1095</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–77, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1967-08-31">Aug. 31, 1967</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 178</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–169, title I, § 106(2)</ref>, <date date="1975-12-23">Dec. 23, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 1017</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–432, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1976-09-30">Sept. 30, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1369</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–508, title VIII, § 8002(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1388–342</ref>; renumbered § 1502 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–83</ref>, §§ 4(b)(1), (2)(E), 5(a), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 404–406</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–103, title II, § 206(a)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-27">Dec. 27, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 990</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–233, title V, § 502(3)</ref>, <date date="2006-06-15">June 15, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 415</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1503.</num>
<heading> Determinations with respect to annual income</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> In determining annual income under this chapter, all payments of any kind or from any source (including salary, retirement or annuity payments, or similar income, which has been waived, irrespective of whether the waiver was made pursuant to statute, contract, or otherwise) shall be included except—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> donations from public or private relief or welfare organizations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> payments under this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> amounts equal to amounts paid by a spouse of a veteran for the expenses of such veteran’s last illness, and by a surviving spouse or child of a deceased veteran for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> such veteran’s just debts,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the expenses of such veteran’s last illness, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the expenses of such veteran’s burial to the extent such expenses are not reimbursed under chapter 23 of this title;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> amounts equal to amounts paid—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> by a veteran for the last illness and burial of such veteran’s deceased spouse or child, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> by the spouse of a living veteran or the surviving spouse of a deceased veteran for the last illness and burial of a child of such veteran;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> payments regarding reimbursements of any kind (including insurance settlement payments) for expenses related to the repayment, replacement, or repair of equipment, vehicles, items, money, or property resulting from—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any accident (as defined by the Secretary), but the amount excluded under this subparagraph shall not exceed the greater of the fair market value or reasonable replacement value of the equipment or vehicle involved at the time immediately preceding the accident;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any theft or loss (as defined by the Secretary), but the amount excluded under this subparagraph shall not exceed the greater of the fair market value or reasonable replacement value of the item or the amount of the money (including legal tender of the United States or of a foreign country) involved at the time immediately preceding the theft or loss; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any casualty loss (as defined by the Secretary), but the amount excluded under this subparagraph shall not exceed the greater of the fair market value or reasonable replacement value of the property involved at the time immediately preceding the casualty loss;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> profit realized from the disposition of real or personal property other than in the course of a business;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> amounts in joint accounts in banks and similar institutions acquired by reason of death of other joint owner;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> amounts equal to amounts paid by a veteran, veterans’ spouse, or surviving spouse or by or on behalf of a veteran’s child for unreimbursed medical expenses, to the extent that such amounts exceed 5 percent of the maximum annual rate of pension (including any amount of increased pension payable on account of family members but not including any amount of pension payable because a person is in need of regular aid and attendance or because a person is permanently house­bound) payable to such veteran, surviving spouse, or child;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> in the case of a veteran or surviving spouse pursuing a course of education or vocational rehabilitation or training, amounts equal to amounts paid by such veteran or surviving spouse for such course of education or vocational rehabilitation or training, including (A) amounts paid for tuition, fees, books, and materials, and (B) in the case of such a veteran or surviving spouse in need of regular aid and attendance, unreimbursed amounts paid for unusual transportation expenses in connection with the pursuit of such course of education or vocational rehabilitation or training, to the extent that such amounts exceed the reasonable expenses which would have been incurred by a nondisabled person using an appropriate means of transportation (public transportation, if reasonably available);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<chapeau> in the case of a child, any current-work income received during the year, to the extent that the total amount of such income does not exceed an amount equal to the sum of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the lowest amount of gross income for which an income tax return is required under section 6012(a) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, to be filed by an individual who is not married (as determined under section 7703 of such Code), is not a surviving spouse (as defined in section 2(a) of such Code), and is not a head of household (as defined in section 2(b) of such Code); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> if the child is pursuing a course of postsecondary education or vocational rehabilitation or training, the amount paid by such child for such course of education or vocational rehabilitation or training, including the amount paid for tuition, fees, books, and materials;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> payment of a monetary amount of up to $5,000 to a veteran from a State or municipality that is paid as a veterans’ benefit due to injury or disease; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> lump-sum proceeds of any life insurance policy on a veteran, for purposes of pension under subchapter III of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Where a fraction of a dollar is involved, annual income shall be fixed at the next lower dollar.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–857</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1134</ref>, § 503; <ref>Pub. L. 86–211, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1959-08-29">Aug. 29, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 432</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–268, § 1(b)</ref>, <date date="1961-09-21">Sept. 21, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 566</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–664, § 1</ref>, <date date="1964-10-13">Oct. 13, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 1094</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–77, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1967-08-31">Aug. 31, 1967</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 178</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–588, § 7</ref>, <date date="1970-12-24">Dec. 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1584</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–198, § 2</ref>, <date date="1971-12-15">Dec. 15, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 664</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–425, § 6(2)</ref>, <date date="1972-09-21">Sept. 21, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 713</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–169, title I</ref>, §§ 101(2)(A), 106(3)–(8), <date date="1975-12-23">Dec. 23, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 1013</ref>, 1017; <ref>Pub. L. 95–588, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1978-11-04">Nov. 4, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2497</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–295, § 4(13)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-12">Oct. 12, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1305</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–687, div. B, title XIV, § 1402(b)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4130</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–54, § 14(b)(5)</ref>, <date date="1991-06-13">June 13, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 283</ref>; renumbered § 1503 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–83</ref>, §§ 4(b)(1), (2)(E), 5(a), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 404–406</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–454, title III, § 303</ref>, <date date="2004-12-10">Dec. 10, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3611</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–275, title VI, § 604(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-13">Oct. 13, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2885</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–154, title V, § 509(a)</ref>, <date date="2012-08-06">Aug. 6, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1195</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–58, title VI, § 601(3)</ref>, <date date="2015-09-30">Sept. 30, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 538</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1504.</num>
<heading> Persons heretofore having a pensionable status</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The pension benefits of subchapters II and III of this chapter shall, notwithstanding the service requirements of such subchapters, be granted to persons heretofore recognized by law as having a pensionable status.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–857</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1134</ref>, § 504; renumbered § 1504, <ref>Pub. L. 102–83, § 5(a)</ref>, <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 406</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1505.</num>
<heading> Payment of pension during confinement in penal institutions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> No pension under public or private laws administered by the Secretary shall be paid to or for an individual who has been imprisoned in a Federal, State, local, or other penal institution or correctional facility as a result of conviction of a felony or misdemeanor for any part of the period beginning sixty-one days after such individual’s imprisonment begins and ending when such individual’s imprisonment ends.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Where any veteran is disqualified for pension for any period solely by reason of subsection (a) of this section, the Secretary may apportion and pay to such veteran’s spouse or children the pension which such veteran would receive for that period but for this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Where any surviving spouse or child of a veteran is disqualified for pension for any period solely by reason of subsection (a) of this section, the Secretary may (1) if the surviving spouse is so disqualified, pay to the child, or children, the pension which would be payable if there were no such surviving spouse or (2) if a child is so disqualified, pay to the surviving spouse or other children, as applicable, the pension which would be payable if there were no such child.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–857</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1134</ref>, § 505; <ref>Pub. L. 94–169, title I, § 106(9)</ref>–(11), <date date="1975-12-23">Dec. 23, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 1017</ref>; renumbered § 1505 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–83</ref>, §§ 4(a)(1), (b)(1), (2)(E), 5(a), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 403–406</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–461, title X, § 1002(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-22">Dec. 22, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3464</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1506.</num>
<heading> Resource reports and overpayment adjustments</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As a condition of granting or continuing pension under section 1521, 1541, or 1542 of this title, the Secretary—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> may require from any person who is an applicant for or a recipient of pension such information, proofs, and evidence as the Secretary determines to be necessary in order to determine the annual income and the value of the corpus of the estate of such person, and of any spouse or child for whom the person is receiving or is to receive increased pension (such a child is hereinafter in this subsection referred to as a “dependent child”), and, in the case of a child applying for or in receipt of pension under <ref>section 1542 of this title</ref> (hereinafter in this subsection referred to as a “surviving child”), of any person with whom such child is residing who is legally responsible for such child’s support;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> may require that any such applicant or recipient file for a calendar year with the Department (on such form as may be prescribed for such purpose by the Secretary) a report showing—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the annual income which such applicant or recipient (and any such spouse or dependent child) received during the preceding year, the corpus of the estate of such applicant or recipient (and of any such spouse or dependent child) at the end of such year, and in the case of a surviving child, the income and corpus of the estate of any person with whom such child is residing who is legally responsible for such child’s support;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> such applicant’s or recipient’s estimate for the then current year of the annual income such applicant or recipient (and any such spouse or dependent child) expects to receive and of any expected increase in the value of the corpus of the estate of such applicant or recipient (and for any such spouse or dependent child); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> in the case of a surviving child, an estimate for the then current year of the annual income of any person with whom such child is residing who is legally responsible for such child’s support and of any expected increase in the value of the corpus of the estate of such person;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> shall require that any such applicant or recipient promptly notify the Secretary whenever there is a material change in the annual income of such applicant or recipient (or of any such spouse or dependent child) or a material change in the value of the corpus of the estate of such applicant or recipient (or of any such spouse or dependent child), and in the case of a surviving child, a material change in the annual income or value of the corpus of the estate of any person with whom such child is residing who is legally responsible for such child’s support; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> shall require that any such applicant or recipient applying for or in receipt of increased pension on account of a person who is a spouse or child of such applicant or recipient promptly notify the Secretary if such person ceases to meet the applicable definition of spouse or child.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 86–211, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="1959-08-29">Aug. 29, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 432</ref>, § 506; amended <ref>Pub. L. 88–664, § 2</ref>, <date date="1964-10-13">Oct. 13, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 1094</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–588, § 6</ref>, <date date="1970-12-24">Dec. 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1584</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–169, title I, § 106(12)</ref>–(14), <date date="1975-12-23">Dec. 23, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 1017</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–588, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1978-11-04">Nov. 4, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2498</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–466, title VI, § 605(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-17">Oct. 17, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2211</ref>; renumbered § 1506 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–83</ref>, §§ 4(a)(3), (4), (b)(1), (2)(E), 5(a), (c)(1), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 404–406</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–271, § 9(b)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-01">July 1, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 743</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1507.</num>
<heading> Disappearance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Where a veteran receiving pension under subchapter II of this chapter disappears, the Secretary may pay the pension otherwise payable to such veteran’s spouse and children. In applying the provisions of this section, the Secretary may presume, without reports pursuant to <ref>section 1506(a) of this title</ref>, that the status of the veteran at the time of disappearance, with respect to permanent and total disability, income, and net worth, continues unchanged. Payments made to a spouse or child under this section shall not exceed the amount to which each would be entitled if the veteran died of a non-service-connected disability.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 89–467, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1966-06-22">June 22, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 218</ref>, § 507; amended <ref>Pub. L. 94–169, title I, § 106(15)</ref>, <date date="1975-12-23">Dec. 23, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 1017</ref>; renumbered § 1507 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–83</ref>, §§ 4(b)(1), (2)(E), 5(a), (c)(1), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 404–406</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1508.</num>
<heading> Frequency of payment of pension benefits</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Except as provided under subsection (b) of this section, benefits under sections 1521, 1541, and 1542 of this title shall be paid monthly.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Under regulations which the Secretary shall prescribe, benefits under sections 1521, 1541, and 1542 of this title may be paid less frequently than monthly if the amount of the annual benefit is less than 4 percent of the maximum annual rate payable to a veteran under <ref>section 1521(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–588, title I, § 104(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-04">Nov. 4, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2499</ref>, § 508; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–54, § 14(b)(6)</ref>, <date date="1991-06-13">June 13, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 283</ref>; renumbered § 1508 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–83</ref>, §§ 4(b)(1), (2)(E), 5(a), (c)(1), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 404–406</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>VETERANS’ PENSIONS</heading>
<level>
<heading class="small-caps">Service Pension</heading>
<section>
<num>[§ 1510.</num>
<heading> Vacant]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1511.</num>
<heading> Indian War veterans</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary shall pay to each veteran of the Indian Wars who meets the service requirements of this section a pension at the following monthly rate:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> $101.59; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> $135.45 if the veteran is in need of regular aid and attendance.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> A veteran meets the service requirements of this section if such veteran served in one of the Indian Wars—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> for thirty days or more; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> for the duration of such Indian War;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">in any military organization, whether or not such service was the result of regular muster into the service of the United States, if such service was under the authority or by the approval of the United States or any State.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Any veteran eligible for pension under this section shall, if such veteran so elects, be paid pension at the rates prescribed by <ref>section 1521 of this title</ref>, and under the conditions (other than the service requirements) applicable to pension paid under that section to veterans of World War I. If pension is paid pursuant to such an election, the election shall be irrevocable, except as provided in paragraph (2).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall pay each month to each veteran of the Indian Wars who is receiving, or entitled to receive, pension based on a need of regular aid and attendance, whichever amount is greater (A) that provided by paragraph (2) of subsection (a) of this section, or (B) that which is payable to the veteran under <ref>section 1521 of this title</ref> if such veteran has elected, or would be payable if such veteran were to elect, to receive pension under such section pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection. Each change in the amount of pension payment required by this paragraph shall be effective as of the first day of the month during which the facts of the particular case warrant such change, and shall be made without specific application therefor.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–857</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1135</ref>, § 511; <ref>Pub. L. 86–670, § 1</ref>, <date date="1960-07-14">July 14, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 545</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–77, title I, § 111(a)</ref>, <date date="1967-08-31">Aug. 31, 1967</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 181</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–169, title I, § 106(16)</ref>, <date date="1975-12-23">Dec. 23, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 1017</ref>; renumbered § 1511 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–83</ref>, §§ 4(b)(1), (2)(E), 5(a), (c)(1), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 404–406</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1512.</num>
<heading> Spanish-American War veterans</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary shall pay to each veteran of the Spanish-American War who meets the service requirements of this subsection a pension at the following monthly rate:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> $101.59; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> $135.45 if the veteran is in need of regular aid and attendance.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> A veteran meets the service requirements of this subsection if such veteran served in the active military or naval service—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> for ninety days or more during the Spanish-American War;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> during the Spanish-American War and was discharged or released from such service for a service-connected disability; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> for a period of ninety consecutive days or more and such period began or ended during the Spanish-American War.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Any veteran eligible for pension under this subsection shall, if such veteran so elects, be paid pension at the rates prescribed by <ref>section 1521 of this title</ref> (except the rate provided under subsection (g) of such section), and under the conditions (other than the service requirements) applicable to pension paid under that section to veterans of a period of war. If pension is paid pursuant to such an election, the election shall be irrevocable.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall pay each month to each Spanish-American War veteran who is receiving, or entitled to receive, pension based on a need of regular aid and attendance, whichever amount is greater (i) that provided by subparagraph (B) of subsection (a)(1) of this section, or (ii) that which is payable to the veteran under <ref>section 1521 of this title</ref> as in effect on <date date="1978-12-31">December 31, 1978</date>, under regulations which the Secretary shall prescribe. Each change in the amount of pension payment required by this subparagraph shall be effective as of the first day of the month during which the facts of the particular case warrant such change, and shall be made without specific application therefor.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary shall pay to each veteran of the Spanish-American War who does not meet the service requirements of subsection (a), but who meets the service requirements of this subsection, a pension at the following monthly rate:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> $67.73; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> $88.04 if the veteran is in need of regular aid and attendance.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> A veteran meets the service requirements of this subsection if such veteran served in the active military or naval service—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> for seventy days or more during the Spanish-American War; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for a period of seventy consecutive days or more and such period began or ended during the Spanish-American War.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–857</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1135</ref>, § 512; <ref>Pub. L. 86–670, § 2</ref>, <date date="1960-07-14">July 14, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 545</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–77, title I, § 111(b)</ref>, <date date="1967-08-31">Aug. 31, 1967</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 181</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–169, title I, § 106(17)</ref>, <date date="1975-12-23">Dec. 23, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 1017</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–588, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1978-11-04">Nov. 4, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2500</ref>; renumbered § 1512 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–83</ref>, §§ 4(b)(1), (2)(E), 5(a), (c)(1), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 404–406</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1513.</num>
<heading> Veterans 65 years of age and older</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall pay to each veteran of a period of war who is 65 years of age or older and who meets the service requirements of <ref>section 1521 of this title</ref> (as prescribed in subsection (j) of that section) pension at the rates prescribed by <ref>section 1521 of this title</ref> and under the conditions (other than the permanent and total disability requirement) applicable to pension paid under that section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> If a veteran is eligible for pension under both this section and <ref>section 1521 of this title</ref>, pension shall be paid to the veteran only under <ref>section 1521 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 107–103, title II, § 207(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-27">Dec. 27, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 991</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 109–233, title V, § 503(2)</ref>, <date date="2006-06-15">June 15, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 416</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</level>
<level>
<heading class="small-caps">Non-Service-Connected Disability Pension</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1521.</num>
<heading> Veterans of a period of war</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall pay to each veteran of a period of war who meets the service requirements of this section (as prescribed in subsection (j) of this section) and who is permanently and totally disabled from non-service-connected disability not the result of the veteran’s willful misconduct, pension at the rate prescribed by this section, as increased from time to time under <ref>section 5312 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> If the veteran is unmarried (or married but not living with or reasonably contributing to the support of such veteran’s spouse) and there is no child of the veteran in the custody of the veteran or to whose support the veteran is reasonably contributing, and unless the veteran is entitled to pension at the rate provided by subsection (d)(1) or (e) of this section, pension shall be paid to the veteran at the annual rate of $11,830, reduced by the amount of the veteran’s annual income.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> If the veteran is married and living with or reasonably contributing to the support of such veteran’s spouse, or if there is a child of the veteran in the custody of the veteran or to whose support the veteran is reasonably contributing, pension shall be paid to the veteran at the annual rate of $15,493, unless the veteran is entitled to pension at the rate provided by subsection (d)(2), (e), or (f) of this section. If the veteran has two or more such family members, such annual rate shall be increased by $2,020 for each such family member in excess of one. The rate payable shall be reduced by the amount of the veteran’s annual income and, subject to subsection (h)(1) of this section, the amount of annual income of such family members.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> If the veteran is in need of regular aid and attendance, the annual rate of pension payable to the veteran under subsection (b) of this section shall be $19,736, reduced by the amount of the veteran’s annual income.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If the veteran is in need of regular aid and attendance, the annual rate of pension payable to the veteran under subsection (c) of this section shall be $23,396. If such veteran has two or more family members, as described in subsection (c) of this section, the annual rate of pension shall be increased by $2,020 for each such family member in excess of one. The rate payable shall be reduced by the amount of the veteran’s annual income and, subject to subsection (h)(1) of this section, the amount of annual income of such family members.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> If the veteran has a disability rated as permanent and total and (1) has additional disability or disabilities independently ratable at 60 per centum or more, or (2) by reason of a disability or disabilities, is permanently housebound but does not qualify for pension at the aid and attendance rate provided by subsection (d) of this section, the annual rate of pension payable to the veteran under subsection (b) of this section shall be $14,457 and the annual rate of pension payable to the veteran under subsection (c) of this section shall be $18,120. If such veteran has two or more family members, as described in subsection (c) of this section, the annual rate of pension shall be increased by $2,020 for each such family member in excess of one. The rate payable shall be reduced by the amount of the veteran’s annual income and, subject to subsection (h)(1) of this section, the annual income of such family members.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> If two veterans are married to one another and each meets the disability and service requirements prescribed in subsections (a) and (j), respectively, of this section, or the age and service requirements prescribed in <ref>section 1513 of this title</ref>, the annual rate of pension payable to such veterans shall be a combined annual rate of $15,493.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If either such veteran is in need of regular aid and attendance, the annual rate provided by paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be $23,396. If both such veterans are in need of regular aid and attendance, such rate shall be $32,433.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> If either such veteran would be entitled (if not married to a veteran) to pension at the rate provided by subsection (e) of this section, the annual rate provided by paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be $18,120. If both such veterans would be entitled (if not married to one another) to such rate, such rate shall be $20,747.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> If one such veteran is in need of regular aid and attendance and the other would be entitled (if not married to a veteran) to the rate provided for under subsection (e) of this section, the annual rate provided by paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be $26,018.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The annual rate provided by paragraph (1), (2), (3), or (4) of this subsection, as appropriate, shall (A) be increased by $2,020 for each child of such veterans (or of either such veteran) who is in the custody of either or both such veterans or to whose support either such veteran is, or both such veterans are, reasonably contributing, and (B) be reduced by the amount of the annual income of both such veterans and, subject to subsection (h)(1) of this section, the annual income of each such child.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> The annual rate of pension payable under subsection (b), (c), (d), (e), or (f) of this section to any veteran who is a veteran of a period of war shall be increased by $2,686 if veterans of such period of war were not provided educational benefits or home loan benefits similar to those provided to veterans of later periods of war under chapters 34 and 37, respectively, of this title or under prior corresponding provisions of law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<chapeau> For the purposes of this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In determining the annual income of a veteran, if there is a child of the veteran who is in the custody of the veteran or to whose support the veteran is reasonably contributing, that portion of the annual income of the child that is reasonably available to or for the veteran shall be considered to be income of the veteran, unless in the judgment of the Secretary to do so would work a hardship on the veteran.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A veteran shall be considered as living with a spouse, even though they reside apart, unless they are estranged.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> If the veteran is entitled under this section to pension on the basis of such veteran’s own service and is also entitled to pension on the basis of any other person’s service, the Secretary shall pay such veteran only the greater benefit.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<chapeau> A veteran meets the service requirements of this section if such veteran served in the active military, naval, air, or space service—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> for ninety days or more during a period of war;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> during a period of war and was discharged or released from such service for a service-connected disability;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> for a period of ninety consecutive days or more and such period began or ended during a period of war; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> for an aggregate of ninety days or more in two or more separate periods of service during more than one period of war.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–857</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1136</ref>, § 521; <ref>Pub. L. 86–211, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="1959-08-29">Aug. 29, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 433</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–101, § 1</ref>, <date date="1961-07-21">July 21, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 218</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–664</ref>, §§ 3(a), (b), 5, 6(a), 7, <date date="1964-10-13">Oct. 13, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 1094</ref>, 1095; <ref>Pub. L. 90–77, title I, § 104</ref>, title II, § 202(a)–(c), <date date="1967-08-31">Aug. 31, 1967</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 179</ref>, 182; <ref>Pub. L. 90–275, § 1(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1968-03-28">Mar. 28, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 64</ref>, 65; <ref>Pub. L. 91–588</ref>, §§ 1(a), (b), 3(b), 9(c), <date date="1970-12-24">Dec. 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1580</ref>, 1583, 1584; <ref>Pub. L. 92–198</ref>, §§ 1(a), (b), 5(b), <date date="1971-12-15">Dec. 15, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 663</ref>, 664; <ref>Pub. L. 93–177, § 1(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1973-12-06">Dec. 6, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 694</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–527, § 2</ref>, <date date="1974-12-21">Dec. 21, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1702</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–169, title I</ref>, §§ 102, 106(18), <date date="1975-12-23">Dec. 23, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 1014</ref>, 1018; <ref>Pub. L. 94–432, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="1976-09-30">Sept. 30, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1369</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–204, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1977-12-02">Dec. 2, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 1455</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–588, title I, § 106(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-04">Nov. 4, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2500</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–40, title IV, § 402(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-05-07">May 7, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 239</ref>; renumbered § 1521 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–83</ref>, §§ 4(b)(1), (2)(E), 5(a), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 404–406</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–103, title II, § 207(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-27">Dec. 27, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 991</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–275, title VI, § 608(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-13">Oct. 13, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2886</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–154, title V, § 508(a)</ref>, <date date="2012-08-06">Aug. 6, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1194</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 926(a)(19)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3830</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1522.</num>
<heading> Net worth limitation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall deny or discontinue the payment of pension to a veteran under section 1513 or 1521 of this title when the corpus of the estate of the veteran or, if the veteran has a spouse, the corpus of the estates of the veteran and of the veteran’s spouse is such that under all the circumstances, including consideration of the annual income of the veteran, the veteran’s spouse, and the veteran’s children, it is reasonable that some part of the corpus of such estates be consumed for the veteran’s maintenance.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall deny or discontinue the payment of increased pension under subsection (c), (d), (e), or (f) of <ref>section 1521 of this title</ref> on account of a child when the corpus of such child’s estate is such that under all the circumstances, including consideration of the veteran’s and spouse’s income, and the income of the veteran’s children, it is reasonable that some part of the corpus of such child’s estate be consumed for the child’s maintenance. During the period such denial or discontinuance remains in effect, such child shall not be considered as the veteran’s child for purposes of this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–857</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1136</ref>, § 522; <ref>Pub. L. 86–211, § 3(b)</ref>, <date date="1959-08-29">Aug. 29, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 434</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–588, title I, § 107</ref>, <date date="1978-11-04">Nov. 4, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2502</ref>; renumbered § 1522 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–83</ref>, §§ 4(b)(1), (2)(E), 5(a), (c)(1), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 404–406</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–103, title II, § 207(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-27">Dec. 27, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 991</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1523.</num>
<heading> Combination of ratings</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall provide that, for the purpose of determining whether or not a veteran is permanently and totally disabled, ratings for service-connected disabilities may be combined with ratings for non-service-connected disabilities.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Where a veteran, by virtue of subsection (a), is found to be entitled to a pension under <ref>section 1521 of this title</ref>, and is entitled to compensation for a service-connected disability, the Secretary shall pay such veteran the greater benefit.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–857</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1136</ref>, § 523; <ref>Pub. L. 94–169, title I, § 106(19)</ref>, <date date="1975-12-23">Dec. 23, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 1018</ref>; renumbered § 1523 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–83</ref>, §§ 4(b)(1), (2)(E), 5(a), (c)(1), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 404–406</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1524.</num>
<heading> Vocational training for certain pension recipients</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In the case of a veteran under age 45 who is awarded a pension during the program period, the Secretary shall, based on information on file with the Department of Veterans Affairs, make a preliminary finding whether such veteran, with the assistance of a vocational training program under this section, has a good potential for achieving employment. If such potential is found to exist, the Secretary shall solicit from the veteran an application for vocational training under this section. If the veteran thereafter applies for such training, the Secretary shall provide the veteran with an evaluation, which may include a personal interview, to determine whether the achievement of a vocational goal is reasonably feasible.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If a veteran who is 45 years of age or older and is awarded pension during the program period, or a veteran who was awarded pension before the beginning of the program period, applies for vocational training under this section and the Secretary makes a preliminary finding on the basis of information in the application that, with the assistance of a vocational training program under subsection (b) of this section, the veteran has a good potential for achieving employment, the Secretary shall provide the veteran with an evaluation in order to determine whether the achievement of a vocational goal by the veteran is reasonably feasible. Any such evaluation shall include a personal interview by a Department employee trained in vocational counseling.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> For the purposes of this section, the term “program period” means the period beginning on <date date="1985-02-01">February 1, 1985</date>, and ending on <date date="1995-12-31">December 31, 1995</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> If the Secretary, based upon an evaluation under subsection (a) of this section, determines that the achievement of a vocational goal by a veteran is reasonably feasible, the veteran shall be offered and may elect to pursue a vocational training program under this subsection. If the veteran elects to pursue such a program, the program shall be designed in consultation with the veteran in order to meet the veteran’s individual needs and shall be set forth in an individualized written plan of vocational rehabilitation of the kind described in <ref>section 3107 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Subject to subparagraph (B) of this paragraph, a vocational training program under this subsection shall consist of vocationally oriented services and assistance of the kind provided under chapter 31 of this title and such other services and assistance of the kind provided under that chapter as are necessary to enable the veteran to prepare for and participate in vocational training or employment.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> A vocational training program under this subsection—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> may not exceed 24 months unless, based on a determination by the Secretary that an extension is necessary in order for the veteran to achieve a vocational goal identified (before the end of the first 24 months of such program) in the written plan formulated for the veteran, the Secretary grants an extension for a period not to exceed 24 months;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> may not include the provision of any loan or subsistence allowance or any automobile adaptive equipment of the kind provided under chapter 39 of this title; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> may include a program of education at an institution of higher learning (as defined in sections 3452(b) and 3452(f), respectively, of this title) only in a case in which the Secretary determines that the program involved is predominantly vocational in content.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> When a veteran completes a vocational training program under this subsection, the Secretary may provide the veteran with counseling of the kind described in <ref>section 3104(a)(2) of this title</ref>, placement and postplacement services of the kind described in <ref>section 3104(a)(5) of this title</ref>, and training of the kind described in <ref>section 3104(a)(6) of this title</ref> during a period not to exceed 18 months beginning on the date of such completion.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> A veteran may not begin pursuit of a vocational training program under this subsection after the later of (A) <date date="1995-12-31">December 31, 1995</date>, or (B) the end of a reasonable period of time, as determined by the Secretary, following either the evaluation of the veteran under subsection (a) of this section or the award of pension to the veteran as described in subsection (a)(2) of this section. Any determination by the Secretary of such a reasonable period of time shall be made pursuant to regulations which the Secretary shall prescribe.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> In the case of a veteran who has been determined to have a permanent and total non-service-connected disability and who, not later than one year after the date the veteran’s eligibility for counseling under subsection (b)(3) of this section expires, secures employment within the scope of a vocational goal identified in the veteran’s individualized written plan of vocational rehabilitation (or in a related field which requires reasonably developed skills and the use of some or all of the training or services furnished the veteran under such plan), the evaluation of the veteran as having a permanent and total disability may not be terminated by reason of the veteran’s capacity to engage in such employment until the veteran first maintains such employment for a period of not less than 12 consecutive months.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> A veteran who pursues a vocational training program under subsection (b) of this section shall have the benefit of the provisions of subsection (a) of <ref>section 1525 of this title</ref> beginning at such time as the veteran’s entitlement to pension is terminated by reason of income from work or training (as defined in subsection (b)(1) of that section) without regard to the date on which the veteran’s entitlement to pension is terminated.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> Payments by the Secretary for education, training, and other services and assistance under subsection (b) of this section (other than the services of Department employees) shall be made from the Department appropriations account from which payments for pension are made.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 98–543, title III, § 301(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-24">Oct. 24, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2744</ref>, § 524; amended <ref>Pub. L. 99–576, title VII, § 703(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-28">Oct. 28, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3303</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–227, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="1987-12-31">Dec. 31, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1555</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–687, div. B, title XIII, § 1303(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4128</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–237, title I, § 114</ref>, <date date="1989-12-18">Dec. 18, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 2065</ref>; renumbered § 1524 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–83</ref>, §§ 4(a)(3), (4), (b)(1), (2)(E), 5(a), (c)(1), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 404–406</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–291, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="1992-05-20">May 20, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 178</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–568, title IV, § 402(a)</ref>–(c)(2)(A), <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4337</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–446, title XII, § 1201(g)(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4687</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1525.</num>
<heading> Protection of health-care eligibility</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> In the case of a veteran whose entitlement to pension is terminated after <date date="1985-01-31">January 31, 1985</date>, by reason of income from work or training, the veteran shall retain for a period of three years beginning on the date of such termination all eligibility for care and services under such chapter that the veteran would have had if the veteran’s entitlement to pension had not been terminated. Care and services for which such a veteran retains eligibility include, when applicable, drugs and medicines under <ref>section 1712(d) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> For purposes of this section, the term “terminated by reason of income from work or training” means terminated as a result of the veteran’s receipt of earnings from activity performed for remuneration or with gain, but only if the veteran’s annual income from sources other than such earnings would, taken alone, not result in the termination of the veteran’s pension.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 98–543, title III, § 301(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-24">Oct. 24, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2746</ref>, § 525; amended <ref>Pub. L. 99–272, title XIX, § 19011(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="1986-04-07">Apr. 7, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 378</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–576, title VII, § 703(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-28">Oct. 28, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3303</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–687, div. B, title XIII, § 1303(c)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4128</ref>; renumbered § 1525 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–83, § 5(a)</ref>, (c)(1), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 406</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–291, § 2(c)</ref>, <date date="1992-05-20">May 20, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 178</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–568, title IV, § 403(a)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4337</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–262, title I, § 101(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-09">Oct. 9, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3180</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</level>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>PENSIONS TO SURVIVING SPOUSES AND CHILDREN</heading>
<level>
<heading class="small-caps">Wars Before World War I</heading>
<section>
<num>[§ 1531.</num>
<heading> Vacant]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1532.</num>
<heading> Surviving spouses of Civil War veterans</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary shall pay to the surviving spouse of each Civil War veteran who met the service requirements of this section a pension at the following monthly rate:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> $40.64 if such surviving spouse is below seventy years of age; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> $70 if such surviving spouse is seventy years of age or older.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> If there is a child of the veteran, the rate of pension paid to the surviving spouse under subsection (a) shall be increased by $8.13 per month for each such child.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> A veteran met the service requirements of this section if such veteran served for ninety days or more in the active military or naval service during the Civil War, as heretofore defined under public laws administered by the Veterans’ Administration, or if such veteran was discharged or released from such service upon a surgeon’s certificate of disability.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> No pension shall be paid to a surviving spouse of a veteran under this section unless such surviving spouse was married to such veteran—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> before <date date="1905-06-27">June 27, 1905</date>; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> for one year or more; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> for any period of time if a child was born of the marriage, or was born to them before the marriage.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–857</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1137</ref>, § 532; <ref>Pub. L. 90–77, title I</ref>, §§ 101(a), 105, <date date="1967-08-31">Aug. 31, 1967</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 178</ref>, 179; <ref>Pub. L. 94–169, title I, § 106(20)</ref>–(23), <date date="1975-12-23">Dec. 23, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 1018</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–54, § 14(b)(7)</ref>, <date date="1991-06-13">June 13, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 283</ref>; renumbered § 1532 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–83</ref>, §§ 4(a)(1), (b)(1), (2)(E), 5(a), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 403–406</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–446, title XII, § 1201(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4682</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1533.</num>
<heading> Children of Civil War veterans</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever there is no surviving spouse entitled to pension under <ref>section 1532 of this title</ref>, the Secretary shall pay to the children of each Civil War veteran who met the service requirements of <ref>section 1532 of this title</ref> a pension at the monthly rate of $73.13 for one child, plus $8.13 for each additional child, with the total amount equally divided.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–857</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1137</ref>, § 533; <ref>Pub. L. 94–169, title I, § 106(25)</ref>, <date date="1975-12-23">Dec. 23, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 1018</ref>; renumbered § 1533 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–83</ref>, §§ 4(b)(1), (2)(E), 5(a), (c)(1), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 404–406</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1534.</num>
<heading> Surviving spouses of Indian War veterans</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary shall pay to the surviving spouse of each Indian War veteran who met the service requirements of <ref>section 1511 of this title</ref> a pension at the following monthly rate:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> $40.64 if such surviving spouse is below seventy years of age; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> $70 if such surviving spouse is seventy years of age or older.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> If there is a child of the veteran, the rate of pension paid to the surviving spouse under subsection (a) shall be increased by $8.13 per month for each such child.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> No pension shall be paid to a surviving spouse of a veteran under this section unless such surviving spouse was married to such veteran—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> before <date date="1917-03-04">March 4, 1917</date>; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> for one year or more; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> for any period of time if a child was born of the marriage, or was born to them before the marriage.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–857</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1137</ref>, § 534; <ref>Pub. L. 90–77, title I</ref>, §§ 101(a), 105, <date date="1967-08-31">Aug. 31, 1967</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 178</ref>, 179; <ref>Pub. L. 94–169, title I, § 106(26)</ref>–(29), <date date="1975-12-23">Dec. 23, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 1018</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–54, § 14(b)(7)</ref>, <date date="1991-06-13">June 13, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 283</ref>; renumbered § 1534 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–83</ref>, §§ 4(b)(1), (2)(E), 5(a), (c)(1), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 404–406</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1535.</num>
<heading> Children of Indian War veterans</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever there is no surviving spouse entitled to pension under <ref>section 1534 of this title</ref>, the Secretary shall pay to the children of each Indian War veteran who met the service requirements of <ref>section 1511 of this title</ref> a pension at the monthly rate of $73.13 for one child, plus $8.13 for each additional child, with the total amount equally divided.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–857</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1137</ref>, § 535; <ref>Pub. L. 94–169, title I, § 106(31)</ref>, <date date="1975-12-23">Dec. 23, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 1018</ref>; renumbered § 1535 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–83</ref>, §§ 4(b)(1), (2)(E), 5(a), (c)(1), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 404–406</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1536.</num>
<heading> Surviving spouses of Spanish-American War veterans</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall pay to the surviving spouse of each Spanish-American War veteran who met the service requirements of <ref>section 1512(a) of this title</ref> a pension at the monthly rate of $70, unless such surviving spouse was the spouse of the veteran during such veteran’s service in the Spanish-American War, in which case the monthly rate shall be $75.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> If there is a child of the veteran, the rate of pension paid to the surviving spouse under subsection (a) shall be increased by $8.13 per month for each such child.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> No pension shall be paid to a surviving spouse of a veteran under this section unless such surviving spouse was married to such veteran—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> before <date date="1938-01-01">January 1, 1938</date>; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> for one year or more; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> for any period of time if a child was born of the marriage, or was born to them before the marriage.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Any surviving spouse eligible for pension under this section shall, if such surviving spouse so elects, be paid pension at the rates prescribed by <ref>section 1541 of this title</ref>, and under the conditions (other than the service requirements) applicable to pension paid under that section to surviving spouses of veterans of a period of war. If pension is paid pursuant to such an election, the election shall be irrevocable.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall pay each month to the surviving spouse of each Spanish-American War veteran who is receiving, or entitled to receive, pension based on a need of regular aid and attendance, whichever amount is greater (A) that which is payable to such surviving spouse under subsections (a) and (b) of this section as increased by section 544 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002023">1</ref> of this title, as in effect on <date date="1978-12-31">December 31, 1978</date>; or (B) that which is payable under <ref>section 1541 of this title</ref>, as in effect on <date date="1978-12-31">December 31, 1978</date>, as increased by such section 544,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002023">1</ref> as in effect on such date, to a surviving spouse of a World War I veteran with the same annual income and corpus of estate. Each change in the amount of pension required by this paragraph shall be effective as of the first day of the month during which the facts of the particular case warrant such change, and shall be made without specific application therefor.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–857</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1138</ref>, § 536; <ref>Pub. L. 90–77, title I</ref>, §§ 101(a), 105, <date date="1967-08-31">Aug. 31, 1967</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 178</ref>, 179; <ref>Pub. L. 92–328, title I, § 107</ref>, <date date="1972-06-30">June 30, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 395</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–169, title I, § 106(32)</ref>–(37), <date date="1975-12-23">Dec. 23, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 1018</ref>, 1019; <ref>Pub. L. 95–588, title I, § 108</ref>, <date date="1978-11-04">Nov. 4, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2502</ref>; renumbered § 1536 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–83</ref>, §§ 4(b)(1), (2)(E), 5(a), (c)(1), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 404–406</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1537.</num>
<heading> Children of Spanish-American War veterans</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever there is no surviving spouse entitled to pension under <ref>section 1536 of this title</ref>, the Secretary shall pay to the children of each Spanish-American War veteran who met the service requirements of <ref>section 1512(a) of this title</ref> a pension at the monthly rate of $73.13 for one child, plus $8.13 for each additional child, with the total amount equally divided.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–857</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1138</ref>, § 537; <ref>Pub. L. 94–169, title I, § 106(39)</ref>, <date date="1975-12-23">Dec. 23, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 1019</ref>; renumbered § 1537 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–83</ref>, §§ 4(b)(1), (2)(E), 5(a), (c)(1), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 404–406</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</level>
<level>
<heading class="small-caps">Other Periods of War</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1541.</num>
<heading> Surviving spouses of veterans of a period of war</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall pay to the surviving spouse of each veteran of a period of war who met the service requirements prescribed in <ref>section 1521(j) of this title</ref>, or who at the time of death was receiving (or entitled to receive) compensation or retirement pay for a service-connected disability, pension at the rate prescribed by this section, as increased from time to time under <ref>section 5312 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> If no child of the veteran is in the custody of the surviving spouse, pension shall be paid to the surviving spouse at the annual rate of $7,933, reduced by the amount of the surviving spouse’s annual income.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> If there is a child of the veteran in the custody of the surviving spouse, pension shall be paid to the surviving spouse at the annual rate of $10,385. If the surviving spouse has custody of two or more such children, the annual pension rate shall be increased by $2,020 for each such child in excess of one. In each case, the rate payable shall be reduced by the amount of the surviving spouse’s annual income and, subject to subsection (g) of this section, the annual income of each such child.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> If a surviving spouse who is entitled to pension under subsection (b) of this section is in need of regular aid and attendance, the annual rate of pension payable to such surviving spouse shall be $12,681, reduced by the amount of the surviving spouse’s annual income.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If a surviving spouse who is entitled to pension under subsection (c) of this section is in need of regular aid and attendance, the annual rate of pension payable to the surviving spouse shall be $15,128. If there are two or more children of the veteran in such surviving spouse’s custody, the annual rate of pension shall be increased by $2,020 for each such child in excess of one. The rate payable shall be reduced by the amount of the surviving spouse’s annual income and, subject to subsection (g) of this section, the annual income of each such child.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> If the surviving spouse is permanently housebound but does not qualify for pension at the aid and attendance rate provided by subsection (d) of this section, the annual rate of pension payable to such surviving spouse under subsection (b) of this section shall be $9,696 and the annual rate of pension payable to such surviving spouse under subsection (c) of this section shall be $12,144. If there are two or more children of the veteran in such surviving spouse’s custody, the annual rate of pension shall be increased by $2,020 for each such child in excess of one. The rate payable shall be reduced by the amount of the surviving spouse’s annual income and, subject to subsection (g) of this section, the income of any child of the veteran for whom the surviving spouse is receiving increased pension.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> For purposes of paragraph (1) of this subsection, the requirement of “permanently house­bound” shall be met when the surviving spouse is substantially confined to such surviving spouse’s house (ward or clinical areas, if institutionalized) or immediate premises by reason of a disability or disabilities reasonably certain to remain throughout such surviving spouse’s lifetime.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<chapeau> No pension shall be paid under this section to a surviving spouse of a veteran unless the spouse was married to the veteran—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> before (A) <date date="1944-12-14">December 14, 1944</date>, in the case of a surviving spouse of a Mexican border period or World War I veteran, (B) <date date="1957-01-01">January 1, 1957</date>, in the case of a surviving spouse of a World War II veteran, (C) <date date="1965-02-01">February 1, 1965</date>, in the case of a surviving spouse of a Korean conflict veteran, (D) <date date="1985-05-08">May 8, 1985</date>, in the case of a surviving spouse of a Vietnam era veteran, or (E) <date date="2001-01-01">January 1, 2001</date>, in the case of a surviving spouse of a veteran of the Persian Gulf War;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> for one year or more; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> for any period of time if a child was born of the marriage, or was born to them before the marriage.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> In determining the annual income of a surviving spouse for the purposes of this section, if there is a child of the veteran in the custody of the surviving spouse, that portion of the annual income of the child that is reasonably available to or for the surviving spouse shall be considered to be income of the surviving spouse, unless in the judgment of the Secretary to do so would work a hardship on the surviving spouse.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<content> As used in this section and <ref>section 1542 of this title</ref>, the term “veteran” includes a person who has completed at least two years of honorable active military, naval, air, or space service, as certified by the Secretary concerned, but whose death in such service was not in line of duty.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–857</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1138</ref>, § 541; <ref>Pub. L. 86–211, § 4</ref>, <date date="1959-08-29">Aug. 29, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 434</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–664, § 3(c)</ref>, (d), <date date="1964-10-13">Oct. 13, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 1095</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–77, title I</ref>, §§ 101(a), 106, title II, § 202(d)–(f), <date date="1967-08-31">Aug. 31, 1967</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 178</ref>, 179, 182; <ref>Pub. L. 90–275, § 1(c)</ref>, (d), <date date="1968-03-28">Mar. 28, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 65</ref>, 66; <ref>Pub. L. 91–588</ref>, §§ 1(c), (d), 9(d), <date date="1970-12-24">Dec. 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1581</ref>, 1584; <ref>Pub. L. 92–198, § 1(c)</ref>–(e), <date date="1971-12-15">Dec. 15, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 663</ref>, 664; <ref>Pub. L. 93–177, § 1(c)</ref>, (d), 2, <date date="1973-12-06">Dec. 6, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 695</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–527, § 3</ref>, <date date="1974-12-21">Dec. 21, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1703</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–169, title I</ref>, §§ 101(2)(B), (C), (H), 103, 106(40), <date date="1975-12-23">Dec. 23, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 1013</ref>, 1014, 1016, 1019; <ref>Pub. L. 94–432, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="1976-09-30">Sept. 30, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1370</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–204, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1977-12-02">Dec. 2, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 1456</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–588, title I, § 109(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-04">Nov. 4, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2503</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–25, title III, § 333(b)</ref>, <date date="1991-04-06">Apr. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 88</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–40, title IV, § 402(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-05-07">May 7, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 239</ref>; renumbered § 1541 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–83</ref>, §§ 4(b)(1), (2)(E), 5(a), (c)(1), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 404–406</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–275, title VI, § 608(b)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-13">Oct. 13, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2887</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 926(a)(20)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3830</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1542.</num>
<heading> Children of veterans of a period of war</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall pay to each child (1) who is the child of a deceased veteran of a period of war who met the service requirements prescribed in <ref>section 1521(j) of this title</ref>, or who at the time of death was receiving (or entitled to receive) compensation or retirement pay for a service-connected disability, and (2) who is not in the custody of a surviving spouse eligible for pension under <ref>section 1541 of this title</ref>, pension at the annual rate of $2,020, as increased from time to time under <ref>section 5312 of this title</ref> and reduced by the amount of such child’s annual income; or, if such child is residing with a person who is legally responsible for such child’s support, at an annual rate equal to the amount by which the appropriate annual rate provided under <ref>section 1541(c) of this title</ref> exceeds the sum of the annual income of such child and such person, but in no event may such annual rate of pension exceed the amount by which $2,020, as increased from time to time under <ref>section 5312 of this title</ref>, exceeds the annual income of such child. The appropriate annual rate under such section 1541(c) for the purposes of the preceding sentence shall be determined in accordance with regulations which the Secretary shall prescribe.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–857</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1138</ref>, § 542; <ref>Pub. L. 86–211, § 4</ref>, <date date="1959-08-29">Aug. 29, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 435</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–664, § 4</ref>, <date date="1964-10-13">Oct. 13, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 1095</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–77, title I, § 107</ref>, title II, § 202(g), (h), <date date="1967-08-31">Aug. 31, 1967</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 180</ref>, 182; <ref>Pub. L. 91–588</ref>, §§ 3(c), 9(e), <date date="1970-12-24">Dec. 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1583</ref>, 1585; <ref>Pub. L. 92–198, § 1(f)</ref>, <date date="1971-12-15">Dec. 15, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 664</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–177, § 3</ref>, <date date="1973-12-06">Dec. 6, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 695</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–527, § 4</ref>, <date date="1974-12-21">Dec. 21, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1703</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–169, title I</ref>, §§ 101(2)(D), 104, <date date="1975-12-23">Dec. 23, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 1014</ref>, 1016; <ref>Pub. L. 94–432, title II, § 204</ref>, <date date="1976-09-30">Sept. 30, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1371</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–204, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1977-12-02">Dec. 2, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 1457</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–588, title I, § 110(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-04">Nov. 4, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2504</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–40, title IV, § 402(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-05-07">May 7, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 239</ref>; renumbered § 1542 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–83</ref>, §§ 4(b)(1), (2)(E), 5(a), (c)(1), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 404–406</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–275, title VI, § 608(c)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-13">Oct. 13, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2887</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1543.</num>
<heading> Net worth limitation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall deny or discontinue payment of pension to a surviving spouse under <ref>section 1541 of this title</ref> when the corpus of the estate of the surviving spouse is such that under all the circumstances, including consideration of the income of the surviving spouse and the income of any child from whom the surviving spouse is receiving increased pension, it is reasonable that some part of the corpus of such estate be consumed for the surviving spouse’s maintenance.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall deny or discontinue the payment of increased pension under subsection (c), (d), or (e) of <ref>section 1541 of this title</ref> on account of a child when the corpus of such child’s estate is such that under all the circumstances, including consideration of the income of the surviving spouse and such child and the income of any other child for whom the surviving spouse is receiving increased pension, it is reasonable that some part of the corpus of the child’s estate be consumed for the child’s maintenance. During the period such denial or discontinuance remains in effect, such child shall not be considered as the surviving spouse’s child for purposes of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall deny or discontinue payment of pension to a child under <ref>section 1542 of this title</ref> when the corpus of the estate of the child is such that under all the circumstances, including consideration of the income of the child, the income of any person with whom such child is residing who is legally responsible for such child’s support, and the corpus of the estate of such person, it is reasonable that some part of the corpus of such estates be consumed for the child’s maintenance.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–857</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1138</ref>, § 543; <ref>Pub. L. 86–211, § 4</ref>, <date date="1959-08-29">Aug. 29, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 435</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–169, title I, § 101(2)(E)</ref>, <date date="1975-12-23">Dec. 23, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 1014</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–588, title I, § 111</ref>, <date date="1978-11-04">Nov. 4, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2504</ref>; renumbered § 1543 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–83</ref>, §§ 4(b)(1), (2)(E), 5(a), (c)(1), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 404–406</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</level>
<level>
<heading class="small-caps">[Surviving Spouses of Veterans of All Periods of War—Repealed]</heading>
<section>
<num>[§ 1544.</num>
<heading> Vacant]</heading>
</section>
</level>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>ARMY, NAVY, AIR FORCE, AND COAST GUARD MEDAL OF HONOR ROLL</heading>
<section>
<num>[§§ 1560, 1561.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title V, § 563(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 768</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1562.</num>
<heading> Special provisions relating to pension</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall pay monthly to each living person whose name has been entered on the Army, Navy, Air Force, and Coast Guard Medal of Honor Roll, and a copy of whose certificate has been delivered to the Secretary under subsection (d) of <ref>section 1134a of title 10</ref>, a special pension at the rate of $1,406.73, as adjusted from time to time under subsection (e),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002024">1</ref> beginning as of the date on which the person’s name is entered on the Army, Navy, Air Force, and Coast Guard Medal of Honor Roll under subsection (b) of such section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Except as provided in subparagraphs (B) and (C), the Secretary shall pay special pension under this section to the surviving spouse of a person whose name has been entered on the Army, Navy, Air Force, and Coast Guard Medal of Honor Roll and a copy of whose certificate has been delivered to the Secretary under <ref>section 1134a(d) of title 10</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> No special pension shall be paid to a surviving spouse of a person under this section unless such surviving spouse was married to such person—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> for one year or more prior to the veteran’s death; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> for any period of time if a child was born of the marriage, or was born to them before the marriage.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> No special pension shall be paid to a surviving spouse of a person under this section if such surviving spouse is receiving benefits under section 1311 or 1318 of this title.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The receipt of special pension shall not deprive any person of any other pension or other benefit, right, or privilege to which such person is or may hereafter be entitled under any existing or subsequent law. Special pension shall be paid in addition to all other payments under laws of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Special pension shall not be subject to any attachment, execution, levy, tax lien, or detention under any process whatever.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> If any person has been awarded more than one medal of honor, or married to more than one person who has been awarded a medal of honor, such person shall not receive more than one special pension.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> Effective as of December 1 each year, the Secretary shall increase the amount of monthly special pension payable under subsection (a) as of November 30 of such year by the same percentage as the percentage by which benefit amounts payable under title II of the Social Security Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 401</ref> et seq.) are increased effective December 1 of such year as a result of a determination under section 215(i) of that Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 415(i)</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall pay, in a lump sum, to each person who is in receipt of special pension payable under paragraph (1) of subsection (a), or under paragraph (2) of such subsection in the case of a posthumous entry on the Army, Navy, Air Force, and Coast Guard Medal of Honor Roll, an amount equal to the total amount of special pension that the person would have received during the period beginning on the first day of the first month beginning after the date of the act for which the person was awarded the Medal of Honor and ending on the last day of the month preceding the month in which the person’s special pension in fact commenced.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> For each month of a period referred to in paragraph (1), the amount of special pension payable to a person shall be determined using the rate of special pension that was in effect for such month, and shall be payable only if the person would have been entitled to payment of special pension for such month under laws for eligibility for special pension (with the exception of the eligibility law requiring a person to have been awarded a Medal of Honor) in effect at the beginning of such month.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A person who is entitled to special pension under subsection (a) may elect not to receive special pension by notifying the Secretary of such election in writing.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Upon receipt of an election made by a person under paragraph (1) not to receive special pension, the Secretary shall cease payments of special pension to the person.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–857</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1140</ref>, § 562; <ref>Pub. L. 87–138, § 3</ref>, <date date="1961-08-14">Aug. 14, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 339</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–77, § 5(2)</ref>, <date date="1963-07-25">July 25, 1963</date>, <ref>77 Stat. 95</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–169, title I, § 106(44)</ref>, (45), <date date="1975-12-23">Dec. 23, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 1019</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–479, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="1978-10-18">Oct. 18, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1565</ref>; renumbered § 1562 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–83</ref>, §§ 4(b)(1), (2)(E), 5(a), (c)(1), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 404–406</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–161, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1967</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–368, title III, § 301(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-11">Nov. 11, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3332</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–330, title III, § 304(a)</ref>–(c), <date date="2002-12-06">Dec. 6, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2826</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title V, § 563(b)</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 767</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–315, title II, § 2003(a)</ref>–(b)(2)(A), <date date="2021-01-05">Jan. 5, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4969</ref>, 4970; <ref>Pub. L. 117–328, div. U, title IV, § 407(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 5495</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>