<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 41—</num>
<heading>JOB COUNSELING, TRAINING, AND PLACEMENT SERVICE FOR VETERANS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4100.</num>
<heading> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress makes the following findings:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> As long as unemployment and underemployment continue as serious problems among disabled veterans and Vietnam-era veterans, alleviating unemployment and underemployment among such veterans is a national responsibility.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Because of the special nature of employment and training needs of such veterans and the national responsibility to meet those needs, policies and programs to increase opportunities for such veterans to obtain employment, job training, counseling, and job placement services and assistance in securing advancement in employment should be effectively and vigorously implemented by the Secretary of Labor and such implementation should be accomplished through the Assistant Secretary of Labor for Veterans’ Employment and Training.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 97–306, title III, § 301(a)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-14">Oct. 14, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1436</ref>, § 2000; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–323, § 15(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1988-05-20">May 20, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 574</ref>; renumbered § 4100, <ref>Pub. L. 102–83, § 5(a)</ref>, <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 406</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4101.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For the purposes of this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “special disabled veteran” has the same meaning provided in <ref>section 4211(1) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “veteran of the Vietnam era” has the same meaning provided in <ref>section 4211(2) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “disabled veteran” has the same meaning provided in <ref>section 4211(3) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “eligible veteran” has the same meaning provided in <ref>section 4211(4) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> The term “eligible person” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the spouse of any person who died of a service-connected disability,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the spouse of any member of the Armed Forces serving on active duty who, at the time of application for assistance under this chapter, is listed, pursuant to <ref>section 556 of title 37</ref> and regulations issued thereunder, by the Secretary concerned in one or more of the following categories and has been so listed for a total of more than ninety days: (i) missing in action, (ii) captured in line of duty by a hostile force, or (iii) forcibly detained or interned in line of duty by a foreign government or power, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the spouse of any person who has a total disability permanent in nature resulting from a service-connected disability or the spouse of a veteran who died while a disability so evaluated was in existence.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The term “State” means each of the several States of the United States, the District of Columbia, and the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and may include, to the extent determined necessary and feasible, Guam, American Samoa, the Virgin Islands, the Commonwealth of the Northern Marianas Islands, and the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The term “employment service delivery system” means a service delivery system at which or through which labor exchange services, including employment, training, and placement services, are offered in accordance with the Wagner-Peyser Act.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Labor.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> The term “career services” means local employment and training services of the type described in section 134(c)(2) of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–857</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1221</ref>, § 2010; renumbered § 2001, <ref>Pub. L. 87–675, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1962-09-19">Sept. 19, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 558</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 89–358, § 6(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1966-03-03">Mar. 3, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 27</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–540, title V, § 502(a)</ref>, <date date="1972-10-24">Oct. 24, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 1094</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–508, title IV, § 401(a)</ref>, <date date="1974-12-03">Dec. 3, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1592</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–466, title V, § 503</ref>, title VIII, § 801(h), <date date="1980-10-17">Oct. 17, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2203</ref>, 2216; <ref>Pub. L. 100–323</ref>, §§ 3(b), 15(a)(1), <date date="1988-05-20">May 20, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 562</ref>, 574; renumbered § 4101 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–83, § 5(a)</ref>, (c)(1), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 406</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–288, § 5(a)(1)(A)</ref>, (c)(1), <date date="2002-11-07">Nov. 7, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2044</ref>, 2045; <ref>Pub. L. 113–128, title V, § 512(gg)(1)</ref>, <date date="2014-07-22">July 22, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1719</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4102.</num>
<heading> Purpose</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Congress declares as its intent and purpose that there shall be an effective (1) job and job training intensive services program, (2) employment placement service program, and (3) job training placement service program for eligible veterans and eligible persons and that, to this end policies and regulations shall be promulgated and administered by an Assistant Secretary of Labor for Veterans’ Employment and Training, established by <ref>section 4102A of this title</ref>, through a Veterans’ Employment and Training Service within the Department of Labor, so as to provide such veterans and persons the maximum of employment and training opportunities, with priority given to the needs of disabled veterans and veterans who served on active duty during a war or in a campaign or expedition for which a campaign badge has been authorized through existing programs, coordination and merger of programs and implementation of new programs, including programs carried out by the Veterans’ Employment and Training Service to implement all efforts to ease the transition of servicemembers to civilian careers that are consistent with, or an outgrowth of, the military experience of the servicemembers.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–857</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1217</ref>, § 2011; renumbered § 2002, <ref>Pub. L. 87–675, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1962-09-19">Sept. 19, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 558</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 89–358, § 6(c)</ref>, <date date="1966-03-03">Mar. 3, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 27</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–540, title V, § 502(a)</ref>, <date date="1972-10-24">Oct. 24, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 1094</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–508, title IV, § 401(b)</ref>, <date date="1974-12-03">Dec. 3, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1592</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–502, title VI, § 601(a)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-15">Oct. 15, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2404</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–466, title V, § 504(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-17">Oct. 17, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2203</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–306, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="1982-10-14">Oct. 14, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1437</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–160, title VII, § 702(15)</ref>, <date date="1983-11-21">Nov. 21, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 1010</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–323, § 15(b)(1)</ref>, (d), <date date="1988-05-20">May 20, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 574</ref>; renumbered § 4102 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–83, § 5(a)</ref>, (c)(1), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 406</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–288, § 5(a)(1)(B)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="2002-11-07">Nov. 7, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2044</ref>, 2045.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4102A.</num>
<heading> Assistant Secretary of Labor for Veterans’ Employment and Training; program functions; Regional Administrators</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment of Position of Assistant Secretary of Labor for Veterans’ Employment and Training</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> There is established within the Department of Labor an Assistant Secretary of Labor for Veterans’ Employment and Training, appointed by the President by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, who shall formulate and implement all departmental policies and procedures to carry out (A) the purposes of this chapter, chapter 42, and chapter 43 of this title, and (B) all other Department of Labor employment, unemployment, and training programs to the extent they affect veterans.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The employees of the Department of Labor administering chapter 43 of this title shall be administratively and functionally responsible to the Assistant Secretary of Labor for Veterans’ Employment and Training.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> There shall be within the Department of Labor a Deputy Assistant Secretary of Labor for Veterans’ Employment and Training. The Deputy Assistant Secretary shall perform such functions as the Assistant Secretary of Labor for Veterans’ Employment and Training prescribes.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> No individual may be appointed as a Deputy Assistant Secretary of Labor for Veterans’ Employment and Training unless the individual has at least five years of service in a management position as an employee of the Federal civil service or comparable service in a management position in the Armed Forces. For purposes of determining such service of an individual, there shall be excluded any service described in subparagraphs (A), (B), and (C) of <ref>section 308(d)(2) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Program Functions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall carry out the following functions:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as expressly provided otherwise, carry out all provisions of this chapter and chapter 43 of this title through the Assistant Secretary of Labor for Veterans’ Employment and Training and administer through such Assistant Secretary all programs under the jurisdiction of the Secretary for the provision of employment and training services designed to meet the needs of all veterans and persons eligible for services furnished under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In order to make maximum use of available resources in meeting such needs, encourage all such programs, and all grantees and contractors under such programs to enter into cooperative arrangements with private industry and business concerns (including small business concerns owned by veterans or disabled veterans), educational institutions, trade associations, and labor unions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Ensure that maximum effectiveness and efficiency are achieved in providing services and assistance to eligible veterans under all such programs by coordinating and consulting with the Secretary of Veterans Affairs with respect to (A) programs conducted under other provisions of this title, with particular emphasis on coordination of such programs with readjustment counseling activities carried out under <ref>section 1712A of this title</ref>, apprenticeship or other on-the-job training programs carried out under <ref>section 3687 of this title</ref>, and rehabilitation and training activities carried out under chapter 31 of this title and (B) determinations covering veteran population in a State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Ensure that employment, training, and placement activities are carried out in coordination and cooperation with appropriate State public employment service officials.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> Subject to subsection (c), make available for use in each State by grant or contract such funds as may be necessary to support—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> disabled veterans’ outreach program specialists appointed under <ref>section 4103A(a)(1) of this title</ref>,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> local veterans’ employment representatives assigned under <ref>section 4104(b) of this title</ref>, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the reasonable expenses of such specialists and representatives described in subparagraphs (A) and (B), respectively, for training, travel, supplies, and other business expenses, including travel expenses and per diem for attendance at the National Veterans’ Employment and Training Services Institute established under <ref>section 4109 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Monitor and supervise on a continuing basis the distribution and use of funds provided for use in the States under paragraph (5).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Establish, and update as appropriate, a comprehensive performance accountability system (as described in subsection (f)) and carry out annual performance reviews of veterans employment, training, and placement services provided through employment service delivery systems, including through disabled veterans’ outreach program specialists and through local veterans’ employment representatives in States receiving grants, contracts, or awards under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> With advice and assistance from the Advisory Committee on Veterans Employment, Training, and Employer Outreach established under <ref>section 4110 of this title</ref>, furnish information to employers (through meetings in person with hiring executives of corporations and otherwise) with respect to the training and skills of veterans and disabled veterans, and the advantages afforded employers by hiring veterans with such training and skills, and to facilitate employment of veterans and disabled veterans through participation in labor exchanges (Internet-based and otherwise), and other means.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Conditions for Receipt of Funds</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The distribution and use of funds under subsection (b)(5) in order to carry out sections 4103A(a) and 4104(a) of this title shall be subject to the continuing supervision and monitoring of the Secretary and shall not be governed by the provisions of any other law, or any regulations prescribed thereunder, that are inconsistent with this section or section 4103A or 4104 of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> A State shall submit to the Secretary an application for a grant or contract under subsection (b)(5). The application shall contain the following information:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> A plan that describes the manner in which the State shall furnish employment, training, and placement services required under this chapter for the program year, including a description of—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> duties assigned by the State to disabled veterans’ outreach program specialists and local veterans’ employment representatives consistent with the requirements of sections 4103A and 4104 of this title;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the manner in which such specialists and representatives are integrated in the employment service delivery systems in the State; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> the program of performance incentive awards described in <ref>section 4112 of this title</ref> in the State for the program year.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The veteran population to be served.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> For each employee of the State who is assigned to perform the duties of a disabled veterans’ outreach program specialist or a local veterans’ employment representative under this chapter—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the date on which the employee is so assigned; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> whether the employee has satisfactorily completed such training by the National Veterans’ Employment and Training Services Institute as the Secretary requires for purposes of paragraph (8).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> Such additional information as the Secretary may require to make a determination with respect to awarding a grant or contract to the State.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> Subject to the succeeding provisions of this subparagraph, of the amount available under subsection (b)(5) for a fiscal year, the Secretary shall make available to each State with an application approved by the Secretary an amount of funding in proportion to the number of veterans seeking employment using such criteria as the Secretary may establish in regulation, including civilian labor force and unemployment data, for the State on an annual basis. The proportion of funding shall reflect the ratio of—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent1">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the total number of veterans residing in the State that are seeking employment; to</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent1">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the total number of veterans seeking employment in all States.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall phase in over the three fiscal-year period that begins on <date date="2003-10-01">October 1, 2003</date>, the manner in which amounts are made available to States under subsection (b)(5) and this subsection, as amended by the Jobs for Veterans Act.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> In carrying out this paragraph, the Secretary may establish minimum funding levels and hold-harmless criteria for States.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> As a condition of a grant or contract under this section for a program year, in the case of a State that the Secretary determines has an entered-employment rate for veterans that is deficient for the preceding program year, the State shall develop a corrective action plan to improve that rate for veterans in the State.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The State shall submit the corrective action plan to the Secretary for approval, and if approved, shall expeditiously implement the plan.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> If the Secretary does not approve a corrective action plan submitted by the State under clause (i), the Secretary shall take such steps as may be necessary to implement corrective actions in the State to improve the entered-employment rate for veterans in that State.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> To carry out subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall establish in regulations a uniform national threshold entered-employment rate for veterans for a program year by which determinations of deficiency may be made under subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> In making a determination with respect to a deficiency under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall take into account the applicable annual unemployment data for the State and consider other factors, such as prevailing economic conditions, that affect performance of individuals providing employment, training, and placement services in the State.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> In determining the terms and conditions of a grant or contract under which funds are made available to a State in order to carry out section 4103A or 4104 of this title, the Secretary shall take into account—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the results of reviews, carried out pursuant to subsection (b)(7), of the performance of the employment, training, and placement service delivery system in the State, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the monitoring carried out under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> Each grant or contract by which funds are made available to a State shall contain a provision requiring the recipient of the funds—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to comply with the provisions of this chapter; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> on an annual basis, to notify the Secretary of, and provide supporting rationale for, each nonveteran who is employed as a disabled veterans’ outreach program specialist and local veterans’ employment representative for a period in excess of 6 months.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Each State shall coordinate employment, training, and placement services furnished to veterans and eligible persons under this chapter with such services furnished with respect to such veterans and persons under the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002084">1</ref> and the Wagner-Peyser Act.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Of the amount of a grant or contract under which funds are made available to a State in order to carry out section 4103A or 4104 of this title for any program year, one percent shall be for the purposes of making cash awards under the program of performance incentive awards described in <ref>section 4112 of this title</ref> in the State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(8)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> As a condition of a grant or contract under which funds are made available to a State in order to carry out section 4103A or 4104 of this title, the Secretary shall require the State to require each employee hired by the State who is assigned to perform the duties of a disabled veterans’ outreach program specialist or a local veterans’ employment representative under this chapter to satisfactorily complete training provided by the National Veterans’ Employment and Training Services Institute during the 18-month period that begins on the date on which the employee is so assigned.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> For any employee described in subparagraph (A) who does not complete such training during such period, the Secretary may reduce by an appropriate amount the amount made available to the State employing that employee.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The Secretary may establish such reasonable exceptions to the completion of training otherwise required under subparagraph (A) as the Secretary considers appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(9)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> As a condition of a grant or contract under which funds are made available to a State in order to carry out section 4103A or 4104 of this title for any program year, the Secretary may require the State—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> to demonstrate that when the State approves or denies a certification or license described in subparagraph (B) for a veteran the State takes into consideration any training received or experience gained by the veteran while serving on active duty in the Armed Forces; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> to disclose to the Secretary in writing the following:</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> Criteria applicants must satisfy to receive a certification or license described in subparagraph (B) by the State.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> A description of the standard practices of the State for evaluating training received by veterans while serving on active duty in the Armed Forces and evaluating the documented work experience of such veterans during such service for purposes of approving or denying a certification or license described in subparagraph (B).</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> Identification of areas in which training and experience described in subclause (II) fails to meet criteria described in subclause (I).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> A certification or license described in this subparagraph is any of the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> A license to be a nonemergency medical professional.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> A license to be an emergency medical professional.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> A commercial driver’s license.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall share the information the Secretary receives under subparagraph (A)(ii) with the Secretary of Defense to help the Secretary of Defense improve training for military occupational specialties so that individuals who receive such training are able to receive a certification or license described in subparagraph (B) from a State.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary shall publish on the Internet website of the Department available to the public—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any guidance the Secretary gives the Secretary of Defense with respect to carrying out this section; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any information the Secretary receives from a State pursuant to subparagraph (A).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Participation in Other Federally Funded Job Training Programs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Assistant Secretary of Labor for Veterans’ Employment and Training shall promote and monitor participation of qualified veterans and eligible persons in employment and training opportunities under title I of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act and other federally funded employment and training programs.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regional Administrators</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall assign to each region for which the Secretary operates a regional office a representative of the Veterans’ Employment and Training Service to serve as the Regional Administrator for Veterans’ Employment and Training in such region.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Each such Regional Administrator shall carry out such duties as the Secretary may require to promote veterans employment and reemployment within the region that the Administrator serves.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment of Performance Standards and Outcomes Measures</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Assistant Secretary of Labor for Veterans’ Employment and Training shall establish and implement a comprehensive performance accountability system to measure the performance of employment service delivery systems, including disabled veterans’ outreach program specialists and local veterans’ employment representatives providing employment, training, and placement services under this chapter in a State to provide accountability of that State to the Secretary for purposes of subsection (c).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Such standards and measures shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> be consistent with State performance accountability measures applicable under section 116(b) of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> be appropriately weighted to provide special consideration for placement of (i) veterans requiring intensive services (as defined in <ref>section 4101(9) of this title</ref>), such as special disabled veterans and disabled veterans, and (ii) veterans who enroll in readjustment counseling under <ref>section 1712A of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority to Provide Technical Assistance to States</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may provide such technical assistance as the Secretary determines appropriate to any State that the Secretary determines has, or may have, an entered-employment rate in the State that is deficient, as determined under subsection (c)(3) with respect to a program year, including assistance in the development of a corrective action plan under that subsection.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consolidation of Disabled Veterans’ Outreach Program Specialists and Veterans’ Employment Representatives</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary may allow the Governor of a State receiving funds under subsection (b)(5) to support specialists and representatives as described in such subsection to consolidate the functions of such specialists and representatives if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the Governor determines, and the Secretary concurs, that such consolidation—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> promotes a more efficient administration of services to veterans with a particular emphasis on services to disabled veterans; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> does not hinder the provision of services to veterans and employers; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Governor submits to the Secretary a proposal therefor at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 94–502, title VI, § 601(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-15">Oct. 15, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2404</ref>, § 2002A; amended <ref>Pub. L. 96–466, title V, § 504(a)(3)</ref>, (4), <date date="1980-10-17">Oct. 17, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2203</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–306, title III, § 303</ref>, <date date="1982-10-14">Oct. 14, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1437</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–160, title VII, § 702(15)</ref>, <date date="1983-11-21">Nov. 21, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 1010</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–323</ref>, §§ 2(a), (e)(3)(A), 15(a)(2), (b)(1), <date date="1988-05-20">May 20, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 556</ref>, 559, 574; <ref>Pub. L. 101–237, title IV, § 423(b)(8)(A)</ref>, <date date="1989-12-18">Dec. 18, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 2093</ref>; renumbered § 4102A and amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–83</ref>, §§ 4(b)(1), (2)(E), 5(a), (c)(1), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 404–406</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–446, title VII, § 701(a)</ref>, title XII, § 1201(a)(4), <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4674</ref>, 4682; <ref>Pub. L. 104–275, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="1996-10-09">Oct. 9, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3332</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. A, § 101(f) [title VIII, § 405(d)(29)(A), (f)(21)(A)]</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–337</ref>, 2681–424, 2681–432; <ref>Pub. L. 105–368, title X, § 1005(b)(13)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-11">Nov. 11, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3365</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–288, § 4(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-07">Nov. 7, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2038</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–183, title VII, § 708(b)(1)(A)</ref>, (2), <date date="2003-12-16">Dec. 16, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2673</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–233, title II, § 201</ref>, title V, § 503(11), <date date="2006-06-15">June 15, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 402</ref>, 416; <ref>Pub. L. 109–461, title VI, § 601(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2006-12-22">Dec. 22, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3436</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–275, title I, § 103(a)</ref>, title X, § 1001(k), <date date="2010-10-13">Oct. 13, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2866</ref>, 2897; <ref>Pub. L. 112–56, title II, § 241(c)</ref>, <date date="2011-11-21">Nov. 21, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 728</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title V, § 544(a)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1737</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–128, title V, § 512(gg)(2)</ref>, <date date="2014-07-22">July 22, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1719</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–58, title VI, § 601(20)</ref>, <date date="2015-09-30">Sept. 30, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 539</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4103.</num>
<heading> Directors and Assistant Directors for Veterans’ Employment and Training; additional Federal personnel</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Directors and Assistant Directors</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall assign to each State a representative of the Veterans’ Employment and Training Service to serve as the Director for Veterans’ Employment and Training, and shall assign full-time Federal clerical or other support personnel to each such Director.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Each Director for Veterans’ Employment and Training for a State shall, at the time of appointment, have been a bona fide resident of the State for at least two years.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Secretary may waive the requirement in subparagraph (A) with respect to a Director for Veterans’ Employment and Training if the Secretary determines that the waiver is in the public interest. Any such waiver shall be made on a case-by-case basis.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Full-time Federal clerical or other support personnel assigned to Directors for Veterans’ Employment and Training shall be appointed in accordance with the provisions of title 5 governing appointments in the competitive service and shall be paid in accordance with the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Additional Federal Personnel</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may also assign as supervisory personnel such representatives of the Veterans’ Employment and Training Service as the Secretary determines appropriate to carry out the employment, training, and placement services required under this chapter, including Assistant Directors for Veterans’ Employment and Training.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Coordination With State Departments of Labor and Veterans Affairs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each Director for Veterans’ Employment and Training for a State shall coordinate the Director’s activities under this chapter with the State department of labor and the State department of veterans affairs.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–857</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1218</ref>, § 2012; renumbered § 2003, <ref>Pub. L. 87–675, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1962-09-19">Sept. 19, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 558</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 89–358, § 6(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1966-03-03">Mar. 3, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 27</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–540, title V, § 502(a)</ref>, <date date="1972-10-24">Oct. 24, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 1094</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–508, title IV, § 401(c)</ref>, <date date="1974-12-03">Dec. 3, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1592</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–502, title VI</ref>, §§ 602, 606(1), <date date="1976-10-15">Oct. 15, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2404</ref>, 2405; <ref>Pub. L. 96–466, title V, § 505</ref>, title VIII, § 801(i), <date date="1980-10-17">Oct. 17, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2204</ref>, 2216; <ref>Pub. L. 97–295, § 4(70)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-12">Oct. 12, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1310</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–306, title III, § 304(a)(1)</ref>, (b), (c), <date date="1982-10-14">Oct. 14, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1437</ref>, 1438; <ref>Pub. L. 100–323</ref>, §§ 5, 7(a), 15(a)(2), (c)(1), (3)(A), <date date="1988-05-20">May 20, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 563</ref>, 564, 574; <ref>Pub. L. 101–237, title IV, § 423(b)(8)(B)</ref>, <date date="1989-12-18">Dec. 18, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 2093</ref>; renumbered § 4103 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–83, § 5(a)</ref>, (c)(1), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 406</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–446, title XII, § 1201(d)(14)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4684</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–275, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="1996-10-09">Oct. 9, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3332</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–288, § 4(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-07">Nov. 7, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2042</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–389, title III, § 316</ref>, <date date="2008-10-10">Oct. 10, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4167</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–315, title V, § 504(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1568</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4103A.</num>
<heading> Disabled veterans’ outreach program</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirement for Employment by States of a Sufficient Number of Specialists</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Subject to approval by the Secretary, a State shall employ such full- or part-time disabled veterans’ outreach program specialists as the State determines appropriate and efficient to carry out intensive services and facilitate placements under this chapter to meet the employment needs of eligible veterans with the following priority in the provision of services:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Special disabled veterans.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Other disabled veterans.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Other eligible veterans in accordance with priorities determined by the Secretary taking into account applicable rates of unemployment and the employment emphases set forth in chapter 42 of this title.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In the provision of services in accordance with this subsection, maximum emphasis in meeting the employment needs of veterans shall be placed on assisting economically or educationally disadvantaged veterans.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> In facilitating placement of a veteran under this program, a disabled veterans’ outreach program specialist shall help to identify job opportunities that are appropriate for the veteran’s employment goals and assist that veteran in developing a cover letter and resume that are targeted for those particular jobs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirement for Qualified Veterans</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A State shall, to the maximum extent practicable, employ qualified veterans to carry out the services referred to in subsection (a). Preference shall be given in the appointment of such specialists to qualified disabled veterans.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Part-Time Employees</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A part-time disabled veterans’ outreach program specialist shall perform the functions of a disabled veterans’ outreach program specialist under this section on a half-time basis.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Additional Requirement for Full-time Employees</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A full-time disabled veterans’ outreach program specialist shall perform only duties related to meeting the employment needs of eligible veterans, as described in subsection (a), and shall not perform other non-veteran-related duties that detract from the specialist’s ability to perform the specialist’s duties related to meeting the employment needs of eligible veterans.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall conduct regular audits to ensure compliance with paragraph (1). If, on the basis of such an audit, the Secretary determines that a State is not in compliance with paragraph (1), the Secretary may reduce the amount of a grant made to the State under <ref>section 4102A(b)(5) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–466, title V, § 506(a)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-17">Oct. 17, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2204</ref>, § 2003A; amended <ref>Pub. L. 97–306, title III, § 305</ref>, <date date="1982-10-14">Oct. 14, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1439</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–323</ref>, §§ 2(e)(1), 7(b), 15(c)(1), <date date="1988-05-20">May 20, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 559</ref>, 565, 574; <ref>Pub. L. 101–237, title IV, § 423(b)(8)</ref>, <date date="1989-12-18">Dec. 18, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 2093</ref>; renumbered § 4103A and amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–83</ref>, §§ 2(c)(4), 5(a), (c)(1), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 402</ref>, 406; <ref>Pub. L. 102–568, title V</ref>, §§ 501, 503, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4340</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–446, title VII, § 701(b)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4674</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. A, § 101(f) [title VIII, § 405(d)(29)(B), (f)(21)(B)]</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–337</ref>, 2681–424, 2681–432; <ref>Pub. L. 105–368, title X, § 1004(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-11">Nov. 11, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3364</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–95, § 9(a)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-21">Dec. 21, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 920</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–288, § 4(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-07">Nov. 7, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2043</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–461, title VI, § 602(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-22">Dec. 22, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3437</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–56, title II</ref>, §§ 234(b), 241(a), <date date="2011-11-21">Nov. 21, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 722</ref>, 728.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4104.</num>
<heading> Local veterans’ employment representatives</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirement for Employment by States of a Sufficient Number of Representatives</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to approval by the Secretary, a State shall employ such full- and part-time local veterans’ employment representatives as the State determines appropriate and efficient to carry out employment, training, and placement services under this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Principal Duties</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>As principal duties, local veterans’ employment representatives shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> conduct outreach to employers in the area to assist veterans in gaining employment, including conducting seminars for employers and, in conjunction with employers, conducting job search workshops and establishing job search groups; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> facilitate employment, training, and placement services furnished to veterans in a State under the applicable State employment service delivery systems.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirement for Qualified Veterans and Eligible Persons</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A State shall, to the maximum extent practicable, employ qualified veterans or eligible persons to carry out the services referred to in subsection (a). Preference shall be accorded in the following order:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> To qualified service-connected disabled veterans.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If no veteran described in paragraph (1) is available, to qualified eligible veterans.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> If no veteran described in paragraph (1) or (2) is available, then to qualified eligible persons.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Part-Time Employees</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A part-time local veterans’ employment representative shall perform the functions of a local veterans’ employment representative under this section on a half-time basis.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Additional Requirements for Full-time Employees</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A full-time local veterans’ employment representative shall perform only duties related to the employment, training, and placement services under this chapter, and shall not perform other non-veteran-related duties that detract from the representative’s ability to perform the representative’s duties related to employment, training, and placement services under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall conduct regular audits to ensure compliance with paragraph (1). If, on the basis of such an audit, the Secretary determines that a State is not in compliance with paragraph (1), the Secretary may reduce the amount of a grant made to the State under <ref>section 4102A(b)(5) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reporting</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each local veterans’ employment representative shall be administratively responsible to the manager of the employment service delivery system and shall provide reports, not less frequently than quarterly, to the manager of such office and to the Director for Veterans’ Employment and Training for the State regarding compliance with Federal law and regulations with respect to special services and priorities for eligible veterans and eligible persons.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–857</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1219</ref>, § 2013; renumbered § 2004, <ref>Pub. L. 87–675, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1962-09-19">Sept. 19, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 558</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 89–358, § 6(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1966-03-03">Mar. 3, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 27</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–540, title V, § 502(a)</ref>, <date date="1972-10-24">Oct. 24, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 1095</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–502, title VI, § 606(2)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-15">Oct. 15, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2405</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–323, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-05-20">May 20, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 560</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–237, title IV, § 423(b)(8)(B)</ref>, <date date="1989-12-18">Dec. 18, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 2093</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–16, § 10(a)(8)</ref>, <date date="1991-03-22">Mar. 22, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 56</ref>; renumbered § 4104 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–83, § 5(a)</ref>, (c)(1), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 406</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–14, § 8(a)(10)</ref>, <date date="2001-06-05">June 5, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 35</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–95, § 9(b)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-21">Dec. 21, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 920</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–288, § 4(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-07">Nov. 7, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2043</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–461, title VI, § 602(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-22">Dec. 22, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3437</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–56, title II, § 241(b)</ref>, <date date="2011-11-21">Nov. 21, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 728</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4104A.</num>
<heading> Collaborative veterans’ training, mentoring, and placement program</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Grants</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall award grants to eligible nonprofit organizations to provide training and mentoring for eligible veterans who seek employment. The Secretary shall award the grants to not more than three organizations, for periods of two years.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Collaboration and Facilitation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall ensure that the recipients of the grants—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> collaborate with—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the appropriate disabled veterans’ outreach specialists (in carrying out the functions described in section 4103A(a)) and the appropriate local veterans’ employment representatives (in carrying out the functions described in section 4104); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the appropriate State boards and local boards (as such terms are defined in section 3 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act) for the areas to be served by recipients of the grants; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> based on the collaboration, facilitate the placement of the veterans that complete the training in meaningful employment that leads to economic self-sufficiency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Application</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, a nonprofit organization shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require. At a minimum, the information shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> information describing how the organization will—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> collaborate with disabled veterans’ outreach specialists and local veterans’ employment representatives and the appropriate State boards and local boards (as such terms are defined in section 3 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> based on the collaboration, provide training that facilitates the placement described in subsection (b)(2); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> make available, for each veteran receiving the training, a mentor to provide career advice to the veteran and assist the veteran in preparing a resume and developing job interviewing skills; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an assurance that the organization will provide the information necessary for the Secretary to prepare the reports described in subsection (d).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reports</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Not later than six months after the date of the enactment of the VOW to Hire Heroes Act of 2011, the Secretary shall prepare and submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report that describes the process for awarding grants under this section, the recipients of the grants, and the collaboration described in subsections (b) and (c).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of the VOW to Hire Heroes Act of 2011, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> conduct an assessment of the performance of the grant recipients, disabled veterans’ outreach specialists, and local veterans’ employment representatives in carrying out activities under this section, which assessment shall include collecting information on the number of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> veterans who applied for training under this section;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> veterans who entered the training;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> veterans who completed the training;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> veterans who were placed in meaningful employment under this section; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> veterans who remained in such employment as of the date of the assessment; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report that includes—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a description of how the grant recipients used the funds made available under this section;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the results of the assessment conducted under subparagraph (A); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the recommendations of the Secretary as to whether amounts should be appropriated to carry out this section for fiscal years after 2013.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authorization of Appropriations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $4,500,000 for the period consisting of fiscal years 2012 and 2013.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the term “appropriate committees of Congress” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pension of the Senate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs and the Committee on Education and Workforce <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002085">1</ref> of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “nonprofit organization” means an organization that is described in section 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and that is exempt from taxation under section 501(a) of such Code.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 112–56, title II, § 234(a)</ref>, <date date="2011-11-21">Nov. 21, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 721</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 113–128, title V, § 512(gg)(3)</ref>, <date date="2014-07-22">July 22, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1719</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4105.</num>
<heading> Cooperation of Federal agencies</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> All Federal agencies shall furnish the Secretary such records, statistics, or information as the Secretary may deem necessary or appropriate in administering the provisions of this chapter, and shall otherwise cooperate with the Secretary in providing continuous employment and training opportunities for eligible veterans and eligible persons.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> For the purpose of assisting the Secretary and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs in identifying employers with potential job training opportunities under the Veterans’ Job Training Act (<ref>Public Law 98–77</ref>; <ref>29 U.S.C. 1721</ref> note) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002086">1</ref> and otherwise in order to carry out this chapter, the Secretary of Defense shall, on the 15th day of each month, provide the Secretary and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs with updated information regarding any list maintained by the Secretary of Defense of employers participating in the National Committee for Employer Support of the Guard and Reserve.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–857</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1219</ref>, § 2014; renumbered § 2005 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 87–675, § 1(a)</ref>, (c), <date date="1962-09-19">Sept. 19, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 558</ref>, 559; <ref>Pub. L. 92–540, title V, § 502(a)</ref>, <date date="1972-10-24">Oct. 24, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 1095</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–508, title IV, § 401(d)</ref>, <date date="1974-12-03">Dec. 3, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1592</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–502, title VI, § 606(3)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-15">Oct. 15, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2405</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–323</ref>, §§ 6(a), 15(a)(2), <date date="1988-05-20">May 20, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 564</ref>, 574; <ref>Pub. L. 101–237, title IV, § 423(b)(8)(A)</ref>, <date date="1989-12-18">Dec. 18, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 2093</ref>; renumbered § 4105, <ref>Pub. L. 102–83, § 5(a)</ref>, <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 406</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–233, title V, § 503(12)</ref>, <date date="2006-06-15">June 15, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 417</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4106.</num>
<heading> Estimate of funds for administration; authorization of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall estimate the funds necessary for the proper and efficient administration of this chapter and chapters 42 and 43 of this title. Such estimated sums shall include the annual amounts necessary for salaries, rents, printing and binding, travel, and communications. Sums thus estimated shall be included as a special item in the annual budget for the Department of Labor. Estimated funds necessary for proper intensive services, placement, and training services to eligible veterans and eligible persons provided by the various State public employment service agencies shall each be separately identified in the budgets of those agencies as approved by the Department of Labor. Funds estimated pursuant to the first sentence of this subsection shall include amounts necessary in all of the States for the purposes specified in paragraph (5) of <ref>section 4102A(b) of this title</ref> and to fund the National Veterans’ Employment and Training Services Institute under <ref>section 4109 of this title</ref> and shall be approved by the Secretary only if the level of funding proposed is in compliance with such sections. Each budget submission with respect to such funds shall include a separate listing of the amount for the National Veterans’ Employment and Training Services Institute together with information demonstrating the compliance of such budget submission with the funding requirements specified in the preceding sentence.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for the proper and efficient administration of this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> In the event that the regular appropriations Act making appropriations for administrative expenses for the Department of Labor with respect to any fiscal year does not specify an amount for the purposes specified in subsection (b) of this section for that fiscal year, then of the amounts appropriated in such Act there shall be available only for the purposes specified in subsection (b) of this section such amount as was set forth in the budget estimate submitted pursuant to subsection (a) of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Any funds made available pursuant to subsections (b) and (c) of this section shall not be available for any purpose other than those specified in such subsections.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 92–540, title V, § 502(a)</ref>, <date date="1972-10-24">Oct. 24, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 1096</ref>, § 2006; amended <ref>Pub. L. 93–508, title IV, § 401(e)</ref>, <date date="1974-12-03">Dec. 3, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1592</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–502, title VI, § 603</ref>, <date date="1976-10-15">Oct. 15, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2404</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–306, title III, § 306</ref>, <date date="1982-10-14">Oct. 14, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1440</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–323</ref>, §§ 2(b), (c), (e)(2), 15(a)(2), <date date="1988-05-20">May 20, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 558</ref>, 559, 574; renumbered § 4106 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–83, § 5(a)</ref>, (c)(1), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 406</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–288</ref>, §§ 4(d)(1), 5(a)(1)(C), <date date="2002-11-07">Nov. 7, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2044</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4107.</num>
<heading> Administrative controls; annual report</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary shall establish administrative controls for the following purposes:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> To insure that each eligible veteran, especially veterans of the Vietnam era and disabled veterans, and each eligible person who requests assistance under this chapter shall promptly be placed in a satisfactory job or job training opportunity or receive some other specific form of assistance designed to enhance such veteran’s and eligible person’s employment prospects substantially, such as individual job development or intensive services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> To determine whether or not the employment service agencies in each State have committed the necessary staff to insure that the provisions of this chapter are carried out; and to arrange for necessary corrective action where staff resources have been determined by the Secretary to be inadequate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall apply performance standards established under <ref>section 4102A(f) of this title</ref> for determining compliance by the State public employment service agencies with the provisions of this chapter and chapter 42 of this title. Not later than February 1 of each year, the Secretary shall report to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the House of Representatives on the performance of States and organizations and entities carrying out employment, training, and placement services under this chapter, as measured under subsection (b)(7) of <ref>section 4102A of this title</ref>. In the case of a State that the Secretary determines has not met the minimum standard of performance (established by the Secretary under subsection (f) of such section), the Secretary shall include an analysis of the extent and reasons for the State’s failure to meet that minimum standard, together with the State’s plan for corrective action during the succeeding year.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> Not later than February 1 of each year, the Secretary shall report to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the House of Representatives on the success during the preceding program year of the Department of Labor and its affiliated State employment service agencies in carrying out the provisions of this chapter and programs for the provision of employment and training services to meet the needs of eligible veterans and eligible persons. The report shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> specification, by State and by age group, of the numbers of eligible veterans, disabled veterans, special disabled veterans, eligible persons, recently separated veterans (as defined in <ref>section 4211(6) of this title</ref>), and servicemembers transitioning to civilian careers who registered for assistance with, or who are identified as veterans by, the public employment service system and, for each of such categories, the numbers referred to and placed in permanent and other jobs, the numbers referred to and placed in jobs and job training programs supported by the Federal Government, the number who received intensive services, and the number who received some, and the number who received no, reportable service;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a comparison of the rate of entered employment (as determined in a manner consistent with State performance measures applicable under section 136(b) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002087">1</ref> of the Workforce Investment Act of 1998) for each of the categories of veterans and persons described in paragraph (1) of this subsection with such rate of entered employment (as so determined) for nonveterans of the same age groups registered for assistance with the public employment system in each State;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> any determination made by the Secretary during the preceding fiscal year under <ref>section 4106 of this title</ref> or subsection (a)(2) of this section and a statement of the reasons for such determination;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> a report on activities carried out during the preceding program year under <ref>section 4212(d) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> a report on the operation during the preceding program year of programs for the provision of employment and training services designed to meet the needs of eligible veterans and eligible persons, including an evaluation of the effectiveness of such programs during such program year in meeting the requirements of <ref>section 4102A(b) of this title</ref>, the efficiency with which services were provided through such programs during such year, and such recommendations for further legislative action relating to veterans’ employment and training as the Secretary considers appropriate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> a report on the operation during the preceding program year of the program of performance incentive awards for quality employment services under <ref>section 4112 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<chapeau> performance measures for the provision of assistance under this chapter, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the percentage of participants in programs under this chapter who find employment before the end of the first 90-day period following their completion of the program;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the percentage of participants described in subparagraph (A) who are employed during the first 180-day period following the period described in such subparagraph;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the median earnings of participants described in subparagraph (A) during the period described in such subparagraph;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the median earnings of participants described in subparagraph (B) during the period described in such subparagraph; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the percentage of participants in programs under this chapter who obtain a certificate, degree, diploma, licensure, or industry-recognized credential relating to the program in which they participated under this chapter during the third 90-day period following their completion of the program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 92–540, title V, § 502(a)</ref>, <date date="1972-10-24">Oct. 24, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 1096</ref>, § 2007; amended <ref>Pub. L. 93–508, title IV, § 401(f)</ref>, <date date="1974-12-03">Dec. 3, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1592</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–502, title VI, § 604</ref>, <date date="1976-10-15">Oct. 15, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2404</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–202, title III, § 309(b)</ref>, <date date="1977-11-23">Nov. 23, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 1446</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–466, title V, § 507</ref>, <date date="1980-10-17">Oct. 17, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2205</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–306, title III, § 307</ref>, <date date="1982-10-14">Oct. 14, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1440</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–323</ref>, §§ 2(d), 15(a)(2), <date date="1988-05-20">May 20, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 558</ref>, 574; renumbered § 4107 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–83, § 5(a)</ref>, (c)(1), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 406</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–288</ref>, §§ 4(a)(3)(B), (e)(1), 5(a)(1)(D), (E), (d)(1), <date date="2002-11-07">Nov. 7, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2042</ref>, 2044, 2045; <ref>Pub. L. 112–56, title II, § 238</ref>, <date date="2011-11-21">Nov. 21, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 726</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4108.</num>
<heading> Cooperation and coordination</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> In carrying out the Secretary’s responsibilities under this chapter, the Secretary shall from time to time consult with the Secretary of Veterans Affairs and keep the Secretary of Veterans Affairs fully advised of activities carried out and all data gathered pursuant to this chapter to insure maximum cooperation and coordination between the Department of Labor and the Department of Veterans Affairs.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall provide to appropriate employment service offices and Department of Labor offices, as designated by the Secretary, on a monthly or more frequent basis, the name and address of each employer located in the areas served by such offices that offer a program of job training which has been approved by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs under section 7 of the Veterans’ Job Training Act (<ref>29 U.S.C. 1721</ref> note).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 92–540, title V, § 502(a)</ref>, <date date="1972-10-24">Oct. 24, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 1097</ref>, § 2008; amended <ref>Pub. L. 94–502, title VI, § 606(4)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-15">Oct. 15, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2405</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–323</ref>, §§ 6(b)(1), (2)(A), 15(a)(2), <date date="1988-05-20">May 20, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 564</ref>, 574; <ref>Pub. L. 101–237, title IV, § 423(b)(8)</ref>, <date date="1989-12-18">Dec. 18, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 2093</ref>; renumbered § 4108, <ref>Pub. L. 102–83, § 5(a)</ref>, <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 406</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4109.</num>
<heading> National Veterans’ Employment and Training Services Institute</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> In order to provide for such training as the Secretary considers necessary and appropriate for the efficient and effective provision of employment, job-training, intensive services, placement, job-search, and related services to veterans, the Secretary shall establish and make available such funds as may be necessary to operate a National Veterans’ Employment and Training Services Institute for the training of disabled veterans’ outreach program specialists, local veterans’ employment representatives, Directors for Veterans’ Employment and Training, and Assistant Directors for Veterans’ Employment and Training, Regional Administrators for Veterans’ Employment and Training, and such other personnel involved in the provision of employment, job-training, intensive services, placement, or related services to veterans as the Secretary considers appropriate, including travel expenses and per diem for attendance at the Institute.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> In implementing this section, the Secretary shall, as the Secretary considers appropriate, provide, out of program funds designated for the Institute, training for Veterans’ Employment and Training Service personnel, including travel expenses and per diem to attend the Institute.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Nothing in this section shall be construed as preventing the Institute to enter into contracts or agreements with departments or agencies of the United States or of a State, or with other organizations, to carry out training of personnel of such departments, agencies, or organizations in the provision of services referred to in subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> All proceeds collected by the Institute under a contract or agreement referred to in paragraph (1) shall be applied to the applicable appropriation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall require that each disabled veterans’ outreach program specialist and local veterans’ employment representative who receives training provided by the Institute, or its successor, is given a final examination to evaluate the specialist’s or representative’s performance in receiving such training.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The results of such final examination shall be provided to the entity that sponsored the specialist or representative who received the training.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 97–306, title III, § 308(a)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-14">Oct. 14, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1440</ref>, § 2009; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–323, § 8(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-05-20">May 20, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 566</ref>; renumbered § 4109, <ref>Pub. L. 102–83, § 5(a)</ref>, <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 406</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–288, § 5(a)(1)(F)</ref>, (e), <date date="2002-11-07">Nov. 7, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2044</ref>, 2046; <ref>Pub. L. 112–56, title II, § 240(a)</ref>, <date date="2011-11-21">Nov. 21, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 727</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4110.</num>
<heading> Advisory Committee on Veterans Employment, Training, and Employer Outreach</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> There is hereby established within the Department of Labor an advisory committee to be known as the Advisory Committee on Veterans Employment, Training, and Employer Outreach.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The advisory committee shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> assess the employment and training needs of veterans and their integration into the workforce;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> determine the extent to which the programs and activities of the Department of Labor are meeting such needs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> assist the Assistant Secretary of Labor for Veterans’ Employment and Training in carrying out outreach activities to employers with respect to the training and skills of veterans and the advantages afforded employers by hiring veterans;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> make recommendations to the Secretary, through the Assistant Secretary of Labor for Veterans’ Employment and Training, with respect to outreach activities and the employment and training of veterans; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> carry out such other activities that are necessary to make the reports and recommendations referred to in subsection (f) of this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Labor shall, on a regular basis, consult with and seek the advice of the advisory committee with respect to the matters referred to in subsection (a)(2) of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Labor shall appoint at least 12, but no more than 16, individuals to serve as members of the advisory committee as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> Seven individuals, one each from among representatives nominated by each of the following organizations:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The National Society of Human Resource Managers.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The Business Roundtable.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> The National Association of State Workforce Agencies.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> The United States Chamber of Commerce.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> The National Federation of Independent Business.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> A nationally recognized labor union or organization.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> The National Governors Association.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Not more than five individuals from among representatives nominated by veterans service organizations that have a national employment program.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Not more than five individuals who are recognized authorities in the fields of business, employment, training, rehabilitation, or labor and who are not employees of the Department of Labor.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A vacancy in the advisory committee shall be filled in the manner in which the original appointment was made.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> The following, or their representatives, shall be ex officio, nonvoting members of the advisory committee:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Veterans Affairs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Director of the Office of Personnel Management.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Assistant Secretary of Labor for Veterans Employment and Training.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The Assistant Secretary of Labor for Employment and Training.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The Administrator of the Small Business Administration.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The advisory committee shall meet at least quarterly.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Labor shall appoint the chairman of the advisory committee who shall serve in that position for no more than 2 consecutive years.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Members of the advisory committee shall serve without compensation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Members of the advisory committee shall be allowed reasonable and necessary travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, at rates authorized for persons serving intermittently in the Government service in accordance with the provisions of subchapter I of chapter 57 of title 5 while away from their homes or regular places of business in the performance of the responsibilities of the advisory committee.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Labor shall provide staff and administrative support to the advisory committee through the Veterans Employment and Training Service.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Not later than December 31 of each year, the advisory committee shall submit to the Secretary and to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and House of Representatives a report on the employment and training needs of veterans, with special emphasis on disabled veterans, for the previous fiscal year. Each such report shall contain—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an assessment of the employment and training needs of veterans and their integration into the workforce;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an assessment of the outreach activities carried out by the Secretary of Labor to employers with respect to the training and skills of veterans and the advantages afforded employers by hiring veterans;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> an evaluation of the extent to which the programs and activities of the Department of Labor are meeting such needs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a description of the activities of the advisory committee during that fiscal year;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> a description of activities that the advisory committee proposes to undertake in the succeeding fiscal year; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> any recommendations for legislation, administrative action, and other action that the advisory committee considers appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In addition to the annual reports made under paragraph (1), the advisory committee may make recommendations to the Secretary of Labor with respect to the employment and training needs of veterans at such times and in such manner as the advisory committee determines appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> Within 60 days after receiving each annual report referred to in subsection (f)(1), the Secretary of Labor shall transmit to Congress a copy of the report together with any comments concerning the report that the Secretary considers appropriate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<content> The advisory committee shall continue until terminated by law.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 97–306, title III, § 308(a)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-14">Oct. 14, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1441</ref>, § 2010; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–323</ref>, §§ 10, 15(a)(2), (3), (b)(1), <date date="1988-05-20">May 20, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 566</ref>, 574; <ref>Pub. L. 101–237, title IV, § 423(b)(8)(A)</ref>, <date date="1989-12-18">Dec. 18, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 2093</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–16, § 8(a)</ref>, <date date="1991-03-22">Mar. 22, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 52</ref>; renumbered § 4110 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–83</ref>, §§ 4(b)(1), (2)(E), 5(a), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 404–406</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–568, title V, § 504</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4340</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–446, title XII, § 1201(a)(5)</ref>, (g)(3), (i)(7), <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4682</ref>, 4687, 4688; <ref>Pub. L. 109–233, title II, § 202(a)(1)</ref>, (2), (b)–(d), <date date="2006-06-15">June 15, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 403</ref>, 404; <ref>Pub. L. 109–461, title VI, § 604(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-22">Dec. 22, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3439</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–387, title IX, § 901(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="2008-10-10">Oct. 10, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4142</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4110A.</num>
<heading> Special unemployment study</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary, through the Bureau of Labor Statistics, shall conduct an annual study of unemployment among each of the following categories of veterans:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Veterans who were called to active duty while members of the National Guard or a Reserve Component.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Veterans who served in combat or in a war zone in the Post 9/11 Global Operations theaters.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Veterans who served on active duty during the Post 9/11 Global Operations period who did not serve in the Post 9/11 Global Operations theaters.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Veterans of the Vietnam era who served in the Vietnam theater of operations during the Vietnam era.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Veterans who served on active duty during the Vietnam era who did not serve in the Vietnam theater of operations.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Veterans discharged or released from active duty within four years of the applicable study.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> Special disabled veterans.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Within each of the categories of veterans specified in paragraph (1), the Secretary shall include a separate category for women who are veterans.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall promptly submit to Congress a report on the results of each study under subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “Post 9/11 Global Operations period” means the period of the Persian Gulf War beginning on <date date="2001-09-11">September 11, 2001</date>, and ending on the date thereafter prescribed by Presidential proclamation or law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “Post 9/11 Global Operations theaters” means Afghanistan, Iraq, or any other theater in which the Global War on Terrorism Expeditionary Medal is awarded for service.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–323, § 9(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-05-20">May 20, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 566</ref>, § 2010A; renumbered § 4110A, <ref>Pub. L. 102–83, § 5(a)</ref>, <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 406</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–446, title VII, § 701(c)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4674</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–368, title X, § 1005(b)(14)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-11">Nov. 11, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3365</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–389, title III, § 317</ref>, <date date="2008-10-10">Oct. 10, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4167</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4110B.</num>
<heading> Coordination and nonduplication</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In carrying out this chapter, the Secretary shall require that an appropriate administrative entity in each State enter into an agreement with the Secretary regarding the implementation of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act that includes the descriptions described in sections 102(b)(2)(B)(ii) and 103(b)(3)(A) of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act and a description of how the State board will carry out the activities described in section 101(d)(3)(F) of such Act.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 105–220, title III, § 322</ref>, <date date="1998-08-07">Aug. 7, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1087</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 109–233, title V, § 503(13)</ref>, <date date="2006-06-15">June 15, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 417</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–128, title V, § 512(gg)(4)</ref>, <date date="2014-07-22">July 22, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1719</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 4111.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 107–95, § 5(e)(3)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-21">Dec. 21, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 918</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4112.</num>
<heading> Performance incentive awards for quality employment, training, and placement services</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Criteria for Performance Incentive Awards</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of carrying out a program of performance incentive awards under <ref>section 4102A(c)(2)(A)(i)(III) of this title</ref>, the Secretary, acting through the Assistant Secretary of Labor for Veterans’ Employment and Training, shall establish criteria for performance incentive awards programs to be administered by States to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> encourage the improvement and modernization of employment, training, and placement services provided under this chapter; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> recognize eligible employees and employment service offices for excellence in the provision of such services or for having made demonstrable improvements in the provision of such services.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall establish such criteria in consultation with representatives of States, political subdivisions of States, and other providers of employment, training, and placement services under the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002088">1</ref> consistent with the performance measures established under <ref>section 4102A(b)(7) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Form of Awards</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Under the criteria established by the Secretary for performance incentive awards to be administered by States, an award under such criteria may be a cash award or such other nonfinancial awards as the Secretary may specify.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Administration and Use of Awards</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Performance incentive cash awards under this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall be made from amounts allocated from the grant or contract amount for a State for a program year under <ref>section 4102A(c)(7) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in the case of such an award made to an eligible employee, shall be in addition to the regular pay of the recipient; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> in the case of such an award made to an employment service office, may be used by that employment service office for any purpose.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Eligible Employee Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the term “eligible employee” means any of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A disabled veterans’ outreach program specialist.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A local veterans’ employment representative.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> An individual providing employment, training, and placement services to veterans under the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 <sup>1</sup> or through an employment service delivery system (as defined in <ref>section 4101(7) of this title</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 107–288, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-07">Nov. 7, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2037</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 109–461, title VI, § 603</ref>, <date date="2006-12-22">Dec. 22, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3437</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4113.</num>
<heading> Transition Assistance Program personnel</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirement to Contract</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In accordance with <ref>section 1144 of title 10</ref>, the Secretary shall enter into a contract with an appropriate private entity or entities to provide the functions described in subsection (b) at all locations where the program described in such section is carried out.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Functions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Contractors under subsection (a) shall provide to members of the Armed Forces who are being separated from active duty (and the spouses of such members) the services described in <ref>section 1144(a)(1) of title 10</ref>, including the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Counseling.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Assistance in identifying employment and training opportunities and help in obtaining such employment and training.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Assessment of academic preparation for enrollment in an institution of higher learning or occupational training.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Other related information and services under such section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Such other services as the Secretary considers appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–183, title III, § 309(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2003-12-16">Dec. 16, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2663</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 109–233, title IV, § 402(e)(2)</ref>, <date date="2006-06-15">June 15, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 411</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–56, title II, § 223(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2011-11-21">Nov. 21, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 717</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4114.</num>
<heading> Credentialing and licensure of veterans: demonstration project</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Demonstration Project Authorized</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Assistant Secretary for Veterans’ Employment and Training shall carry out a demonstration project on credentialing in accordance with this section for the purpose of facilitating the seamless transition of members of the Armed Forces from service on active duty to civilian employment.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Identification of Military Occupational Specialties and Associated Credentials and Licenses</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Assistant Secretary for Veterans’ Employment and Training shall, in consultation with the Assistant Secretary for Employment and Training, select not more than five military occupational specialties for purposes of the demonstration project. Each specialty so selected by the Assistant Secretary for Veterans’ Employment and Training shall require a skill or set of skills that is required for civilian employment in an industry with high growth or high worker demand.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Assistant Secretary shall enter into a contract with an appropriate entity representing a coalition of State governors to consult with appropriate Federal, State, and industry officials and identify requirements for credentials, certifications, and licenses that require a skill or set of skills required by a military occupational specialty selected under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Assistant Secretary shall analyze the requirements identified under paragraph (2) to determine which requirements may be satisfied by the skills, training, or experience acquired by members of the Armed Forces with the military occupational specialties selected under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Elimination of Barriers to Credentialing and Licensure</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Assistant Secretary shall cooperate with appropriate Federal, State, and industry officials to reduce or eliminate any barriers to providing a credential, certification, or license to a veteran who acquired any skill, training, or experience while serving as a member of the Armed Forces with a military occupational specialty selected under subsection (b)(1) that satisfies the Federal and State requirements for the credential, certification, or license.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Period of Project</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The period during which the Assistant Secretary shall carry out the demonstration project under this section shall be the two-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of the VOW to Hire Heroes Act of 2011.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–461, title VI, § 604(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-22">Dec. 22, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3437</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 112–56, title II, § 237(a)</ref>, <date date="2011-11-21">Nov. 21, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 725</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4115.</num>
<heading> Longitudinal study of job counseling, training, and placement service for veterans</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Study Required</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall enter into a contract with a non-government entity to conduct a longitudinal study of a statistically valid sample of each of the groups of individuals described in paragraph (2). The contract shall provide for the study of each such group over a period of at least 5 years.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The groups of individuals described in this paragraph are the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Veterans who have received intensive services.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Veterans who did not receive intensive services but who otherwise received services under this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Veterans who did not seek or receive services under this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The study required by this subsection shall include the collection of the following information for each individual who participates in the study:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The average number of months such individual served on active duty.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The disability ratings of such individual.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Any unemployment benefits received by such individual.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The average number of months such individual was employed during the year covered by the report.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The average annual starting and ending salaries of any such individual who was employed during the year covered by the report.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> The average annual income of such individual.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> The average total household income of such individual for the year covered by the report.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> The percentage of such individuals who own their principal residences.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> The employment status of such individual.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> In the case of such an individual who received services under this chapter, whether the individual believes that any service provided by a disabled veterans’ outreach program specialist or local veterans’ employment representative helped the individual to become employed.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(K)</num>
<chapeau> In the case of such an individual who believes such a service helped the individual to become employed, whether—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the individual retained the position of employment for a period of 1 year or longer; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the individual believes such a service helped the individual to secure a higher wage or salary.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(L)</num>
<content> The conditions under which such individual was discharged or released from the Armed Forces.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(M)</num>
<content> Whether such individual has used any educational assistance to which the individual is entitled under this title.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(N)</num>
<content> Whether such individual has participated in a rehabilitation program under chapter 31 of this title.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(O)</num>
<content> Whether such individual had contact with a One-Stop Career Center employee while attending a workshop or job fair under the Transition GPS Program of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(P)</num>
<content> Demographic information about such individual.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(Q)</num>
<content> Such other information as the Secretary determines appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Report</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> By not later than July 1 of each year covered by the study required under subsection (a), the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on the outcomes of the study during the preceding year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary shall include in each report submitted under paragraph (1) the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> Information with respect to job fairs attended by One-Stop Career Center employees at which the employees had contact with a veteran, including, for the year preceding the year in which the report is submitted, the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The number of job fairs attended by One-Stop Career Center employees at which the employees had contact with a veteran.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The number of veterans contacted at each such job fair.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Such information as the Secretary determines is necessary to determine the long-term outcomes of the individuals in the groups described in subsection (a)(2).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–315, title V, § 502(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1566</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>