<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 72—</num>
<heading>UNITED STATES COURT OF APPEALS FOR VETERANS CLAIMS</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>ORGANIZATION AND JURISDICTION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7251.</num>
<heading> Status</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is hereby established, under Article I of the Constitution of the United States, a court of record to be known as the United States Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–687, div. A, title III, § 301(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4113</ref>, § 4051; renumbered § 7251, <ref>Pub. L. 102–40, title IV, § 402(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-05-07">May 7, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 238</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–368, title V, § 511(b)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-11">Nov. 11, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3341</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7252.</num>
<heading> Jurisdiction; finality of decisions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims shall have exclusive jurisdiction to review decisions of the Board of Veterans’ Appeals. The Secretary may not seek review of any such decision. The Court shall have power to affirm, modify, or reverse a decision of the Board or to remand the matter, as appropriate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Review in the Court shall be on the record of proceedings before the Secretary and the Board. The extent of the review shall be limited to the scope provided in <ref>section 7261 of this title</ref>. The Court may not review the schedule of ratings for disabilities adopted under <ref>section 1155 of this title</ref> or any action of the Secretary in adopting or revising that schedule.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Decisions by the Court are subject to review as provided in <ref>section 7292 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–687, div. A, title III, § 301(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4113</ref>, § 4052; renumbered § 7252 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–40, title IV, § 402(b)(1)</ref>, (d)(1), <date date="1991-05-07">May 7, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 238</ref>, 239; <ref>Pub. L. 102–54, § 14(e)(3)</ref>, <date date="1991-06-13">June 13, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 287</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–83</ref>, §§ 4(b)(1), (2)(E), 5(c)(1), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 404–406</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–368, title V, § 512(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-11">Nov. 11, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3341</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7253.</num>
<heading> Composition</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Composition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims is composed of at least three and not more than seven judges, one of whom shall serve as chief judge in accordance with subsection (d).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appointment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The judges of the Court shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, solely on the grounds of fitness to perform the duties of the office. A person may not be appointed to the Court who is not a member in good standing of the bar of a Federal court or of the highest court of a State. Not more than the number equal to the next whole number greater than one-half of the number of judges of the Court may be members of the same political party.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Term of Office</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term of office of the judges of the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims shall be 15 years. A judge who is nominated by the President for appointment to an additional term on the Court without a break in service and whose term of office expires while that nomination is pending before the Senate may continue in office for up to 1 year while that nomination is pending.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Chief Judge</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The chief judge of the Court is the head of the Court. The chief judge of the Court shall be the judge of the Court in regular active service who is senior in commission among the judges of the Court who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> have served for one or more years as judges of the Court;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> have at least 3 years remaining in term of office; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> have not previously served as chief judge.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> In any case in which there is no judge of the Court in regular active service who meets the requirements under paragraph (1), the judge of the Court in regular active service who is senior in commission and meets subparagraph (A) or (B) and subparagraph (C) of paragraph (1) shall act as the chief judge.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> In any case under subparagraph (A) of this paragraph in which there is no judge of the Court in regular active service who meets subparagraph (A) or (B) and subparagraph (C) of paragraph (1), the judge of the Court in regular active service who is senior in commission and meets subparagraph (C) shall act as the chief judge.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraph (4), a judge of the Court shall serve as the chief judge under paragraph (1) for a term of five years or until the judge becomes age 70, whichever occurs first. If no other judge is eligible under paragraph (1) to serve as chief judge upon the expiration of that term, that judge shall continue to serve as chief judge until another judge becomes eligible under that paragraph to serve as chief judge.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> The term of a chief judge shall be terminated before the end of the term prescribed by paragraph (3) if—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the chief judge leaves regular active service as a judge of the Court; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the chief judge notifies the other judges of the Court in writing that such judge desires to be relieved of the duties of chief judge.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The effective date of a termination of the term under subparagraph (A) shall be the date on which the chief judge leaves regular active service or the date of the notification under subparagraph (A)(ii), as the case may be.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> If a chief judge is temporarily unable to perform the duties of chief judge, those duties shall be performed by the judge of the Court in active service who is present, able and qualified to act, and is next in precedence.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Judges who have the same seniority in commission shall be eligible for service as chief judge in accordance with their relative precedence.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Salary</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each judge of the Court shall receive a salary at the same rate as is received by judges of the United States district courts.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Removal</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A judge of the Court may be removed from office by the President on grounds of misconduct, neglect of duty, engaging in the practice of law, or violating <ref>section 7255(c) of this title</ref>. A judge of the Court may not be removed from office by the President on any other ground.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Before a judge may be removed from office under this subsection, the judge shall be provided with a full specification of the reasons for the removal and an opportunity to be heard.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rules</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Court shall prescribe rules, consistent with the provisions of chapter 16 of title 28, establishing procedures for the filing of complaints with respect to the conduct of any judge of the Court and for the investigation and resolution of such complaints. In investigating and taking action with respect to any such complaint, the Court shall have the powers granted to a judicial council under such chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The provisions of sections 354(b) through 360 of title 28, regarding referral or certification to, and petition for review in, the Judicial Conference of the United States and action thereon, shall apply to the exercise by the Court of the powers of a judicial council under paragraph (1) of this subsection. The grounds for removal from office specified in subsection (f)(1) shall provide a basis for a determination pursuant to section 354(b) or 355 of title 28, and certification and transmittal by the Conference shall be made to the President for consideration under subsection (f).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> In conducting hearings pursuant to paragraph (1), the Court may exercise the authority provided under <ref>section 1821 of title 28</ref> to pay the fees and allowances described in that section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Court shall have the power provided under <ref>section 361 of title 28</ref> to award reimbursement for the reasonable expenses described in that section. Reimbursements under this subparagraph shall be made from funds appropriated to the Court.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Temporary Expansion of Court</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> During the period from <date date="2002-01-01">January 1, 2002</date>, through <date date="2005-08-15">August 15, 2005</date>, the authorized number of judges of the Court specified in subsection (a) is increased by two.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> Of the two additional judges authorized by this subsection—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> only one may be appointed pursuant to a nomination made in 2002; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> only one may be appointed pursuant to a nomination made in 2003.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> If a judge is not appointed under this subsection pursuant to a nomination made in 2002, a judge may be appointed under this subsection pursuant to a nomination made in 2004. If a judge is not appointed under this subsection pursuant to a nomination made in 2003, a judge may be appointed under this subsection pursuant to a nomination made in 2004. In either case, such an appointment may be made only pursuant to a nomination made before <date date="2004-10-01">October 1, 2004</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term of office and the eligibility for retirement of a judge appointed under this subsection, other than a judge described in paragraph (4), are governed by the provisions of section 1012 of the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims Amendments of 1999 (title X of <ref>Public Law 106–117</ref>; <ref>113 Stat. 1590</ref>; <ref>38 U.S.C. 7296</ref> note) if the judge is one of the first two judges appointed to the Court after <date date="1999-11-30">November 30, 1999</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> A judge of the Court as of <date date="2001-12-27">December 27, 2001</date>, who was appointed to the Court before <date date="1991-01-01">January 1, 1991</date>, may accept appointment as a judge of the Court under this subsection notwithstanding that the term of office of the judge on the Court has not yet expired under this section. The term of office of an incumbent judge who receives an appointment as described in the preceding sentence shall be 15 years, which includes any period remaining in the unexpired term of the judge. Any service following an appointment under this subsection shall be treated as though served as part of the original term of office of that judge on the Court.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding paragraph (1), an appointment may not be made to the Court if the appointment would result in there being more than seven judges on the Court who were appointed after <date date="1997-01-01">January 1, 1997</date>. For the purposes of this paragraph, a judge serving in recall status under <ref>section 7257 of this title</ref> shall be disregarded in counting the number of judges appointed to the Court after such date.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Additional Temporary Expansion of Court</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Subject to paragraph (2), effective during the period beginning on <date date="2009-12-31">December 31, 2009</date>, and ending on the date of the enactment of the Veterans Benefits Improvement Act of 2024, the authorized number of judges of the Court specified in subsection (a) is increased by two.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Subject to paragraph (2), effective as of the date of the enactment of the Veterans Benefits Improvement Act of 2024, the authorized number of judges of the Court specified in subsection (a) is increased by three.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Effective as of <date date="2028-01-01">January 1, 2028</date>, an appointment may not be made to the Court if the appointment would result in there being more judges of the Court than the authorized number of judges of the Court specified in subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–687, div. A, title III, § 301(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4114</ref>, § 4053; amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–94, title I, § 102(c)</ref>, <date date="1989-08-16">Aug. 16, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 626</ref>; renumbered § 7253, <ref>Pub. L. 102–40, title IV, § 402(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-05-07">May 7, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 238</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–82, § 3</ref>, <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 375</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–585, title VIII, § 801</ref>, <date date="1992-11-04">Nov. 4, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4980</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–368, title V</ref>, §§ 501, 512(a)(1), <date date="1998-11-11">Nov. 11, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3340</ref>, 3341; <ref>Pub. L. 106–117, title X</ref>, §§ 1031, 1032(a), 1033, <date date="1999-11-30">Nov. 30, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1594</ref>, 1595; <ref>Pub. L. 107–103, title VI, § 601</ref>, <date date="2001-12-27">Dec. 27, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 998</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. C, title I, § 11043(f)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1856</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–454, title VIII, § 802</ref>, <date date="2004-12-10">Dec. 10, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3625</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–233, title V, § 503(15)</ref>, <date date="2006-06-15">June 15, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 417</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–389, title VI, § 601</ref>, <date date="2008-10-10">Oct. 10, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4176</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–260, title III, § 302(b)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-10">Jan. 10, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 2425</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–315, title II</ref>, §§ 201(a), 204(a), <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1548</ref>, 1549; <ref>Pub. L. 116–159, div. E, title II, § 5205</ref>, <date date="2020-10-01">Oct. 1, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 750</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–196, § 7</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2675</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7254.</num>
<heading> Organization</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims shall have a seal which shall be judicially noticed.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Court may hear cases by judges sitting alone or in panels, as determined pursuant to procedures established by the Court. Any such panel shall have not less than three judges. The Court shall establish procedures for the assignment of the judges of the Court to such panels and for the designation of the chief of each such panel.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A majority of the judges of the Court shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of the business of the Court. A vacancy in the Court shall not impair the powers or affect the duties of the Court or of the remaining judges of the Court.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A majority of the judges of a panel of the Court shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of the business of the panel. A vacancy in a panel of the Court shall not impair the powers or affect the duties of the panel or of the remaining judges of the panel.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Precedence of Judges</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The chief judge of the Court shall have precedence and preside at any session that the chief judge attends. The other judges shall have precedence and preside according to the seniority of their original commissions. Judges whose commissions bear the same date shall have precedence according to seniority in age.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> Judges of the Court shall have the authority to administer oaths.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–687, div. A, title III, § 301(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4114</ref>, § 4054; amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–94, title IV, § 402</ref>, <date date="1989-08-16">Aug. 16, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 628</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–237, title VI, § 602(b)</ref>, <date date="1989-12-18">Dec. 18, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 2095</ref>; renumbered § 7254, <ref>Pub. L. 102–40, title IV, § 402(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-05-07">May 7, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 238</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–54, § 14(e)(4)</ref>, <date date="1991-06-13">June 13, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 287</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–82, § 8(3)</ref>, <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 377</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–368, title V, § 512(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-11">Nov. 11, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3341</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–117, title X, § 1034</ref>, <date date="1999-11-30">Nov. 30, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1595</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7255.</num>
<heading> Offices, duty stations, and residences</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Principal Office</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The principal office of the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims shall be in the Washington, D.C., metropolitan area, but the Court may sit at any place within the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Official Duty Stations</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraph (2), the official duty station of each judge while in active service shall be the principal office of the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The place where a recall-eligible retired judge maintains the actual abode in which such judge customarily lives shall be considered the recall-eligible retired judge’s official duty station.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Residences</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraph (2), after appointment and while in active service, each judge of the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims shall reside within 50 miles of the Washington, D.C., metropolitan area.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Paragraph (1) shall not apply to recall-eligible retired judges of the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–687, div. A, title III, § 301(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4114</ref>, § 4055; renumbered § 7255, <ref>Pub. L. 102–40, title IV, § 402(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-05-07">May 7, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 238</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–368, title V, § 512(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-11">Nov. 11, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3341</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–454, title VIII, § 801</ref>, <date date="2004-12-10">Dec. 10, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3625</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–260, title III, § 302(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-10">Jan. 10, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 2425</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7256.</num>
<heading> Times and places of sessions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The times and places of sessions of the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims shall be prescribed by the chief judge.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–687, div. A, title III, § 301(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4115</ref>, § 4056; renumbered § 7256, <ref>Pub. L. 102–40, title IV, § 402(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-05-07">May 7, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 238</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–368, title V, § 512(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-11">Nov. 11, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3341</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7257.</num>
<heading> Recall of retired judges</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A retired judge of the Court may be recalled for further service on the Court in accordance with this section. To be eligible to be recalled for such service, a retired judge must at the time of the judge’s retirement provide to the chief judge of the Court (or, in the case of the chief judge, to the clerk of the Court) notice in writing that the retired judge is available for further service on the Court in accordance with this section and is willing to be recalled under this section. Such a notice provided by a retired judge to whom <ref>section 7296(c)(1)(B) of this title</ref> applies is irrevocable.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> For the purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a retired judge is a judge of the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims who retires from the Court under <ref>section 7296 of this title</ref> or under chapter 83 or 84 of title 5; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a recall-eligible retired judge is a retired judge who has provided a notice under paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The chief judge may recall for further service on the Court a recall-eligible retired judge in accordance with this section. Such a recall shall be made upon written certification by the chief judge that substantial service is expected to be performed by the retired judge for such period, not to exceed 90 days (or the equivalent), as determined by the chief judge to be necessary to meet the needs of the Court.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A recall-eligible retired judge may not be recalled for more than 90 days (or the equivalent) during any calendar year without the judge’s consent.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> If a recall-eligible retired judge is recalled by the chief judge in accordance with this section and (other than in the case of a judge who has previously during that calendar year served at least 90 days (or the equivalent) of recalled service on the court) declines (other than by reason of disability) to perform the service to which recalled, the chief judge shall remove that retired judge from the status of a recall-eligible judge. This paragraph shall not apply to a judge to whom section 7296(c)(1)(A) or 7296(c)(1)(B) of this title applies and who has, in the aggregate, served at least five years of recalled service on the Court under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> A recall-eligible retired judge who becomes permanently disabled and as a result of that disability is unable to perform further service on the Court shall be removed from the status of a recall-eligible judge. Determination of such a disability shall be made pursuant to section 7253(g) or 7296(g) of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> A retired judge who is recalled under this section may exercise all of the judicial powers and duties of the office of a judge in active service.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The pay of a recall-eligible retired judge to whom <ref>section 7296(c)(1)(B) of this title</ref> applies is the pay specified in that section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A judge who is recalled under this section who retired under chapter 83 or 84 of title 5 or to whom <ref>section 7296(c)(1)(A) of this title</ref> applies shall be paid, during the period for which the judge serves in recall status, pay at the rate of pay in effect under <ref>section 7253(e) of this title</ref> for a judge performing active service, less the amount of the judge’s annuity under the applicable provisions of chapter 83 or 84 of title 5 or the judge’s annuity under <ref>section 7296(c)(1)(A) of this title</ref>, whichever is applicable.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in subsection (d), a judge who is recalled under this section who retired under chapter 83 or 84 of title 5 shall be considered to be a reemployed annuitant under that chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Nothing in this section affects the right of a judge who retired under chapter 83 or 84 of title 5 to serve as a reemployed annuitant in accordance with the provisions of title 5.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–117, title X, § 1021(a)</ref>, <date date="1999-11-30">Nov. 30, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1590</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 110–389, title VI, § 603(a)</ref>, (b)(3)–(c), <date date="2008-10-10">Oct. 10, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4177</ref>, 4178.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>PROCEDURE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7261.</num>
<heading> Scope of review</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> In any action brought under this chapter, the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims, to the extent necessary to its decision and when presented, shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> decide all relevant questions of law, interpret constitutional, statutory, and regulatory provisions, and determine the meaning or applicability of the terms of an action of the Secretary;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> compel action of the Secretary unlawfully withheld or unreasonably delayed;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> hold unlawful and set aside decisions, findings (other than those described in clause (4) of this subsection), conclusions, rules, and regulations issued or adopted by the Secretary, the Board of Veterans’ Appeals, or the Chairman of the Board found to be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> arbitrary, capricious, an abuse of discretion, or otherwise not in accordance with law;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> contrary to constitutional right, power, privilege, or immunity;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> in excess of statutory jurisdiction, authority, or limitations, or in violation of a statutory right; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> without observance of procedure required by law; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> in the case of a finding of material fact adverse to the claimant made in reaching a decision in a case before the Department with respect to benefits under laws administered by the Secretary, hold unlawful and set aside or reverse such finding if the finding is clearly erroneous.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> In making the determinations under subsection (a), the Court shall review the record of proceedings before the Secretary and the Board of Veterans’ Appeals pursuant to <ref>section 7252(b) of this title</ref> and shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> take due account of the Secretary’s application of <ref>section 5107(b) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> take due account of the rule of prejudicial error.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> In no event shall findings of fact made by the Secretary or the Board of Veterans’ Appeals be subject to trial de novo by the Court.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> When a final decision of the Board of Veterans’ Appeals is adverse to a party and the sole stated basis for such decision is the failure of the party to comply with any applicable regulation prescribed by the Secretary, the Court shall review only questions raised as to compliance with and the validity of the regulation.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–687, div. A, title III, § 301(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4115</ref>, § 4061; amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–237, title VI, § 602(c)</ref>, <date date="1989-12-18">Dec. 18, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 2095</ref>; renumbered § 7261, <ref>Pub. L. 102–40, title IV, § 402(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-05-07">May 7, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 238</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–54, § 14(e)(3)</ref>, <date date="1991-06-13">June 13, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 287</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–83, § 4(a)(1)</ref>, (3), (4), (b)(1), (2)(E), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 403–405</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–368, title V, § 512(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-11">Nov. 11, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3341</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–330, title IV, § 401(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2002-12-06">Dec. 6, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2832</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7262.</num>
<heading> Fee for filing appeals</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims may impose a fee of not more than $50 for the filing of any appeal with the Court. The Court shall establish procedures under which such a fee may be waived in the case of an appeal filed by or on behalf of a person who demonstrates that the requirement that such fee be paid will impose a hardship on that person. A decision as to such a waiver is final and may not be reviewed in any other court.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Court may from time to time adjust the maximum amount permitted for a fee imposed under subsection (a) of this section based upon inflation and similar fees charged by other courts established under Article I of the Constitution.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–687, div. A, title III, § 301(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4115</ref>, § 4062; renumbered § 7262, <ref>Pub. L. 102–40, title IV, § 402(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-05-07">May 7, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 238</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–368, title V, § 512(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-11">Nov. 11, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3341</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7263.</num>
<heading> Representation of parties; fee agreements</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall be represented before the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims by the General Counsel of the Department.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Representation of appellants shall be in accordance with the rules of practice prescribed by the Court under <ref>section 7264 of this title</ref>. In addition to members of the bar admitted to practice before the Court in accordance with such rules of practice, the Court may allow other persons to practice before the Court who meet standards of proficiency prescribed in such rules of practice.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> A person who represents an appellant before the Court shall file a copy of any fee agreement between the appellant and that person with the Court at the time the appeal is filed. The Court, on its own motion or the motion of any party, may review such a fee agreement.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> In reviewing a fee agreement under subsection (c) of this section or under <ref>section 5904(c)(2) of this title</ref>, the Court may affirm the finding or order of the Board and may order a reduction in the fee called for in the agreement if it finds that the fee is excessive or unreasonable. An order of the Court under this subsection is final and may not be reviewed in any other court.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–687, div. A, title III, § 301(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4116</ref>, § 4063; renumbered § 7263 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–40, title IV, § 402(b)(1)</ref>, (d)(1), <date date="1991-05-07">May 7, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 238</ref>, 239; <ref>Pub. L. 102–83, § 4(a)(3)</ref>, (4), (b)(1), (2)(E), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 404</ref>, 405; <ref>Pub. L. 105–368, title V, § 512(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-11">Nov. 11, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3341</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7264.</num>
<heading> Rules of practice and procedure</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The proceedings of the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims shall be conducted in accordance with such rules of practice and procedure as the Court prescribes.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The mailing of a pleading, decision, order, notice, or process in respect of proceedings before the Court shall be held sufficient service of such pleading, decision, order, notice, or process if it is properly addressed to the address furnished by the appellant on the notice of appeal filed under <ref>section 7266 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content><ref>Section 455 of title 28</ref> shall apply to judges and proceedings of the Court.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–687, div. A, title III, § 301(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4116</ref>, § 4064; renumbered § 7264 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–40, title IV, § 402(b)(1)</ref>, (d)(1), <date date="1991-05-07">May 7, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 238</ref>, 239; <ref>Pub. L. 102–82, § 4</ref>, <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 376</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–368, title V, § 512(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-11">Nov. 11, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3341</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7265.</num>
<heading> Contempt authority; assistance to the Court</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Court shall have power to punish by fine or imprisonment such contempt of its authority as—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> misbehavior of any person in its presence or so near thereto as to obstruct the administration of justice;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> misbehavior of any of its officers in their official transactions; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> disobedience or resistance to its lawful writ, process, order, rule, decree, or command.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Court shall have such assistance in the carrying out of its lawful writ, process, order, rule, decree, or command as is available to a court of the United States. The United States marshal for a district in which the Court is sitting shall, if requested by the chief judge of the Court, attend any session of the Court in that district.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–687, div. A, title III, § 301(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4116</ref>, § 4065; renumbered § 7265, <ref>Pub. L. 102–40, title IV, § 402(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-05-07">May 7, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 238</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7266.</num>
<heading> Notice of appeal</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> In order to obtain review by the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims of a final decision of the Board of Veterans’ Appeals, a person adversely affected by such decision shall file a notice of appeal with the Court within 120 days after the date on which notice of the decision is issued pursuant to <ref>section 7104(e) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> An appellant shall file a notice of appeal under this section by delivering or mailing the notice to the Court.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> A notice of appeal shall be deemed to be received by the Court as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> On the date of receipt by the Court, if the notice is delivered.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> On the date of the United States Postal Service postmark stamped on the cover in which the notice is posted, if the notice is properly addressed to the Court and is mailed.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> For a notice of appeal mailed to the Court to be deemed to be received under subsection (c)(2) on a particular date, the United States Postal Service postmark on the cover in which the notice is posted must be legible. The Court shall determine the legibility of any such postmark and the Court’s determination as to legibility shall be final and not subject to review by any other Court.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–687, div. A, title III, § 301(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4116</ref>, § 4066; renumbered § 7266 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–40, title IV, § 402(b)(1)</ref>, (d)(1), <date date="1991-05-07">May 7, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 238</ref>, 239; <ref>Pub. L. 102–83, § 4(b)(1)</ref>, (2)(E), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 404</ref>, 405; <ref>Pub. L. 103–446, title V, § 511(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4670</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–368, title V, § 512(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-11">Nov. 11, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3341</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–103, title V, § 507</ref>, <date date="2001-12-27">Dec. 27, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 997</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–168, title VIII, § 807(a)(8)</ref>, <date date="2022-08-10">Aug. 10, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 1806</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7267.</num>
<heading> Decisions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> A decision upon a proceeding before the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims shall be made as quickly as practicable. In a case heard by a panel of the Court, the decision shall be made by a majority vote of the panel in accordance with the rules of the Court. The decision of the judge or panel hearing the case so made shall be the decision of the Court.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> A judge or panel shall make a determination upon any proceeding before the Court, and any motion in connection with such a proceeding, that is assigned to the judge or panel. The judge or panel shall make a report of any such determination which constitutes the judge or panel’s final disposition of the proceeding.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Court shall designate in its decision in any case those specific records of the Government on which it relied (if any) in making its decision. The Secretary shall preserve records so designated for not less than the period of time designated by the Archivist of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–687, div. A, title III, § 301(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4117</ref>, § 4067; renumbered § 7267, <ref>Pub. L. 102–40, title IV, § 402(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-05-07">May 7, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 238</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–82</ref>, §§ 1, 8(1), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 375</ref>, 377; <ref>Pub. L. 102–83, § 4(b)(1)</ref>, (2)(E), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 404</ref>, 405; <ref>Pub. L. 105–368, title V, § 512(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-11">Nov. 11, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3341</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7268.</num>
<heading> Availability of proceedings</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, all decisions of the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims and all briefs, motions, documents, and exhibits received by the Court (including a transcript of the stenographic report of the hearings) shall be public records open to the inspection of the public.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Court may make any provision which is necessary to prevent the disclosure of confidential information, including a provision that any such document or information be placed under seal to be opened only as directed by the Court.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> After the decision of the Court in a proceeding becomes final, the Court may, upon motion of the appellant or the Secretary, permit the withdrawal by the party entitled thereto of originals of books, documents, and records, and of models, diagrams, and other exhibits, submitted to the Court or the Court may, on its own motion, make such other disposition thereof as it considers advisable.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Court shall prescribe rules, in accordance with <ref>section 7264(a) of this title</ref>, to protect privacy and security concerns relating to all filing of documents and the public availability under this subsection of documents retained by the Court or filed electronically with the Court.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The rules prescribed under paragraph (1) shall be consistent to the extent practicable with rules addressing privacy and security issues throughout the Federal courts.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The rules prescribed under paragraph (1) shall take into consideration best practices in Federal and State courts to protect private information or otherwise maintain necessary information security.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–687, div. A, title III, § 301(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4117</ref>, § 4068; renumbered § 7268, <ref>Pub. L. 102–40, title IV, § 402(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-05-07">May 7, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 238</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–82, § 8(2)</ref>, <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 377</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–368, title V, § 512(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-11">Nov. 11, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3341</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–389, title VI, § 602</ref>, <date date="2008-10-10">Oct. 10, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4177</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7269.</num>
<heading> Publication of decisions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims shall provide for the publication of decisions of the Court in such form and manner as may be best adapted for public information and use. The Court may make such exceptions, or may authorize the chief judge to make such exceptions, to the requirement for publication in the preceding sentence as may be appropriate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Such authorized publication shall be competent evidence of the decisions of the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims therein contained in all courts of the United States and of the several States without any further proof or authentication thereof.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Such publications shall be subject to sale in the same manner and upon the same terms as other public documents.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–687, div. A, title III, § 301(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4118</ref>, § 4069; renumbered § 7269, <ref>Pub. L. 102–40, title IV, § 402(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-05-07">May 7, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 238</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–368, title V, § 512(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-11">Nov. 11, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3341</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7281.</num>
<heading> Employees</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims may appoint a clerk without regard to the provisions of title 5 governing appointments in the competitive service. The clerk shall serve at the pleasure of the Court.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The judges of the Court may appoint law clerks and secretaries, in such numbers as the Court may approve, without regard to the provisions of title 5 governing appointments in the competitive service. Any such law clerk or secretary shall serve at the pleasure of the appointing judge.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The clerk, with the approval of the Court, may appoint necessary deputies and employees without regard to the provisions of title 5 governing appointments in the competitive service.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The Court may fix and adjust the rates of basic pay for the clerk and other employees of the Court without regard to the provisions of chapter 51, subchapter III of chapter 53, or <ref>section 5373 of title 5</ref>. To the maximum extent feasible, the Court shall compensate employees at rates consistent with those for employees holding comparable positions in the judicial branch.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> In making appointments under subsections (a) through (c) of this section, preference shall be given, among equally qualified persons, to persons who are preference eligibles (as defined in <ref>section 2108(3) of title 5</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> The Court may procure the services of experts and consultants under <ref>section 3109 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> The chief judge of the Court may exercise the authority of the Court under this section whenever there are not at least two other judges of the Court.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<content> The Court shall not be considered to be an agency within the meaning of <ref>section 3132(a)(1) of title 5</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The Court may accept and utilize voluntary services and uncompensated (gratuitous) services, including services as authorized by <ref>section 3102(b) of title 5</ref> and may accept, hold, administer, and utilize gifts and bequests of personal property for the purposes of aiding or facilitating the work of the Court. Gifts or bequests of money to the Court shall be covered into the Treasury.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<content> For purposes of chapter 87 of title 5, a judge who is in regular active service and a judge who is retired under <ref>section 7296 of this title</ref> or under chapter 83 or 84 of title 5 shall be treated as an employee described in <ref>section 8701(a)(5) of title 5</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(k)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Court may pay on behalf of its judges, who are age 65 or older, any increase in the cost of Federal Employees’ Group Life Insurance imposed after <date date="1999-04-24">April 24, 1999</date>, including any expenses generated by such payments, as authorized by the chief judge of the Court in a manner consistent with such payment authorized by the Judicial Conference of the United States pursuant to <ref>section 604(a)(5) of title 28</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–687, div. A, title III, § 301(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4118</ref>, § 4081; amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–94, title II, § 204(a)</ref>, <date date="1989-08-16">Aug. 16, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 627</ref>; renumbered § 7281, <ref>Pub. L. 102–40, title IV, § 402(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-05-07">May 7, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 238</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–82, § 7</ref>, <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 377</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–368, title V, § 512(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-11">Nov. 11, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3341</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–117, title X, § 1035(1)</ref>, <date date="1999-11-30">Nov. 30, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1595</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–315, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1549</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7282.</num>
<heading> Budget and expenditures</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The budget of the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims as submitted by the Court for inclusion in the budget of the President for any fiscal year shall be included in that budget without review within the executive branch.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Court may make such expenditures (including expenditures for personal services and rent at the seat of Government and elsewhere, and for law books, books of reference, and periodicals) as may be necessary to execute efficiently the functions vested in the Court.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> All expenditures of the Court shall be allowed and paid upon presentation of itemized vouchers signed by the certifying officer designated by the chief judge. Except as provided in <ref>section 7285 of this title</ref>, all such expenditures shall be paid out of moneys appropriated for purposes of the Court.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–687, div. A, title III, § 301(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4118</ref>, § 4082; renumbered § 7282 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–40, title IV, § 402(b)(1)</ref>, (d)(1), <date date="1991-05-07">May 7, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 238</ref>, 239; <ref>Pub. L. 105–368, title V, § 512(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-11">Nov. 11, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3341</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7283.</num>
<heading> Disposition of fees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except for amounts received pursuant to <ref>section 7285 of this title</ref>, all fees received by the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims shall be covered into the Treasury as miscellaneous receipts.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–687, div. A, title III, § 301(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4118</ref>, § 4083; renumbered § 7283 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–40, title IV, § 402(b)(1)</ref>, (d)(1), <date date="1991-05-07">May 7, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 238</ref>, 239; <ref>Pub. L. 105–368, title V, § 512(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-11">Nov. 11, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3341</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7284.</num>
<heading> Fee for transcript of record</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims may fix a fee, not in excess of the fee authorized by law to be charged and collected therefor by the clerks of the district courts, for comparing, or for preparing and comparing, a transcript of the record of any proceeding before the Court, or for copying any record, entry, or other paper and the comparison and certification thereof.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–687, div. A, title III, § 301(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4118</ref>, § 4084; renumbered § 7284, <ref>Pub. L. 102–40, title IV, § 402(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-05-07">May 7, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 238</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–368, title V, § 512(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-11">Nov. 11, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3341</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7285.</num>
<heading> Practice and registration fees</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims may impose a reasonable periodic registration fee on persons admitted to practice before the Court. The frequency and amount of such fee shall be determined by the Court. The Court may also impose a reasonable registration fee on persons (other than judges of the Court) participating at judicial conferences convened pursuant to <ref>section 7286 of this title</ref> or in any other court-sponsored activity.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Amounts received by the Court under subsection (a) of this section shall be available to the Court for the following purposes:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Conducting investigations and proceedings, including employing independent counsel, to pursue disciplinary matters.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Defraying the expenses of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> judicial conferences convened pursuant to <ref>section 7286 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> other activities and programs of the Court that are intended to support and foster communication and relationships between the Court and persons practicing before the Court or the study, understanding, public commemoration, or improvement of veterans law or of the work of the Court.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–687, div. A, title III, § 301(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4119</ref>, § 4085; renumbered § 7285, <ref>Pub. L. 102–40, title IV, § 402(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-05-07">May 7, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 238</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–368, title V, § 512(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-11">Nov. 11, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3341</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–103, title VI, § 604(a)</ref>–(c)(1), <date date="2001-12-27">Dec. 27, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 999</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–389, title VI, § 605</ref>, <date date="2008-10-10">Oct. 10, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4179</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7286.</num>
<heading> Judicial Conference of the Court</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Chief Judge of the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims may summon the judges of the Court to an annual judicial conference, at a time and place that the Chief Judge designates, for the purpose of considering the business of the Court and recommending means of improving the administration of justice within the Court’s jurisdiction. The Court shall provide by its rules for representation and active participation at such conference by persons admitted to practice before the Court and by other persons active in the legal profession.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–82, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 375</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–368, title V, § 512(a)(1)</ref>, (2)(A), <date date="1998-11-11">Nov. 11, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3341</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7287.</num>
<heading> Administration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims may exercise, for purposes of management, administration, and expenditure of funds of the Court, the authorities provided for such purposes by any provision of law (including any limitation with respect to such provision of law) applicable to a court of the United States (as that term is defined in <ref>section 451 of title 28</ref>), except to the extent that such provision of law is inconsistent with a provision of this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 107–103, title VI, § 605(a)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-27">Dec. 27, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1000</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7288.</num>
<heading> Annual report</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The chief judge of the Court shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress each year a report summarizing the workload of the Court for the fiscal year ending during the preceding year.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each report under subsection (a) shall include, with respect to the fiscal year covered by such report, the following information:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The number of appeals filed with the Court.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The number of petitions filed with the Court.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The number of applications filed with the Court under <ref>section 2412 of title 28</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> The total number of dispositions by each of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Court as a whole.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Clerk of the Court.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> A single judge of the Court.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> A multi-judge panel of the Court.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The full Court.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The number of each type of disposition by the Court, including settlement, affirmation, remand, vacation, dismissal, reversal, grant, and denial.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> The median time from filing an appeal to disposition by each of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Court as a whole.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Clerk of the Court.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> A single judge of the Court.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Multiple judges of the Court (including a multi-judge panel of the Court or the full Court).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The median time from filing a petition to disposition by the Court.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> The median time from filing an application under <ref>section 2412 of title 28</ref> to disposition by the Court.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> The median time from the completion of briefing requirements by the parties to disposition by the Court.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> The number of oral arguments before the Court.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> The number of cases appealed to the United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> The number and status of appeals and petitions pending with the Court and of applications described in paragraph (3) as of the end of such fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> The number of cases pending with the Court more than 18 months as of the end of such fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> A summary of any service performed for the Court by a recalled retired judge of the Court.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<chapeau> An assessment of the workload of each judge of the Court, including consideration of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The time required of each judge for disposition of each type of case.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The number of cases reviewed by the Court.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The average workload of other Federal judges.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appropriate Committees of Congress Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the term “appropriate committees of Congress” means—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–389, title VI, § 604(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-10-10">Oct. 10, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4178</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>DECISIONS AND REVIEW</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7291.</num>
<heading> Date when Court decision becomes final</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> A decision of the United States Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims shall become final upon the expiration of the time allowed for filing, under <ref>section 7292 of this title</ref>, a notice of appeal from such decision, if no such notice is duly filed within such time. If such a notice is filed within such time, such a decision shall become final—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> upon the expiration of the time allowed for filing a petition for certiorari with the Supreme Court of the United States, if the decision of the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims is affirmed or the appeal is dismissed by the United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit and no petition for certiorari is duly filed;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> upon the denial of a petition for certiorari, if the decision of the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims is affirmed or the appeal is dismissed by the United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> upon the expiration of 30 days from the date of issuance of the mandate of the Supreme Court, if that Court directs that the decision of the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims be affirmed or the appeal dismissed.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> If the Supreme Court directs that the decision of the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims be modified or reversed, the decision of the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims rendered in accordance with the mandate of the Supreme Court shall become final upon the expiration of 30 days from the time it was rendered, unless within such 30 days either the Secretary or the petitioner has instituted proceedings to have such decision corrected to accord with the mandate, in which event the decision of the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims shall become final when so corrected.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> If the decision of the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims is modified or reversed by the United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit and if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the time allowed for filing a petition for certiorari has expired and no such petition has been duly filed, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the petition for certiorari has been denied, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the decision of the United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit has been affirmed by the Supreme Court,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">then the decision of the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims rendered in accordance with the mandate of the United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit shall become final upon the expiration of 30 days from the time such decision of the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims was rendered, unless within such 30 days either the Secretary or the petitioner has instituted proceedings to have such decision corrected so that it will accord with the mandate, in which event the decision of the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims shall become final when so corrected.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> If the Supreme Court orders a rehearing, or if the case is remanded by the United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit to the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims for a rehearing, and if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the time allowed for filing a petition for certiorari has expired and no such petition has been duly filed, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the petition for certiorari has been denied, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the decision of the United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit has been affirmed by the Supreme Court,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">then the decision of the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims rendered upon such rehearing shall become final in the same manner as though no prior decision of the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims had been rendered.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> As used in this section, the term “mandate”, in case a mandate has been recalled before the expiration of 30 days from the date of issuance thereof, means the final mandate.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–687, div. A, title III, § 301(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4119</ref>, § 4091; renumbered § 7291 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–40, title IV, § 402(b)(1)</ref>, (d)(1), <date date="1991-05-07">May 7, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 238</ref>, 239; <ref>Pub. L. 102–83, § 4(b)(1)</ref>, (2)(E), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 404</ref>, 405; <ref>Pub. L. 105–368, title V, § 512(a)(1)</ref>, (2)(B), <date date="1998-11-11">Nov. 11, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3341</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7292.</num>
<heading> Review by United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> After a decision of the United States Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims is entered in a case, any party to the case may obtain a review of the decision with respect to the validity of a decision of the Court on a rule of law or of any statute or regulation (other than a refusal to review the schedule of ratings for disabilities adopted under <ref>section 1155 of this title</ref>) or any interpretation thereof (other than a determination as to a factual matter) that was relied on by the Court in making the decision. Such a review shall be obtained by filing a notice of appeal with the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims within the time and in the manner prescribed for appeal to United States courts of appeals from United States district courts.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> When a judge or panel of the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims, in making an order not otherwise appealable under this section, determines that a controlling question of law is involved with respect to which there is a substantial ground for difference of opinion and that there is in fact a disagreement between the appellant and the Secretary with respect to that question of law and that the ultimate termination of the case may be materially advanced by the immediate consideration of that question, the judge or panel shall notify the chief judge of that determination. Upon receiving such a notification, the chief judge shall certify that such a question is presented, and any party to the case may then petition the Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit to decide the question. That court may permit an interlocutory appeal to be taken on that question if such a petition is filed with it within 10 days after the certification by the chief judge of the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims. Neither the application for, nor the granting of, an appeal under this paragraph shall stay proceedings in the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims, unless a stay is ordered by a judge of the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims or by the Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> For purposes of subsections (d) and (e) of this section, an order described in this paragraph shall be treated as a decision of the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit shall have exclusive jurisdiction to review and decide any challenge to the validity of any statute or regulation or any interpretation thereof brought under this section, and to interpret constitutional and statutory provisions, to the extent presented and necessary to a decision. The judgment of such court shall be final subject to review by the Supreme Court upon certiorari, in the manner provided in <ref>section 1254 of title 28</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit shall decide all relevant questions of law, including interpreting constitutional and statutory provisions. The court shall hold unlawful and set aside any regulation or any interpretation thereof (other than a determination as to a factual matter) that was relied upon in the decision of the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims that the Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit finds to be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> arbitrary, capricious, an abuse of discretion, or otherwise not in accordance with law;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> contrary to constitutional right, power, privilege, or immunity;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> in excess of statutory jurisdiction, authority, or limitations, or in violation of a statutory right; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> without observance of procedure required by law.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Except to the extent that an appeal under this chapter presents a constitutional issue, the Court of Appeals may not review (A) a challenge to a factual determination, or (B) a challenge to a law or regulation as applied to the facts of a particular case.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Upon such review, the Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit shall have power to affirm or, if the decision of the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims is not in accordance with law, to modify or reverse the decision of the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims or to remand the matter, as appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Rules for review of decisions of the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims shall be those prescribed by the Supreme Court under <ref>section 2072 of title 28</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–687, div. A, title III, § 301(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4120</ref>, § 4092; amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–94, title III, § 302(b)</ref>, <date date="1989-08-16">Aug. 16, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 628</ref>; renumbered § 7292, <ref>Pub. L. 102–40, title IV, § 402(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-05-07">May 7, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 238</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–54, § 14(e)(5)</ref>, <date date="1991-06-13">June 13, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 287</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–83</ref>, §§ 4(b)(1), (2)(E), 5(c)(1), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 404–406</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–368, title V, § 512(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-11">Nov. 11, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3341</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–330, title IV, § 402(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-06">Dec. 6, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2832</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER V—</num>
<heading>RETIREMENT AND SURVIVORS ANNUITIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7296.</num>
<heading> Retirement of judges</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “Court” means the United States Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “judge” means a judge of the Court.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A judge who meets the age and service requirements set forth in the following table may retire:<table width="50%" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><colgroup><col/><col/></colgroup><thead><tr class="header"><th><p><b> The judge has attained age:</b></p></th><th><p><b>And the years of service as a judge are at least</b></p></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>65</span></p></td><td><p>15   </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>66</span></p></td><td><p>14   </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>67</span></p></td><td><p>13   </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>68</span></p></td><td><p>12   </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>69</span></p></td><td><p>11   </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>70</span></p></td><td><p>10   </p></td></tr></tbody></table>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A judge who is not reappointed following the expiration of the term for which appointed may retire upon the completion of that term if the judge has served as a judge of the Court for 15 years or more.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A judge who becomes permanently disabled and as a result of that disability is unable to perform the duties of the office shall retire.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> A judge who is appointed on or after the date of the enactment of the Veterans’ Benefits Improvement Act of 2008 and who retires under subsection (b) and elects under subsection (d) to receive retired pay under this subsection shall (except as provided in paragraph (2)) receive retired pay as follows:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> In the case of a judge who is a recall-eligible retired judge under <ref>section 7257 of this title</ref>, the retired pay of the judge shall (subject to <ref>section 7257(d)(2) of this title</ref>) be the rate of pay applicable to that judge at the time of retirement, as adjusted from time to time under subsection (f)(3).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> In the case of a judge other than a recall-eligible retired judge, the retired pay of the judge shall be the rate of pay applicable to that judge at the time of retirement.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> A judge who retired before the date of the enactment of the Veterans’ Benefits Improvement Act of 2008 and elected under subsection (d) to receive retired pay under this subsection, or a judge who retires under subsection (b) and elects under subsection (d) to receive retired pay under this subsection, shall (except as provided in paragraph (2)) receive retired pay as follows:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> In the case of a judge who is a recall-eligible retired judge under <ref>section 7257 of this title</ref> or who was a recall-eligible retired judge under that section and was removed from recall status under subsection (b)(4) of that section by reason of disability, the retired pay of the judge shall be the pay of a judge of the court.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> In the case of a judge who at the time of retirement did not provide notice under <ref>section 7257 of this title</ref> of availability for service in a recalled status, the retired pay of the judge shall be the rate of pay applicable to that judge at the time of retirement.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> In the case of a judge who was a recall-eligible retired judge under <ref>section 7257 of this title</ref> and was removed from recall status under subsection (b)(3) of that section, the retired pay of the judge shall be the pay of the judge at the time of the removal from recall status.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> An individual who serves as a judge for less than 10 years and who retires under subsection (b)(3) of this section and elects under subsection (d) of this section to receive retired pay under this subsection shall receive retired pay at a rate equal to one-half of the rate of pay in effect at the time of retirement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Retired pay under this subsection shall begin to accrue on the day following the day on which the individual’s salary as judge ceases to accrue and shall continue to accrue during the remainder of the individual’s life. Retired pay under this subsection shall be paid in the same manner as the salary of a judge.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> A judge may elect to receive retired pay under subsection (c) of this section. Such an election—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> may be made only while an individual is a judge (except that, in the case of an individual who fails to be reappointed as judge at the expiration of a term of office, the election may be made at any time before the date after the day on which the individual’s successor takes office); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> may not be revoked after the retired pay begins to accrue.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In the case of a judge other than the chief judge, such an election shall be made by filing notice of the election in writing with the chief judge. In the case of the chief judge, such an election shall be made by filing notice of the election in writing with the Director of the Office of Personnel Management.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The chief judge shall transmit to the Director of the Office of Personnel Management a copy of each notice filed with the chief judge under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> If an individual for whom an election to receive retired pay under subsection (c) is in effect accepts compensation for employment with the United States, the individual shall, to the extent of the amount of that compensation, forfeit all rights to retired pay under subsection (c) of this section for the period for which the compensation is received.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, the provisions of the civil service retirement laws (including the provisions relating to the deduction and withholding of amounts from basic pay, salary, and compensation) shall apply with respect to service as a judge as if this section had not been enacted.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> In the case of any individual who has filed an election to receive retired pay under subsection (c) of this section—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> no annuity or other payment shall be payable to any person under the civil service retirement laws with respect to any service performed by such individual (whether performed before or after such election is filed and whether performed as judge or otherwise) except as authorized by <ref>section 8440d of title 5</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> no deduction for purposes of the Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund shall be made from retired pay payable to that individual under subsection (c) of this section or from any other salary, pay, or compensation payable to that individual, for any period beginning after the day on which such election is filed; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> such individual shall be paid the lump-sum credit computed under section 8331(8) or 8401(a) of title 5, whichever applies, upon making application therefor with the Office of Personnel Management.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A cost-of-living adjustment provided by law in annuities payable under civil service retirement laws shall apply to retired pay under this section only in the case of retired pay computed under paragraph (1)(A)(i) or (2) of subsection (c).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> If such a cost-of-living adjustment would (but for this subparagraph) result in the retired pay of a retired judge being in excess of the annual rate of pay in effect for judges of the Court as provided in <ref>section 7253(e) of this title</ref>, such adjustment may be made only in such amount as results in the retired pay of the retired judge being equal to that annual rate of pay (as in effect on the effective date of such adjustment).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A judge who becomes permanently disabled and as a result of that disability is unable to perform the duties of the office shall certify to the President in writing that such permanent disability exists. If the chief judge retires for such a disability, the retirement of the chief judge shall not take effect until concurred in by the President. If any other judge retires for such a disability, the chief judge shall furnish to the President a certificate of disability signed by the chief judge.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Whenever the President finds that a judge has become permanently disabled and as a result of that disability is unable to perform the duties of the office, the President shall declare that judge to be retired. Before a judge may be retired under this paragraph, the judge shall be provided with a full specification of the reasons for the retirement and an opportunity to be heard.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> An individual who has filed an election to receive retired pay under subsection (c) of this section may revoke such election at any time before the first day on which retired pay would (but for such revocation) begin to accrue with respect to such individual.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any revocation under this subsection shall be made by filing a notice of the election in writing with the Director of the Office of Personnel Management. The Office of Personnel Management shall transmit to the chief judge a copy of each notice filed under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> In the case of a revocation under this subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> for purposes of this section, the individual shall be treated as not having filed an election to receive retired pay under subsection (c) of this section;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> for purposes of <ref>section 7297 of this title</ref>—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the individual shall be treated as not having filed an election under <ref>section 7297(b) of this title</ref>, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content><ref>section 7297(e) of this title</ref> shall not apply and the amount credited to such individual’s account (together with interest at 3 percent per year, compounded on December 31 of each year to the date on which the revocation is filed) shall be returned to the individual;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> no credit shall be allowed for any service as a judge of the Court unless with respect to such service either there has been deducted and withheld the amount required by the civil service retirement laws or there has been deposited in the Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund an amount equal to the amount so required, with interest;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Court shall deposit in the Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund an amount equal to the additional amount it would have contributed to such Fund but for the election under subsection (d); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> if subparagraphs (C) and (D) of this paragraph are complied with, service on the Court shall be treated as service with respect to which deductions and contributions had been made during the period of service.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Beginning with the next pay period after the Director of the Office of Personnel Management receives a notice under subsection (d) of this section that a judge has elected to receive retired pay under this section, the Director shall deduct and withhold 1 percent of the salary of such judge. Amounts shall be so deducted and withheld in a manner determined by the Director. Amounts deducted and withheld under this subsection shall be deposited in the Treasury of the United States to the credit of the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims Judges Retirement Fund. Deductions under this subsection from the salary of a judge shall terminate upon the retirement of the judge or upon the completion of 15 years of service for which either deductions under this subsection or a deposit under subsection (j) of this section has been made, whichever occurs first.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Each judge who makes an election under subsection (d) of this section shall be considered to agree to the deductions from salary which are made under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<content> A judge who makes an election under subsection (d) of this section shall deposit, for service on the Court performed before the election for which contributions may be made under this section, an amount equal to 1 percent of the salary received for the first years, not exceeding 15 years, of that service. Retired pay may not be allowed until a deposit required by this subsection has been made.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(k)</num>
<content> The amounts deducted and withheld under subsection (i) of this section, and the amounts deposited under subsection (j) of this section, shall be deposited in the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims Retirement Fund for credit to individual accounts in the name of each judge from whom such amounts are received.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–94, title I, § 101(a)</ref>, <date date="1989-08-16">Aug. 16, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 617</ref>, § 4096; renumbered § 7296 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–40, title IV, § 402(b)(1)</ref>, (d)(1), <date date="1991-05-07">May 7, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 238</ref>, 239; <ref>Pub. L. 102–82, § 5(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 376</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–198, § 7(c)(4)(D)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-09">Dec. 9, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1625</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–368, title V, § 512(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-11">Nov. 11, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3341</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–117, title X</ref>, §§ 1022, 1035(2), <date date="1999-11-30">Nov. 30, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1592</ref>, 1595; <ref>Pub. L. 107–103, title VI, § 602</ref>, <date date="2001-12-27">Dec. 27, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 999</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–389, title VI, § 603(b)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="2008-10-10">Oct. 10, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4177</ref>, 4178.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7297.</num>
<heading> Survivor annuities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “Court” means the United States Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “judge” means a judge of the Court who is in active service or who has retired under <ref>section 7296 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “pay” means salary received under <ref>section 7253(e) of this title</ref> and retired pay received under <ref>section 7296 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “retirement fund” means the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims Retirement Fund established under <ref>section 7298 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The term “surviving spouse” means a surviving spouse of an individual who (A) was married to such individual for at least one year immediately preceding the individual’s death, or (B) is a parent of issue by the marriage.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The term “dependent child” has the meaning given the term “child” in <ref>section 376(a)(5) of title 28</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The term “Member of Congress” means a Representative, a Senator, a Delegate to Congress, or the Resident Commissioner of Puerto Rico.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> The term “assassination” as applied to a judge shall have the meaning provided that term in <ref>section 376(a)(7) of title 28</ref> as applied to a judicial official.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> A judge may become a participant in the annuity program under this section by filing a written election under this subsection while in office or within six months after the date on which the judge marries if the judge has retired under <ref>section 7296 of this title</ref>. Any such election shall be made in such manner as may be prescribed by the Court.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> There shall be deducted and withheld each pay period from the pay of a judge who has made an election under subsection (b) of this section a sum equal to that percentage of the judge’s pay that is the same as provided for the deduction from the salary or retirement salary of a judge of the United States Court of Federal Claims for the purpose of a survivor annuity under <ref>section 376(b)(1)(B) of title 28</ref>. Amounts so deducted and withheld shall be deposited in the retirement fund. A judge who makes an election under subsection (b) of this section shall be considered by that election to agree to the deductions from the judge’s pay required by this subsection.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A judge who makes an election under subsection (b) of this section shall deposit, with interest at 3 percent per year compounded on December 31 of each year, to the credit of the retirement fund, an amount equal to 3.5 percent of the judge’s pay and of the judge’s basic salary, pay, or compensation for service as a Member of Congress, and for any other civilian service within the purview of <ref>section 8332 of title 5</ref>. Each such judge may elect to make such deposits in installments during the judge’s period of service in such amount and under such conditions as may be determined in each instance by the chief judge. Notwithstanding the failure of a judge to make such deposit, credit shall be allowed for the service rendered, but the annual annuity of the surviving spouse of such judge shall be reduced by an amount equal to 10 percent of the amount of such deposit, computed as of the date of the death of such judge, unless the surviving spouse elects to eliminate such service entirely from credit under subsection (k) of this section. However, a deposit shall not be required from a judge for any year with respect to which deductions from the judge’s pay, or a deposit, were actually made (and not withdrawn) under the civil service retirement laws.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The interest required under the first sentence of paragraph (1) shall not be required for any period—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> during which a judge was separated from any service described in <ref>section 376(d)(2) of title 28</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> during which the judge was not receiving retired pay based on service as a judge or receiving any retirement salary as described in <ref>section 376(d)(1) of title 28</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<chapeau> If the service of a judge who makes an election under subsection (b) of this section terminates other than pursuant to the provisions of <ref>section 7296 of this title</ref>, or if any judge ceases to be married after making the election under subsection (b) of this section and revokes (in a writing filed as provided in subsection (b) of this section) such election, the amount credited to the judge’s individual account (together with interest at 3 percent per year compounded on December 31 of each year to the date of the judge’s relinquishment of office) shall be returned to the judge. For the purpose of this section, the service of a judge making an election under subsection (b) of this section shall be considered to have terminated pursuant to <ref>section 7296 of this title</ref> if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the judge is not reappointed following expiration of the term for which appointed; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> at or before the time of the expiration of that term, the judge is eligible for and elects to receive retired pay under <ref>section 7296 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> If a judge who makes an election under subsection (b) of this section dies after having rendered at least 18 months of civilian service (computed as prescribed in subsection (<i>l</i>) of this section), for the last 18 months of which the salary deductions provided for by subsection (c) of this section or the deposits required by subsection (d) of this section have actually been made (and not withdrawn) or the salary deductions required by the civil service retirement laws have actually been made (and not withdrawn)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> if the judge is survived by a surviving spouse but not by a dependent child, there shall be paid to the surviving spouse an annuity beginning with the day of the death of the judge, in an amount computed as provided in subsection (k) of this section; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> if the judge is survived by a surviving spouse and a dependent child or children, there shall be paid to the surviving spouse an immediate annuity in an amount computed as provided in subsection (k) of this section and there shall also be paid to or on behalf of each such child an immediate annuity equal to the lesser of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> 10 percent of the average annual pay of such judge (determined in accordance with subsection (k) of this section), or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> 20 percent of such average annual pay, divided by the number of such children; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> if the judge is not survived by a surviving spouse but is survived by a dependent child or children, there shall be paid to or on behalf of each such child an immediate annuity equal to the lesser of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> 20 percent of the average annual pay of such judge (determined in accordance with subsection (k) of this section), or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> 40 percent of such average annual pay, divided by the number of such children.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The annuity payable to a surviving spouse under this subsection shall be terminated—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> upon the surviving spouse’s death; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> upon the remarriage of the surviving spouse before age 55.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The annuity payable to a child under this subsection shall be terminated upon the child’s death.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> In case of the death of a surviving spouse of a judge leaving a dependent child or children of the judge surviving the spouse, the annuity of such child or children under paragraph (1)(B) of this subsection shall be recomputed and paid as provided in paragraph (1)(C) of this subsection. In any case in which the annuity of a dependent child is terminated, the annuities of any remaining dependent child or children, based upon the service of the same judge, shall be recomputed and paid as though the child whose annuity was so terminated had not survived the judge.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> If a judge dies as a result of an assassination and leaves a survivor or survivors who are otherwise entitled to receive annuity payments under this section, the 18-month requirement in the matter in paragraph (1) preceding subparagraph (A) shall not apply.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> Questions of family relationships, dependency, and disability arising under this section shall be determined in the same manner as such questions arising under chapter 84 of title 5 are determined.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> If—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a judge making an election under subsection (b) of this section dies while in office (i) before having rendered 5 years of civilian service computed as prescribed in subsection (<i>l</i>) of this section, or (ii) after having rendered 5 years of such civilian service but without a survivor entitled to annuity benefits provided by subsection (f) of this section; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the right of all persons entitled to an annuity under subsection (f) of this section based on the service of such judge terminates before a claim for such benefits has been established,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">the total amount credited to the individual account of such judge (with interest at 3 percent per year, compounded on December 31 of each year, to the date of the death of such judge) shall be paid in the manner specified in paragraph (2) of this subsection.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> An amount payable under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be paid, upon the establishment of a valid claim therefor, to the person or persons surviving at the date title to the payment arises, in the following order of precedence:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> To the beneficiary or beneficiaries whom the judge designated in writing filed before death with the chief judge (except that in the case of the chief judge such designation shall be filed before death as prescribed by the Court).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> To the surviving spouse of the judge.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> To the child or children of the judge (and the descendants of any deceased children by representation).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> To the parents of the judge or the survivor of them.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> To the executor or administrator of the estate of the judge.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> To such other next of kin of the judge as may be determined by the chief judge to be entitled under the laws of the domicile of the judge at the time of the judge’s death.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Determination as to the surviving spouse, child, or parent of a judge for the purposes of paragraph (2) of this subsection shall be made without regard to the definitions in subsection (a) of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Payment under this subsection in the manner provided in this subsection shall be a bar to recovery by any other person.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> In a case in which the annuities of all persons entitled to annuity based upon the service of a judge terminate before the aggregate amount of annuity paid equals the total amount credited to the individual account of such judge (with interest at 3 percent per year, compounded on December 31 of each year to the date of the death of the judge), the difference shall be paid, upon establishment of a valid claim therefor, in the order of precedence prescribed in paragraph (2) of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> Any accrued annuity remaining unpaid upon the termination (other than by death) of the annuity of any individual based upon the service of a judge shall be paid to that individual. Any accrued annuity remaining unpaid upon the death of an individual receiving an annuity based upon the service of a judge shall be paid, upon the establishment of a valid claim therefor, in the following order of precedence:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> To the executor or administrator of the estate of that person.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> After 30 days after the date of the death of such individual, to such individual or individuals as may appear in the judgment of the chief judge to be legally entitled thereto.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Such payment shall be a bar to recovery by any other individual.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> When a payment under this section is to be made to a minor, or to a person mentally incompetent or under other legal disability adjudged by a court of competent jurisdiction, the payment may be made to the person who is constituted guardian or other fiduciary by the law of the State of residence of such claimant or is otherwise legally vested with the care of the claimant or the claimant’s estate. If no guardian or other fiduciary of the person under legal disability has been appointed under the laws of the State of residence of the claimant, the chief judge shall determine the person who is otherwise legally vested with the care of the claimant or the claimant’s estate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<content> Annuities under this section shall accrue monthly and shall be due and payable in monthly installments on the first business day of the month following the month or other period for which the annuity has accrued. An annuity under this section is not assignable, either in law or in equity, or subject to execution, levy, attachment, garnishment, or other legal process.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(k)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The annuity of the surviving spouse of a judge making an election under subsection (b) of this section shall be an amount equal to the sum of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> The product of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> 1.5 percent of the judge’s average annual pay; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the sum of the judge’s years of judicial service, the judge’s years of prior allowable service as a Member of Congress, the judge’s years of prior allowable service performed as a member of the Armed Forces, and the judge’s years, not exceeding 15, of prior allowable service performed as a congressional employee (as defined in <ref>section 2107 of title 5</ref>).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Three-fourths of 1 percent of the judge’s average annual pay multiplied by the judge’s years of allowable service not counted under subparagraph (A) of this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> An annuity computed under this subsection may not exceed 50 percent of the judge’s average annual pay and may not be less than 25 percent of such average annual pay. Such annuity shall be further reduced in accordance with subsection (d) of this section (if applicable).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> For purposes of this subsection, the term “average annual pay”, with respect to a judge, means the average annual pay received by the judge for judicial service (including periods in which the judge received retired pay under <ref>section 7296(d) of this title</ref>) or for any other prior allowable service during the period of three consecutive years in which the judge received the largest such average annual pay.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(l)</num>
<content> Subject to subsection (d) of this section, the years of service of a judge which are allowable as the basis for calculating the amount of the annuity of the judge’s surviving spouse shall include the judge’s years of service as a judge of the Court, the judge’s years of service as a Member of Congress, the judge’s years of active service as a member of the Armed Forces not exceeding 5 years in the aggregate and not including any such service for which credit is allowed for the purposes of retirement or retired pay under any other provision of law, and the judge’s years of any other civilian service within the purview of <ref>section 8332 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(m)</num>
<content> Nothing contained in this section shall be construed to prevent a surviving spouse eligible therefor from simultaneously receiving an annuity under this section and any annuity to which such spouse would otherwise be entitled under any other law without regard to this section, but in computing such other annuity service used in the computation of such spouse’s annuity under this section shall not be credited.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(n)</num>
<content> A judge making an election under subsection (b) of this section shall, at the time of such election, waive all benefits under the civil service retirement laws except <ref>section 8440d of title 5</ref>. Such a waiver shall be made in the same manner and shall have the same force and effect as an election filed under <ref>section 7296(d) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(o)</num>
<content> Each survivor annuity payable from the retirement fund shall be increased at the same time as, and by the same percentage by which, annuities payable from the Judicial Survivors’ Annuities Fund are increased pursuant to <ref>section 376(m) of title 28</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(p)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A covered judge who makes an election under subsection (b) may purchase, in 3-month increments, up to an additional year of service credit for each year of Federal judicial service completed, under the terms set forth in this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> In this subsection, the term “covered judge” means any of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A judge in regular active service.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A retired judge who is a recall-eligible retired judge pursuant to subsection (a) of <ref>section 7257 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> A retired judge who would be a recall-eligible retired judge pursuant to subsection (a) of section 7257 but for—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> meeting the aggregate recall service requirements under subsection (b)(3) of such section; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> being permanently disabled as described by subsection (b)(4) of such section.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–94, title I, § 101(a)</ref>, <date date="1989-08-16">Aug. 16, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 620</ref>, § 4097; renumbered § 7297 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–40, title IV, § 402(b)(1)</ref>, (d)(1), <date date="1991-05-07">May 7, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 238</ref>, 239; <ref>Pub. L. 102–54, § 14(e)(6)</ref>, <date date="1991-06-13">June 13, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 287</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–82, § 5(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 376</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–198, § 7(c)(4)(E)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-09">Dec. 9, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1625</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–368, title V</ref>, §§ 503, 512(a)(1), <date date="1998-11-11">Nov. 11, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3340</ref>, 3341; <ref>Pub. L. 106–117, title X</ref>, §§ 1023, 1035(2), <date date="1999-11-30">Nov. 30, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1592</ref>, 1595; <ref>Pub. L. 114–315, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1549</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7298.</num>
<heading> Retirement Fund</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> There is established in the Treasury a fund known as the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims Retirement Fund.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Amounts in the fund are available for the payment of judges’ retired pay under <ref>section 7296 of this title</ref> and of annuities, refunds, and allowances under <ref>section 7297 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Amounts deposited by, or deducted and withheld from the salary and retired pay of, a judge under section 7296 or 7297 of this title shall be deposited in the fund and credited to an individual account of the judge.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The chief judge of the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims shall submit to the President an annual estimate of the expenditures and appropriations necessary for the maintenance and operation of the fund, and such supplemental and deficiency estimates as may be required from time to time for the same purposes, according to law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The chief judge may cause periodic examinations of the retirement fund to be made by an actuary, who may be an actuary employed by another department of the Government temporarily assigned for the purpose.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Subject to the availability of appropriations, there shall be deposited in the Treasury to the credit of the retirement fund, not later than the close of each fiscal year, such amounts as may be required to reduce to zero the unfunded liability (if any) of the fund. Such deposits shall be taken from sums available for that fiscal year for the payment of the expenses of the Court.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of subparagraph (A) of this paragraph, the term “unfunded liability”, with respect to any fiscal year, means the amount estimated by the chief judge to be equal to the excess (as of the close of that fiscal year) of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the present value of all benefits payable from the fund (determined on an annual basis in accordance with <ref>section 9503 of title 31</ref>), over</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> the sum of—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the present values of future deductions under sections 7296(i) and 7297(c) of this title and future deposits under sections 7296(j) and 7296(d) of this title, and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the balance in the fund as of the close of the fiscal year.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> For purposes of subparagraph (B), the term “present value” includes a value determined by an actuary with respect to a payment that may be made under subsection (b) from the retirement fund within the contemplation of law.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Amounts deposited in the retirement fund under this paragraph shall not be credited to the account of any individual.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Treasury shall invest from time to time, in interest-bearing securities of the United States, such portions of the retirement fund as in such Secretary’s judgment may not be immediately required for payments from the fund. The income derived from such investments shall constitute a part of the fund.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> For purpose of section 255(g)(1)(B) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 (<ref>2 U.S.C. 905(g)(1)(B)</ref>), the retirement fund shall be treated in the same manner as the Claims Judges’ Retirement Fund.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–94, title I, § 101(a)</ref>, <date date="1989-08-16">Aug. 16, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 625</ref>, § 4098; renumbered § 7298 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–40, title IV, § 402(b)(1)</ref>, (d)(1), <date date="1991-05-07">May 7, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 238</ref>, 239; <ref>Pub. L. 105–368, title V</ref>, §§ 502, 512(a)(1), (2)(C), <date date="1998-11-11">Nov. 11, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3340</ref>, 3341; <ref>Pub. L. 106–117, title X, § 1011(j)</ref>, <date date="1999-11-30">Nov. 30, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1589</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7299.</num>
<heading> Limitation on activities of retired judges</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> A retired judge of the Court who is recall-eligible under <ref>section 7257 of this title</ref> and who in the practice of law represents (or supervises or directs the representation of) a client in making any claim relating to veterans’ benefits against the United States or any agency thereof shall, pursuant to such section, be considered to have declined recall service and be removed from the status of a recall-eligible judge. The pay of such a judge, pursuant to <ref>section 7296 of this title</ref>, shall be the pay of the judge at the time of the removal from recall status.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> A recall-eligible judge shall be considered to be an officer or employee of the United States, but only during periods when the judge is serving in recall status. Any prohibition, limitation, or restriction that would otherwise apply to the activities of a recall-eligible judge shall apply only during periods when the judge is serving in recall status.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–117, title X, § 1024(a)</ref>, <date date="1999-11-30">Nov. 30, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1593</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>