<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 61—</num>
<heading>PENAL AND FORFEITURE PROVISIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6101.</num>
<heading> Misappropriation by fiduciaries</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Whoever, being a fiduciary (as defined in <ref>section 5506 of this title</ref>) for the benefit of a minor, incompetent, or other beneficiary under laws administered by the Secretary, shall lend, borrow, pledge, hypothecate, use, or exchange for other funds or property, except as authorized by law, or embezzle or in any manner misappropriate any such money or property derived therefrom in whole or in part and coming into such fiduciary’s control in any manner whatever in the execution of such fiduciary’s trust, or under color of such fiduciary’s office or service as such fiduciary, shall be fined in accordance with title 18, or imprisoned not more than five years, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Any willful neglect or refusal to make and file proper accountings or reports concerning such money or property as required by law shall be taken to be sufficient evidence prima facie of such embezzlement or misappropriation.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–857</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1239</ref>, § 3501; <ref>Pub. L. 99–576, title VII, § 701(82)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-28">Oct. 28, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3298</ref>; renumbered § 6101, <ref>Pub. L. 102–40, title IV, § 402(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-05-07">May 7, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 238</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–54, § 14(d)(7)</ref>, <date date="1991-06-13">June 13, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 286</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–83, § 4(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 403</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–446, title XII, § 1201(e)(17)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4686</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–454, title V, § 501(c)</ref>, <date date="2004-12-10">Dec. 10, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3618</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6102.</num>
<heading> Fraudulent acceptance of payments</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Any person entitled to monetary benefits under any of the laws administered by the Secretary whose right to payment thereof ceases upon the happening of any contingency, who thereafter fraudulently accepts any such payment, shall be fined in accordance with title 18, or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Whoever obtains or receives any money or check under any of the laws administered by the Secretary without being entitled to it, and with intent to defraud the United States or any beneficiary of the United States, shall be fined in accordance with title 18, or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–857</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1239</ref>, § 3502; renumbered § 6102, <ref>Pub. L. 102–40, title IV, § 402(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-05-07">May 7, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 238</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–54, § 14(d)(7)</ref>, <date date="1991-06-13">June 13, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 286</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–83, § 4(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 403</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6103.</num>
<heading> Forfeiture for fraud</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Whoever knowingly makes or causes to be made or conspires, combines, aids, or assists in, agrees to, arranges for, or in any way procures the making or presentation of a false or fraudulent affidavit, declaration, certificate, statement, voucher, or paper, concerning any claim for benefits under any of the laws administered by the Secretary (except laws pertaining to insurance benefits) shall forfeit all rights, claims, and benefits under all laws administered by the Secretary (except laws pertaining to insurance benefits).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Whenever a veteran entitled to disability compensation has forfeited the right to such compensation under this section, the compensation payable but for the forfeiture shall thereafter be paid to the veteran’s spouse, children, and parents. Payments made to a spouse, children, and parents under the preceding sentence shall not exceed the amounts payable to each if the veteran had died from service-connected disability. No spouse, child, or parent who participated in the fraud for which forfeiture was imposed shall receive any payment by reason of this subsection. An apportionment award under this subsection may not be made in any case after <date date="1959-09-01">September 1, 1959</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Forfeiture of benefits by a veteran shall not prohibit payment of the burial allowance, death compensation, dependency and indemnity compensation, or death pension in the event of the veteran’s death.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> After <date date="1959-09-01">September 1, 1959</date>, no forfeiture of benefits may be imposed under this section or <ref>section 6104 of this title</ref> upon any individual who was a resident of, or domiciled in, a State at the time the act or acts occurred on account of which benefits would, but not for this subsection, be forfeited unless such individual ceases to be a resident of, or domiciled in, a State before the expiration of the period during which criminal prosecution could be instituted. This subsection shall not apply with respect to (A) any forfeiture occurring before <date date="1959-09-01">September 1, 1959</date>, or (B) an act or acts which occurred in the Philippine Islands before <date date="1946-07-04">July 4, 1946</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary is hereby authorized and directed to review all cases in which, because of a false or fraudulent affidavit, declaration, certificate, statement, voucher, or paper, a forfeiture of gratuitous benefits under laws administered by the Secretary was imposed, pursuant to this section or prior provisions of law, on or before <date date="1959-09-01">September 1, 1959</date>. In any such case in which the Secretary determines that the forfeiture would not have been imposed under the provisions of this section in effect after <date date="1959-09-01">September 1, 1959</date>, the Secretary shall remit the forfeiture, effective <date date="1972-06-30">June 30, 1972</date>. Benefits to which the individual concerned becomes eligible by virtue of any such remission may be awarded, upon application therefor, and the effective date of any award of compensation, dependency and indemnity compensation, or pension made in such a case shall be fixed in accordance with the provisions of <ref>section 5110(g) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–857</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1240</ref>, § 3503; <ref>Pub. L. 86–222, § 1</ref>, <date date="1959-09-01">Sept. 1, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 452</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–24, § 13(a)</ref>, <date date="1969-06-11">June 11, 1969</date>, <ref>83 Stat. 34</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–328, title II, § 206</ref>, <date date="1972-06-30">June 30, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 397</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–160, title VII, § 703(6)</ref>, <date date="1983-11-21">Nov. 21, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 1011</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–576, title VII, § 701(83)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-28">Oct. 28, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3298</ref>; renumbered § 6103 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–40, title IV, § 402(b)(1)</ref>, (d)(1), <date date="1991-05-07">May 7, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 238</ref>, 239; <ref>Pub. L. 102–54, § 14(d)(8)</ref>, <date date="1991-06-13">June 13, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 286</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–83, § 4(a)(1)</ref>, (b)(1), (2)(E), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 403–405</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–446, title XII, § 1201(e)(18)</ref>, (f)(5), <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4686</ref>, 4687.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6104.</num>
<heading> Forfeiture for treason</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Any person shown by evidence satisfactory to the Secretary to be guilty of mutiny, treason, sabotage, or rendering assistance to an enemy of the United States or of its allies shall forfeit all accrued or future gratuitous benefits under laws administered by the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Secretary, in the Secretary’s discretion, may apportion and pay any part of benefits forfeited under subsection (a) to the dependents of the person forfeiting such benefits. No dependent of any person shall receive benefits by reason of this subsection in excess of the amount to which the dependent would be entitled if such person were dead.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> In the case of any forfeiture under this section there shall be no authority after <date date="1959-09-01">September 1, 1959</date> (1) to make an apportionment award pursuant to subsection (b) or (2) to make an award to any person of gratuitous benefits based on any period of military, naval, air, or space service commencing before the date of commission of the offense.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–857</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1240</ref>, § 3504; <ref>Pub. L. 86–222, § 2</ref>, <date date="1959-09-01">Sept. 1, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 452</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–24, § 13(b)</ref>, <date date="1969-06-11">June 11, 1969</date>, <ref>83 Stat. 34</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–295, § 4(78)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-12">Oct. 12, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1311</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–576, title VII, § 701(84)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-28">Oct. 28, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3298</ref>; renumbered § 6104, <ref>Pub. L. 102–40, title IV, § 402(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-05-07">May 7, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 238</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–83, § 4(a)(1)</ref>, (b)(1), (2)(E), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 403–405</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 926(a)(56)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3830</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6105.</num>
<heading> Forfeiture for subversive activities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Any individual who is convicted after <date date="1959-09-01">September 1, 1959</date>, of any offense listed in subsection (b) of this section shall, from and after the date of commission of such offense, have no right to gratuitous benefits (including the right to burial in a national cemetery) under laws administered by the Secretary based on periods of military, naval, air, or space service commencing before the date of the commission of such offense and no other person shall be entitled to such benefits on account of such individual. After receipt of notice of the return of an indictment for such an offense the Secretary shall suspend payment of such gratuitous benefits pending disposition of the criminal proceedings. If any individual whose right to benefits has been terminated pursuant to this section is granted a pardon of the offense by the President of the United States, the right to such benefits shall be restored as of the date of such pardon.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> The offenses referred to in subsection (a) of this section are those offenses for which punishment is prescribed in—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> sections 894, 904, and 906 of title 10 (articles 94, 104, and 106 of the Uniform Code of Military Justice);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> sections 175, 229, 792, 793, 794, 798, 831, 1091, 2332a, 2332b, 2381, 2382, 2383, 2384, 2385, 2387, 2388, 2389, 2390, and chapter 105 of title 18;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> sections 222, 223, 224, 225, and 226 of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 2272</ref>, 2273, 2274, 2275, and 2276); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> section 4 of the Internal Security Act of 1950 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 783</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of Homeland Security, as appropriate, shall notify the Secretary in each case in which an individual is convicted of an offense listed in paragraph (1) of subsection (b). The Attorney General shall notify the Secretary in each case in which an individual is indicted or convicted of an offense listed in paragraph (2), (3), or (4) of subsection (b).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 86–222, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="1959-09-01">Sept. 1, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 453</ref>, § 3505; amended <ref>Pub. L. 92–128, § 2(c)</ref>, <date date="1971-09-25">Sept. 25, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 348</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–43, § 8</ref>, <date date="1973-06-18">June 18, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 88</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–295, § 4(79)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-12">Oct. 12, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1311</ref>; renumbered § 6105, <ref>Pub. L. 102–40, title IV, § 402(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-05-07">May 7, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 238</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–54, § 14(d)(9)</ref>, <date date="1991-06-13">June 13, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 287</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–83, § 4(a)(1)</ref>, (2)(A)(xiv), (b)(1), (2)(E), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 403–405</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–446, title XII, § 1201(e)(19)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4686</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–296, title XVII, § 1704(d)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2315</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–183, title VII, § 705(a)</ref>, <date date="2003-12-16">Dec. 16, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2672</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 926(a)(57)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3830</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6106.</num>
<heading> Misuse of benefits by fiduciaries</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Fee Forfeiture in Case of Benefit Misuse by Fiduciaries</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A fiduciary may not collect a fee from a beneficiary for any month with respect to which the Secretary or a court of competent jurisdiction has determined that the fiduciary misused all or part of the individual’s benefit, and any amount so collected by the fiduciary as a fee for such month shall be treated as a misused part of the individual’s benefit.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Misuse of Benefits Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of this chapter, misuse of benefits by a fiduciary occurs in any case in which the fiduciary receives payment, under any of laws administered by the Secretary, for the use and benefit of a beneficiary and uses such payment, or any part thereof, for a use other than for the use and benefit of such beneficiary or that beneficiary’s dependents. Retention by a fiduciary of an amount of a benefit payment as a fiduciary fee or commission, or as attorney’s fees (including expenses) and court costs, if authorized by the Secretary or a court of competent jurisdiction, shall be considered to be for the use or benefit of such beneficiary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may prescribe by regulation the meaning of the term “use and benefit” for purposes of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–454, title V, § 503(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2004-12-10">Dec. 10, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3619</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6107.</num>
<heading> Reissuance of benefits</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Negligent Failure by Secretary</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In any case in which the negligent failure of the Secretary to investigate or monitor a fiduciary results in misuse of benefits by the fiduciary, the Secretary shall pay to the beneficiary or the beneficiary’s successor fiduciary an amount equal to the amount of benefits that were so misused.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> There shall be considered to have been a negligent failure by the Secretary to investigate and monitor a fiduciary in the following cases:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A case in which the Secretary failed to review a fiduciary’s accounting within 60 days of the date on which that accounting is scheduled for review.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A case in which the Secretary was notified of allegations of misuse, but failed to act within 60 days of the date of such notification to terminate the fiduciary.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> In any other case in which actual negligence is shown.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reissuance of Misused Benefits in Other Cases</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In any case not covered by subsection (a) in which a fiduciary misuses all or part of an individual’s benefit paid to such fiduciary, the Secretary shall pay to the beneficiary or the beneficiary’s successor fiduciary an amount equal to the amount of such benefit so misused.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In any other case in which the Secretary obtains recoupment from a fiduciary who has misused benefits, the Secretary shall promptly remit payment of the recouped amounts to the beneficiary or the beneficiary’s successor fiduciary as the case may be.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reissuance of Amounts in the Case of a Deceased Beneficiary</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> If a beneficiary described in subsection (a) predeceases a payment under subsection (a) or (b), the Secretary shall pay such benefits, subject to paragraph (2), to an individual or entity in accordance with <ref>section 5121 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary may not make a payment under this subsection to a fiduciary who misused benefits of the beneficiary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Total Amount Paid</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The total of the amounts paid to a beneficiary (or a beneficiary’s successor fiduciary) under this section may not exceed the total benefit amount misused by the fiduciary with respect to that beneficiary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Recoupment of Amounts Reissued</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In any case in which the Secretary reissues a benefit payment (in whole or in part) under this section, the Secretary shall make a good faith effort to obtain recoupment from the fiduciary to whom the payment was originally made.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–454, title V, § 503(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2004-12-10">Dec. 10, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3619</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–315, title VII, § 7005(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-05">Jan. 5, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 5059</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–114, § 2</ref>, <date date="2024-11-25">Nov. 25, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1605</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6108.</num>
<heading> Authority for judicial orders of restitution</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Any Federal court, when sentencing a defendant convicted of an offense arising from the misuse of benefits under this title, may order, in addition to or in lieu of any other penalty authorized by law, that the defendant make restitution to the Department.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Sections 3612, 3663, and 3664 of title 18 shall apply with respect to the issuance and enforcement of orders of restitution under subsection (a). In so applying those sections, the Department shall be considered the victim.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> If the court does not order restitution, or orders only partial restitution, under subsection (a), the court shall state on the record the reasons therefor.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Amounts received in connection with misuse by a fiduciary of funds paid as benefits under laws administered by the Secretary shall be paid to the individual whose benefits were misused. If the Secretary has previously reissued the misused benefits, the amounts shall be treated in the same manner as overpayments recouped by the Secretary and shall be deposited to the credit of the applicable revolving fund, trust fund, or appropriation.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–454, title V, § 504(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2004-12-10">Dec. 10, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3621</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>