<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 63—</num>
<heading>OUTREACH ACTIVITIES</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>OUTREACH SERVICES PROGRAM</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6301.</num>
<heading> Purpose; definitions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Purpose</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Congress declares that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the outreach services program authorized by this subchapter is for the purpose of ensuring that all veterans (especially those who have been recently discharged or released from active military, naval, air, or space service, or from a reserve component, and those who are eligible for readjustment or other benefits and services under laws administered by the Department) are provided timely and appropriate assistance to aid and encourage them in applying for and obtaining such benefits and services in order that they may achieve a rapid social and economic readjustment to civilian life and obtain a higher standard of living for themselves and their dependents; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the outreach services program authorized by this subchapter is for the purpose of charging the Department with the affirmative duty of seeking out eligible veterans and eligible dependents and providing them with such services.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For the purposes of this subchapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “outreach” means the act or process of reaching out in a systematic manner to proactively provide information, services, and benefits counseling to veterans, and to the spouses, children, and parents of veterans who may be eligible to receive benefits under the laws administered by the Secretary, to ensure that such individuals are fully informed about, and receive assistance in applying for, such benefits;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “other governmental programs” includes all programs under State or local laws as well as all programs under Federal law other than those authorized by this title; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “eligible dependent” means a spouse, surviving spouse, child, or dependent parent of a person who served in the active military, naval, air, or space service.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–233, title IV, § 402(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-06-15">June 15, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 407</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title XVII, § 1710</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 494</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 926(a)(58)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3830</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–205, § 2(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2022-10-17">Oct. 17, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2233</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6302.</num>
<heading> Biennial plan</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Biennial Plan Required</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall, during the first nine months of every odd-numbered year, prepare a biennial plan for the outreach activities of the Department for the two-fiscal-year period beginning on October 1 of that year.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each biennial plan under subsection (a) shall include the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Plans for efforts to identify eligible veterans and eligible dependents who are not enrolled or registered with the Department for benefits or services under the programs administered by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Plans for informing eligible veterans and eligible dependents of modifications of the benefits and services under the programs administered by the Secretary, including eligibility for medical and nursing care and services.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Coordination in Development</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In developing the biennial plan under subsection (a), the Secretary shall consult with the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Directors or other appropriate officials of organizations approved by the Secretary under <ref>section 5902 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Directors or other appropriate officials of State and local education and training programs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Representatives of nongovernmental organizations that carry out veterans outreach programs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Representatives of State and local veterans employment organizations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Other individuals and organizations that the Secretary considers appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–233, title IV, § 402(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-06-15">June 15, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 408</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6303.</num>
<heading> Outreach services</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirement To Provide Services</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In carrying out the purposes of this subchapter, the Secretary shall provide the outreach services specified in subsections (b) through (d). In areas where a significant number of eligible veterans and eligible dependents speak a language other than English as their principal language, such services shall, to the maximum feasible extent, be provided in the principal language of such persons.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Individual Notice to New Veterans</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall by letter advise each veteran at the time of the veteran’s discharge or release from active military, naval, air, or space service (or as soon as possible after such discharge or release) of all benefits and services under laws administered by the Department for which the veteran may be eligible. In carrying out this subsection, the Secretary shall ensure, through the use of veteran-student services under <ref>section 3485 of this title</ref>, that contact, in person or by telephone, is made with those veterans who, on the basis of their military service records, do not have a high school education or equivalent at the time of discharge or release.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Distribution of Information</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall distribute full information to eligible veterans and eligible dependents regarding all benefits and services to which they may be entitled under laws administered by the Secretary; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> may, to the extent feasible, distribute information on other governmental programs (including manpower and training programs) which the Secretary determines would be beneficial to veterans.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Whenever a veteran or dependent first applies for any benefit under laws administered by the Secretary (including a request for burial or related benefits or an application for life insurance proceeds), the Secretary shall provide to the veteran or dependent information concerning benefits and health care services under programs administered by the Secretary. Such information shall be provided not later than three months after the date of such application.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Provision of Aid and Assistance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall provide, to the maximum extent possible, aid and assistance (including personal interviews) to members of the Armed Forces, veterans, and eligible dependents with respect to subsections (b) and (c) and in the preparation and presentation of claims under laws administered by the Department.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Assignment of Employees</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall assign such employees as the Secretary considers appropriate to conduct outreach programs and provide outreach services for homeless veterans. Such outreach services may include site visits through which homeless veterans can be identified and provided assistance in obtaining benefits and services that may be available to them.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–233, title IV, § 402(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-06-15">June 15, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 408</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 926(a)(59)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3830</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–205, § 2(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2022-10-17">Oct. 17, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2233</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6304.</num>
<heading> Veterans assistance offices</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall establish and maintain veterans assistance offices at such places throughout the United States and its territories and possessions, and in the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, as the Secretary determines to be necessary to carry out the purposes of this subchapter. The Secretary may maintain such offices on such military installations located elsewhere as the Secretary, after consultation with the Secretary of Defense and taking into account recommendations, if any, of the Secretary of Labor, determines to be necessary to carry out such purposes.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Location of Offices</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In establishing and maintaining such offices, the Secretary shall give due regard to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the geographical distribution of veterans recently discharged or released from active military, naval, air, or space service;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the special needs of educationally disadvantaged veterans (including their need for accessibility of outreach services); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the necessity of providing appropriate outreach services in less populated areas.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–233, title IV, § 402(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-06-15">June 15, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 409</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 926(a)(60)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3830</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–205, § 2(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2022-10-17">Oct. 17, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2233</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6305.</num>
<heading> Outstationing of counseling and outreach personnel</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary may station employees of the Department at locations other than Department offices, including educational institutions, to provide—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> counseling and other assistance regarding benefits under this title to veterans and other persons eligible for benefits under this title; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> outreach services under this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–233, title IV, § 402(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-06-15">June 15, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 409</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 117–205, § 2(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2022-10-17">Oct. 17, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2233</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6306.</num>
<heading> Use of other agencies</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> In carrying out this subchapter, the Secretary shall arrange with the Secretary of Labor for the State employment service to match the particular qualifications of an eligible veteran or eligible dependent with an appropriate job or job training opportunity, including, where possible, arrangements for outstationing the State employment personnel who provide such assistance at appropriate facilities of the Department.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> In carrying out this subchapter, the Secretary shall, in consultation with the Secretary of Labor, actively seek to promote the development and establishment of employment opportunities, training opportunities, and other opportunities for veterans, with particular emphasis on the needs of veterans with service-connected disabilities and other eligible veterans, taking into account applicable rates of unemployment and the employment emphases set forth in chapter 42 of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> In carrying out this subchapter, the Secretary shall cooperate with and use the services of any Federal department or agency or any State or local governmental agency or recognized national or other organization.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> In carrying out this subchapter, the Secretary shall, where appropriate, make referrals to any Federal department or agency or State or local governmental unit or recognized national or other organization.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> In carrying out this subchapter, the Secretary may furnish available space and office facilities for the use of authorized representatives of such governmental unit or other organization providing services.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> In carrying out this subchapter, the Secretary shall conduct and provide for studies, in consultation with appropriate Federal departments and agencies, to determine the most effective program design to carry out the purposes of this subchapter.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–233, title IV, § 402(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-06-15">June 15, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 409</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 117–205, § 2(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2022-10-17">Oct. 17, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2233</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6307.</num>
<heading> Grants to States and Indian Tribes to improve outreach to veterans</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Purpose</inline>.—</heading>
<content>It is the purpose of this section to provide for assistance by the Secretary to States and Indian Tribes to carry out programs that improve covered outreach and assistance to veterans and the spouses, children, and parents of veterans, to ensure that such individuals are fully informed about, and assisted in applying for, any veterans and veterans-related benefits and programs (including veterans programs of a State or Indian Tribe) for which they may be eligible and facilitate opportunities for such individuals to receive competent, qualified services in the preparation, presentation and prosecution of veterans benefits claims.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary may award grants to States and Indian Tribes—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> to carry out, coordinate, improve, or otherwise enhance—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> covered outreach activities; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> activities to assist in the development and submittal of claims for veterans and veterans-related benefits; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to increase the number of county or Tribal veterans service officers serving in the State by hiring new, additional such officers.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Application</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> To be eligible for a grant under this section, a State or Indian Tribe shall submit to the Secretary an application therefor at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Each application submitted under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A detailed plan for the use of the grant.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A description of the programs through which the State or Indian Tribe will meet the outcome measures developed by the Secretary under subsection (j).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> A description of how the State or Indian Tribe will distribute grant amounts equitably among counties or Tribal lands with varying levels of urbanization.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> A plan for how the grant will be used to meet the unique needs of American Indian veterans, Alaska Native veterans, or Native Hawaiian veterans, elderly veterans, and veterans from other underserved communities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Distribution</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall seek to ensure that grants awarded under this section are equitably distributed among States and Indian Tribes with varying levels of urbanization.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Set-aside</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Of the amounts authorized to be appropriated or otherwise made available for grants under this section for any fiscal year, the Secretary shall ensure that not less than five percent is used to make grants to Indian Tribes.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Priority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall prioritize awarding grants under this section that will serve the following areas:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Areas with a critical shortage of county or Tribal veterans service officers.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Areas with high rates of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> suicide among veterans; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> referrals to the Veterans Crisis Line.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of County or Tribal Veterans Service Officers</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A State or Indian Tribe that receives a grant under this section to carry out an activity described in subsection (b)(1) shall carry out the activity through—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a county or Tribal veterans service officer of the State; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> if the State or Indian Tribe does not have a county or Tribal veterans service officer, or if the county or Tribal veterans service officers of the State or Indian Tribe cover only a portion of that State or Indian Tribe, an appropriate entity of a State, local, or Tribal government, as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Required Activities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Any grant awarded under this section shall be used—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to expand existing programs, activities, and services;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to hire new, additional county or Tribal veterans service officers; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> for travel and transportation to facilitate carrying out paragraph (1) or (2).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authorized Activities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A grant under this section may be used to provide education and training, including on-the-job training, for State, county, local, and Tribal government employees who provide (or when trained will provide) covered outreach services in order for those employees to obtain accreditation in accordance with procedures approved by the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Outcome Measures</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary shall develop and provide to each State or Indian Tribe that receives a grant under this section written guidance on the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Outcome measures.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Policies of the Department.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> In developing outcome measures under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall consider the following goals:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Increasing the use of veterans and veterans-related benefits, particularly among vulnerable populations.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Increasing the number of county and Tribal veterans service officers recognized by the Secretary for the representation of veterans under chapter 59 of this title.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(k)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Tracking Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> With respect to each grant awarded under this section, the Secretary shall track the use of veterans and veterans-related benefits among the population served by the grant, including the average period of time between the date on which a veteran applies for such a benefit and the date on which the veteran receives the benefit, disaggregated by type of benefit.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Not less frequently than annually during the life of the grant program established under this section, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the information tracked under paragraph (1);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> how the grants awarded under this section serve the unique needs of American Indian veterans, Alaska Native veterans, or Native Hawaiian veterans, elderly veterans, and veterans from other underserved communities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> other information provided by States and Indian Tribes pursuant to the grant reporting requirements.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(l)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Performance Review</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> review the performance of each State or Indian Tribe that receives a grant under this section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> make information regarding such performance publicly available.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(m)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Remediation Plan</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In the case of a State or Indian Tribe that receives a grant under this section and does not meet the outcome measures developed by the Secretary under subsection (j), the Secretary shall require the State or Indian Tribe to submit a remediation plan under which the State shall describe how and when it plans to meet such outcome measures.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary may not award a subsequent grant under this section to a State or Indian Tribe described in paragraph (1) unless the Secretary approves the remediation plan submitted by the State or Indian Tribe.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(n)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “county or Tribal veterans service officer” includes a local equivalent veterans service officer.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The term “covered outreach” means outreach with respect to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> benefits administered by the Under Secretary for Benefits; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> similar benefits administered by a State or Indian Tribe.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “Indian Tribe” has the meaning given such term in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<ref>25 U.S.C. 5304</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “State” includes the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, and any territory or possession of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The term “Veterans Crisis Line” means the toll-free hotline for veterans established under <ref>section 1720F(h) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 118–210, title III, § 302(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2025-01-02">Jan. 2, 2025</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2789</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6308.</num>
<heading> Outreach for eligible dependents</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Needs of Dependents</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In carrying out this subchapter, the Secretary shall ensure that the needs of eligible dependents are fully addressed.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Information as to Availability of Outreach Services for Dependents</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall ensure that the availability of outreach services and assistance for eligible dependents under this subchapter is made known through a variety of means, including the Internet, announcements in veterans publications, and announcements to the media.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–233, title IV, § 402(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-06-15">June 15, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 410</ref>, § 6307; amended <ref>Pub. L. 117–205, § 2(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2022-10-17">Oct. 17, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2233</ref>; renumbered § 6308, <ref>Pub. L. 118–210, title III, § 302(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2025-01-02">Jan. 2, 2025</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2789</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6309.</num>
<heading> Biennial report to Congress</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report Required</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall, not later than December 1 of every even-numbered year (beginning in 2008), submit to Congress a report on the outreach activities carried out by the Department.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Content</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each report under this section shall include the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A description of the implementation during the preceding fiscal year of the current biennial plan under <ref>section 6302 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Recommendations for the improvement or more effective administration of the outreach activities of the Department.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–233, title IV, § 402(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-06-15">June 15, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 410</ref>, § 6308; renumbered § 6309, <ref>Pub. L. 118–210, title III, § 302(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2025-01-02">Jan. 2, 2025</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2789</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>OTHER OUTREACH PROGRAMS AND ACTIVITIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6320.</num>
<heading> Solid Start program</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall carry out a program, to be known as the “Solid Start program”, under which the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> build the capacity of the Department to efficiently and effectively respond to the queries and needs of veterans who have recently separated from the Armed Forces; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> systemically integrate and coordinate efforts to assist veterans, including efforts—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to proactively reach out to newly separated veterans to inform them of their eligibility for programs of and benefits provided by the Department, including how to enroll in the system of annual patient enrollment established and operated under <ref>section 1705 of this title</ref> and the ability to seek care and services under sections 1703 and 1710 of this title; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to connect veterans in crisis to resources that address their immediate needs.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Activities of the Solid Start Program</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary, in coordination with the Secretary of Defense, shall carry out the Solid Start program of the Department by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> collecting up-to-date contact information during transition classes or separation counseling for all members of the Armed Forces who are separating from the Armed Forces, while explaining the existence and purpose of the Solid Start program;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> calling each veteran, regardless of separation type or characterization of service, three times within the first year after separation of the veteran from the Armed Forces;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> providing information about the Solid Start program on the website of the Department and in materials of the Department, especially transition booklets and other resources;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> ensuring calls are truly tailored to the needs of each veteran’s unique situation by conducting quality assurance tests;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> prioritizing outreach to veterans who have accessed mental health resources prior to separation from the Armed Forces;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> providing women veterans with information that is tailored to their specific health care and benefit needs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> as feasible, providing information on access to State and local resources, including Vet Centers and veterans service organizations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> gathering and analyzing data assessing the effectiveness of the Solid Start program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary, in coordination with the Secretary of Defense, may carry out the Solid Start program by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> encouraging members of the Armed Forces who are transitioning to civilian life to authorize alternate points of contact who can be reached should the member be unavailable during the first year following the separation of the member from the Armed Forces; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> following up missed phone calls with tailored mailings to ensure the veteran still receives similar information.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> In this subsection:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The term “Vet Center” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 1712A(h) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The term “veterans service organization” means an organization recognized by the Secretary for the representation of veterans under <ref>section 5902 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–205, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-10-17">Oct. 17, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2232</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 118–210, title I, § 102(b)</ref>, <date date="2025-01-02">Jan. 2, 2025</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2710</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>