<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 51—</num>
<heading>CLAIMS, EFFECTIVE DATES, AND PAYMENTS</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>CLAIMS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5100.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “claimant” means any individual applying for, or submitting a claim for, any benefit under the laws administered by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “notice” means a communication issued through means (including electronic means) prescribed by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–168, title VIII, § 807(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2022-08-10">Aug. 10, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 1805</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5101.</num>
<heading> Claims and forms</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Except as provided in subparagraph (B), a specific claim in the form prescribed by the Secretary (or jointly with the Commissioner of Social Security, as prescribed by <ref>section 5105 of this title</ref>) must be filed in order for benefits to be paid or furnished to any individual under the laws administered by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The Secretary may pay benefits under chapters 13 and 15 and sections 2303, 2307, and 5121 of this title to a survivor of a veteran who has not filed a formal claim if the Secretary determines that the record contains sufficient evidence to establish the entitlement of the survivor to such benefits.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of this subparagraph and <ref>section 5110 of this title</ref>, the earlier of the following dates shall be treated as the date of the receipt of the survivor’s application for benefits described in clause (i):</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent1">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> The date on which the survivor of a veteran (or the representative of such a survivor) notifies the Secretary of the death of the veteran through a death certificate or other relevant evidence that establishes entitlement to survivors’ benefits identified in clause (i).</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent1">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> The head of any other department or agency of the Federal Government notifies the Secretary of the death of the veteran.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> In notifying the Secretary of the death of a veteran as described in clause (ii)(I), the survivor (or the representative of such a survivor) may submit to the Secretary additional documents relating to such death without being required to file a formal claim.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If an individual has not attained the age of 18 years, is mentally incompetent, or is physically unable to sign a form, a form filed under paragraph (1) for the individual may be signed by a court-appointed representative, a person who is responsible for the care of the individual, including a spouse or other relative, or an attorney in fact or agent authorized to act on behalf of the individual under a durable power of attorney. If the individual is in the care of an institution, the manager or principal officer of the institution may sign the form.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A claim by a surviving spouse or child for compensation or dependency and indemnity compensation shall also be considered to be a claim for death pension and accrued benefits, and a claim by a surviving spouse or child for death pension shall be considered to be a claim for death compensation (or dependency and indemnity compensation) and accrued benefits.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A claim by a parent for compensation or dependency and indemnity compensation shall also be considered to be a claim for accrued benefits.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Any person who applies for, signs a form on behalf of an individual to apply for, or is in receipt of any compensation or pension benefit under laws administered by the Secretary shall, if requested by the Secretary, furnish the Secretary with the social security number of such person, or TIN in the case that the person is not an individual, and the social security number of any claimant, dependent, or beneficiary on whose behalf, or based upon whom, such person applies for or is in receipt of such benefit. A person is not required to furnish the Secretary with a social security number for any person to whom a social security number has not been assigned.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall deny the application of or terminate the payment of compensation or pension to a person who fails to furnish the Secretary with a social security number or TIN required to be furnished pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection. The Secretary may thereafter reconsider the application or reinstate payment of compensation or pension, as the case may be, if such person furnishes the Secretary with such social security number or TIN.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The costs of administering this subsection shall be paid for from amounts available to the Department of Veterans Affairs for the payment of compensation and pension.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary shall publish in a central location on the internet website of the Department—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the disability benefit questionnaire forms of the Department for the submittal of evidence from non-Department medical providers regarding a disability of a claimant, including any form or process that replaces any such disability benefit questionnaire form, including (except as provided in paragraph (4)(A)) all disability benefit questionnaire forms available to personnel of the Veterans Health Administration and covered non-Department providers for the completion of examinations with respect to medical disability of applicants for benefits under laws administered by the Secretary; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> details about the process used by the Department for submittal of evidence described in subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Subject to <ref>section 6103 of this title</ref>, if the Secretary updates a form described in paragraph (1)(A), the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> accept the previous version of the form filed by a claimant if—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the claimant provided to the non-Department medical provider the previous version of the form before the date on which the updated version of the form was made available; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the claimant files the previous version of the form during the one-year period following the date the form was completed by the non-Department medical provider;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> request from the claimant (or from a non-Department medical provider if the claimant has authorized the provider to share health information with the Secretary) any other information that the updated version of the form requires; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> apply the laws and regulations required to adjudicate the claim as if the claimant filed the updated version of the form.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary may waive any interagency approval process required to approve a modification to a disability benefit questionnaire form if such requirement only applies by reason of the forms being made public.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Secretary may exclude from publication under clauses (i) and (ii) of paragraph (1)(A) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002093">1</ref> any form described in subparagraph (B) of this paragraph that the Secretary determines could not reasonably be completed to a clinically acceptable standard by someone not an employee or a contractor of the Department.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> A form described in this subparagraph is a form that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> was available or in use at any time after the date of the enactment of the Veterans Benefits Improvement Act of 2024; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> has not been published under paragraph (1).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall include on the same internet website as the website on which forms are published under paragraph (1)(A) a list of forms that have been excluded from publication pursuant to subparagraph (A), and for each such form, a justification for the exclusion of the form from publication.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<chapeau> In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The term “mentally incompetent” with respect to an individual means that the individual lacks the mental capacity—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to provide substantially accurate information needed to complete a form; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to certify that the statements made on a form are true and complete.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “TIN” has the meaning given the term in section 7701(a)(41) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “covered non-Department provider” means a medical provider who is not an employee of the Department and who provides examinations with respect to medical disability of applicants for benefits under laws administered by the Secretary pursuant to a contract with the Department.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–857</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1225</ref>, § 3001; <ref>Pub. L. 97–295, § 4(95)(A)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-12">Oct. 12, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1313</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–576, title VII, § 701(61)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-28">Oct. 28, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3296</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–508, title VIII, § 8053(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1388–352</ref>; renumbered § 5101 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–40, title IV, § 402(b)(1)</ref>, (d)(1), <date date="1991-05-07">May 7, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 238</ref>, 239; <ref>Pub. L. 102–83, § 4(a)(1)</ref>, (b)(1), (2)(E), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 403–405</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–183, title VII, § 708(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2003-12-16">Dec. 16, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2674</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–154, title V, § 502(a)</ref>, <date date="2012-08-06">Aug. 6, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1190</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–315, title I, § 101(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1538</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–315, title II</ref>, §§ 2006(a), 2202(b)(1)(E), <date date="2021-01-05">Jan. 5, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4975</ref>, 4985; <ref>Pub. L. 118–196, § 2</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2671</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5102.</num>
<heading> Application forms furnished upon request; notice to claimants of incomplete applications</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Furnishing Forms</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Upon request made by any person claiming or applying for, or expressing an intent to claim or apply for, a benefit under the laws administered by the Secretary, the Secretary shall furnish such person, free of all expense, all instructions and forms necessary to apply for that benefit.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Incomplete Applications</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If a claimant’s application for a benefit under the laws administered by the Secretary is incomplete, the Secretary shall notify the claimant and the claimant’s representative, if any, of the information necessary to complete the application.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Time Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> If information that a claimant and the claimant’s representative, if any, are notified under subsection (b) is necessary to complete an application is not received by the Secretary within one year from the date such notice is sent, no benefit may be paid or furnished by reason of the claimant’s application.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> This subsection shall not apply to any application or claim for Government life insurance benefits.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–475, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="2000-11-09">Nov. 9, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2096</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–183, title VII, § 701(a)</ref>, <date date="2003-12-16">Dec. 16, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2670</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5103.</num>
<heading> Notice to claimants of required information and evidence</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Required Information and Evidence</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraph (3), the Secretary shall provide to the claimant and the claimant’s representative, if any, by the most effective means available, including electronic communication or notification in writing, notice of any information, and any medical or lay evidence, not previously provided to the Secretary that is necessary to substantiate the claim. As part of that notice, the Secretary shall indicate which portion of that information and evidence, if any, is to be provided by the claimant and which portion, if any, the Secretary, in accordance with <ref>section 5103A of this title</ref> and any other applicable provisions of law, will attempt to obtain on behalf of the claimant.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall prescribe in regulations requirements relating to the contents of notice to be provided under this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> The regulations required by this paragraph—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> shall specify different contents for notice based on whether the claim concerned is an original claim or a supplemental claim;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> shall provide that the contents for such notice be appropriate to the type of benefits or services sought under the claim;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> shall specify for each type of claim for benefits the general information and evidence required to substantiate the basic elements of such type of claim; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> shall specify the time period limitations required pursuant to subsection (b).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The requirement to provide notice under paragraph (1) shall not apply with respect to a supplemental claim that is filed within the timeframe set forth in subparagraphs (B) and (D) of <ref>section 5110(a)(2) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Time Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In the case of information or evidence that the claimant is notified under subsection (a) is to be provided by the claimant, such information or evidence must be received by the Secretary within one year from the date such notice is sent.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> This subsection shall not apply to any application or claim for Government life insurance benefits.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Nothing in paragraph (1) shall be construed to prohibit the Secretary from making a decision on a claim before the expiration of the period referred to in that subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> Nothing in this section shall require the Secretary to provide notice for a subsequent claim that is filed while a previous claim is pending if the notice previously provided for such pending claim—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> provides sufficient notice of the information and evidence necessary to substantiate such subsequent claim; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> was sent within one year of the date on which the subsequent claim was filed.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> This section shall not apply to any claim or issue where the Secretary may award the maximum benefit in accordance with this title based on the evidence of record.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> For purposes of this paragraph, the term “maximum benefit” means the highest evaluation assignable in accordance with the evidence of record, as long as such evidence is adequate for rating purposes and sufficient to grant the earliest possible effective date in accordance with <ref>section 5110 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–475, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="2000-11-09">Nov. 9, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2096</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–14, § 8(a)(12)</ref>, <date date="2001-06-05">June 5, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 35</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–183, title VII, § 701(b)</ref>, <date date="2003-12-16">Dec. 16, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2670</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–389, title I, § 101(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-10-10">Oct. 10, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4147</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–154, title V, § 504(a)</ref>, <date date="2012-08-06">Aug. 6, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1191</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–55, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="2017-08-23">Aug. 23, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1105</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5103A.</num>
<heading> Duty to assist claimants</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duty To Assist</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall make reasonable efforts to assist a claimant in obtaining evidence necessary to substantiate the claimant’s claim for a benefit under a law administered by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary is not required to provide assistance to a claimant under this section if no reasonable possibility exists that such assistance would aid in substantiating the claim.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary may defer providing assistance under this section pending the submission by the claimant of essential information missing from the claimant’s application.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Assistance in Obtaining Private Records</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> As part of the assistance provided under subsection (a), the Secretary shall make reasonable efforts to obtain relevant private records that the claimant adequately identifies to the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> Whenever the Secretary, after making such reasonable efforts, is unable to obtain all of the relevant records sought, the Secretary shall notify the claimant that the Secretary is unable to obtain records with respect to the claim. Such a notification shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> identify the records the Secretary is unable to obtain;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> briefly explain the efforts that the Secretary made to obtain such records; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> explain that the Secretary will decide the claim based on the evidence of record but that this section does not prohibit the submission of records at a later date if such submission is otherwise allowed.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall make not less than two requests to a custodian of a private record in order for an effort to obtain relevant private records to be treated as reasonable under this section, unless it is made evident by the first request that a second request would be futile in obtaining such records.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> This section shall not apply if the evidence of record allows for the Secretary to award the maximum benefit in accordance with this title based on the evidence of record.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> For purposes of this paragraph, the term “maximum benefit” means the highest evaluation assignable in accordance with the evidence of record, as long as such evidence is adequate for rating purposes and sufficient to grant the earliest possible effective date in accordance with <ref>section 5110 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, the Secretary—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall encourage claimants to submit relevant private medical records of the claimant to the Secretary if such submission does not burden the claimant; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in obtaining relevant private records under paragraph (1), may require the claimant to authorize the Secretary to obtain such records if such authorization is required to comply with Federal, State, or local law.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Obtaining Records for Compensation Claims</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> In the case of a claim for disability compensation, the assistance provided by the Secretary under this section shall include obtaining the following records if relevant to the claim:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The claimant’s service medical records and, if the claimant has furnished the Secretary information sufficient to locate such records, other relevant records pertaining to the claimant’s active military, naval, air, or space service that are held or maintained by a governmental entity.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Records of relevant medical treatment or examination of the claimant at Department health-care facilities or at the expense of the Department, if the claimant furnishes information sufficient to locate those records.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Any other relevant records held by any Federal department or agency that the claimant adequately identifies and authorizes the Secretary to obtain.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Whenever the Secretary attempts to obtain records from a Federal department or agency under this subsection, the efforts to obtain those records shall continue until the records are obtained unless it is reasonably certain that such records do not exist or that further efforts to obtain those records would be futile.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Medical Examinations for Compensation Claims</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In the case of a claim for disability compensation, the assistance provided by the Secretary under subsection (a) shall include providing a medical examination or obtaining a medical opinion when such an examination or opinion is necessary to make a decision on the claim.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary shall treat an examination or opinion as being necessary to make a decision on a claim for purposes of paragraph (1) if the evidence of record before the Secretary, taking into consideration all information and lay or medical evidence (including statements of the claimant)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> contains competent evidence that the claimant has a current disability, or persistent or recurrent symptoms of disability; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> indicates that the disability or symptoms may be associated with the claimant’s active military, naval, air, or space service; but</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> does not contain sufficient medical evidence for the Secretary to make a decision on the claim.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Applicability of Duty to Assist</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary’s duty to assist under this section shall apply only to a claim, or supplemental claim, for a benefit under a law administered by the Secretary until the time that a claimant is provided notice of the agency of original jurisdiction’s decision with respect to such claim, or supplemental claim, under <ref>section 5104 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary’s duty to assist under this section shall not apply to higher-level review by the agency of original jurisdiction, pursuant to <ref>section 5104B of this title</ref>, or to review on appeal by the Board of Veterans’ Appeals.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Correction of Duty to Assist Errors</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> If, during review of the agency of original jurisdiction decision under <ref>section 5104B of this title</ref>, the higher-level adjudicator identifies or learns of an error on the part of the agency of original jurisdiction to satisfy its duties under this section, and that error occurred prior to the agency of original jurisdiction decision being reviewed, unless the Secretary may award the maximum benefit in accordance with this title based on the evidence of record, the higher-level adjudicator shall return the claim for correction of such error and readjudication.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> If the Board of Veterans’ Appeals, during review on appeal of an agency of original jurisdiction decision, identifies or learns of an error on the part of the agency of original jurisdiction to satisfy its duties under this section, and that error occurred prior to the agency of original jurisdiction decision on appeal, unless the Secretary may award the maximum benefit in accordance with this title based on the evidence of record, the Board shall remand the claim to the agency of original jurisdiction for correction of such error and readjudication.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Remand for correction of such error may include directing the agency of original jurisdiction to obtain an advisory medical opinion under <ref>section 5109 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to imply that the Secretary, during the consideration of a claim, does not have a duty to correct an error described in paragraph (1) or (2) that was erroneously not identified during higher-level review or during review on appeal with respect to the claim.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall prescribe regulations to carry out this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rule With Respect to Disallowed Claims</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section shall be construed to require the Secretary to readjudicate a claim that has been disallowed except when new and relevant evidence is presented or secured, as described in <ref>section 5108 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Other Assistance Not Precluded</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section shall be construed as precluding the Secretary from providing such other assistance under subsection (a) to a claimant in substantiating a claim as the Secretary considers appropriate.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–475, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="2000-11-09">Nov. 9, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2097</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 112–154, title V, § 505(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2012-08-06">Aug. 6, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1192</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–55, § 2(c)</ref>, (d), <date date="2017-08-23">Aug. 23, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1105</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 926(a)(51)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3830</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5104.</num>
<heading> Decisions and notices of decisions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> In the case of a decision by the Secretary under <ref>section 511 of this title</ref> affecting the provision of benefits to a claimant, the Secretary shall, on a timely basis, provide to the claimant (and to the claimant’s representative) notice of such decision. The notice shall include an explanation of the procedure for obtaining review of the decision.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Each notice provided under subsection (a) shall also include all of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Identification of the issues adjudicated.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A summary of the evidence considered by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A summary of the applicable laws and regulations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Identification of findings favorable to the claimant.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> In the case of a denial, identification of elements not satisfied leading to the denial.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> An explanation of how to obtain or access evidence used in making the decision.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> If applicable, identification of the criteria that must be satisfied to grant service connection or the next higher level of compensation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Secretary may provide notice under subsection (a) electronically if a claimant (or the claimant’s representative) elects to receive such notice electronically. A claimant (or the claimant’s representative) may revoke such an election at any time, by means prescribed by the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary shall annually—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> solicit recommendations from stakeholders on how to improve notice under this section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> publish such recommendations on a publicly available website of the Department.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–237, title I, § 115(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1989-12-18">Dec. 18, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 2065</ref>, § 3004; renumbered § 5104, <ref>Pub. L. 102–40, title IV, § 402(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-05-07">May 7, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 238</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–54, § 14(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-06-13">June 13, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 285</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–446, title XII, § 1201(d)(15)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4684</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–55, § 2(e)</ref>, <date date="2017-08-23">Aug. 23, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1106</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–168, title VIII, § 807(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2022-08-10">Aug. 10, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 1806</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5104A.</num>
<heading> Binding nature of favorable findings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any finding favorable to the claimant as described in <ref>section 5104(b)(4) of this title</ref> shall be binding on all subsequent adjudicators within the Department, unless clear and convincing evidence is shown to the contrary to rebut such favorable finding.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–55, § 2(f)(1)</ref>, <date date="2017-08-23">Aug. 23, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1107</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5104B.</num>
<heading> Higher-level review by the agency of original jurisdiction</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A claimant may request a review of the decision of the agency of original jurisdiction by a higher-level adjudicator within the agency of original jurisdiction.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall approve each request for review under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Time and Manner of Request</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> A request for higher-level review by the agency of original jurisdiction shall be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in writing in such form as the Secretary may prescribe; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> made within one year of the notice of the agency of original jurisdiction’s decision.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Such request may specifically indicate whether such review is requested by a higher-level adjudicator at the same office within the agency of original jurisdiction or by an adjudicator at a different office of the agency of original jurisdiction. The Secretary shall not deny such request for review by an adjudicator at a different office of the agency of original jurisdiction without good cause.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Decision</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Notice of a higher-level review decision under this section shall be provided to the claimant (and any representative of such claimant) and shall include a general statement—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> reflecting whether evidence was not considered pursuant to subsection (d); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> noting the options available to the claimant to have the evidence described in paragraph (1), if any, considered by the Department.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Evidentiary Record for Review</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The evidentiary record before the higher-level adjudicator shall be limited to the evidence of record in the agency of original jurisdiction decision being reviewed.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">De Novo Review</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A review of the decision of the agency of original jurisdiction by a higher-level adjudicator within the agency of original jurisdiction shall be de novo.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–55, § 2(g)(1)</ref>, <date date="2017-08-23">Aug. 23, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1107</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 117–168, title VIII, § 807(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2022-08-10">Aug. 10, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 1806</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5104C.</num>
<heading> Options following decision by agency of original jurisdiction</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Within One Year of Decision</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Subject to paragraph (2), in any case in which the Secretary renders a decision on a claim, the claimant may take any of the following actions on or before the date that is one year after the date on which the agency of original jurisdiction issues a decision with respect to that claim:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> File a request for higher-level review under <ref>section 5104B of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> File a supplemental claim under <ref>section 5108 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> File a notice of disagreement under <ref>section 7105 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> Once a claimant takes an action set forth in paragraph (1), the claimant may not take another action set forth in that paragraph with respect to the same claim or same issue contained within the claim until—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the higher-level review, supplemental claim, or notice of disagreement is adjudicated; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the request for higher-level review, supplemental claim, or notice of disagreement is withdrawn.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Nothing in this subsection shall prohibit a claimant from taking any of the actions set forth in paragraph (1) in succession with respect to a claim or an issue contained within the claim.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Nothing in this subsection shall prohibit a claimant from taking different actions set forth in paragraph (1) with respect to different claims or different issues contained within a claim.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary may, as the Secretary considers appropriate, develop and implement a policy for claimants who—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> take an action under paragraph (1);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> wish to withdraw the action before the higher-level review, supplemental claim, or notice of disagreement is adjudicated; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> in lieu of such action take a different action under paragraph (1).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">More Than One Year After Decision</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In any case in which the Secretary renders a decision on a claim and more than one year has passed since the date on which the agency of original jurisdiction issues a decision with respect to that claim, the claimant may file a supplemental claim under <ref>section 5108 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–55, § 2(h)(1)</ref>, <date date="2017-08-23">Aug. 23, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1108</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5105.</num>
<heading> Joint applications for social security and dependency and indemnity compensation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary and the Commissioner of Social Security may jointly prescribe forms for use by survivors of members and former members of the uniformed services in filing application for benefits under chapter 13 of this title and title II of the Social Security Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 401</ref> et seq.). Such forms shall request information sufficient to constitute an application for benefits under both chapter 13 of this title and title II of the Social Security Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 401</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> When an application on any document indicating an intent to apply for survivor benefits is filed with either the Secretary or the Commissioner of Social Security, it shall be deemed to be an application for benefits under both chapter 13 of this title and title II of the Social Security Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 401</ref> et seq.). A copy of each such application filed with either the Secretary or the Commissioner, together with any additional information and supporting documents (or certifications thereof) which may have been received by the Secretary or the Commissioner with such application, and which may be needed by the other official in connection therewith, shall be transmitted by the Secretary or the Commissioner receiving the application to the other official. The preceding sentence shall not prevent the Secretary and the Commissioner of Social Security from requesting the applicant, or any other individual, to furnish such additional information as may be necessary for purposes of chapter 13 of this title and title II of the Social Security Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 401</ref> et seq.), respectively.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–857</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1226</ref>, § 3005; <ref>Pub. L. 97–295, § 4(95)(A)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-12">Oct. 12, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1313</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–160, title VII, § 702(16)</ref>, <date date="1983-11-21">Nov. 21, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 1010</ref>; renumbered § 5105, <ref>Pub. L. 102–40, title IV, § 402(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-05-07">May 7, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 238</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–83, § 4(b)(9)</ref>, <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 405</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–296, title I, § 108(k)</ref>, <date date="1994-08-15">Aug. 15, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1488</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–154, title V, § 503</ref>, <date date="2012-08-06">Aug. 6, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1191</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5106.</num>
<heading> Furnishing of information by other agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The head of any Federal department or agency shall provide such information to the Secretary as the Secretary may request for purposes of determining eligibility for or amount of benefits, or verifying other information with respect thereto. The cost of providing information to the Secretary under this section shall be borne by the department or agency providing the information.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 94–432, title IV, § 403(2)</ref>, <date date="1976-09-30">Sept. 30, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1372</ref>, § 3006; amended <ref>Pub. L. 99–576, title VII, § 701(62)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-28">Oct. 28, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3296</ref>; renumbered § 5106, <ref>Pub. L. 102–40, title IV, § 402(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-05-07">May 7, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 238</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–83, § 4(b)(1)</ref>, (2)(E), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 404</ref>, 405; <ref>Pub. L. 106–475, § 5</ref>, <date date="2000-11-09">Nov. 9, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2099</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5107.</num>
<heading> Claimant responsibility; benefit of the doubt</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Claimant Responsibility</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as otherwise provided by law, a claimant has the responsibility to present and support a claim for benefits under laws administered by the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Benefit of the Doubt</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall consider all information and lay and medical evidence of record in a case before the Secretary with respect to benefits under laws administered by the Secretary. When there is an approximate balance of positive and negative evidence regarding any issue material to the determination of a matter, the Secretary shall give the benefit of the doubt to the claimant.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–687, div. A, title I, § 103(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4106</ref>, § 3007; renumbered § 5107 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–40, title IV, § 402(b)(1)</ref>, (d)(1), <date date="1991-05-07">May 7, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 238</ref>, 239; <ref>Pub. L. 102–83, § 4(a)(1)</ref>, (3), (4), (b)(1), (2)(E), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 403–405</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title XVI, § 1611(a)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–359; <ref>Pub. L. 106–419, title I, § 104(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2000-11-01">Nov. 1, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1828</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–475, § 4</ref>, <date date="2000-11-09">Nov. 9, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2098</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5108.</num>
<heading> Supplemental claims</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If new and relevant evidence is presented or secured with respect to a supplemental claim, the Secretary shall readjudicate the claim taking into consideration all of the evidence of record.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duty to Assist</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> If a claimant, in connection with a supplemental claim, reasonably identifies existing records, whether or not in the custody of a Federal department or agency, the Secretary shall assist the claimant in obtaining the records in accordance with <ref>section 5103A of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Assistance under paragraph (1) shall not be predicated upon a finding that new and relevant evidence has been presented or secured.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–687, div. A, title I, § 103(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4107</ref>, § 3008; renumbered § 5108, <ref>Pub. L. 102–40, title IV, § 402(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-05-07">May 7, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 238</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–83, § 4(b)(1)</ref>, (2)(E), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 404</ref>, 405; <ref>Pub. L. 115–55, § 2(i)(1)</ref>, <date date="2017-08-23">Aug. 23, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1109</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5109.</num>
<heading> Independent medical opinions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> When, in the judgment of the Secretary, expert medical opinion, in addition to that available within the Department, is warranted by the medical complexity or controversy involved in a case being considered by the Department, the Secretary may secure an advisory medical opinion from one or more independent medical experts who are not employees of the Department.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall make necessary arrangements with recognized medical schools, universities, or clinics to furnish such advisory medical opinions. Any such arrangement shall provide that the actual selection of the expert or experts to give the advisory opinion in an individual case shall be made by an appropriate official of such institution.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall furnish a claimant with notice that an advisory medical opinion has been requested under this section with respect to the claimant’s case and shall furnish the claimant with a copy of such opinion when it is received by the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Board of Veterans’ Appeals shall remand a claim to direct the agency of original jurisdiction to obtain an advisory medical opinion from an independent medical expert under this section if the Board finds that the Veterans Benefits Administration should have exercised its discretion to obtain such an opinion.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Board’s remand instructions shall include the questions to be posed to the independent medical expert providing the advisory medical opinion.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–687, div. A, title I, § 103(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4107</ref>, § 3009; renumbered § 5109, <ref>Pub. L. 102–40, title IV, § 402(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-05-07">May 7, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 238</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–83, § 4(a)(3)</ref>, (4), (b)(1), (2)(E), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 404</ref>, 405; <ref>Pub. L. 115–55, § 2(j)</ref>, <date date="2017-08-23">Aug. 23, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1109</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5109A.</num>
<heading> Revision of decisions on grounds of clear and unmistakable error</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> A decision by the Secretary under this chapter is subject to revision on the grounds of clear and unmistakable error. If evidence establishes the error, the prior decision shall be reversed or revised.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> For the purposes of authorizing benefits, a rating or other adjudicative decision that constitutes a reversal or revision of a prior decision on the grounds of clear and unmistakable error has the same effect as if the decision had been made on the date of the prior decision.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Review to determine whether clear and unmistakable error exists in a case may be instituted by the Secretary on the Secretary’s own motion or upon request of the claimant.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> A request for revision of a decision of the Secretary based on clear and unmistakable error may be made at any time after that decision is made.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> Such a request shall be submitted to the Secretary and shall be decided in the same manner as any other claim.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 105–111, § 1(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-21">Nov. 21, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 2271</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5109B.</num>
<heading> Expedited treatment of returned and remanded claims</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall take such actions as may be necessary to provide for the expeditious treatment by the Veterans Benefits Administration of any claim that is returned by a higher-level adjudicator under <ref>section 5104B of this title</ref> or remanded by the Board of Veterans’ Appeals.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–183, title VII, § 707(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2003-12-16">Dec. 16, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2672</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–55, § 2(k)(1)</ref>, <date date="2017-08-23">Aug. 23, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1109</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>EFFECTIVE DATES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5110.</num>
<heading> Effective dates of awards</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Unless specifically provided otherwise in this chapter, the effective date of an award based on an initial claim, or a supplemental claim, of compensation, dependency and indemnity compensation, or pension, shall be fixed in accordance with the facts found, but shall not be earlier than the date of receipt of application therefor.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of determining the effective date of an award under this section, the date of application shall be considered the date of the filing of the initial application for a benefit if the claim is continuously pursued by filing any of the following, either alone or in succession:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A request for higher-level review under <ref>section 5104B of this title</ref> on or before the date that is one year after the date on which the agency of original jurisdiction issues a decision.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A supplemental claim under <ref>section 5108 of this title</ref> on or before the date that is one year after the date on which the agency of original jurisdiction issues a decision.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> A notice of disagreement on or before the date that is one year after the date on which the agency of original jurisdiction issues a decision.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> A supplemental claim under <ref>section 5108 of this title</ref> on or before the date that is one year after the date on which the Board of Veterans’ Appeals issues a decision.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> A supplemental claim under <ref>section 5108 of this title</ref> on or before the date that is one year after the date on which the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims issues a decision.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Except as otherwise provided in this section, for supplemental claims received more than one year after the date on which the agency of original jurisdiction issued a decision or the Board of Veterans’ Appeals issued a decision, the effective date shall be fixed in accordance with the facts found, but shall not be earlier than the date of receipt of the supplemental claim.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The effective date of an award of disability compensation to a veteran shall be the day following the date of the veteran’s discharge or release if application therefor is received within one year from such date of discharge or release.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The effective date of an award of disability compensation to a veteran who submits an application therefor that sets forth an original claim that is fully-developed (as determined by the Secretary) as of the date of submittal shall be fixed in accordance with the facts found, but shall not be earlier than the date that is one year before the date of receipt of the application.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> For purposes of this paragraph, an original claim is an initial claim filed by a veteran for disability compensation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> This paragraph shall take effect on the date that is one year after the date of the enactment of the Honoring America’s Veterans and Caring for Camp Lejeune Families Act of 2012 and shall not apply with respect to claims filed after the date that is three years after the date of the enactment of such Act.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The effective date of an award of increased compensation shall be the earliest date as of which it is ascertainable that an increase in disability had occurred, if application is received within one year from such date.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The effective date of an award of disability pension to a veteran described in subparagraph (B) of this paragraph shall be the date of application or the date on which the veteran became permanently and totally disabled, if the veteran applies for a retroactive award within one year from such date, whichever is to the advantage of the veteran.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A veteran referred to in subparagraph (A) of this paragraph is a veteran who is permanently and totally disabled and who is prevented by a disability from applying for disability pension for a period of at least 30 days beginning on the date on which the veteran became permanently and totally disabled.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The effective date of an award of disability compensation by reason of <ref>section 1151 of this title</ref> shall be the date such injury or aggravation was suffered if an application therefor is received within one year from such date.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The effective date of an award of death compensation, dependency and indemnity compensation, or death pension for which application is received within one year from the date of death shall be the first day of the month in which the death occurred.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the effective date of an award of dependency and indemnity compensation to a child shall be the first day of the month in which the child’s entitlement arose if application therefor is received within one year from such date.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In the case of a child who is eighteen years of age or over and who immediately before becoming eighteen years of age was counted under <ref>section 1311(b) of this title</ref> in determining the amount of the dependency and indemnity compensation of a surviving spouse, the effective date of an award of dependency and indemnity compensation to such child shall be the date the child attains the age of eighteen years if application therefor is received within one year from such date.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> An award of additional compensation on account of dependents based on the establishment of a disability rating in the percentage evaluation specified by law for the purpose shall be payable from the effective date of such rating; but only if proof of dependents is received within one year from the date of notification of such rating action.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> Subject to the provisions of <ref>section 5101 of this title</ref>, where compensation, dependency and indemnity compensation, or pension is awarded or increased pursuant to any Act or administrative issue, the effective date of such award or increase shall be fixed in accordance with the facts found but shall not be earlier than the effective date of the Act or administrative issue. In no event shall such award or increase be retroactive for more than one year from the date of application therefor or the date of administrative determination of entitlement, whichever is earlier.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<content> Where an award of pension has been deferred or pension has been awarded at a rate based on anticipated income for a year and the claimant later establishes that income for that year was at a rate warranting entitlement or increased entitlement, the effective date of such entitlement or increase shall be fixed in accordance with the facts found if satisfactory evidence is received before the expiration of the next calendar year.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Whenever any disallowed claim is readjudicated and thereafter allowed on the basis of new and relevant evidence resulting from the correction of the military records of the proper service department under <ref>section 1552 of title 10</ref>, or the change, correction, or modification of a discharge or dismissal under <ref>section 1553 of title 10</ref>, or from other corrective action by competent authority, the effective date of commencement of the benefits so awarded shall be the date on which an application was filed for correction of the military record or for the change, modification, or correction of a discharge or dismissal, as the case may be, or the date such disallowed claim was filed, whichever date is the later, but in no event shall such award of benefits be retroactive for more than one year from the date of readjudication of such disallowed claim. This subsection shall not apply to any application or claim for Government life insurance benefits.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<content> Where a report or a finding of death of any person in the active military, naval, air, or space service has been made by the Secretary concerned, the effective date of an award of death compensation, dependency and indemnity compensation, or death pension, as applicable, shall be the first day of the month fixed by that Secretary as the month of death in such report or finding, if application therefor is received within one year from the date such report or finding has been made; however, such benefits shall not be payable to any person for any period for which such person has received, or was entitled to receive, an allowance, allotment, or service pay of the deceased.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(k)</num>
<content> The effective date of the award of benefits to a surviving spouse or of an award or increase of benefits based on recognition of a child, upon annulment of a marriage shall be the date the judicial decree of annulment becomes final if a claim therefor is filed within one year from the date the judicial decree of annulment becomes final; in all other cases the effective date shall be the date the claim is filed.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(l)</num>
<content> The effective date of an award of benefits to a surviving spouse based upon a termination of a remarriage by death or divorce, or of an award or increase of benefits based on recognition of a child upon termination of the child’s marriage by death or divorce, shall be the date of death or the date the judicial decree or divorce becomes final, if an application therefor is received within one year from such termination.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>[(m)</num>
<content> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 103–446, title XII, § 1201(i)(8)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4688</ref>.]</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(n)</num>
<content> The effective date of the award of any benefit or any increase therein by reason of marriage or the birth or adoption of a child shall be the date of such event if proof of such event is received by the Secretary within one year from the date of the marriage, birth, or adoption.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–857</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1226</ref>, § 3010; <ref>Pub. L. 87–674, § 3</ref>, <date date="1962-09-19">Sept. 19, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 558</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–825, § 1</ref>, <date date="1962-10-15">Oct. 15, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 948</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–376, § 7</ref>, <date date="1970-08-12">Aug. 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 790</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–584, § 13</ref>, <date date="1970-12-24">Dec. 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1578</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–177, § 6(a)</ref>, <date date="1973-12-06">Dec. 6, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 696</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–527, § 9(b)</ref>, <date date="1974-12-21">Dec. 21, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1705</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–71, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="1975-08-05">Aug. 5, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 396</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–66, title II, § 204(b)</ref>, <date date="1981-10-17">Oct. 17, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1029</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–160, title VII, § 703(1)</ref>, <date date="1983-11-21">Nov. 21, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 1010</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–223, title II, § 213(3)</ref>, <date date="1984-03-02">Mar. 2, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 46</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–369, div. B, title V, § 2501(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1116</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–576, title VII, § 701(63)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-28">Oct. 28, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3296</ref>; renumbered § 5110 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–40, title IV, § 402(b)(1)</ref>, (d)(1), <date date="1991-05-07">May 7, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 238</ref>, 239; <ref>Pub. L. 102–83</ref>, §§ 4(a)(2)(A)(vi), (b)(4)(B), 5(c)(1), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 403</ref>, 405, 406; <ref>Pub. L. 103–446, title XII, § 1201(i)(8)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4688</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–454, title III, § 305</ref>, <date date="2004-12-10">Dec. 10, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3611</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–154, title V, § 506</ref>, <date date="2012-08-06">Aug. 6, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1193</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–55, § 2</ref>(<i>l</i>), <date date="2017-08-23">Aug. 23, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1110</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 926(a)(52)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3830</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5111.</num>
<heading> Commencement of period of payment</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding <ref>section 5110 of this title</ref> or any other provision of law and except as provided in paragraph (2) and subsection (c), payment of monetary benefits based on an award or an increased award of compensation, dependency and indemnity compensation, or pension may not be made to an individual for any period before the first day of the calendar month following the month in which the award or increased award became effective as provided under <ref>section 5110 of this title</ref> or such other provision of law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> In the case of a veteran who is retired or separated from the active military, naval, air, or space service for a catastrophic disability or disabilities, payment of monetary benefits based on an award of compensation based on an original claim shall be made as of the date on which such award becomes effective as provided under <ref>section 5110 of this title</ref> or another applicable provision of law.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> For the purposes of this paragraph, the term “catastrophic disability”, with respect to a veteran, means a permanent, severely disabling injury, disorder, or disease that compromises the ability of the veteran to carry out the activities of daily living to such a degree that the veteran requires personal or mechanical assistance to leave home or bed, or requires constant supervision to avoid physical harm to self or others.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, during the period between the effective date of an award or increased award as provided under <ref>section 5110 of this title</ref> or other provision of law and the commencement of the period of payment based on such award as provided under subsection (a) of this section, an individual entitled to receive monetary benefits shall be deemed to be in receipt of such benefits for the purpose of all laws administered by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If any person who is in receipt of retired or retirement pay would also be eligible to receive compensation or pension upon the filing of a waiver of such pay in accordance with <ref>section 5305 of this title</ref>, such waiver shall not become effective until the first day of the month following the month in which such waiver is filed, and nothing in this section shall prohibit the receipt of retired or retirement pay for any period before such effective date.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> This section shall not apply to payments made pursuant to <ref>section 5310 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In the case of a temporary increase in compensation for hospitalization or treatment where such hospitalization or treatment commences and terminates within the same calendar month, the period of payment shall commence on the first day of such month.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> For the purposes of this section, the term “award or increased award” means—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an original award or award based on a supplemental claim; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an award that is increased because of an added dependent, increase in disability or disability rating, or reduction in income.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 97–253, title IV, § 401(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-08">Sept. 8, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 801</ref>, § 3011; amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–223, title I, § 113</ref>, <date date="1984-03-02">Mar. 2, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 40</ref>; renumbered § 5111 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–40, title IV, § 402(b)(1)</ref>, (d)(1), <date date="1991-05-07">May 7, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 238</ref>, 239; <ref>Pub. L. 102–83, § 4(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 403</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–275, title VI, § 605(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-13">Oct. 13, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2885</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–154, title V, § 507(b)</ref>, <date date="2012-08-06">Aug. 6, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1194</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–55, § 2(m)</ref>, <date date="2017-08-23">Aug. 23, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1110</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 926(a)(53)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3830</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5112.</num>
<heading> Effective dates of reductions and discontinuances</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Except as otherwise specified in this section, the effective date of reduction or discontinuance of compensation, dependency and indemnity compensation, or pension shall be fixed in accordance with the facts found.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> The effective date of a reduction or discontinuance of compensation, dependency and indemnity compensation, or pension—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> by reason of marriage or remarriage, or death of a payee shall be the last day of the month before such marriage, remarriage, or death occurs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> by reason of marriage, annulment, divorce, or death of a dependent of a payee shall be the last day of the month in which such marriage, annulment, divorce, or death occurs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> by reason of receipt of active service pay or retirement pay shall be the day before the date such pay began;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> by reason of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> change in income shall (except as provided in <ref>section 5312 of this title</ref>) be the last day of the month in which the change occurred; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> change in corpus of estate shall be the last day of the calendar year in which the change occurred;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> by reason of a change in disability or employability of a veteran in receipt of pension shall be the last day of the month in which discontinuance of the award is approved;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> by reason of change in law or administrative issue, change in interpretation of a law or administrative issue, or, for compensation purposes, a change in service-connected or employability status or change in physical condition shall be the last day of the month following sixty days from the date of notice to the payee of the reduction or discontinuance;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> by reason of the discontinuance of school attendance of a payee or a dependent of a payee shall be the last day of the month in which such discontinuance occurred;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> by reason of termination of a temporary increase in compensation for hospitalization or treatment shall be the last day of the month in which the hospital discharge or termination of treatment occurred, whichever is earlier;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> by reason of an erroneous award based on an act of commission or omission by the beneficiary, or with the beneficiary’s knowledge, shall be the effective date of the award; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> by reason of an erroneous award based solely on administrative error or error in judgment shall be the date of last payment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–857</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1227</ref>, § 3012; <ref>Pub. L. 87–825, § 2</ref>, <date date="1962-10-15">Oct. 15, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 949</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–730, § 3</ref>, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1159</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–275, § 5</ref>, <date date="1968-03-28">Mar. 28, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 68</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–198, § 3</ref>, <date date="1971-12-15">Dec. 15, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 664</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–433, title IV, § 402</ref>, <date date="1976-09-30">Sept. 30, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1378</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–588, title III, § 303</ref>, <date date="1978-11-04">Nov. 4, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2506</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–253, title IV, § 402(a)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-08">Sept. 8, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 802</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–576, title V, § 503</ref>, title VII, § 701(64), <date date="1986-10-28">Oct. 28, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3286</ref>, 3296; renumbered § 5112 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–40, title IV, § 402(b)(1)</ref>, (d)(1), <date date="1991-05-07">May 7, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 238</ref>, 239; <ref>Pub. L. 107–103, title II, § 204(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-27">Dec. 27, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 990</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–168, title VIII, § 807(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="2022-08-10">Aug. 10, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 1806</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5113.</num>
<heading> Effective dates of educational benefits</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Except as provided in subsections (b) and (c), effective dates relating to awards under chapters 30, 31, 32, 34, and 35 of this title or chapter 106 of title 10 shall, to the extent feasible, correspond to effective dates relating to awards of disability compensation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> When determining the effective date of an award under chapter 35 of this title for an individual described in paragraph (2) based on an original claim, the Secretary may consider the individual’s application as having been filed on the eligibility date of the individual if that eligibility date is more than one year before the date of the initial rating decision.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> An individual referred to in paragraph (1) is an eligible person who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> submits to the Secretary an original application for educational assistance under chapter 35 of this title within one year of the date that the Secretary makes the rating decision;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> claims such educational assistance for pursuit of an approved program of education during a period preceding the one-year period ending on the date on which the application was received by the Secretary; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> would have been entitled to such educational assistance for such course pursuit if the individual had submitted such an application on the individual’s eligibility date.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> In this subsection:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The term “eligibility date” means the date on which an individual becomes an eligible person.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The term “eligible person” has the meaning given that term under subparagraphs (A), (B), (D), and (E) of <ref>section 3501(a)(1) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The term “initial rating decision” means with respect to an eligible person a decision made by the Secretary that establishes (i) service connection for the death of the person from whom such eligibility is derived or (ii) the existence of the service-connected total disability permanent in nature (or, in the case of a person made eligible under section 3501(a)(1)(E), the total disability permanent in nature incurred or aggravated in the line of duty in the active military, naval, air, or space service) of the person from whom such eligibility is derived, as the case may be.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The effective date of an adjustment of benefits under any chapter referred to in subsection (a) of this section, if made on the basis of a certification made by the veteran or person and accepted by the Secretary under <ref>section 3680(g) of this title</ref>, shall be the date of the change.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–857</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1227</ref>, § 3013; <ref>Pub. L. 89–358, § 4(p)</ref>, <date date="1966-03-03">Mar. 3, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 25</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–576, title III, § 321(10)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-28">Oct. 28, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3278</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–322, title III, § 323</ref>, <date date="1988-05-20">May 20, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 536</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–237, title IV, § 419</ref>, <date date="1989-12-18">Dec. 18, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 2087</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–16, § 10(a)(9)</ref>, <date date="1991-03-22">Mar. 22, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 56</ref>; renumbered § 5113, <ref>Pub. L. 102–40, title IV, § 402(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-05-07">May 7, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 238</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–83, § 5(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 406</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–419, title I, § 113(a)</ref>, <date date="2000-11-01">Nov. 1, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1832</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–444, § 3(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-21">Dec. 21, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3307</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–461, title III, § 301(c)(2)</ref>, title X, § 1006(b), <date date="2006-12-22">Dec. 22, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3427</ref>, 3468; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 926(a)(54)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3830</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>PAYMENT OF BENEFITS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5120.</num>
<heading> Payment of benefits; delivery</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Monetary benefits under laws administered by the Secretary shall be paid by checks drawn, pursuant to certification by the Secretary, in such form as to protect the United States against loss, and payable by the Treasurer of the United States. Such checks shall be payable without separate vouchers or receipts except in any case in which the Secretary may consider a voucher necessary for the protection of the Government. Such checks shall be transmitted by mail to the payee thereof at the payee’s last known address and, if the payee has moved and filed a regular change of address notice with the United States Postal Service, shall be forwarded to the payee. The envelope or cover of each such checks shall bear on the face thereof the following notice: “POSTMASTER: PLEASE FORWARD if addressee has moved and filed a regular change-of-address notice. If addressee is deceased, return the letter with date of death, if known.”</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Postmasters, delivery clerks, letter carriers, and all other postal employees are prohibited from delivering any mail addressed by the United States and containing any such check to any person whomsoever if such person has died or in the case of a surviving spouse, if the postal employee believes that the surviving spouse has remarried (unless the mail is addressed to the surviving spouse in the name the surviving spouse has acquired by the remarriage). The preceding sentence shall apply in the case of checks in payment of benefits other than pension, compensation, dependency and indemnity compensation, and insurance, only insofar as the Secretary deems it necessary to protect the United States against loss.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Whenever mail is not delivered because of the prohibition of subsection (b), such mail shall be returned forthwith by the postmaster with a statement of the reason for so doing, and if because of death or remarriage, the date thereof, if known. Checks returned under this subsection because of death or remarriage shall be canceled.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding subsection (a) of this section, pursuant to an agreement with the Department of the Treasury under which the Secretary certifies such benefits for payment, monetary benefits under laws administered by the Secretary may be paid other than by check upon the written request of the person to whom such benefits are to be paid, if such noncheck payment is determined by the Secretary to be in the best interest of such payees and the management of monetary benefits programs by the Department.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> Whenever the first day of any calendar month falls on a Saturday, Sunday, or legal public holiday (as defined in <ref>section 6103 of title 5</ref>), the Secretary shall, to the maximum extent practicable, certify benefit payments for such month in such a way that such payments will be delivered by mail, or transmitted for credit to the payee’s account pursuant to subsection (d) of this section, on the Friday immediately preceding such Saturday or Sunday, or in the case of a legal holiday, the weekday (other than Saturday) immediately preceding such legal public holiday, notwithstanding that such delivery or transmission of such payments is made in the same calendar month for which such payments are issued.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In the case of a payee who does not have a mailing address, payments of monetary benefits under laws administered by the Secretary shall be delivered under an appropriate method prescribed pursuant to paragraph (2) of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall prescribe an appropriate method or methods for the delivery of payments of monetary benefits under laws administered by the Secretary in cases described in paragraph (1) of this subsection. To the maximum extent practicable, such method or methods shall be designed to ensure the delivery of payments in such cases.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–857</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1227</ref>, § 3020; <ref>Pub. L. 95–117, title IV, § 402(a)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="1977-10-03">Oct. 3, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 1065</ref>, 1066; <ref>Pub. L. 97–295, § 4(73)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-12">Oct. 12, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1310</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–570, title XI, § 11007(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3207–170</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–576, title VII, § 701(65)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-28">Oct. 28, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3296</ref>; renumbered § 5120, <ref>Pub. L. 102–40, title IV, § 402(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-05-07">May 7, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 238</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–83, § 4(a)(1)</ref>, (3), (4), (b)(1), (2)(E), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 403–405</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5121.</num>
<heading> Payment of certain accrued benefits upon death of a beneficiary</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Except as provided in sections 3329 and 3330 of title 31, periodic monetary benefits (other than insurance and servicemen’s indemnity) under laws administered by the Secretary to which an individual was entitled at death under existing ratings or decisions or those based on evidence in the file at date of death (hereinafter in this section and <ref>section 5122 of this title</ref> referred to as “accrued benefits”) and due and unpaid, shall, upon the death of such individual be paid as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Upon the death of a person receiving an apportioned share of benefits payable to a veteran, all or any part of such benefits to the veteran or to any other dependent or dependents of the veteran, as may be determined by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Upon the death of a veteran, to the living person first listed below:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The veteran’s spouse.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The veteran’s children (in equal shares).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The veteran’s dependent parents (in equal shares).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Upon the death of a surviving spouse or remarried surviving spouse, to the children of the deceased veteran.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Upon the death of a child, to the surviving children of the veteran who are entitled to death compensation, dependency and indemnity compensation, or death pension.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Upon the death of a child claiming benefits under chapter 18 of this title, to the surviving parents.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> In all other cases, only so much of the accrued benefits may be paid as may be necessary to reimburse the person who bore the expense of last sickness and burial.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> No part of any accrued benefits shall be used to reimburse any political subdivision of the United States for expenses incurred in the last sickness or burial of any beneficiary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Applications for accrued benefits must be filed within one year after the date of death. If a claimant’s application is incomplete at the time it is originally submitted, the Secretary shall notify the claimant of the evidence necessary to complete the application. If such evidence is not received within one year from the date of such notification, no accrued benefits may be paid.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–857</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1228</ref>, § 3021; <ref>Pub. L. 92–328, title I, § 105(b)</ref>, <date date="1972-06-30">June 30, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 395</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–258, § 3(k)(4)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1065</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–160, title VII, § 703(1)</ref>, <date date="1983-11-21">Nov. 21, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 1010</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–576, title VII, § 701(66)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-28">Oct. 28, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3296</ref>; renumbered § 5121 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–40, title IV, § 402(b)(1)</ref>, (d)(1), <date date="1991-05-07">May 7, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 238</ref>, 239; <ref>Pub. L. 102–83, § 4(a)(1)</ref>, (b)(1), (2)(E), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 403–405</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–275, title V, § 507</ref>, <date date="1996-10-09">Oct. 9, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3343</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–14, § 8(a)(16)</ref>, <date date="2001-06-05">June 5, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 35</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–183, title I, § 104(a)</ref>–(c), <date date="2003-12-16">Dec. 16, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2656</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5121A.</num>
<heading> Substitution in case of death of claimant</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Substitution</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> If a claimant dies while a claim for any benefit under a law administered by the Secretary, or an appeal of a decision with respect to such a claim, is pending, a living person who would be eligible to receive accrued benefits due to the claimant under <ref>section 5121(a) of this title</ref> may, not later than one year after the date of the death of such claimant, file a request to be substituted as the claimant for the purposes of processing the claim to completion.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any person seeking to be substituted for the claimant shall present evidence of the right to claim such status within such time as prescribed by the Secretary in regulations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Substitution under this subsection shall be in accordance with such regulations as the Secretary may prescribe.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Those who are eligible to make a claim under this section shall be determined in accordance with <ref>section 5121 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–389, title II, § 212(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-10-10">Oct. 10, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4151</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5122.</num>
<heading> Cancellation of checks mailed to deceased payees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A check received by a payee in payment of accrued benefits shall, if the payee died on or after the last day of the period covered by the check, be returned to the issuing office and canceled, unless negotiated by the payee or the duly appointed representative of the payee’s estate. The amount represented by such check, or any amount recovered by reason of improper negotiation of any such check, shall be payable in the manner provided in <ref>section 5121 of this title</ref>, without regard to <ref>section 5121(c) of this title</ref>. Any amount not paid in the manner provided in <ref>section 5121 of this title</ref> shall be paid to the estate of the deceased payee unless the estate will escheat.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–857</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1229</ref>, § 3022; <ref>Pub. L. 99–576, title VII, § 701(67)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-28">Oct. 28, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3296</ref>; renumbered § 5122 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–40, title IV, § 402(b)(1)</ref>, (d)(1), <date date="1991-05-07">May 7, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 238</ref>, 239; <ref>Pub. L. 104–316, title II, § 202(t)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3845</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5123.</num>
<heading> Rounding down of pension rates</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The monthly or other periodic rate of pension payable to an individual under section 1521, 1541, or 1542 of this title or under section 306(a) of the Veterans’ and Survivors’ Pension Improvement Act of 1978 (<ref>Public Law 95–588</ref>), if not a multiple of $1, shall be rounded down to the nearest dollar.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 97–253, title IV, § 403(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-08">Sept. 8, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 802</ref>, § 3023; renumbered § 5123, <ref>Pub. L. 102–40, title IV, § 402(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-05-07">May 7, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 238</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–83, § 5(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 406</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5124.</num>
<heading> Acceptance of claimant’s statement as proof of relationship</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> For purposes of benefits under laws administered by the Secretary, the Secretary may accept the written statement of a claimant as proof of the existence of any relationship specified in subsection (b) for the purpose of acting on such individual’s claim for benefits.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Subsection (a) applies to proof of the existence of any of the following relationships between a claimant and another person:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Marriage.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Dissolution of a marriage.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Birth of a child.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Death of any family member.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary may require the submission of documentation in support of the claimant’s statement if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the claimant does not reside within a State;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the statement on its face raises a question as to its validity;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> there is conflicting information of record; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> there is reasonable indication, in the statement or otherwise, of fraud or misrepresentation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–446, title III, § 301(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4657</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5125.</num>
<heading> Acceptance of reports of private physician examinations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of establishing any claim for benefits under chapter 11 or 15 of this title, a report of a medical examination administered by a private physician that is provided by a claimant in support of a claim for benefits under that chapter may be accepted without a requirement for confirmation by an examination by a physician employed by the Veterans Health Administration if the report is sufficiently complete to be adequate for the purpose of adjudicating such claim.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–446, title III, § 301(b)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4658</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5126.</num>
<heading> Benefits not to be denied based on lack of mailing address</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Benefits under laws administered by the Secretary may not be denied a claimant on the basis that the claimant does not have a mailing address.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–475, § 3(b)</ref>, <date date="2000-11-09">Nov. 9, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2098</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>