<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 21—</num>
<heading>SPECIALLY ADAPTED HOUSING FOR DISABLED VETERANS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2101.</num>
<heading> Acquisition and adaptation of housing: eligible veterans</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Acquisition of Housing With Special Features</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Subject to paragraphs (3) and (4), the Secretary may assist a disabled veteran described in paragraph (2) in acquiring a suitable housing unit with special fixtures or movable facilities made necessary by the nature of the veteran’s disability, and necessary land therefor.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> A veteran is described in this paragraph if the veteran—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is entitled to compensation under chapter 11 of this title for a service-connected disability that meets any of the criteria described in subparagraph (B); or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> served in the Armed Forces on or after <date date="2001-09-11">September 11, 2001</date>, and is entitled to compensation under chapter 11 of this title for a permanent service-connected disability that meets the criterion described in subparagraph (C).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> The criteria described in this subparagraph are as follows:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The permanent and total disability is due to the loss, or loss of use, of both lower extremities such as to preclude locomotion without the aid of braces, crutches, canes, or a wheelchair.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The permanent disability is due to blindness in both eyes, having central visual acuity of 20/200 or less in the better eye with the use of a standard correcting lens. For the purposes of this clause, an eye with a limitation in the fields of vision such that the widest diameter of the visual field subtends an angle no greater than 20 degrees shall be considered as having a central visual acuity of 20/200 or less.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> The permanent and total disability is due to the loss or loss of use of one lower extremity together with—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> residuals of organic disease or injury; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the loss or loss of use of one upper extremity,</content>
</subclause>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">which so affect the functions of balance or propulsion as to preclude locomotion without the aid of braces, crutches, canes, or a wheelchair.</continuation>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> The permanent and total disability is due to the loss, or loss of use, of both upper extremities such as to preclude use of the arms at or above the elbows.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> The permanent and total disability is due to a severe burn injury (as determined pursuant to regulations prescribed by the Secretary).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> The criterion described in this subparagraph is that the disability—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> was incurred on or after <date date="2001-09-11">September 11, 2001</date>; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> is due to the loss or loss of use of one or more lower extremities which so affects the functions of balance or propulsion as to preclude ambulating without the aid of braces, crutches, canes, or a wheelchair.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The regulations prescribed under subsection (d) shall require that assistance under paragraph (1) may be provided to a veteran only if the Secretary finds that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> it is medically feasible for the veteran to reside in the proposed housing unit and in the proposed locality;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the proposed housing unit bears a proper relation to the veteran’s present and anticipated income and expenses; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the nature and condition of the proposed housing unit are such as to be suitable to the veteran’s needs for dwelling purposes.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> In any fiscal year, the Secretary may not approve more than 120 applications for assistance under paragraph (1) for disabled veterans described in paragraph (2)(A)(ii).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Adaptations to Residence of Veteran</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Subject to paragraph (3), the Secretary shall assist any disabled veteran described in paragraph (2) (other than a veteran who is eligible for assistance under subsection (a))—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in acquiring such adaptations to such veteran’s residence as are determined by the Secretary to be reasonably necessary because of such disability; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in acquiring a residence already adapted with special features determined by the Secretary to be reasonably necessary for the veteran because of such disability.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> A veteran is described in this paragraph if the veteran is entitled to compensation under chapter 11 of this title for a service-connected disability that meets any of the following criteria:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A permanent and total disability that includes the anatomical loss or loss of use of both hands.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A permanent and total disability that is due to a severe burn injury (as so determined).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> Assistance under paragraph (1) may be provided only to a veteran who the Secretary determines—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is residing in and reasonably intends to continue residing in a residence owned by such veteran or by a member of such veteran’s family; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> if the veteran’s residence is to be constructed or purchased, will be residing in and reasonably intends to continue residing in a residence owned by such veteran or by a member of such veteran’s family.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Assistance under this section shall be provided in accordance with such regulations as the Secretary may prescribe.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–857</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1168</ref>, § 801; <ref>Pub. L. 86–239</ref>, <date date="1959-09-08">Sept. 8, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 472</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–401</ref>, <date date="1964-08-04">Aug. 4, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 380</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–22, § 1</ref>, <date date="1969-06-06">June 6, 1969</date>, <ref>83 Stat. 32</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–117, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="1977-10-03">Oct. 3, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 1065</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–385, title III, § 301(a)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-07">Oct. 7, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1531</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–576, title IV, § 401(a)</ref>, title VII, §§ 701(48), 702(7), <date date="1986-10-28">Oct. 28, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3280</ref>, 3295, 3302; renumbered § 2101 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–83</ref>, §§ 4(b)(1), (2)(E), 5(a), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 404–406</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–183, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="2003-12-16">Dec. 16, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2664</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–454, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="2004-12-10">Dec. 10, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3614</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–233, title I, § 105(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-06-15">June 15, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 402</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–289, div. B, title VI</ref>, §§ 2602(b)(1), (7)(A), 2603, <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2859</ref>, 2860; <ref>Pub. L. 112–154, title II</ref>, §§ 202(a), (c), 203(a), <date date="2012-08-06">Aug. 6, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1176</ref>, 1177; <ref>Pub. L. 113–37, § 2(g)</ref>, <date date="2013-09-30">Sept. 30, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 524</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–175, title IV, § 405</ref>, <date date="2014-09-26">Sept. 26, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1905</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–58, title IV, § 407</ref>, title VI, § 601(10), (11), <date date="2015-09-30">Sept. 30, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 535</ref>, 538; <ref>Pub. L. 114–228, title IV, § 408</ref>, <date date="2016-09-29">Sept. 29, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 940</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–62, title IV, § 407</ref>, <date date="2017-09-29">Sept. 29, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1164</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–251, title I, § 121</ref>, <date date="2018-09-29">Sept. 29, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 3169</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–154</ref>, §§ 2, 3(b), <date date="2020-08-08">Aug. 8, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 690</ref>, 691.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2101A.</num>
<heading> Eligibility for benefits and assistance: members of the Armed Forces with service-connected disabilities; individuals residing outside the United States</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Members With Service-Connected Disabilities</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary may provide assistance under this chapter to a member of the Armed Forces serving on active duty who is suffering from a disability that meets applicable criteria for benefits under this chapter if the disability is incurred or aggravated in line of duty in the active military, naval, air, or space service. Such assistance shall be provided to the same extent as assistance is provided under this chapter to veterans eligible for assistance under this chapter and subject to the same requirements as veterans under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> For purposes of this chapter, any reference to a veteran or eligible individual shall be treated as a reference to a member of the Armed Forces described in subsection (a) who is similarly situated to the veteran or other eligible individual so referred to.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Benefits and Assistance for Individuals Residing Outside the United States</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Subject to paragraph (2), the Secretary may, at the Secretary’s discretion, provide benefits and assistance under this chapter (other than benefits under <ref>section 2106 of this title</ref>) to any individual otherwise eligible for such benefits and assistance who resides outside the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary may provide benefits and assistance to an individual under paragraph (1) only if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the country or political subdivision in which the housing or residence involved is or will be located permits the individual to have or acquire a beneficial property interest (as determined by the Secretary) in such housing or residence; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the individual has or will acquire a beneficial property interest (as so determined) in such housing or residence.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding subsections (a) and (b), this section shall not apply to the provision of assistance under <ref>section 2102B of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Benefits and assistance under this chapter by reason of this section shall be provided in accordance with such regulations as the Secretary may prescribe.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–289, div. B, title VI, § 2602(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2858</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–177, § 1(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2018-06-01">June 1, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1377</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 926(a)(34)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3830</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2102.</num>
<heading> Limitations on assistance furnished</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The assistance authorized by <ref>section 2101(a) of this title</ref> shall be afforded under one of the following plans, at the option of the individual—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> where the individual elects to construct a housing unit on land to be acquired by such individual, the Secretary shall pay not to exceed 50 percent of the total cost to the individual of (A) the housing unit and (B) the necessary land upon which it is to be situated;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> where the individual elects to construct a housing unit on land acquired by such individual prior to application for assistance under this chapter, the Secretary shall pay not to exceed the smaller of the following sums: (A) 50 percent of the total cost to the individual of the housing unit and the land necessary for such housing unit, or (B) 50 percent of the cost to the individual of the housing unit plus the full amount of the unpaid balance, if any, of the cost to the individual of the land necessary for such housing unit;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> where the individual elects to remodel a dwelling which is not adapted to the requirements of such individual’s disability, acquired by such individual prior to application for assistance under this chapter, the Secretary shall pay not to exceed (A) the cost to the individual of such remodeling; or (B) 50 percent of the cost to the individual of such remodeling; plus the smaller of the following sums: (i) 50 percent of the cost to the individual of such dwelling and the necessary land upon which it is situated, or (ii) the full amount of the unpaid balance, if any, of the cost to the individual of such dwelling and the necessary land upon which it is situated; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> where the individual has acquired a suitable housing unit, the Secretary shall pay not to exceed the smaller of the following sums: (A) 50 percent of the cost to the individual of such housing unit and the necessary land upon which it is situated, or (B) the full amount of the unpaid balance, if any, of the cost to the individual of such housing unit and the necessary land upon which it is situated.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Except as provided in <ref>section 2104(b) of this title</ref>, the assistance authorized by <ref>section 2101(b) of this title</ref> shall be limited to the lesser of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the actual cost, or, in the case of an individual acquiring a residence already adapted with special features, the fair market value, of the adaptations determined by the Secretary under such section 2101(b) to be reasonably necessary, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> $19,733.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The amount of assistance afforded under subsection (a) for an individual authorized assistance by <ref>section 2101(a) of this title</ref> shall not be reduced by reason that title to the housing unit, which is vested in the individual, is also vested in any other person, if the individual resides in the housing unit.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The aggregate amount of assistance available to an individual under <ref>section 2101(a) of this title</ref> shall be limited to $98,492.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The aggregate amount of assistance available to an individual under <ref>section 2101(b) of this title</ref> shall be limited to $19,733.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Subject to subsection (f), no veteran may receive more than six grants of assistance under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Effective on October 1 of each year (beginning in 2009), the Secretary shall increase the amounts described in subsection (b)(2) and paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (d) in accordance with this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The increase in amounts under paragraph (1) to take effect on October 1 of a year shall be by an amount of such amounts equal to the percentage by which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the residential home cost-of-construction index for the preceding calendar year, exceeds</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the residential home cost-of-construction index for the year preceding the year described in subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall establish a residential home cost-of-construction index for the purposes of this subsection. The index shall reflect a uniform, national average change in the cost of residential home construction, determined on a calendar year basis. The Secretary may use an index developed in the private sector that the Secretary determines is appropriate for purposes of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Beginning <date date="2030-10-01">October 1, 2030</date>, notwithstanding the aggregate amounts specified in subsection (d), a covered veteran may apply for and receive an additional amount of assistance under subsection (a) or (b) of <ref>section 2101 of this title</ref> in an amount that does not exceed half of the amount specified in subsection (d).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> In this subsection, a covered veteran is a veteran who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is described in subsection (a)(2) or (b)(2) of <ref>section 2101 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> as of the date of the veteran’s application for assistance under paragraph (1), most recently received assistance under this chapter more than 10 years before such date; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> lives in a home that the Secretary determines does not have adaptations that are reasonably necessary because of the veteran’s disability.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Whenever the Secretary finds that an overpayment has been made to, or on behalf of, a person described in paragraph (2), the Secretary shall determine—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the amounts to recover, if any; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> who is liable to the United States for such overpayment.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> A person described in this paragraph is any of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> An individual who applied for assistance—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> under this chapter; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> under chapter 31 of this title who is pursuing a rehabilitation program under such chapter in acquiring adaptations to a residence.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> An owner or seller of real estate used, or intended to be used, in connection with assistance under this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> A builder, contractor, supplier, tradesperson, corporation, trust, partnership, or other person, who provided services or goods relating to assistance under this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> An attorney, escrow agent, or financial institution, that receives, or holds in escrow, funds relating to assistance under this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> A surviving spouse, heir, assignee, or successor in interest of or to, any person described in this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Any overpayment referred to in this subsection may be recovered in the same manner as any other debt due the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> In recovering the overpayment, the Secretary may charge administrative costs, fees, and interest, as appropriate, in a manner similar to the authority under <ref>section 5315 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The recovery of any overpayment referred to in this subsection may be waived by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Waiver of any such overpayment as to a person described in paragraph (2) shall in no way release any other person described in such paragraph from liability.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall waive recovery under this subsection of any overpayment to a person described in paragraph (2)(A), or a dependent or survivor of such person, that arises from administrative error described in paragraph (7)(A).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Nothing in this subsection shall be construed as precluding the imposition of any civil or criminal liability under this title or any other law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(7)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary shall prescribe in regulations what constitutes an overpayment for the purposes of this subsection, which, at a minimum, shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> administrative error that results in an individual receiving assistance to which that individual is not entitled;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> the failure of any person described in paragraph (2) to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> perform or allow to be performed any act relating to assistance under this chapter; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> compensate any party performing services or supplying goods relating to assistance under this chapter; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any disbursement of funds relating to assistance under this chapter, that, in the sole discretion of the Secretary, constitutes a misuse of such assistance.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(8)</num>
<chapeau> Prior to collecting an overpayment under this subsection, the Secretary shall provide to the person whom the Secretary has determined liable for such overpayment—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> notice of the finding by the Secretary of such overpayment;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a reasonable opportunity for such person to remedy the circumstances that effectuated the overpayment; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a reasonable opportunity for such person to present evidence to the Secretary that an overpayment was not made.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> For the purposes of <ref>section 511 of this title</ref>, a decision to collect an overpayment from a person other than a person described in paragraph (2)(A), or a dependent or survivor of such person, may not be treated as a decision that affects the provision of benefits.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–857</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1168</ref>, § 802; <ref>Pub. L. 91–22, § 2</ref>, <date date="1969-06-06">June 6, 1969</date>, <ref>83 Stat. 32</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–506, § 6</ref>, <date date="1970-10-23">Oct. 23, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1113</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–341</ref>, <date date="1972-07-10">July 10, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 432</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–569, § 9</ref>, <date date="1974-12-31">Dec. 31, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1867</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–476, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1978-10-18">Oct. 18, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1497</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–385, title III, § 301(b)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-07">Oct. 7, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1531</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–66, title V, § 502</ref>, <date date="1981-10-17">Oct. 17, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1032</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–295, § 4(33)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-12">Oct. 12, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1307</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–543, title III, § 304(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-24">Oct. 24, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2748</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–576, title IV, § 401(b)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-28">Oct. 28, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3280</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–322, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="1988-05-20">May 20, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 534</ref>; renumbered § 2102 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–83</ref>, §§ 4(b)(1), (2)(E), 5(a), (c)(1), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 404–406</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–178, title VIII, § 8204(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-06-09">June 9, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 494</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–419, title III, § 321</ref>, <date date="2000-11-01">Nov. 1, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1855</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–103, title IV, § 404</ref>, <date date="2001-12-27">Dec. 27, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 993</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–183, title IV, § 402(a)</ref>, <date date="2003-12-16">Dec. 16, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2664</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–233, title I, § 101(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-06-15">June 15, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 398</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–289, div. B, title VI</ref>, §§ 2602(b)(2), 2605(a), <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2859</ref>, 2861; <ref>Pub. L. 112–154, title II, § 204(a)</ref>, <date date="2012-08-06">Aug. 6, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1177</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–154</ref>, §§ 3(a), (c)–(e), 4, <date date="2020-08-08">Aug. 8, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 690</ref>, 691; <ref>Pub. L. 116–315, title II, § 2104</ref>, <date date="2021-01-05">Jan. 5, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4982</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2102A.</num>
<heading> Assistance for individuals residing temporarily in housing owned by a family member</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Provision of Assistance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In the case of a disabled individual who is described in subsection (a)(2) or (b)(2) of <ref>section 2101 of this title</ref> and who is residing, but does not intend to permanently reside, in a residence owned by a member of such individual’s family, the Secretary may assist the individual in acquiring such adaptations to such residence as are determined by the Secretary to be reasonably necessary because of the individual’s disability.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Amount of Assistance</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The assistance authorized under subsection (a) may not exceed—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> $28,000, in the case of an individual described in <ref>section 2101(a)(2) of this title</ref>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> $5,000, in the case of an individual described in <ref>section 2101(b)(2) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Effective on October 1 of each year (beginning in 2012), the Secretary shall use the same percentage calculated pursuant to <ref>section 2102(e) of this title</ref> to increase the amounts described in paragraph (1) of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The assistance authorized by subsection (a) shall be limited in the case of any individual to one residence.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Assistance under this section shall be provided in accordance with such regulations as the Secretary may prescribe.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Termination</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No assistance may be provided under this section after <date date="2025-09-30">September 30, 2025</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–233, title I, § 101(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-06-15">June 15, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 398</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 110–289, div. B, title VI</ref>, §§ 2602(b)(3), (7)(B), 2604, <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2859–2861</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–37, § 14</ref>, <date date="2011-10-05">Oct. 5, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 397</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–154, title II, § 205(a)</ref>–(c), <date date="2012-08-06">Aug. 6, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1178</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–180, div. E, title II, § 204</ref>, <date date="2022-09-30">Sept. 30, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2137</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–83, div. B, title III, § 321</ref>, <date date="2024-09-26">Sept. 26, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1540</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2102B.</num>
<heading> Adaptations to residences of veterans in rehabilitation programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to subsections (b) and (c), the Secretary may assist a veteran who is entitled to services and assistance under chapter 31 of this title and is pursuing a rehabilitation program under such chapter in acquiring such adaptations to such veteran’s residence as are determined necessary by the Secretary to accomplish the purposes of such rehabilitation program.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Amount</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The aggregate amount of assistance available to a veteran under subsection (a) may not exceed $77,307. The Secretary may waive this limitation for a veteran if the Secretary determines a waiver is necessary for the rehabilitation program of the veteran.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Effective on October 1 of each year (beginning in 2017), the Secretary shall increase the amount described in paragraph (1) by the percentage calculated under <ref>section 2102(e)(2) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Beginning on <date date="2019-10-01">October 1, 2019</date>, the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and House of Representatives a biennial report on the use of the waiver authority under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to carry out this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rehabilitation Program Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “rehabilitation program” has the meaning given such term in <ref>section 3101 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–177, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-06-01">June 1, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1376</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2103.</num>
<heading> Furnishing of plans and specifications</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Plans and Specifications</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary is authorized to furnish to individuals eligible for assistance under this chapter, without cost to the individuals, model plans and specifications of suitable housing units.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Handbook for Design</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall make available to veterans eligible for assistance under this chapter, without cost to the veterans, a handbook containing appropriate designs for specially adapted housing. The Secretary shall update such handbook at least once every six years to take into account any new or unique disabilities, including vision impairments, impairments specific to the upper limbs, and burn injuries.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–857</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1168</ref>, § 803; renumbered § 2103 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–83</ref>, §§ 4(b)(1), (2)(E), 5(a), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 404–406</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–289, div. B, title VI, § 2602(b)(4)</ref>, <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2859</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–389, title V, § 503</ref>, <date date="2008-10-10">Oct. 10, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4176</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2104.</num>
<heading> Benefits additional to benefits under other laws</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Any individual who accepts the benefits of this chapter shall not by reason thereof be denied the benefits of chapter 37 of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> An individual eligible for assistance under <ref>section 2101(b) of this title</ref> shall not by reason of such eligibility be denied benefits for which such individual becomes eligible under <ref>section 2101(a) of this title</ref> or benefits relating to home health services under <ref>section 1717(a)(2) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Secretary may not provide assistance to a veteran under this chapter if the Secretary determines such assistance would result in a duplication of benefits under this title to the veteran.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–857</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1169</ref>, § 804; <ref>Pub. L. 96–385, title III, § 301(c)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-07">Oct. 7, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1531</ref>; renumbered § 2104 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–83, § 5(a)</ref>, (c)(1), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 406</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–262, title I, § 101(e)(2)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-09">Oct. 9, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3180</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–289, div. B, title VI, § 2602(b)(5)</ref>, <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2859</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–177, § 1(c)(3)</ref>, <date date="2018-06-01">June 1, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1377</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2105.</num>
<heading> Nonliability of United States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Government of the United States shall have no liability in connection with any housing unit, or necessary land therefor, or adaptation acquired under the provisions of this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–857</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1169</ref>, § 805; <ref>Pub. L. 96–385, title III, § 301(d)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-07">Oct. 7, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1531</ref>; renumbered § 2105, <ref>Pub. L. 102–83, § 5(a)</ref>, <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 406</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2106.</num>
<heading> Veterans’ mortgage life insurance</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary shall insure any individual under 70 years of age who has received assistance under this chapter against the death of the individual except for an individual who—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> elects in writing to not receive insurance under this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> fails to respond in a timely manner to a request from the Secretary for information on which the premium for such insurance can be based; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> receives such assistance under <ref>section 2102B of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The amount of insurance provided an individual under this section may not exceed the lesser of $150,000, or after <date date="2012-01-01">January 1, 2012</date>, $200,000, or the amount of the loan outstanding on the housing unit. The amount of such insurance shall be reduced according to the amortization schedule of the loan and may not at any time exceed the amount of the outstanding loan with interest. If there is no outstanding loan on the housing unit, insurance is not payable under this section. If an eligible individual elects not to be insured under this section, the individual may thereafter be insured under this section, but only upon submission of an application, payment of required premiums, and compliance with such health requirements and other terms and conditions as may be prescribed by the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The premiums charged an individual for insurance under this section shall be paid at such time and in such manner as the Secretary prescribes. The rates for such premiums shall be based on such mortality data as the Secretary considers appropriate to cover only the mortality cost of insuring standard lives. In the case of an individual receiving compensation or other cash benefits paid to the individual by the Secretary, the Secretary shall deduct from such compensation or other benefits the premiums charged the individual under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The United States shall bear the costs of insurance under this section to the extent that such costs exceed premiums established by the Secretary. Premiums collected on insurance under this section shall be credited to the “Veterans Insurance and Indemnities” appropriation account, and all disbursements of insurance proceeds under this section shall be made from that account.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary for such account such amounts as may be necessary to carry out this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> Any amount of insurance in force under this section on the date of the death of an individual insured under this section shall be paid to the holder of the mortgage loan, for payment of which the insurance was granted, for credit on the loan indebtedness. Any liability of the United States under such insurance shall be satisfied when such payment is made. If the Secretary is the holder of the mortgage loan, the insurance proceeds shall be credited to the loan indebtedness and deposited in the Veterans Housing Benefit Program Fund established by <ref>section 3722 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> The Secretary may prescribe such regulations relating to eligibility for insurance under this section, the maximum amount of insurance, the effective date of insurance, the maximum duration of insurance, and other pertinent matters not specifically provided for in this section as the Secretary determines are in the best interest of veterans or the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> The amount of the insurance in force at any time shall be the amount necessary to pay the mortgage indebtedness in full, except as otherwise limited by subsection (b) of this section or regulations prescribed by the Secretary under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall issue to each individual insured under this section a certificate setting forth the benefits to which the individual is entitled under the insurance.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> Insurance under this section shall terminate upon whichever of the following events first occurs:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Satisfaction of the individual’s indebtedness under the loan upon which the insurance is based.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Termination of the individual’s ownership of the property securing the loan.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Discontinuance of payment of premiums by the individual.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<content> Termination of life insurance under this section shall not affect the guaranty or insurance of the loan by the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 92–95, § 1</ref>, <date date="1971-08-11">Aug. 11, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 320</ref>, § 806; amended <ref>Pub. L. 94–433, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="1976-09-30">Sept. 30, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1377</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–576, title VII, § 701(49)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-28">Oct. 28, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3295</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–322, title III, § 333(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1988-05-20">May 20, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 537</ref>; renumbered § 2106 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–83</ref>, §§ 4(b)(1), (2)(E), 5(a), (c)(1), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 404–406</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–568, title II, § 204(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4325</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–446, title XII, § 1201(h)(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4688</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–368, title VI, § 602(e)(2)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-11">Nov. 11, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3347</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–330, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="2002-12-06">Dec. 6, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2824</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–289, div. B, title VI, § 2602(b)(6)</ref>, <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2860</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–275, title IV, § 407(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-13">Oct. 13, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2880</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–177, § 1(c)(4)</ref>, <date date="2018-06-01">June 1, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1377</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2107.</num>
<heading> Coordination of administration of benefits</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall provide for the coordination of the administration of programs to provide specially adapted housing that are administered by the Under Secretary for Health and such programs that are administered by the Under Secretary for Benefits under this chapter, chapter 17, and chapter 31 of this title.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–233, title I, § 101(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-06-15">June 15, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 399</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2108.</num>
<heading> Specially adapted housing assistive technology grant program</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority to Make Grants</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall make grants to encourage the development of new assistive technologies for specially adapted housing.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Application</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A person or entity seeking a grant under this section shall submit to the Secretary an application for the grant in such form and manner as the Secretary shall specify.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Grant Funds</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Each grant awarded under this section shall be in an amount of not more than $200,000 per fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> For each fiscal year in which the Secretary makes a grant under this section, the Secretary shall make the grant by not later than April 1 of that year.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of Funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The recipient of a grant under this section shall use the grant to develop assistive technologies for use in specially adapted housing.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not later than March 1 of each fiscal year following a fiscal year in which the Secretary makes a grant, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report containing information related to each grant awarded under this section during the preceding fiscal year, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the name of the grant recipient;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the amount of the grant; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the goal of the grant.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Funding</inline>.—</heading>
<content>From amounts appropriated to the Department for readjustment benefits for each fiscal year for which the Secretary is authorized to make a grant under this section, $1,000,000 shall be available for that fiscal year for the purposes of the program under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duration</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The authority to make a grant under this section shall begin on <date date="2011-10-01">October 1, 2011</date>, and shall terminate on <date date="2025-09-30">September 30, 2025</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–275, title II, § 203(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-13">Oct. 13, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2874</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 114–228, title IV, § 409</ref>, <date date="2016-09-29">Sept. 29, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 940</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–62, title IV, § 408</ref>, <date date="2017-09-29">Sept. 29, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1164</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–251, title I, § 122</ref>, <date date="2018-09-29">Sept. 29, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 3169</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–159, div. E, title II, § 5201</ref>, <date date="2020-10-01">Oct. 1, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 749</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–180, div. E, title II, § 205</ref>, <date date="2022-09-30">Sept. 30, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2138</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–83, div. B, title III, § 322</ref>, <date date="2024-09-26">Sept. 26, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1540</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2109.</num>
<heading> Specially adapted housing destroyed or damaged by natural disasters</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding the provisions of sections 2102 and 2102A of this title, the Secretary may provide assistance to a veteran whose home was previously adapted with assistance of a grant under this chapter in the event the adapted home which was being used and occupied by the veteran was destroyed or substantially damaged in a natural or other disaster, as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of Funds</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subject to subsection (c), assistance provided under subsection (a) shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> be available to acquire a suitable housing unit with special fixtures or moveable facilities made necessary by the veteran’s disability, and necessary land therefor;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> be available to a veteran to the same extent as if the veteran had not previously received assistance under this chapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> not be deducted from the maximum uses or from the maximum amount of assistance available under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The amount of the assistance provided under subsection (a) may not exceed the lesser of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the reasonable cost, as determined by the Secretary, of repairing or replacing the damaged or destroyed home in excess of the available insurance coverage on such home; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the maximum amount of assistance to which the veteran would have been entitled under sections 2101(a), 2101(b), and 2102A of this title had the veteran not obtained previous assistance under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 112–154, title VII, § 701(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2012-08-06">Aug. 6, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1202</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 114–58, title VI, § 601(12)</ref>, <date date="2015-09-30">Sept. 30, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 538</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>