<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 77—</num>
<heading>VETERANS BENEFITS ADMINISTRATION</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>ORGANIZATION; GENERAL</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7701.</num>
<heading> Organization of the Administration</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> There is in the Department of Veterans Affairs a Veterans Benefits Administration. The primary function of the Veterans Benefits Administration is the administration of nonmedical benefits programs of the Department which provide assistance to veterans and their dependents and survivors.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Veterans Benefits Administration is under the Under Secretary for Benefits, who is directly responsible to the Secretary for the operations of the Administration. The Under Secretary for Benefits may be referred to as the Chief Benefits Director.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–83, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 399</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–405, title III, § 302(c)(1)</ref>, (3), <date date="1992-10-09">Oct. 9, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 1984</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7703.</num>
<heading> Functions of the Administration</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Veterans Benefits Administration is responsible for the administration of the following programs of the Department:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Compensation and pension programs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Vocational rehabilitation and educational assistance programs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Veterans’ housing loan programs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Veterans’ and servicemembers’ life insurance programs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Outreach programs and other veterans’ services programs.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–83, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 399</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>QUALITY ASSURANCE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7731.</num>
<heading> Establishment</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall carry out a quality assurance program in the Veterans Benefits Administration. The program may be carried out through a single quality assurance division in the Administration or through separate quality assurance entities for each of the principal organizational elements (known as “services”) of the Administration.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall ensure that any quality assurance entity established and operated under subsection (a) is established and operated so as to meet generally applicable governmental standards for independence and internal controls for the performance of quality reviews of Government performance and results.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall enter into a contract with an independent third-party entity to conduct, during the three-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of the Veterans’ Benefits Improvement Act of 2008, an assessment of the quality assurance program carried out under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The assessment conducted under paragraph (1) shall evaluate the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The quality and accuracy of the work of employees of the Veterans Benefits Administration, using a statistically valid sample of such employees and a statistically valid sample of such work.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The performance of each regional office of the Veterans Benefits Administration.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The accuracy of the disability ratings assigned under the schedule for rating disabilities under <ref>section 1155 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The consistency of disability ratings among regional offices of the Veterans Benefits Administration, based on a sample of specific disabilities.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The performance of employees and managers of the Veterans Benefits Administration.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall develop a mechanism for the automated gathering and producing of data that can be used to monitor and assess trends relating to the items described in paragraph (2).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> Beginning on the date that is six months after the date of the enactment of the Veterans’ Benefits Improvement Act of 2008, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> for each claim for disability compensation under laws administered by the Secretary submitted to the Secretary on or after such date, retain, monitor, and store in an accessible format the data described in subparagraph (B); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> develop a demographic baseline for the data retained, monitored, and stored under subparagraph (A).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> The data described in this subparagraph includes the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> For each claim for disability compensation under laws administered by the Secretary submitted by a claimant—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the State in which the claimant resided when the claim was submitted;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the decision of the Secretary with respect to the claim and each issue claimed; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> the regional office and individual employee of the Department responsible for rating the claim.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The State in which the claimant currently resides.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Such other data as the Secretary determines is appropriate for monitoring the accuracy and consistency of decisions with respect to such claims.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to require the Secretary to replace the quality assurance program under subsection (a) that was in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–117, § 801(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1999-11-30">Nov. 30, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1585</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 110–389, title II, § 224(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-10-10">Oct. 10, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4157</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7732.</num>
<heading> Functions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Under Secretary for Benefits, acting through the quality assurance entities established under section 7731(a), shall on an ongoing basis perform and oversee quality reviews of the functions of each of the principal organizational elements of the Veterans Benefits Administration.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–117, § 801(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1999-11-30">Nov. 30, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1585</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7732A.</num>
<heading> Employee certification</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Development of Certification Examination</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall provide for an examination of appropriate employees and managers of the Veterans Benefits Administration who are responsible for processing claims for compensation and pension benefits under the laws administered by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> In developing the examination required by paragraph (1), the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> consult with appropriate individuals or entities, including examination development experts, interested stakeholders, and employee representatives; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> consider the data gathered and produced under <ref>section 7731(c)(3) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Employee and Manager Requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall require appropriate employees and managers of the Veterans Benefits Administration who are responsible for processing claims for compensation and pension benefits under the laws administered by the Secretary to take the examination provided under subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–389, title II, § 225(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2008-10-10">Oct. 10, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4158</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7733.</num>
<heading> Personnel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall ensure that the number of full-time employees of the Veterans Benefits Administration assigned to quality assurance functions under this subchapter is adequate to perform the quality assurance functions for which they have responsibility.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–117, § 801(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1999-11-30">Nov. 30, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1585</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7734.</num>
<heading> Annual report to Congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall include in the annual report to the Congress required by <ref>section 529 of this title</ref> a report on the quality assurance activities carried out under this subchapter. Each such report shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> an appraisal of the quality of services provided by the Veterans Benefits Administration, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the number of decisions reviewed;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a summary of the findings on the decisions reviewed;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the number of full-time equivalent employees assigned to quality assurance in each division or entity;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> specific documentation of compliance with the standards for independence and internal control required by <ref>section 7731(b) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> actions taken to improve the quality of services provided and the results obtained;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> information with respect to the accuracy of decisions, including trends in that information; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> such other information as the Secretary considers appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–117, § 801(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1999-11-30">Nov. 30, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1585</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>