<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 83—</num>
<heading>BUY AMERICAN</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 8301.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Public building, public use, and public work</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The terms “public building”, “public use”, and “public work” mean a public building of, use by, and a public work of, the Federal Government, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, American Samoa, and the Virgin Islands.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">United states</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “United States” includes any place subject to the jurisdiction of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Federal agency</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “Federal agency” has the meaning given the term “executive agency” in <ref>section 133 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3830</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–58, div. G, title IX, § 70922(d)</ref>, <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1304</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8302.</num>
<heading> American materials required for public use</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">In General.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Allowable materials</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Only unmanufactured articles, materials, and supplies that have been mined or produced in the United States, and only manufactured articles, materials, and supplies that have been manufactured in the United States substantially all from articles, materials, or supplies mined, produced, or manufactured in the United States, shall be acquired for public use unless the head of the Federal agency concerned determines their acquisition to be inconsistent with the public interest, their cost to be unreasonable, or that the articles, materials, or supplies of the class or kind to be used, or the articles, materials, or supplies from which they are manufactured, are not mined, produced, or manufactured in the United States in sufficient and reasonably available commercial quantities and of a satisfactory quality.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exceptions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>This section does not apply—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to articles, materials, or supplies for use outside the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to any articles, materials, or supplies procured pursuant to a reciprocal defense procurement memorandum of understanding (as described in <ref>section 8304 of this title</ref>), or a trade agreement or least developed country designation described in subpart 25.400 of the Federal Acquisition Regulation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to manufactured articles, materials, or supplies procured under any contract with an award value that is not more than the micro-purchase threshold under <ref>section 1902 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Reports.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 180 days after the end of the fiscal year during which the Build America, Buy America Act is enacted, and annually thereafter for 4 years, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, in consultation with the Administrator of General Services, shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Oversight and Reform of the House of Representatives a report on the total amount of acquisitions made by Federal agencies in the relevant fiscal year of articles, materials, or supplies acquired from entities that mine, produce, or manufacture the articles, materials, or supplies outside the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception for intelligence community</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This subsection does not apply to acquisitions made by an agency, or component of an agency, that is an element of the intelligence community as specified in, or designated under, section 3 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3003</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Special Rules</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The following rules apply in carrying out the provisions of subsection (a):</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Iron and steel manufactured in the united states</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of this section, manufactured articles, materials, and supplies of iron and steel are deemed manufactured in the United States only if all manufacturing processes involved in the production of such iron and steel, from the initial melting stage through the application of coatings, occurs in the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on exception for commercially available off-the-shelf items</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding any law or regulation to the contrary, including <ref>section 1907 of this title</ref> and the Federal Acquisition Regulation, the requirements of this section apply to all iron and steel articles, materials, and supplies.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3831</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–58, div. G, title IX, § 70922(a)</ref>, (c), (e)(1), <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1303</ref>, 1304.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8303.</num>
<heading> Contracts for public works</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Every contract for the construction, alteration, or repair of any public building or public work in the United States shall contain a provision that in the performance of the work the contractor, subcontractors, material men, or suppliers shall use only—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> unmanufactured articles, materials, and supplies that have been mined or produced in the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> manufactured articles, materials, and supplies that have been manufactured in the United States substantially all from articles, materials, or supplies mined, produced, or manufactured in the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Exceptions.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>This section does not apply—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to articles, materials, or supplies for use outside the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to any articles, materials, or supplies procured pursuant to a reciprocal defense procurement memorandum of understanding (as described in section 8304), or a trade agreement or least developed country designation described in subpart 25.400 of the Federal Acquisition Regulation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to manufactured articles, materials, or supplies procured under any contract with an award value that is not more than the micro-purchase threshold under <ref>section 1902 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Particular article, material, or supply</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the head of the Federal agency making the contract finds that it is impracticable to comply with subsection (a) for a particular article, material, or supply or that it would unreasonably increase the cost, an exception shall be noted in the specifications for that article, material, or supply and a public record of the findings that justified the exception shall be made.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Waiver authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subsection (a) shall be regarded as requiring the purchase, for public use within the United States, of articles, materials, or supplies manufactured in the United States in sufficient and reasonably available commercial quantities and of a satisfactory quality, unless the head of the Federal agency concerned determines their acquisition to be inconsistent with the public interest, their cost to be unreasonable, or that the articles, materials, or supplies of the class or kind to be used, or the articles, materials, or supplies from which they are manufactured, are not mined, produced, or manufactured in the United States in sufficient and reasonably available commercial quantities and of a satisfactory quality.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Special Rules.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Production of iron and steel</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of this section, manufactured articles, materials, and supplies of iron and steel are deemed manufactured in the United States only if all manufacturing processes involved in the production of such iron and steel, from the initial melting stage through the application of coatings, occurs in the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on exception for commercially available off-the-shelf items</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding any law or regulation to the contrary, including <ref>section 1907 of this title</ref> and the Federal Acquisition Regulation, the requirements of this section apply to all iron and steel articles, materials, and supplies used in contracts described in subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Results of Failure To Comply</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the head of a Federal agency that has made a contract containing the provision required by subsection (a) finds that there has been a failure to comply with the provision in the performance of the contract, the head of the Federal agency shall make the findings public. The findings shall include the name of the contractor obligated under the contract. The contractor, and any subcontractor, material man, or supplier associated or affiliated with the contractor, shall not be awarded another contract for the construction, alteration, or repair of any public building or public work for 3 years after the findings are made public.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3832</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–58, div. G, title IX, § 70922(b)</ref>, (e)(2), <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1303</ref>, 1305.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8304.</num>
<heading> Waiver rescission</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Type of Agreement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An agreement referred to in subsection (b) is a reciprocal defense procurement memorandum of understanding between the United States and a foreign country pursuant to which the Secretary of Defense has prospectively waived this chapter for certain products in that country.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Determination by Secretary of Defense</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the Secretary of Defense, after consultation with the United States Trade Representative, determines that a foreign country that is party to an agreement described in subsection (a) has violated the agreement by discriminating against certain types of products produced in the United States that are covered by the agreement, the Secretary of Defense shall rescind the Secretary’s blanket waiver of this chapter with respect to those types of products produced in that country.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3833</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8305.</num>
<heading> Annual report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 60 days after the end of each fiscal year, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to Congress a report on the amount of purchases by the Department of Defense from foreign entities in that fiscal year. The report shall separately indicate the dollar value of items for which this chapter was waived pursuant to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a reciprocal defense procurement memorandum of understanding described in <ref>section 8304(a) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Trade Agreements Act of 1979 (<ref>19 U.S.C. 2501</ref> et seq.); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> an international agreement to which the United States is a party.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3833</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>