<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 15—</num>
<heading>COST ACCOUNTING STANDARDS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1501.</num>
<heading> Cost Accounting Standards Board</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Organization</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Cost Accounting Standards Board is an independent board in the Office of Federal Procurement Policy.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Membership.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Number of members, chairman, and appointment</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Board consists of 5 members. One member is the Administrator, who serves as Chairman. The other 4 members, all of whom shall have experience in Federal Government contract cost accounting, are as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> 2 representatives of the Federal Government—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> one of whom is a representative of the Department of Defense appointed by the Secretary of Defense; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> one of whom is an officer or employee of the General Services Administration appointed by the Administrator of General Services.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> 2 individuals from the private sector, each of whom is appointed by the Administrator, and—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> one of whom is a representative of industry; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> one of whom is particularly knowledgeable about cost accounting problems and systems and, if possible, is a representative of a public accounting firm.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Term of office.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Length of term</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term of office of each member, other than the Administrator, is 4 years. The terms are staggered, with the terms of 2 members expiring in the same year, the term of another member expiring the next year, and the term of the last member expiring the year after that.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Individual required to remain with appointing agency</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A member appointed under paragraph (1)(A) may not continue to serve after ceasing to be an officer or employee of the agency from which that member was appointed.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Vacancy</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A vacancy on the Board shall be filled in the same manner in which the original appointment was made. A member appointed to fill a vacancy serves for the remainder of the term for which that member’s predecessor was appointed.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duties</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Board shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> ensure that the cost accounting standards used by Federal contractors rely, to the maximum extent practicable, on commercial standards and accounting practices and systems;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> within one year after the date of enactment of this subsection, and on an ongoing basis thereafter, review any cost accounting standards established under <ref>section 1502 of this title</ref> and conform such standards, where practicable, to Generally Accepted Accounting Principles; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> annually review disputes involving such standards brought to the boards established in <ref>section 7105 of this title</ref> or Federal courts, and consider whether greater clarity in such standards could avoid such disputes.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Meetings</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Board shall meet not less than once each quarter and shall publish in the Federal Register notice of each meeting and its agenda before such meeting is held.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Board shall annually submit a report to the congressional defense committees, the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate describing the actions taken during the prior year—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to conform the cost accounting standards established under <ref>section 1502 of this title</ref> with Generally Accepted Accounting Principles; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to minimize the burden on contractors while protecting the interests of the Federal Government.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Senior Staff</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Administrator, after consultation with the Board—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> without regard to the provisions of title 5 governing appointments in the competitive service—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall appoint an executive secretary; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> may appoint, or detail pursuant to <ref>section 3341 of title 5</ref>, two additional staff members; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> may pay those employees without regard to the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5 relating to classification and General Schedule pay rates, except that those employees may not receive pay in excess of the maximum rate of basic pay payable for level IV of the Executive Schedule.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Other Staff</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator may appoint, fix the compensation of, and remove additional employees of the Board under the applicable provisions of title 5.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Detailed and Temporary Personnel</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For service on advisory committees and task forces to assist the Board in carrying out its functions and responsibilities—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Board, with the consent of the head of a Federal agency, may use, without reimbursement, personnel of that agency; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Administrator, after consultation with the Board, may procure temporary and intermittent services of personnel under <ref>section 3109(b) of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Compensation.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Officers and employees of the government</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Members of the Board who are officers or employees of the Federal Government, and officers and employees of other agencies of the Federal Government who are used under subsection (h)(1), shall not receive additional compensation for services but shall continue to be compensated by the employing department or agency of the officer or employee.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appointees from private sector</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each member of the Board appointed from the private sector shall receive compensation at a rate not to exceed the daily equivalent of the rate for level IV of the Executive Schedule for each day (including travel time) in which the member is engaged in the actual performance of duties vested in the Board.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Temporary and intermittent personnel</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An individual hired under subsection (h)(2) may receive compensation at a rate fixed by the Administrator, but not to exceed the daily equivalent of the rate for level V of the Executive Schedule for each day (including travel time) in which the individual is properly engaged in the actual performance of duties under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Travel expenses</inline>.—</heading>
<content>While serving away from home or regular place of business, Board members and other individuals serving on an intermittent basis under this chapter shall be allowed travel expenses in accordance with <ref>section 5703 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3695</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title VIII, § 820(a)(1)</ref>, (3), <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2273</ref>, 2274.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1502.</num>
<heading> Cost accounting standards</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Authority.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Cost accounting standards board</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Cost Accounting Standards Board has exclusive authority to prescribe, amend, and rescind cost accounting standards, and interpretations of the standards, designed to achieve uniformity and consistency in the cost accounting standards governing measurement, assignment, and allocation of costs to contracts with the Federal Government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Administrator for federal procurement policy</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator, after consultation with the Board, shall prescribe rules and procedures governing actions of the Board under this chapter. The rules and procedures shall require that any action to prescribe, amend, or rescind a standard or interpretation be approved by majority vote of the Board.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Mandatory Use of Standards.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Subcontract.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this paragraph, the term “subcontract” includes a transfer of commercial products or commercial services between divisions, subsidiaries, or affiliates of a contractor or subcontractor.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">When standards are to be used</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Cost accounting standards prescribed under this chapter are mandatory for use by all executive agencies and by contractors and subcontractors in estimating, accumulating, and reporting costs in connection with the pricing and administration of, and settlement of disputes concerning, all negotiated prime contract and subcontract procurements with the Federal Government in excess of the amount set forth in <ref>section 3702(a)(1)(A) of title 10</ref> as the amount is adjusted in accordance with applicable requirements of law.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Nonapplication of standards</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subparagraph (B) does not apply to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a contract or subcontract for the acquisition of a commercial product or commercial service;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a contract or subcontract where the price negotiated is based on a price set by law or regulation;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a firm, fixed-price contract or subcontract awarded on the basis of adequate price competition without submission of certified cost or pricing data; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> a contract or subcontract with a value of less than $7,500,000 if, when the contract or subcontract is entered into, the segment of the contractor or subcontractor that will perform the work has not been awarded at least one contract or subcontract with a value of more than $7,500,000 that is covered by the standards.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exemptions and waivers by board</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Board may—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> exempt classes of contractors and subcontractors from the requirements of this chapter; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> establish procedures for the waiver of the requirements of this chapter for individual contracts and subcontracts.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Waiver by head of executive agency.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The head of an executive agency may waive the applicability of the cost accounting standards for a contract or subcontract with a value of less than $100,000,000 if that official determines in writing that the segment of the contractor or subcontractor that will perform the work—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is primarily engaged in the sale of commercial products or commercial services; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> would not otherwise be subject to the cost accounting standards under this section.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In exceptional circumstances</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The head of an executive agency may waive the applicability of the cost accounting standards for a contract or subcontract under exceptional circumstances when necessary to meet the needs of the agency. A determination to waive the applicability of the standards under this subparagraph shall be set forth in writing and shall include a statement of the circumstances justifying the waiver.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Restriction on delegation of authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The head of an executive agency may not delegate the authority under subparagraph (A) or (B) to an official in the executive agency below the senior policymaking level in the executive agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contents of federal acquisition regulation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Federal Acquisition Regulation shall include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> criteria for selecting an official to be delegated authority to grant waivers under subparagraph (A) or (B); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the specific circumstances under which the waiver may be granted.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The head of each executive agency shall report the waivers granted under subparagraphs (A) and (B) for that agency to the Board on an annual basis.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Required Board Action for Prescribing Standards and Interpretations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Before prescribing cost accounting standards and interpretations, the Board shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> take into account, after consultation and discussions with the Comptroller General, professional accounting organizations, contractors, and other interested parties—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the probable costs of implementation, including any inflationary effects, compared to the probable benefits;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the advantages, disadvantages, and improvements anticipated in the pricing and administration of, and settlement of disputes concerning, contracts; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the scope of, and alternatives available to, the action proposed to be taken;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> prepare and publish a report in the Federal Register on the issues reviewed under paragraph (1);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> publish an advanced notice of proposed rulemaking in the Federal Register to solicit comments on the report prepared under paragraph (2);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provide all parties affected at least 60 days after publication to submit their views and comments; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> during the 60-day period, consult with the Comptroller General and consider any recommendation the Comptroller General may make; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> publish a notice of proposed rulemaking in the Federal Register and provide all parties affected at least 60 days after publication to submit their views and comments.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Effective Dates</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Rules, regulations, cost accounting standards, and modifications thereof prescribed or amended under this chapter shall have the full force and effect of law, and shall become effective within 120 days after publication in the Federal Register in final form, unless the Board determines that a longer period is necessary. The Board shall determine implementation dates for contractors and subcontractors. The dates may not be later than the beginning of the second fiscal year of the contractor or subcontractor after the standard becomes effective.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Accompanying Material</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Rules, regulations, cost accounting standards, and modifications thereof prescribed or amended under this chapter shall be accompanied by prefatory comments and by illustrations, if necessary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Implementing Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Board shall prescribe regulations for the implementation of cost accounting standards prescribed or interpreted under this section. The regulations shall be incorporated into the Federal Acquisition Regulation and shall require contractors and subcontractors as a condition of contracting with the Federal Government to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> disclose in writing their cost accounting practices, including methods of distinguishing direct costs from indirect costs and the basis used for allocating indirect costs; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> agree to a contract price adjustment, with interest, for any increased costs paid to the contractor or subcontractor by the Federal Government because of a change in the contractor’s or subcontractor’s cost accounting practices or a failure by the contractor or subcontractor to comply with applicable cost accounting standards.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Nonapplicability of Certain Sections of Title </inline>5.—</heading>
<content>Functions exercised under this chapter are not subject to sections 551, 553 to 559, and 701 to 706 of title 5.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3696</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title VIII, § 820(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2274</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 836(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1860</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1702(h)(3)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2158</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1503.</num>
<heading> Contract price adjustment</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Disagreement Constitutes a Dispute</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the Federal Government and a contractor or subcontractor fail to agree on a contract price adjustment, including whether the contractor or subcontractor has complied with the applicable cost accounting standards, the disagreement will constitute a dispute under chapter 71 of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Amount of Adjustment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A contract price adjustment undertaken under <ref>section 1502(f)(2) of this title</ref> shall be made, where applicable, on relevant contracts between the Federal Government and the contractor that are subject to the cost accounting standards so as to protect the Federal Government from payment, in the aggregate, of increased costs, as defined by the Cost Accounting Standards Board. The Federal Government may not recover costs greater than the aggregate increased cost to the Federal Government, as defined by the Board, on the relevant contracts subject to the price adjustment unless the contractor made a change in its cost accounting practices of which it was aware or should have been aware at the time of the price negotiation and which it failed to disclose to the Federal Government.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Interest</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The interest rate applicable to a contract price adjustment is the annual rate of interest established under section 6621 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (<ref>26 U.S.C. 6621</ref>) for the period. Interest accrues from the time payments of the increased costs were made to the contractor or subcontractor to the time the Federal Government receives full compensation for the price adjustment.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3699</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1504.</num>
<heading> Effect on other standards and regulations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Previously Existing Standards</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>All cost accounting standards, waivers, exemptions, interpretations, modifications, rules, and regulations prescribed by the Cost Accounting Standards Board under section 719 of the Defense Production Act of 1950 (50 U.S.C. App. 2168)— <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002003">1</ref></chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> remain in effect until amended, superseded, or rescinded by the Board under this chapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> are subject to the provisions of this division in the same manner as if prescribed by the Board under this division.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inconsistent Agency Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>To ensure that a regulation or proposed regulation of an executive agency is not inconsistent with a cost accounting standard prescribed or amended under this chapter, the Administrator, under the authority in sections 1121, 1122(a) to (c)(1), 1125, 1126, 1130, 1131, and 2305 of this title, shall rescind or deny the promulgation of the inconsistent regulation or proposed regulation and take other appropriate action authorized under sections 1121, 1122(a) to (c)(1), 1125, 1126, 1130, 1131, and 2305.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Costs Not Subject to Different Standards</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Costs that are the subject of cost accounting standards prescribed under this chapter are not subject to regulations established by another executive agency that differ from those standards with respect to the measurement, assignment, and allocation of those costs.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3699</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1505.</num>
<heading> Examinations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To determine whether a contractor or subcontractor has complied with cost accounting standards prescribed under this chapter and has followed consistently the contractor’s or subcontractor’s disclosed cost accounting practices, an authorized representative of the head of the agency concerned, of the offices of inspector general established under chapter 4 of title 5, or of the Comptroller General shall have the right to examine and copy documents, papers, or records of the contractor or subcontractor relating to compliance with the standards.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3700</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(b)(71)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4350</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1506.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Necessary amounts may be appropriated to carry out this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3700</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>