<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 87—</num>
<heading>KICKBACKS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 8701.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contracting agency</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “contracting agency”, when used with respect to a prime contractor, means a department, agency, or establishment of the Federal Government that enters into a prime contract with a prime contractor.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Kickback</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “kickback” means any money, fee, commission, credit, gift, gratuity, thing of value, or compensation of any kind that is provided to a prime contractor, prime contractor employee, subcontractor, or subcontractor employee to improperly obtain or reward favorable treatment in connection with a prime contract or a subcontract relating to a prime contract.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Person</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “person” means a corporation, partnership, business association of any kind, trust, joint-stock company, or individual.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prime contract</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “prime contract” means a contract or contractual action entered into by the Federal Government to obtain supplies, materials, equipment, or services of any kind.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prime contractor</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “prime contractor” means a person that has entered into a prime contract with the Federal Government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prime contractor employee</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “prime contractor employee” means an officer, partner, employee, or agent of a prime contractor.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Subcontract</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “subcontract” means a contract or contractual action entered into by a prime contractor or subcontractor to obtain supplies, materials, equipment, or services of any kind under a prime contract.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Subcontractor</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “subcontractor”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> means a person, other than the prime contractor, that offers to furnish or furnishes supplies, materials, equipment, or services of any kind under a prime contract or a subcontract entered into in connection with the prime contract; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> includes a person that offers to furnish or furnishes general supplies to the prime contractor or a higher tier subcontractor.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Subcontractor employee</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “subcontractor employee” means an officer, partner, employee, or agent of a subcontractor.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3838</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8702.</num>
<heading> Prohibited conduct</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A person may not—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provide, attempt to provide, or offer to provide a kickback;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> solicit, accept, or attempt to accept a kickback; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> include the amount of a kickback prohibited by paragraph (1) or (2) in the contract price—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a subcontractor charges a prime contractor or a higher tier subcontractor; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a prime contractor charges the Federal Government.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3839</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8703.</num>
<heading> Contractor responsibilities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirements Included in Contracts</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each contracting agency shall include in each prime contract awarded by the agency a requirement that the prime contractor shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> have in place and follow reasonable procedures designed to prevent and detect violations of <ref>section 8702 of this title</ref> in its own operations and direct business relationships; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> cooperate fully with a Federal Government agency investigating a violation of <ref>section 8702 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Full Cooperation Required</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding subsection (d), a prime contractor shall cooperate fully with a Federal Government agency investigating a violation of <ref>section 8702 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Reporting Requirement.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A prime contractor or subcontractor that has reasonable grounds to believe that a violation of <ref>section 8702 of this title</ref> may have occurred shall promptly report the possible violation in writing to the inspector general of the contracting agency, the head of the contracting agency if the agency does not have an inspector general, or the Attorney General.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Supplying information as favorable evidence</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In an administrative or contractual action to suspend or debar a person who is eligible to enter into contracts with the Federal Government, evidence that the person has supplied information to the Federal Government pursuant to paragraph (1) is favorable evidence of the person’s responsibility for the purposes of Federal procurement laws and regulations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inapplicability to Certain Prime Contracts</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subsection (a) does not apply to a prime contract—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> that is not greater than $100,000; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> for the acquisition of commercial products or commercial services (as defined in sections 103 and 103a, respectively, of this title).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3839</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 836(b)(20)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1864</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8704.</num>
<heading> Inspection authority</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>To ascertain whether there has been a violation of <ref>section 8702 of this title</ref> with respect to a prime contract, the Comptroller General and the inspector general of the contracting agency, or a representative of the contracting agency designated by the head of the agency if the agency does not have an inspector general, shall have access to and may inspect the facilities and audit the books and records, including electronic data or records, of a prime contractor or subcontractor under a prime contract awarded by the agency.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section does not apply to a prime contract for the acquisition of commercial products or commercial services (as defined in sections 103 and 103a, respectively, of this title).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3839</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 836(b)(20)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1864</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8705.</num>
<heading> Administrative offsets</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “contracting officer” has the meaning given that term in chapter 71 of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Offset Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A contracting officer of a contracting agency may offset the amount of a kickback provided, accepted, or charged in violation of <ref>section 8702 of this title</ref> against amounts the Federal Government owes the prime contractor under the prime contract to which the kickback relates.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Duties of Prime Contractor.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Withholding and paying over or retaining amounts</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>On direction of a contracting officer of a contracting agency with respect to a prime contract, the prime contractor shall withhold from amounts owed to a subcontractor under a subcontract of the prime contract the amount of a kickback which was or may be offset against the prime contractor under subsection (b). The contracting officer may order that amounts withheld—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> be paid over to the contracting agency; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> be retained by the prime contractor if the Federal Government has already offset the amount against the prime contractor.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The prime contractor shall notify the contracting officer when an amount is withheld and retained under paragraph (1)(B).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Offset, Direction, or Order is Claim of Federal Government</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An offset under subsection (b) or a direction or order of a contracting officer under subsection (c) is a claim by the Federal Government for the purposes of chapter 71 of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3840</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8706.</num>
<heading> Civil actions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Amount</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Federal Government in a civil action may recover from a person—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> that knowingly engages in conduct prohibited by <ref>section 8702 of this title</ref> a civil penalty equal to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> twice the amount of each kickback involved in the violation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> not more than $10,000 for each occurrence of prohibited conduct; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> whose employee, subcontractor, or subcontractor employee violates <ref>section 8702 of this title</ref> by providing, accepting, or charging a kickback a civil penalty equal to the amount of that kickback.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Statute of Limitations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A civil action under this section must be brought within 6 years after the later of the date on which—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the prohibited conduct establishing the cause of action occurred; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Federal Government first knew or should reasonably have known that the prohibited conduct had occurred.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3840</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8707.</num>
<heading> Criminal penalties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A person that knowingly and willfully engages in conduct prohibited by <ref>section 8702 of this title</ref> shall be fined under title 18, imprisoned for not more than 10 years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3841</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>