<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 17—</num>
<heading>AGENCY RESPONSIBILITIES AND PROCEDURES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1701.</num>
<heading> Cooperation with the Administrator</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">On the request of the Administrator, each executive agency shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> make its services, personnel, and facilities available to the Office of Federal Procurement Policy to the greatest practicable extent for the performance of functions under this division; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> except when prohibited by law, furnish to the Administrator, and give the Administrator access to, all information and records in its possession that the Administrator may determine to be necessary for the performance of the functions of the Office.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3700</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1702.</num>
<heading> Chief Acquisition Officers and senior procurement executives</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appointment or Designation of Chief Acquisition Officer</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The head of each executive agency described in section 901(b)(1) (other than the Department of Defense) or 901(b)(2)(C) of title 31 with a Chief Financial Officer appointed or designated under <ref>section 901(a) of title 31</ref> shall appoint or designate a non-career employee as Chief Acquisition Officer for the agency.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Authority and Functions of Chief Acquisition Officer.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Primary duty</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The primary duty of a Chief Acquisition Officer is acquisition management.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Advice and assistance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A Chief Acquisition Officer shall advise and assist the head of the executive agency and other agency officials to ensure that the mission of the executive agency is achieved through the management of the agency’s acquisition activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Other functions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The functions of each Chief Acquisition Officer include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> monitoring the performance of acquisition activities and acquisition programs of the executive agency, evaluating the performance of those programs on the basis of applicable performance measurements, and advising the head of the executive agency regarding the appropriate business strategy to achieve the mission of the executive agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> increasing the use of full and open competition in the acquisition of property and services by the executive agency by establishing policies, procedures, and practices that ensure that the executive agency receives a sufficient number of sealed bids or competitive proposals from responsible sources to fulfill the Federal Government’s requirements (including performance and delivery schedules) at the lowest cost or best value considering the nature of the property or service procured;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> increasing appropriate use of performance-based contracting and performance specifications;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> making acquisition decisions consistent with all applicable laws and establishing clear lines of authority, accountability, and responsibility for acquisition decisionmaking within the executive agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> managing the direction of acquisition policy for the executive agency, including implementation of the unique acquisition policies, regulations, and standards of the executive agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> advising the executive agency on the applicability of relevant policy on the contracts of the agency for overseas contingency operations and ensuring the compliance of the contracts and contracting activities of the agency with such policy;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> developing and maintaining an acquisition career management program in the executive agency to ensure that there is an adequate professional workforce; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<chapeau> as part of the strategic planning and performance evaluation process required under <ref>section 306 of title 5</ref> and sections 1105(a)(28), 1115, 1116, and 9703 (added by <ref>section 5(a) of Public Law 103–62</ref> (<ref>107 Stat. 289</ref>)) of title 31—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> assessing the requirements established for agency personnel regarding knowledge and skill in acquisition resources management and the adequacy of those requirements for facilitating the achievement of the performance goals established for acquisition management;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> developing strategies and specific plans for hiring, training, and professional development to rectify a deficiency in meeting those requirements; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> reporting to the head of the executive agency on the progress made in improving acquisition management capability.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Senior Procurement Executive.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The head of each executive agency shall designate a senior procurement executive.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Responsibility</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The senior procurement executive is responsible for management direction of the procurement system of the executive agency, including implementation of the unique procurement policies, regulations, and standards of the executive agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">When chief acquisition officer appointed or designated</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For an executive agency for which a Chief Acquisition Officer has been appointed or designated under subsection (a), the head of the executive agency shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> designate the Chief Acquisition Officer as the senior procurement executive for the executive agency; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> ensure that the senior procurement executive designated under paragraph (1) reports directly to the Chief Acquisition Officer without intervening authority.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Overseas Contingency Operations Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “overseas contingency operations” means military operations outside the United States and its territories and possessions that are a contingency operation (as that term is defined in <ref>section 101(a)(13) of title 10</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3701</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title VIII, § 849</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1853</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1703.</num>
<heading> Acquisition workforce</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Description</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of this section, the acquisition workforce of an agency consists of all employees serving in acquisition positions listed in subsection (g)(1)(A).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Applicability.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Nonapplicability to certain executive agencies</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in subsection (i), this section does not apply to an executive agency that is subject to chapter 87 of title 10.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Applicability of programs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The programs established by this section apply to the acquisition workforce of each executive agency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Management Policies.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Duties of head of executive agency.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establish policies and procedures</inline>.—</heading>
<content>After consultation with the Administrator, the head of each executive agency shall establish policies and procedures for the effective management (including accession, education, training, career development, and performance incentives) of the acquisition workforce of the agency. The development of acquisition workforce policies under this section shall be carried out consistent with the merit system principles set forth in <ref>section 2301(b) of title 5</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Ensure uniform implementation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The head of each executive agency shall ensure that, to the maximum extent practicable, acquisition workforce policies and procedures established are uniform in their implementation throughout the agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Duties of administrator.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall issue policies to promote uniform implementation of this section by executive agencies, with due regard for differences in program requirements among agencies that may be appropriate and warranted in view of the agency mission. The Administrator shall coordinate with the Deputy Director for Management of the Office of Management and Budget to ensure that the policies are consistent with the policies and procedures established, and enhanced system of incentives provided, pursuant to section 5051(c) of the Federal Acquisition Streamlining Act of 1994 (<ref>Public Law 103–355</ref>, <ref>108 Stat. 3351</ref>). The Administrator shall evaluate the implementation of this section by executive agencies.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Government-wide training standards and certification</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Administrator, acting through the Federal Acquisition Institute, shall provide and update government-wide training standards and certification requirements, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> developing and modifying acquisition certification programs;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> ensuring quality assurance for agency implementation of government-wide training and certification standards;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> analyzing the acquisition training curriculum to ascertain if all certification competencies are covered or if adjustments are necessary;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> developing career path information for certified professionals to encourage retention in government positions;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> coordinating with the Office of Personnel Management for human capital efforts; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> managing rotation assignments to support opportunities to apply skills included in certification.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority and Responsibility of Senior Procurement Executive</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to the authority, direction, and control of the head of an executive agency, the senior procurement executive of the agency shall carry out all powers, functions, and duties of the head of the agency with respect to implementing this section. The senior procurement executive shall ensure that the policies of the head of the executive agency established in accordance with this section are implemented throughout the agency.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Collecting and Maintaining Information</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall ensure that the heads of executive agencies collect and maintain standardized information on the acquisition workforce related to implementing this section. To the maximum extent practicable, information requirements shall conform to standards the Director of the Office of Personnel Management establishes for the Central Personnel Data File.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Career Development.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Career paths.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Identification</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The head of each executive agency shall ensure that appropriate career paths for personnel who desire to pursue careers in acquisition are identified in terms of the education, training, experience, and assignments necessary for career progression to the most senior acquisition positions. The head of each executive agency shall make available information on those career paths.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Critical duties and tasks</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For each career path, the head of each executive agency shall identify the critical acquisition-related duties and tasks in which, at minimum, employees of the agency in the career path shall be competent to perform at full performance grade levels. For this purpose, the head of the executive agency shall provide appropriate coverage of the critical duties and tasks identified by the Director of the Federal Acquisition Institute.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Mandatory training and education</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For each career path, the head of each executive agency shall establish requirements for the completion of course work and related on-the-job training in the critical acquisition-related duties and tasks of the career path. The head of each executive agency also shall encourage employees to maintain the currency of their acquisition knowledge and generally enhance their knowledge of related acquisition management disciplines through academic programs and other self-developmental activities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Performance incentives</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The head of each executive agency shall provide for an enhanced system of incentives to encourage excellence in the acquisition workforce that rewards performance of employees who contribute to achieving the agency’s performance goals. The system of incentives shall include provisions that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> relate pay to performance (including the extent to which the performance of personnel in the workforce contributes to achieving the cost goals, schedule goals, and performance goals established for acquisition programs pursuant to <ref>section 3103(b) of this title</ref>); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provide for consideration, in personnel evaluations and promotion decisions, of the extent to which the performance of personnel in the workforce contributes to achieving the cost goals, schedule goals, and performance goals.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Qualification Requirements.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subject to paragraph (2), the Administrator shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> establish qualification requirements, including education requirements, for—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> entry-level positions in the General Schedule Contracting series (GS–1102);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> senior positions in the General Schedule Contracting series (GS–1102);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> all positions in the General Schedule Purchasing series (GS–1105); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> positions in other General Schedule series in which significant acquisition-related functions are performed; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> prescribe the manner and extent to which the qualification requirements shall apply to an individual serving in a position described in subparagraph (A) at the time the requirements are established.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Relationship to requirements applicable to defense acquisition workforce</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall establish qualification requirements and make prescriptions under paragraph (1) that are comparable to those established for the same or equivalent positions pursuant to chapter 87 of title 10 with appropriate modifications.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Approval of requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall submit any requirement established or prescription made under paragraph (1) to the Director of the Office of Personnel Management for approval. The Director is deemed to have approved the requirement or prescription if the Director does not disapprove the requirement or prescription within 30 days after receiving it.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Education and Training.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Funding levels</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The head of an executive agency shall set forth separately the funding levels requested for educating and training the acquisition workforce in the budget justification documents submitted in support of the President’s budget submitted to Congress under <ref>section 1105 of title 31</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Tuition assistance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The head of an executive agency may provide tuition reimbursement in education (including a full-time course of study leading to a degree) in accordance with <ref>section 4107 of title 5</ref> for personnel serving in acquisition positions in the agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Restricted obligation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Amounts appropriated for education and training under this section may not be obligated for another purpose.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Training Fund.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Purposes</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The purposes of this subsection are to ensure that the Federal acquisition workforce—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> adapts to fundamental changes in the nature of Federal Government acquisition of property and services associated with the changing roles of the Federal Government; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> acquires new skills and a new perspective to enable it to contribute effectively in the changing environment of the 21st century.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment and management of fund</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is an acquisition workforce training fund. The Administrator of General Services shall manage the fund through the Federal Acquisition Institute to support the activities set forth in <ref>section 1201(a) of this title</ref>, except as provided in paragraph (5). The Administrator of General Services shall consult with the Administrator in managing the fund.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Credits to fund</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Five percent of the fees collected by executive agencies (other than the Department of Defense) under the following contracts shall be credited to the fund:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Government-wide task and delivery-order contracts entered into under sections 4103 and 4105 of this title.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Government-wide contracts for the acquisition of information technology as defined in <ref>section 11101 of title 40</ref> and multiagency acquisition contracts for that technology authorized by <ref>section 11314 of title 40</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> multiple-award schedule contracts entered into by the Administrator of General Services.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Remittance by head of executive agency</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The head of an executive agency that administers a contract described in paragraph (3) shall remit to the General Services Administration the amount required to be credited to the fund with respect to the contract at the end of each quarter of the fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transfer and use of fees collected from department of defense</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator of General Services shall transfer to the Secretary of Defense fees collected from the Department of Defense pursuant to paragraph (3). The Defense Acquisition University shall use the fees for acquisition workforce training.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Amounts not to be used for other purposes</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator of General Services, through the Office of Federal Procurememt <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002004">1</ref> Policy, shall ensure that amounts collected under this section are not used for a purpose other than the activities set forth in <ref>section 1201(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Amounts are in addition to other amounts for education and training</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Amounts credited to the fund are in addition to amounts requested and appropriated for education and training referred to in subsection (h)(1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Availability of amounts</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Amounts credited to the fund remain available to be expended only in the fiscal year for which they are credited and the 2 succeeding fiscal years.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Recruitment Program.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Shortage category positions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of sections 3304, 5333, and 5753 of title 5, the head of a department or agency of the Federal Government (other than the Secretary of Defense) may determine, under regulations prescribed by the Office of Personnel Management, that certain Federal acquisition positions (as described in subsection (g)(1)(A)) are shortage category positions in order to use the authorities in those sections to recruit and appoint highly qualified individuals directly to those positions in the department or agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Termination of authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The head of a department or agency may not appoint an individual to a position of employment under this subsection after <date date="2017-09-30">September 30, 2017</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(k)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Reemployment Without Loss of Annuity.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment of policies and procedures</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The head of each executive agency, after consultation with the Administrator and the Director of the Office of Personnel Management, shall establish policies and procedures under which the agency head may reemploy in an acquisition-related position (as described in subsection (g)(1)(A)) an individual receiving an annuity from the Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund, on the basis of the individual’s service, without discontinuing the annuity. The head of each executive agency shall keep the Administrator informed of the agency’s use of this authority.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Criteria for continuation of annuity</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Policies and procedures established under paragraph (1) shall authorize the head of the executive agency, on a case-by-case basis, to continue an annuity if any of the following makes the reemployment of an individual essential:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The unusually high or unique qualifications of an individual receiving an annuity from the Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund on the basis of the individual’s service.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The exceptional difficulty in recruiting or retaining a qualified employee.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> A temporary emergency hiring need.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Service not subject to csrs or fers</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An individual reemployed under this subsection shall not be deemed an employee for purposes of chapter 83 or 84 of title 5.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reporting requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall submit annually to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report on the use of the authority under this subsection, including the number of employees reemployed under authority of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Sunset provision</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The authority under this subsection expires on <date date="2011-12-31">December 31, 2011</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(l)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Acquisition Internship and Training Programs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>All Federal civilian agency acquisition internship or acquisition training programs shall follow guidelines provided by the Office of Federal Procurement Policy to ensure consistent training standards necessary to develop uniform core competencies throughout the Federal Government.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3702</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–74, div. C, title V, § 526</ref>, <date date="2011-12-23">Dec. 23, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 914</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title VIII, § 864(c)</ref>, (d), <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1525</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title X, § 1076(a)(15)</ref>, title XI, § 1103, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1948</ref>, 1973.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1704.</num>
<heading> Planning and policy-making for acquisition workforce</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Associate Administrator</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “Associate Administrator” means the Associate Administrator for Acquisition Workforce Programs as designated by the Administrator pursuant to subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Chief Acquisition Officer</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “Chief Acquisition Officer” means a Chief Acquisition Officer for an executive agency appointed pursuant to <ref>section 1702 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Associate Administrator for Acquisition Workforce Programs</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Administrator shall designate a member of the Senior Executive Service as the Associate Administrator for Acquisition Workforce Programs. The Associate Administrator shall be chosen on the basis of demonstrated knowledge and expertise in acquisition, human capital, and management. The Associate Administrator shall be located in the Office of Federal Procurement Policy. The Associate Administrator shall be responsible for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> supervising the acquisition workforce training fund established under <ref>section 1703(i) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> developing, in coordination with Chief Acquisition Officers and Chief Human Capital Officers, a strategic human capital plan for the acquisition workforce of the Federal Government;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> reviewing and providing input to individual agency acquisition workforce succession plans;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> recommending to the Administrator and other senior government officials appropriate programs, policies, and practices to increase the quantity and quality of the Federal acquisition workforce;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> implementing workforce programs under subsections (f) through (<i>l</i>) of <ref>section 1703 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> carrying out other functions that the Administrator may assign.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Acquisition and Contracting Training Programs Within Executive Agencies.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Chief Acquisition Officer authorities and responsibilities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to the authority, direction, and control of the head of an executive agency, the Chief Acquisition Officer for that agency shall carry out all powers, functions, and duties of the head of the agency with respect to implementation of this subsection. The Chief Acquisition Officer shall ensure that the policies established by the head of the agency in accordance with this subsection are implemented throughout the agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The head of each executive agency, after consultation with the Associate Administrator, shall establish and operate acquisition and contracting training programs. The programs shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> have curricula covering a broad range of acquisition and contracting disciplines corresponding to the specific acquisition and contracting needs of the agency involved;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> be developed and applied according to rigorous standards; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> be designed to maximize efficiency, through the use of self-paced courses, online courses, on-the-job training, and the use of remote instructors, wherever those features can be applied without reducing the effectiveness of the training or negatively affecting academic standards.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps"> Government-wide Policies and Evaluation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall issue policies to promote the development of performance standards for training and uniform implementation of this section by executive agencies, with due regard for differences in program requirements among agencies that may be appropriate and warranted in view of the agency mission. The Administrator shall evaluate the implementation of the provisions of subsection (c) by executive agencies.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Information on Acquisition and Contracting Training</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall ensure that the heads of executive agencies collect and maintain standardized information on the acquisition and contracting workforce related to the implementation of subsection (c).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Acquisition Workforce Human Capital Succession Plan.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each Chief Acquisition Officer for an executive agency shall develop, in consultation with the Chief Human Capital Officer for the agency and the Associate Administrator, a succession plan consistent with the agency’s strategic human capital plan for the recruitment, development, and retention of the agency’s acquisition workforce, with a particular focus on warranted contracting officers and program managers of the agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Content of plan</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The acquisition workforce succession plan shall address—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> recruitment goals for personnel from procurement intern programs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the agency’s acquisition workforce training needs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> actions to retain high performing acquisition professionals who possess critical relevant skills;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> recruitment goals for personnel from the Federal Career Intern Program; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> recruitment goals for personnel from the Presidential Management Fellows Program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Acquisition Workforce Development Strategic Plan.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Purpose</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The purpose of this subsection is to authorize the preparation and completion of the Acquisition Workforce Development Strategic Plan, which is a plan for Federal agencies other than the Department of Defense to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> develop a specific and actionable 5-year plan to increase the size of the acquisition workforce; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> operate a government-wide acquisition intern program for the Federal agencies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment of plan</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Associate Administrator shall be responsible for the management, oversight, and administration of the Acquisition Workforce Development Strategic Plan in cooperation and consultation with the Office of Federal Procurement Policy and with the assistance of the Federal Acquisition Institute.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Criteria</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Acquisition Workforce Development Strategic Plan shall include an examination of the following matters:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The variety and complexity of acquisitions conducted by each Federal agency covered by the plan, and the workforce needed to effectively carry out the acquisitions.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The development of a sustainable funding model to support efforts to hire, retain, and train an acquisition workforce of appropriate size and skill to effectively carry out the acquisition programs of the Federal agencies covered by the plan, including an examination of interagency funding methods and a discussion of how the model of the Defense Acquisition Workforce Development Fund could be applied to civilian agencies.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Any strategic human capital planning necessary to hire, retain, and train an acquisition workforce of appropriate size and skill at each Federal agency covered by the plan.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Methodologies that Federal agencies covered by the plan can use to project future acquisition workforce personnel hiring requirements, including an appropriate distribution of such personnel across each category of positions designated as acquisition workforce personnel under <ref>section 1703(g) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Government-wide training standards and certification requirements necessary to enhance the mobility and career opportunities of the Federal acquisition workforce within the Federal agencies covered by the plan.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> If the Associate Administrator recommends as part of the plan a growth in the acquisition workforce of the Federal agencies covered by the plan below 25 percent over the next 5 years, an examination of each of the matters specified in subparagraphs (A) to (E) in the context of a 5-year plan that increases the size of such acquisition workforce by not less than 25 percent, or an explanation why such a level of growth would not be in the best interest of the Federal Government.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Deadline for completion</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Acquisition Workforce Development Strategic Plan shall be completed not later than one year after <date date="2008-10-14">October 14, 2008</date>, and in a fashion that allows for immediate implementation of its recommendations and guidelines.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The acquisition workforce development strategic plan shall be funded from the acquisition workforce training fund under <ref>section 1703(i) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Training in the Acquisition of Architect and Engineering Services</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall ensure that a sufficient number of Federal employees are trained in the acquisition of architect and engineering services.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Utilization of Recruitment and Retention Authorities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator, in coordination with the Director of the Office of Personnel Management, shall encourage executive agencies to use existing authorities, including direct hire authority and tuition assistance programs, to recruit and retain acquisition personnel and consider recruiting acquisition personnel who may be retiring from the private sector, consistent with existing laws and regulations.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3706</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title X, § 1075(e)(15)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4375</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title VIII, § 864(a)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1522</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title X, § 1076(a)(14)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1948</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1705.</num>
<heading> Advocates for competition</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Establishment and Designation.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each executive agency has an advocate for competition.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The head of each executive agency shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> designate for the executive agency and for each procuring activity of the executive agency one officer or employee serving in a position authorized for the executive agency on <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date> (other than the senior procurement executive designated pursuant to <ref>section 1702(c) of this title</ref>) to serve as the advocate for competition;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> not assign those officers or employees duties or responsibilities that are inconsistent with the duties and responsibilities of the advocates for competition; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> provide those officers or employees with the staff or assistance necessary to carry out the duties and responsibilities of the advocate for competition, such as individuals who are specialists in engineering, technical operations, contract administration, financial management, supply management, and utilization of small and disadvantaged business concerns.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duties and Functions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The advocate for competition of an executive agency shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> be responsible for challenging barriers to, and promoting full and open competition in, the procurement of property and services by the executive agency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> review the procurement activities of the executive agency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> identify and report to the senior procurement executive of the executive agency—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> opportunities and actions taken to achieve full and open competition in the procurement activities of the executive agency; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any condition or action which has the effect of unnecessarily restricting competition in the procurement actions of the executive agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> prepare and transmit to the senior procurement executive an annual report describing—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the advocate’s activities under this section;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> new initiatives required to increase competition; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> remaining barriers to full and open competition;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> recommend to the senior procurement executive—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> goals and the plans for increasing competition on a fiscal year basis; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a system of personal and organizational accountability for competition, which may include the use of recognition and awards to motivate program managers, contracting officers, and others in authority to promote competition in procurement programs; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> describe other ways in which the executive agency has emphasized competition in programs for procurement training and research.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Responsibilities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The advocate for competition for each procuring activity is responsible for promoting full and open competition, promoting the acquisition of commercial products and commercial services, and challenging barriers to acquisition, including unnecessarily restrictive statements of need, unnecessarily detailed specifications, and unnecessarily burdensome contract clauses.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3709</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 836(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1861</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1706.</num>
<heading> Personnel evaluation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The head of each executive agency subject to division C shall ensure, with respect to the employees of that agency whose primary duties and responsibilities pertain to the award of contracts subject to the provisions of the Small Business and Federal Procurement Competition Enhancement Act of 1984 (<ref>Public Law 98–577</ref>, <ref>98 Stat. 3066</ref>), that the performance appraisal system applicable to those employees affords appropriate recognition to, among other factors, efforts to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> increase competition and achieve cost savings through the elimination of procedures that unnecessarily inhibit full and open competition;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> further the purposes of the Small Business and Federal Procurement Competition Enhancement Act of 1984 (<ref>Public Law 98–577</ref>, <ref>98 Stat. 3066</ref>) and the Defense Procurement Reform Act of 1984 (<ref>Public Law 98–525, title XII</ref>, <ref>98 Stat. 2588</ref>); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> further other objectives and purposes of the Federal acquisition system authorized by law.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3710</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1707.</num>
<heading> Publication of proposed regulations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Covered Policies, Regulations, Procedures, and Forms.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Required comment period</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Except as provided in subsection (d), a procurement policy, regulation, procedure, or form (including an amendment or modification thereto) may not take effect until 60 days after it is published for public comment in the Federal Register pursuant to subsection (b) if it—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> relates to the expenditure of appropriated funds; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> has a significant effect beyond the internal operating procedures of the agency issuing the policy, regulation, procedure, or form; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> has a significant cost or administrative impact on contractors or offerors.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A policy, regulation, procedure, or form may take effect earlier than 60 days after the publication date when there are compelling circumstances for the earlier effective date, but the effective date may not be less than 30 days after the publication date.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Publication in Federal Register and Comment Period</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to subsection (c), the head of the agency shall have published in the Federal Register a notice of the proposed procurement policy, regulation, procedure, or form and provide for a public comment period for receiving and considering the views of all interested parties on the proposal. The length of the comment period may not be less than 30 days.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contents of Notice</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Notice of a proposed procurement policy, regulation, procedure, or form prepared for publication in the Federal Register shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the text of the proposal or, if it is impracticable to publish the full text of the proposal, a summary of the proposal and a statement specifying the name, address, and telephone number of the officer or employee of the executive agency from whom the full text may be obtained; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a request for interested parties to submit comments on the proposal and the name and address of the officer or employee of the Federal Government designated to receive the comments.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Waiver</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The requirements of subsections (a) and (b) may be waived by the officer authorized to issue a procurement policy, regulation, procedure, or form if urgent and compelling circumstances make compliance with the requirements impracticable.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Effectiveness of Policy, Regulation, Procedure, or Form.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Temporary basis</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A procurement policy, regulation, procedure, or form for which the requirements of subsections (a) and (b) are waived under subsection (d) is effective on a temporary basis if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a notice of the policy, regulation, procedure, or form is published in the Federal Register and includes a statement that the policy, regulation, procedure, or form is temporary; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provision is made for a public comment period of 30 days beginning on the date on which the notice is published.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Final policy, regulation, procedure, or form</inline>.—</heading>
<content>After considering the comments received, the head of the agency waiving the requirements of subsections (a) and (b) under subsection (d) may issue the final procurement policy, regulation, procedure, or form.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3710</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1708.</num>
<heading> Procurement notice</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice Requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Except as provided in subsection (b)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an executive agency intending to solicit bids or proposals for a contract for property or services for a price expected to exceed $10,000, but not to exceed $25,000, shall post, for not less than 10 days, in a public place at the contracting office issuing the solicitation a notice of solicitation described in subsection (c);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> an executive agency shall publish a notice of solicitation described in subsection (c) if the agency intends to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> solicit bids or proposals for a contract for property or services for a price expected to exceed $25,000; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> place an order, expected to exceed $25,000, under a basic agreement, basic ordering agreement, or similar arrangement; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> an executive agency awarding a contract for property or services for a price exceeding $25,000, or placing an order exceeding $25,000 under a basic agreement, basic ordering agreement, or similar arrangement, shall furnish for publication a notice announcing the award or order if there is likely to be a subcontract under the contract or order.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Exemptions.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A notice is not required under subsection (a) if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> the proposed procurement is for an amount not greater than the simplified acquisition threshold and is to be conducted by—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> using widespread electronic public notice of the solicitation in a form that allows convenient and universal user access through a single, Government-wide point of entry; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> permitting the public to respond to the solicitation electronically;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the notice would disclose the executive agency’s needs and disclosure would compromise national security;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> the proposed procurement would result from acceptance of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an unsolicited proposal that demonstrates a unique and innovative research concept and publication of a notice of the unsolicited research proposal would disclose the originality of thought or innovativeness of the proposal or would disclose proprietary information associated with the proposal; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a proposal submitted under section 9 of the Small Business Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 638</ref>);</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the procurement is made against an order placed under a requirements contract, a task order contract, or a delivery order contract;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the procurement is made for perishable subsistence supplies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the procurement is for utility services, other than telecommunication services, and only one source is available; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> the procurement is for the services of an expert for use in any litigation or dispute (including any reasonably foreseeable litigation or dispute) involving the Federal Government in a trial, hearing, or proceeding before a court, administrative tribunal, or agency, or in any part of an alternative dispute resolution process, whether or not the expert is expected to testify.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Certain procurements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The requirements of subsection (a)(2) do not apply to a procurement—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> under conditions described in paragraph (2), (3), (4), (5), or (7) of <ref>section 3304(a) of this title</ref> or paragraph (2), (3), (4), (5), or (7) of <ref>section 3204(a) of title 10</ref>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for which the head of the executive agency makes a determination in writing, after consultation with the Administrator and the Administrator of the Small Business Administration, that it is not appropriate or reasonable to publish a notice before issuing a solicitation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Implementation consistent with international agreements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Paragraph (1)(A) shall be implemented in a manner consistent with applicable international agreements.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contents of Notice</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each notice of solicitation required by paragraph (1) or (2) of subsection (a) shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> an accurate description of the property or services to be contracted for, which description—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall not be unnecessarily restrictive of competition; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> shall include, as appropriate, the agency nomenclature, National Stock Number or other part number, and a brief description of the item’s form, fit, or function, physical dimensions, predominant material of manufacture, or similar information that will assist a prospective contractor to make an informed business judgment as to whether a copy of the solicitation should be requested;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> provisions that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> state whether the technical data required to respond to the solicitation will not be furnished as part of the solicitation; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> identify the source in the Federal Government, if any, from which the technical data may be obtained; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> state whether an offeror or its product or service must meet a qualification requirement in order to be eligible for award; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> if so, identify the office from which the qualification requirement may be obtained;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the name, business address, and telephone number of the contracting officer;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> a statement that all responsible sources may submit a bid, proposal, or quotation (as appropriate) that the agency shall consider;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> in the case of a procurement using procedures other than competitive procedures, a statement of the reason justifying the use of those procedures and the identity of the intended source; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> in the case of a contract in an amount estimated to be greater than $25,000 but not greater than the simplified acquisition threshold, or a contract for the procurement of commercial products or commercial services using special simplified procedures—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a description of the procedures to be used in awarding the contract; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a statement specifying the periods for prospective offerors and the contracting officer to take the necessary preaward and award actions.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Electronic Publication of Notice of Solicitation, Award, or Order</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A notice of solicitation, award, or order required to be published under subsection (a) shall be published by electronic means. The notice must be electronically accessible in a form that allows convenient and universal user access through the single Government-wide point of entry designated in the Federal Acquisition Regulation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Time Limitations.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Issuing notice of solicitation and establishing deadline for submitting bids and proposals</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An executive agency required by subsection (a)(2) to publish a notice of solicitation may not—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> issue the solicitation earlier than 15 days after the date on which the notice is published; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> in the case of a contract or order expected to be greater than the simplified acquisition threshold, establish a deadline for the submission of all bids or proposals in response to the notice required by subsection (a)(2) that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> in the case of a solicitation for research and development, is earlier than 45 days after the date the notice required for a bid or proposal for a contract described in subsection (a)(2)(A) is published;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in the case of an order under a basic agreement, basic ordering agreement, or similar arrangement, is earlier than 30 days after the date the notice required for an order described in subsection (a)(2)(B) is published; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> in any other case, is earlier than 30 days after the date the solicitation is issued.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishing deadline when none provided by statute</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An executive agency shall establish a deadline for the submission of all bids or proposals in response to a solicitation for which a deadline is not provided by statute. Each deadline for the submission of offers shall afford potential offerors a reasonable opportunity to respond.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Flexible deadlines</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall prescribe regulations defining limited circumstances in which flexible deadlines can be used under paragraph (1) for the issuance of solicitations and the submission of bids or proposals for the procurement of commercial products or commercial services.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consideration of Certain Timely Received Offers</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An executive agency intending to solicit offers for a contract for which a notice of solicitation is required to be posted under subsection (a)(1) shall ensure that contracting officers consider each responsive offer timely received from an offeror.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Availability of Complete Solicitation Package and Payment of Fee</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An executive agency shall make available to a business concern, or the authorized representative of a concern, the complete solicitation package for any on-going procurement announced pursuant to a notice of solicitation under subsection (a). An executive agency may require the payment of a fee, not exceeding the actual cost of duplication, for a copy of the package.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3711</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 836(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1861</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1702(h)(4)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2158</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1709.</num>
<heading> Contracting functions performed by Federal personnel</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered Personnel</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Personnel referred to in subsection (b) are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an employee, as defined in <ref>section 2105 of title 5</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a member of the armed forces; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> an individual assigned to a Federal agency pursuant to subchapter VI of chapter 33 of title 5.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Payment for Advisory and Assistance Services</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>No individual who is not an individual described in subsection (a) may be paid by an executive agency for services to conduct evaluations or analyses of any aspect of a proposal submitted for an acquisition unless personnel described in subsection (a) with adequate training and capabilities to perform the evaluations and analyses are not readily available in the agency or another Federal agency. When administering this subsection, the head of each executive agency shall determine in accordance with standards and procedures prescribed in the Federal Acquisition Regulation whether—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a sufficient number of personnel described in subsection (a) in the agency or another Federal agency are readily available to perform a particular evaluation or analysis for the head of the executive agency making the determination; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the readily available personnel have the training and capabilities necessary to perform the evaluation or analysis.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Certain Relationship Not Affected</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section does not affect the relationship between the Federal Government and a Federally funded research and development center.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3714</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1710.</num>
<heading> Public-private competition required before conversion to contractor performance</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Public-private competition.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">When conversion to contractor performance is allowed</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A function of an executive agency performed by 10 or more agency civilian employees may not be converted, in whole or in part, to performance by a contractor unless the conversion is based on the results of a public-private competition that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> formally compares the cost of performance of the function by agency civilian employees with the cost of performance by a contractor;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> creates an agency tender, including a most efficient organization plan, in accordance with Office of Management and Budget Circular A76, as implemented on <date date="2003-05-29">May 29, 2003</date>, or any successor circular;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> includes the issuance of a solicitation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> determines whether the submitted offers meet the needs of the executive agency with respect to factors other than cost, including quality, reliability, and timeliness;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<chapeau> examines the cost of performance of the function by agency civilian employees and the cost of performance of the function by one or more contractors to demonstrate whether converting to performance by a contractor will result in savings to the Federal Government over the life of the contract, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the estimated cost to the Federal Government (based on offers received) for performance of the function by a contractor;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the estimated cost to the Federal Government for performance of the function by agency civilian employees; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> an estimate of all other costs and expenditures that the Federal Government would incur because of the award of the contract;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<chapeau> requires continued performance of the function by agency civilian employees unless the difference in the cost of performance of the function by a contractor compared to the cost of performance of the function by agency civilian employees would, over all performance periods required by the solicitation, be equal to or exceed the lesser of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> 10 percent of the personnel-related costs for performance of that function in the agency tender; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> $10,000,000; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> examines the effect of performance of the function by a contractor on the agency mission associated with the performance of the function.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Not a new requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A function that is performed by the executive agency and is reengineered, reorganized, modernized, upgraded, expanded, or changed to become more efficient, but still essentially provides the same service, shall not be considered a new requirement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In no case may a function being performed by executive agency personnel be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> modified, reorganized, divided, or in any way changed for the purpose of exempting the conversion of the function from the requirements of this section; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> converted to performance by a contractor to circumvent a civilian personnel ceiling.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Consulting With Affected Employees or Their Representatives.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consulting with affected employees</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each civilian employee of an executive agency responsible for determining under Office of Management and Budget Circular A76 whether to convert to contractor performance any function of the executive agency—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall, at least monthly during the development and preparation of the performance work statement and the management efficiency study used in making that determination, consult with civilian employees who will be affected by that determination and consider the views of the employees on the development and preparation of that statement and that study; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> may consult with the employees on other matters relating to that determination.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Consulting with representatives.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Employees represented by a labor organization</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In the case of employees represented by a labor organization accorded exclusive recognition under <ref>section 7111 of title 5</ref>, consultation with representatives of that labor organization shall satisfy the consultation requirement in paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Employees not represented by a labor organization</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In the case of employees other than employees referred to in subparagraph (A), consultation with appropriate representatives of those employees shall satisfy the consultation requirement in paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The head of each executive agency shall prescribe regulations to carry out this subsection. The regulations shall include provisions for the selection or designation of appropriate representatives of employees referred to in paragraph (2)(B) for purposes of consultation required by paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Congressional Notification.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Before commencing a public-private competition under subsection (a), the head of an executive agency shall submit to Congress a report containing the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The function for which the public-private competition is to be conducted.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The location at which the function is performed by agency civilian employees.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The number of agency civilian employee positions potentially affected.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The anticipated length and cost of the public-private competition, and a specific identification of the budgetary line item from which funds will be used to cover the cost of the public-private competition.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> A certification that a proposed performance of the function by a contractor is not a result of a decision by an official of an executive agency to impose predetermined constraints or limitations on agency civilian employees in terms of man years, end strengths, full-time equivalent positions, or maximum number of employees.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Examination of potential economic effect</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The report required under paragraph (1) shall include an examination of the potential economic effect of performance of the function by a contractor on—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> agency civilian employees who would be affected by such a conversion in performance; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the local community and the Federal Government, if more than 50 agency civilian employees perform the function.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Objections to public-private competition.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Grounds</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A representative individual or entity at a facility where a public-private competition is conducted may submit to the head of the executive agency an objection to the public-private competition on the grounds that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the report required by paragraph (1) has not been submitted; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the certification required by paragraph (1)(E) was not included in the report required by paragraph (1).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Deadlines</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The objection shall be in writing and shall be submitted within 90 days after the following date:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> In the case of a failure to submit the report when required, the date on which the representative individual or an official of the representative entity authorized to pose the objection first knew or should have known of that failure.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> In the case of a failure to include the certification in a submitted report, the date on which the report was submitted to Congress.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report and certification required before solicitation or award of contract</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the head of the executive agency determines that the report required by paragraph (1) was not submitted or that the required certification was not included in the submitted report, the function for which the public-private competition was conducted for which the objection was submitted may not be the subject of a solicitation of offers for, or award of, a contract until, respectively, the report is submitted or a report containing the certification in full compliance with the certification requirement is submitted.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exemption for the Purchase of Products and Services of the Blind and Other Severely Disabled People</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>This section shall not apply to a commercial or industrial type function of an executive agency that is—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> included on the procurement list established pursuant to <ref>section 8503 of this title</ref>; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> planned to be changed to performance by a qualified nonprofit agency for the blind or by a qualified nonprofit agency for other severely disabled people in accordance with chapter 85 of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inapplicability During War or Emergency</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The provisions of this section shall not apply during war or during a period of national emergency declared by the President or Congress.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3715</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1711.</num>
<heading> Value engineering</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each executive agency shall establish and maintain cost-effective procedures and processes for analyzing the functions of a program, project, system, product, item of equipment, building, facility, service, or supply of the agency. The analysis shall be—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> performed by qualified agency or contractor personnel; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> directed at improving performance, reliability, quality, safety, and life cycle costs.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3718</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1712.</num>
<heading> Record requirements</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Maintaining Records on Computer</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each executive agency shall establish and maintain for 5 years a computer file, by fiscal year, containing unclassified records of all procurements greater than the simplified acquisition threshold in that fiscal year.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contents</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The record established under subsection (a) shall include, with respect to each procurement carried out using—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> competitive procedures—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the date of contract award;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> information identifying the source to whom the contract was awarded;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the property or services the Federal Government obtains under the procurement; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the total cost of the procurement; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> procedures other than competitive procedures—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the information described in paragraph (1);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the reason under <ref>section 3304(a) of this title</ref> or <ref>section 3204(a) of title 10</ref> for using the procedures; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the identity of the organization or activity that conducted the procurement.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Separate Record Category for Procurements Resulting in One Bid or Proposal</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Information included in a record pursuant to subsection (b)(1) that relates to procurements resulting in the submission of a bid or proposal by only one responsible source shall be separately categorized from the information relating to other procurements included in the record. The record of that information shall be designated “noncompetitive procurements using competitive procedures”.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transmission and Data Entry of Information</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The head of each executive agency shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> ensure the accuracy of the information included in the record established and maintained by the agency under subsection (a); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> transmit in a timely manner such information to the General Services Administration for entry into the Federal Procurement Data System referred to in <ref>section 1122(a)(4) of this title</ref>, or any successor system.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3718</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1702(h)(5)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2158</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1713.</num>
<heading> Procurement data</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Qualified hubzone small business concern</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “qualified HUBZone small business concern” has the meaning given that term in section 31(b) of the Small Business Act.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Small business concern owned and controlled by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “small business concern owned and controlled by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals” has the meaning given that term in section 8(d) of the Small Business Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 637(d)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Small business concern owned and controlled by women</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “small business concern owned and controlled by women” has the meaning given that term in section 8(d) of the Small Business Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 637(d)</ref>) and section 204 of the Women’s Business Ownership Act of 1988 (<ref>Public Law 100–533</ref>, <ref>102 Stat. 2692</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reporting</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each Federal agency shall report to the Office of Federal Procurement Policy the number of qualified HUBZone small business concerns, the number of small businesses owned and controlled by women, and the number of small business concerns owned and controlled by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals, by gender, that are first time recipients of contracts from the agency. The Office shall take appropriate action to ascertain, for each fiscal year, the number of those small businesses that have newly entered the Federal market.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3719</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(a)(4)(F)(ii)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1796</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>