<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 13—</num>
<heading>ACQUISITION COUNCILS</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>FEDERAL ACQUISITION REGULATORY COUNCIL</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1301.</num>
<heading> Definition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this subchapter, the term “Council” means the Federal Acquisition Regulatory Council established under <ref>section 1302(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3691</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1302.</num>
<heading> Establishment and membership</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is a Federal Acquisition Regulatory Council to assist in the direction and coordination of Government-wide procurement policy and Government-wide procurement regulatory activities in the Federal Government.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Membership.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Makeup of council</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Council consists of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Administrator;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Defense;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Administrator of National Aeronautics and Space; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Administrator of General Services.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Designation of other officials.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Officials who may be designated</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Notwithstanding section 121(d)(1) and (2) of title 40, the officials specified in subparagraphs (B) to (D) of paragraph (1) may designate to serve on and attend meetings of the Council in place of that official—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the official assigned by statute with the responsibility for acquisition policy in each of their respective agencies or, in the case of the Secretary of Defense, an official at an organizational level not lower than an Assistant Secretary of Defense within the Office of the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> if no official of that agency is assigned by statute with the responsibility for acquisition policy for that agency, the official designated pursuant to <ref>section 1702(c) of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on designation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No other official or employee may be designated to serve on the Council.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3691</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title IX, § 902(88)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1554</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1303.</num>
<heading> Functions and authority</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Functions.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Issue and maintain federal acquisition regulation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to sections 1121, 1122(a) to (c)(1), 1125, 1126, 1130, 1131, and 2305 of this title, the Administrator of General Services, the Secretary of Defense, and the Administrator of National Aeronautics and Space, pursuant to their respective authorities under division C of this subtitle, chapter 4 of title 10, chapter 137 legacy provisions (as such term is defined in <ref>section 3016 of title 10</ref>), and the National Aeronautics and Space Act of 1958 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 2451</ref> et seq.),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002002">1</ref> shall jointly issue and maintain in accordance with subsection (d) a single Government-wide procurement regulation, to be known as the Federal Acquisition Regulation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on other regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Other regulations relating to procurement issued by an executive agency shall be limited to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> regulations essential to implement Government-wide policies and procedures within the agency; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> additional policies and procedures required to satisfy the specific and unique needs of the agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Ensure consistent regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator, in consultation with the Council, shall ensure that procurement regulations prescribed by executive agencies are consistent with the Federal Acquisition Regulation and in accordance with the policies prescribed pursuant to <ref>section 1121(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Request to review regulation.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Basis for request</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Under procedures the Administrator establishes, a person may request the Administrator to review a regulation relating to procurement on the basis that the regulation is inconsistent with the Federal Acquisition Regulation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Period of review</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Unless the request is frivolous or does not, on its face, state a valid basis for the review, the Administrator shall complete the review not later than 60 days after receiving the request. The time for completion of the review may be extended if the Administrator determines that an additional period of review is required. The Administrator shall advise the requester of the reasons for the extension and the date by which the review will be completed.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">When regulation is inconsistent or needs to be improved</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the Administrator determines that a regulation relating to procurement is inconsistent with the Federal Acquisition Regulation or that the regulation otherwise should be revised to remove an inconsistency with the policies prescribed under <ref>section 1121(b) of this title</ref>, the Administrator shall rescind or deny the promulgation of the regulation or take other action authorized under sections 1121, 1122(a) to (c)(1), 1125, 1126, 1130, 1131, and 2305 of this title as may be necessary to remove the inconsistency. If the Administrator determines that the regulation, although not inconsistent with the Federal Acquisition Regulation or those policies, should be revised to improve compliance with the Regulation or policies, the Administrator shall take action authorized under sections 1121, 1122(a) to (c)(1), 1125, 1126, 1130, 1131, and 2305 as may be necessary and appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Decisions to be in writing and publicly available</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The decisions of the Administrator shall be in writing and made publicly available.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Additional Responsibilities of Membership.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subject to the authority, direction, and control of the head of the agency concerned, each official who represents an agency on the Council pursuant to <ref>section 1302(b) of this title</ref> shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> approve or disapprove all regulations relating to procurement that are proposed for public comment, prescribed in final form, or otherwise made effective by that agency before the regulation may be prescribed in final form, or otherwise made effective, except that the official may grant an interim approval, without review, for not more than 60 days for a procurement regulation in urgent and compelling circumstances;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> carry out the responsibilities of that agency set forth in chapter 35 of title 44 for each information collection request that relates to procurement rules or regulations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> eliminate or reduce—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any redundant or unnecessary levels of review and approval in the procurement system of that agency; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> redundant or unnecessary procurement regulations which are unique to that agency.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on delegation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The authority to review and approve or disapprove regulations under paragraph (1)(A) may not be delegated to an individual outside the office of the official who represents the agency on the Council pursuant to <ref>section 1302(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Governing Policies</inline>.—</heading>
<content>All actions of the Council and of members of the Council shall be in accordance with and furtherance of the policies prescribed under <ref>section 1121(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General Authority With Respect to Federal Acquisition Regulation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to <ref>section 1121(d) of this title</ref>, the Council shall manage, coordinate, control, and monitor the maintenance of, issuance of, and changes in, the Federal Acquisition Regulation.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3691</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1702(h)(2)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2158</ref></sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1304.</num>
<heading> Contract clauses and certifications</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Repetitive Nonstandard Contract Clauses Discouraged</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Council shall prescribe regulations to discourage the use of a nonstandard contract clause on a repetitive basis. The regulations shall include provisions that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> clearly define what types of contract clauses are to be treated as nonstandard clauses; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> require prior approval for the use of a nonstandard clause on a repetitive basis by an official at a level of responsibility above the contracting officer.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">When Certification Required.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">By law</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A provision of law may not be construed as requiring a certification by a contractor or offeror in a procurement made or to be made by the Federal Government unless that provision of law specifically provides that such a certification shall be required.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In federal acquisition regulation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A requirement for a certification by a contractor or offeror may not be included in the Federal Acquisition Regulation unless—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the certification requirement is specifically imposed by statute; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> written justification for the certification requirement is provided to the Administrator by the Council and the Administrator approves in writing the inclusion of the certification requirement.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Executive agency procurement regulation.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In subparagraph (B), the term “head of the executive agency” with respect to a military department means the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">When certification requirement may be included in regulation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A requirement for a certification by a contractor or offeror may not be included in a procurement regulation of an executive agency unless—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the certification requirement is specifically imposed by statute; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> written justification for the certification requirement is provided to the head of the executive agency by the senior procurement executive of the agency and the head of the executive agency approves in writing the inclusion of the certification requirement.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3693</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>CHIEF ACQUISITION OFFICERS COUNCIL</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1311.</num>
<heading> Establishment and membership</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is in the executive branch a Chief Acquisition Officers Council.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps"> Membership</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The members of the Council are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Deputy Director for Management of the Office of Management and Budget;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Administrator;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the chief acquisition officer of each executive agency that is required to have a chief acquisition officer under <ref>section 1702 of this title</ref> and the senior procurement executive of each military department; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> any other senior agency officer of each executive agency, appointed by the head of the agency in consultation with the Chairman of the Council, who can effectively assist the Council in performing the functions set forth in <ref>section 1312(b) of this title</ref> and supporting the associated range of acquisition activities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Leadership and Support.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Chairman</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Deputy Director for Management of the Office of Management and Budget is the Chairman of the Council.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Vice chairman</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Vice Chairman of the Council shall be selected by the Council from among its members. The Vice Chairman serves for one year and may serve multiple terms.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Leader of activities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall lead the activities of the Council on behalf of the Deputy Director for Management.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Support</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator of General Services shall provide administrative and other support for the Council.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3694</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title IX, § 902(89)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1554</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1312.</num>
<heading> Functions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Principal Forum</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Chief Acquisition Officers Council is the principal interagency forum for monitoring and improving the Federal acquisition system.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Functions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Council shall perform functions that include the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Develop recommendations for the Director of the Office of Management and Budget on Federal acquisition policies and requirements.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Share experiences, ideas, best practices, and innovative approaches related to Federal acquisition.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Assist the Administrator in the identification, development, and coordination of multiagency projects and other innovative initiatives to improve Federal acquisition.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Promote effective business practices that ensure the timely delivery of best value products to the Federal Government and achieve appropriate public policy objectives.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Further integrity, fairness, competition, openness, and efficiency in the Federal acquisition system.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Work with the Office of Personnel Management to assess and address the hiring, training, and professional development needs of the Federal Government related to acquisition.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Work with the Administrator and the Federal Acquisition Regulatory Council to promote the business practices referred to in paragraph (4) and other results of the functions carried out under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3694</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>FEDERAL ACQUISITION SUPPLY CHAIN SECURITY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1321.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this subchapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appropriate congressional committees and leadership</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “appropriate congressional committees and leadership” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs, the Committee on the Judiciary, the Committee on Appropriations, the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation, the Select Committee on Intelligence, and the majority and minority leader of the Senate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, the Committee on the Judiciary, the Committee on Appropriations, the Committee on Homeland Security, the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Energy and Commerce, the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence, and the Speaker and minority leader of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Council</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “Council” means the Federal Acquisition Security Council established under <ref>section 1322(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered article</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “covered article” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 4713 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered procurement action</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “covered procurement action” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 4713 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Information and communications technology</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “information and communications technology” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 4713 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Intelligence community</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “intelligence community” has the meaning given that term in section 3(4) of the National Security Act of 1947 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3003(4)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">National security system</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “national security system” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 3552 of title 44</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Supply chain risk</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “supply chain risk” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 4713 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–390, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5178</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1322.</num>
<heading> Federal Acquisition Security Council establishment and membership</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is established in the executive branch a Federal Acquisition Security Council.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Membership.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The following agencies shall be represented on the Council:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Office of Management and Budget.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The General Services Administration.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The Department of Homeland Security, including the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The Office of the Director of National Intelligence, including the National Counterintelligence and Security Center.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The Department of Justice, including the Federal Bureau of Investigation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> The Department of Defense, including the National Security Agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> The Department of Commerce, including the National Institute of Standards and Technology.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> Such other executive agencies as determined by the Chairperson of the Council.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Lead representatives.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Designation.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 45 days after the date of the enactment of the Federal Acquisition Supply Chain Security Act of 2018, the head of each agency represented on the Council shall designate a representative of that agency as the lead representative of the agency on the Council.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The representative of an agency designated under clause (i) shall have expertise in supply chain risk management, acquisitions, or information and communications technology.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Functions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The lead representative of an agency designated under subparagraph (A) shall ensure that appropriate personnel, including leadership and subject matter experts of the agency, are aware of the business of the Council.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Chairperson.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 45 days after the date of the enactment of the Federal Acquisition Supply Chain Security Act of 2018, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall designate a senior-level official from the Office of Management and Budget to serve as the Chairperson of the Council.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Functions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Chairperson shall perform functions that include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> subject to subsection (d), developing a schedule for meetings of the Council;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> designating executive agencies to be represented on the Council under subsection (b)(1)(H);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> in consultation with the lead representative of each agency represented on the Council, developing a charter for the Council; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> not later than 7 days after completion of the charter, submitting the charter to the appropriate congressional committees and leadership.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Meetings</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Council shall meet not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of the Federal Acquisition Supply Chain Security Act of 2018 and not less frequently than quarterly thereafter.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–390, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5178</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1323.</num>
<heading> Functions and authorities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Council shall perform functions that include the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Identifying and recommending development by the National Institute of Standards and Technology of supply chain risk management standards, guidelines, and practices for executive agencies to use when assessing and developing mitigation strategies to address supply chain risks, particularly in the acquisition and use of covered articles under <ref>section 1326(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Identifying or developing criteria for sharing information with executive agencies, other Federal entities, and non-Federal entities with respect to supply chain risk, including information related to the exercise of authorities provided under this section and sections 1326 and 4713 of this title. At a minimum, such criteria shall address—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the content to be shared;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the circumstances under which sharing is mandated or voluntary; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the circumstances under which it is appropriate for an executive agency to rely on information made available through such sharing in exercising the responsibilities and authorities provided under this section and <ref>section 4713 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> Identifying an appropriate executive agency to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> accept information submitted by executive agencies based on the criteria established under paragraph (2);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> facilitate the sharing of information received under subparagraph (A) to support supply chain risk analyses under <ref>section 1326 of this title</ref>, recommendations under this section, and covered procurement actions under <ref>section 4713 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> share with the Council information regarding covered procurement actions by executive agencies taken under <ref>section 4713 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> inform the Council of orders issued under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> Identifying, as appropriate, executive agencies to provide—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shared services, such as support for making risk assessments, validation of products that may be suitable for acquisition, and mitigation activities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> common contract solutions to support supply chain risk management activities, such as subscription services or machine-learning-enhanced analysis applications to support informed decision making.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Identifying and issuing guidance on additional steps that may be necessary to address supply chain risks arising in the course of executive agencies providing shared services, common contract solutions, acquisitions vehicles, or assisted acquisitions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Engaging with the private sector and other nongovernmental stakeholders in performing the functions described in paragraphs (1) and (2) and on issues relating to the management of supply chain risks posed by the acquisition of covered articles.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Carrying out such other actions, as determined by the Council, that are necessary to reduce the supply chain risks posed by acquisitions and use of covered articles.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Program Office and Committees</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Council may establish a program office and any committees, working groups, or other constituent bodies the Council deems appropriate, in its sole and unreviewable discretion, to carry out its functions.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Authority for Exclusion or Removal Orders.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Criteria</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>To reduce supply chain risk, the Council shall establish criteria and procedures for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> recommending orders applicable to executive agencies requiring the exclusion of sources or covered articles from executive agency procurement actions (in this section referred to as “exclusion orders”);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> recommending orders applicable to executive agencies requiring the removal of covered articles from executive agency information systems (in this section referred to as “removal orders”);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> requesting and approving exceptions to an issued exclusion or removal order when warranted by circumstances, including alternative mitigation actions or other findings relating to the national interest, including national security reviews, national security investigations, or national security agreements; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> ensuring that recommended orders do not conflict with standards and guidelines issued under <ref>section 11331 of title 40</ref> and that the Council consults with the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology regarding any recommended orders that would implement standards and guidelines developed by the National Institute of Standards and Technology.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Recommendations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Council shall use the criteria established under paragraph (1), information made available under subsection (a)(3), and any other information the Council determines appropriate to issue recommendations, for application to executive agencies or any subset thereof, regarding the exclusion of sources or covered articles from any executive agency procurement action, including source selection and consent for a contractor to subcontract, or the removal of covered articles from executive agency information systems. Such recommendations shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> information necessary to positively identify the sources or covered articles recommended for exclusion or removal;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> information regarding the scope and applicability of the recommended exclusion or removal order;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a summary of any risk assessment reviewed or conducted in support of the recommended exclusion or removal order;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a summary of the basis for the recommendation, including a discussion of less intrusive measures that were considered and why such measures were not reasonably available to reduce supply chain risk;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> a description of the actions necessary to implement the recommended exclusion or removal order; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> where practicable, in the Council’s sole and unreviewable discretion, a description of mitigation steps that could be taken by the source that may result in the Council rescinding a recommendation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice of recommendation and review</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A notice of the Council’s recommendation under paragraph (2) shall be issued to any source named in the recommendation advising—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> that a recommendation has been made;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> of the criteria the Council relied upon under paragraph (1) and, to the extent consistent with national security and law enforcement interests, of information that forms the basis for the recommendation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> that, within 30 days after receipt of notice, the source may submit information and argument in opposition to the recommendation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> of the procedures governing the review and possible issuance of an exclusion or removal order pursuant to paragraph (5); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> where practicable, in the Council’s sole and unreviewable discretion, a description of mitigation steps that could be taken by the source that may result in the Council rescinding the recommendation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Confidentiality</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Any notice issued to a source under paragraph (3) shall be kept confidential until—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an exclusion or removal order is issued pursuant to paragraph (5); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the source has been notified pursuant to paragraph (6).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Exclusion and removal orders.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Order issuance</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Recommendations of the Council under paragraph (2), together with any information submitted by a source under paragraph (3) related to such a recommendation, shall be reviewed by the following officials, who may issue exclusion and removal orders based upon such recommendations:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Homeland Security, for exclusion and removal orders applicable to civilian agencies, to the extent not covered by clause (ii) or (iii).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense, for exclusion and removal orders applicable to the Department of Defense and national security systems other than sensitive compartmented information systems.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> The Director of National Intelligence, for exclusion and removal orders applicable to the intelligence community and sensitive compartmented information systems, to the extent not covered by clause (ii).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Delegation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The officials identified in subparagraph (A) may not delegate any authority under this subparagraph to an official below the level one level below the Deputy Secretary or Principal Deputy Director, except that the Secretary of Defense may delegate authority for removal orders to the Commander of the United States Cyber Command, who may not redelegate such authority to an official below the level one level below the Deputy Commander.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Facilitation of exclusion orders</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If officials identified under this paragraph from the Department of Homeland Security, the Department of Defense, and the Office of the Director of National Intelligence issue orders collectively resulting in a governmentwide exclusion, the Administrator for General Services and officials at other executive agencies responsible for management of the Federal Supply Schedules, governmentwide acquisition contracts and multi-agency contracts shall help facilitate implementation of such orders by removing the covered articles or sources identified in the orders from such contracts.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Review of exclusion and removal orders</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The officials identified under this paragraph shall review all exclusion and removal orders issued under subparagraph (A) not less frequently than annually pursuant to procedures established by the Council.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rescission</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Orders issued pursuant to subparagraph (A) may be rescinded by an authorized official from the relevant issuing agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notifications</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Upon issuance of an exclusion or removal order pursuant to paragraph (5)(A), the official identified under that paragraph who issued the order shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> notify any source named in the order of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the exclusion or removal order; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> to the extent consistent with national security and law enforcement interests, information that forms the basis for the order;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provide classified or unclassified notice of the exclusion or removal order to the appropriate congressional committees and leadership; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> provide the exclusion or removal order to the agency identified in subsection (a)(3).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Compliance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Executive agencies shall comply with exclusion and removal orders issued pursuant to paragraph (5).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority To Request Information</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Council may request such information from executive agencies as is necessary for the Council to carry out its functions.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Relationship to Other Councils</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Council shall consult and coordinate, as appropriate, with other relevant councils and interagency committees, including the Chief Information Officers Council, the Chief Acquisition Officers Council, the Federal Acquisition Regulatory Council, and the Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States, with respect to supply chain risks posed by the acquisition and use of covered articles.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rules of Construction</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Nothing in this section shall be construed—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to limit the authority of the Office of Federal Procurement Policy to carry out the responsibilities of that Office under any other provision of law; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to authorize the issuance of an exclusion or removal order based solely on the fact of foreign ownership of a potential procurement source that is otherwise qualified to enter into procurement contracts with the Federal Government.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–390, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5180</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1324.</num>
<heading> Strategic plan</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of the Federal Acquisition Supply Chain Security Act of 2018, the Council shall develop a strategic plan for addressing supply chain risks posed by the acquisition of covered articles and for managing such risks that includes—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the criteria and processes required under <ref>section 1323(a) of this title</ref>, including a threshold and requirements for sharing relevant information about such risks with all executive agencies and, as appropriate, with other Federal entities and non-Federal entities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an identification of existing authorities for addressing such risks;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> an identification and promulgation of best practices and procedures and available resources for executive agencies to assess and mitigate such risks;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> recommendations for any legislative, regulatory, or other policy changes to improve efforts to address such risks;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> recommendations for any legislative, regulatory, or other policy changes to incentivize the adoption of best practices for supply chain risk management by the private sector;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> an evaluation of the effect of implementing new policies or procedures on existing contracts and the procurement process;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> a plan for engaging with executive agencies, the private sector, and other nongovernmental stakeholders to address such risks;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> a plan for identification, assessment, mitigation, and vetting of supply chain risks from existing and prospective information and communications technology made available by executive agencies to other executive agencies through common contract solutions, shared services, acquisition vehicles, or other assisted acquisition services; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<chapeau> plans to strengthen the capacity of all executive agencies to conduct assessments of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the supply chain risk posed by the acquisition of covered articles; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> compliance with the requirements of this subchapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Submission to Congress</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 7 calendar days after completion of the strategic plan required by subsection (a), the Chairperson of the Council shall submit the plan to the appropriate congressional committees and leadership.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–390, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5184</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1325.</num>
<heading> Annual report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than December 31 of each year, the Chairperson of the Council shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees and leadership a report on the activities of the Council during the preceding 12-month period.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–390, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5184</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1326.</num>
<heading> Requirements for executive agencies</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The head of each executive agency shall be responsible for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> assessing the supply chain risk posed by the acquisition and use of covered articles and avoiding, mitigating, accepting, or transferring that risk, as appropriate and consistent with the standards, guidelines, and practices identified by the Council under section 1323(a)(1); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> prioritizing supply chain risk assessments conducted under paragraph (1) based on the criticality of the mission, system, component, service, or asset.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inclusions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The responsibility for assessing supply chain risk described in subsection (a) includes—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> developing an overall supply chain risk management strategy and implementation plan and policies and processes to guide and govern supply chain risk management activities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> integrating supply chain risk management practices throughout the life cycle of the system, component, service, or asset;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> limiting, avoiding, mitigating, accepting, or transferring any identified risk;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> sharing relevant information with other executive agencies as determined appropriate by the Council in a manner consistent with <ref>section 1323(a) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> reporting on progress and effectiveness of the agency’s supply chain risk management consistent with guidance issued by the Office of Management and Budget and the Council; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> ensuring that all relevant information, including classified information, with respect to acquisitions of covered articles that may pose a supply chain risk, consistent with <ref>section 1323(a) of this title</ref>, is incorporated into existing processes of the agency for conducting assessments described in subsection (a) and ongoing management of acquisition programs, including any identification, investigation, mitigation, or remediation needs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Interagency Acquisitions.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in paragraph (2), in the case of an interagency acquisition, subsection (a) shall be carried out by the head of the executive agency whose funds are being used to procure the covered article.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Assisted acquisitions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In an assisted acquisition, the parties to the acquisition shall determine, as part of the interagency agreement governing the acquisition, which agency is responsible for carrying out subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this subsection, the terms “assisted acquisition” and “interagency acquisition” have the meanings given those terms in section 2.101 of title 48, Code of Federal Regulations (or any corresponding similar regulation or ruling).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Assistance</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Homeland Security may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> assist executive agencies in conducting risk assessments described in subsection (a) and implementing mitigation requirements for information and communications technology; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provide such additional guidance or tools as are necessary to support actions taken by executive agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–390, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5184</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1327.</num>
<heading> Judicial review procedures</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in subsection (b) and chapter 71 of this title, and notwithstanding any other provision of law, an action taken under section 1323 or 4713 of this title, or any action taken by an executive agency to implement such an action, shall not be subject to administrative review or judicial review, including bid protests before the Government Accountability Office or in any Federal court.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Petitions.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 60 days after a party is notified of an exclusion or removal order under <ref>section 1323(c)(6) of this title</ref> or a covered procurement action under <ref>section 4713 of this title</ref>, the party may file a petition for judicial review in the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit claiming that the issuance of the exclusion or removal order or covered procurement action is unlawful.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Standard of review</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Court shall hold unlawful a covered action taken under sections 1323 or 4713 of this title, in response to a petition that the court finds to be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> arbitrary, capricious, an abuse of discretion, or otherwise not in accordance with law;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> contrary to constitutional right, power, privilege, or immunity;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> in excess of statutory jurisdiction, authority, or limitation, or short of statutory right;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> lacking substantial support in the administrative record taken as a whole or in classified information submitted to the court under paragraph (3); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> not in accord with procedures required by law.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exclusive jurisdiction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit shall have exclusive jurisdiction over claims arising under sections 1323(c)(5) or 4713 of this title against the United States, any United States department or agency, or any component or official of any such department or agency, subject to review by the Supreme Court of the United States under <ref>section 1254 of title 28</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Administrative record and procedures.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The procedures described in this paragraph shall apply to the review of a petition under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Administrative record.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Filing of record</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The United States shall file with the court an administrative record, which shall consist of the information that the appropriate official relied upon in issuing an exclusion or removal order under section 1323(c)(5) or a covered procurement action under <ref>section 4713 of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Unclassified, nonprivileged information</inline>.—</heading>
<content>All unclassified information contained in the administrative record that is not otherwise privileged or subject to statutory protections shall be provided to the petitioner with appropriate protections for any privileged or confidential trade secrets and commercial or financial information.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In camera and ex parte</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The following information may be included in the administrative record and shall be submitted only to the court ex parte and in camera:</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> Classified information.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> Sensitive security information, as defined by section 1520.5 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> Privileged law enforcement information.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> Information obtained or derived from any activity authorized under the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 1801</ref> et seq.), except that, with respect to such information, subsections (c), (e), (f), (g), and (h) of section 106 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 1806</ref>), subsections (d), (f), (g), (h), and (i) of section 305 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 1825</ref>), subsections (c), (e), (f), (g), and (h) of section 405 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 1845</ref>), and section 706 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 1881e</ref>) of that Act shall not apply.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(V)</num>
<content> Information subject to privilege or protections under any other provision of law.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Under seal</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any information that is part of the administrative record filed ex parte and in camera under clause (iii), or cited by the court in any decision, shall be treated by the court consistent with the provisions of this subparagraph and shall remain under seal and preserved in the records of the court to be made available consistent with the above provisions in the event of further proceedings. In no event shall such information be released to the petitioner or as part of the public record.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Return</inline>.—</heading>
<content>After the expiration of the time to seek further review, or the conclusion of further proceedings, the court shall return the administrative record, including any and all copies, to the United States.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exclusive remedy</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A determination by the court under this subsection shall be the exclusive judicial remedy for any claim described in this section against the United States, any United States department or agency, or any component or official of any such department or agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rule of construction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section shall be construed as limiting, superseding, or preventing the invocation of, any privileges or defenses that are otherwise available at law or in equity to protect against the disclosure of information.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the term “classified information”—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> has the meaning given that term in section 1(a) of the Classified Information Procedures Act (18 U.S.C. App.); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any information or material that has been determined by the United States Government pursuant to an Executive order, statute, or regulation to require protection against unauthorized disclosure for reasons of national security; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any restricted data, as defined in section 11 of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 2014</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–390, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5185</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1328.</num>
<heading> Termination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This subchapter shall terminate on <date date="2033-12-31">December 31, 2033</date>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–390, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5188</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. E, title LIX, § 5949(k)(1)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3492</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>