<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 61—</num>
<heading>ADVERTISING</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6101.</num>
<heading> Advertising requirement for Federal Government purchases and sales</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appropriation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “appropriation” includes amounts made available by legislation under <ref>section 9104 of title 31</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Federal government</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “Federal Government” includes the government of the District of Columbia.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Purchases.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Unless otherwise provided in the appropriation concerned or other law, purchases and contracts for supplies or services for the Federal Government may be made or entered into only after advertising for proposals for a sufficient time.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitations on applicability</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Paragraph (1) does not apply when—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the amount involved in any one case does not exceed $25,000;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> public exigencies require the immediate delivery of articles or performance of services;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> only one source of supply is available and the Federal Government purchasing or contracting officer so certifies; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> services are required to be performed by a contractor in person and are—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> of a technical and professional nature; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> under Federal Government supervision and paid for on a time basis.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Sales</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except when otherwise authorized by law or when the reasonable value involved in any one case does not exceed $500, sales and contracts of sale by the Federal Government are governed by the requirements of this section for advertising.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Application to Wholly Owned Government Corporations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For wholly owned Government corporations, this section applies only to administrative transactions.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3801</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6102.</num>
<heading> Exceptions from advertising requirement</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">American Battle Monuments Commission</inline>.—</heading>
<content><ref>Section 6101 of this title</ref> does not apply to the American Battle Monuments Commission with respect to leases in foreign countries for office or garage space.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Bureau of Interparliamentary Union for Promotion of International Arbitration</inline>.—</heading>
<content><ref>Section 6101 of this title</ref> does not apply to the Bureau of Interparliamentary Union for Promotion of International Arbitration with respect to necessary stenographic reporting services by contract.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Department of State</inline>.—</heading>
<content><ref>Section 6101 of this title</ref> does not apply to the Department of State when the purchase or service relates to the packing of personal and household effects of Diplomatic, Consular, and Foreign Service officers and clerks for foreign shipment.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">International Committee of Aerial Legal Experts</inline>.—</heading>
<content><ref>Section 6101 of this title</ref> does not apply to the International Committee of Aerial Legal Experts with respect to necessary stenographic and other services by contract.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Architect of the Capitol</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The purchase of supplies and equipment and the procurement of services for all branches under the Architect of the Capitol may be made in the open market according to common business practice, without compliance with <ref>section 6101 of this title</ref>, when the aggregate amount of the purchase or the service does not exceed $25,000 in any instance.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Forest Products From Indian Reservations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Lumber and other forest products produced by Indian enterprises from forests on Indian reservations may be sold under regulations the Secretary of the Interior prescribes, without compliance with <ref>section 6101 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">House of Representatives</inline>.—</heading>
<content><ref>Section 6101 of this title</ref> does not apply to purchases and contracts for supplies or services for any office of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Congressional Budget Office</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Director of the Congressional Budget Office may enter into agreements or contracts without regard to <ref>section 6101 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Senate</inline>.—</heading>
<content><ref>Section 6101 of this title</ref> does not apply to agreements, contracts or purchases by any office of the Senate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Librarian of Congress</inline>.—</heading>
<content><ref>Section 6101 of this title</ref> does not apply to a procurement made against an order placed under a task order contract or a delivery order contract (as such terms are defined in <ref>section 4101 of this title</ref>) entered into by the Librarian of Congress.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3802</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. I, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 772</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–103, div. I, title I, § 142(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-03-15">Mar. 15, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 519</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6103.</num>
<heading> Opening of bids</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever proposals for supplies have been solicited, the parties responding to the solicitation shall be notified of the time and place of the opening of the bids, and be permitted to be present either in person or by attorney. A record of each bid shall be made at the time and place of the opening of the bids.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3803</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>