<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 63—</num>
<heading>GENERAL CONTRACT PROVISIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6301.</num>
<heading> Authorization requirement</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A contract or purchase on behalf of the Federal Government shall not be made unless the contract or purchase is authorized by law or is under an appropriation adequate to its fulfillment.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Exception.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this subsection, the term “defined Secretary” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Defense; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Homeland Security with respect to the Coast Guard when the Coast Guard is not operating as a service in the Navy.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subsection (a) does not apply to a contract or purchase made by a defined Secretary for clothing, subsistence, forage, fuel, quarters, transportation, or medical and hospital supplies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Current year limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A contract or purchase made by a defined Secretary under this subsection may not exceed the necessities of the current year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reports</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The defined Secretary shall immediately advise Congress when authority is exercised under this subsection. The defined Secretary shall report quarterly on the estimated obligations incurred pursuant to the authority granted in this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Special Rule for Purchase of Land</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Land may not be purchased by the Federal Government unless the purchase is authorized by law.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3803</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–281, title IX, § 903(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3010</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6302.</num>
<heading> Contracts for fuel made by Secretary of the Army</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Army, when the Secretary believes it is in the interest of the United States, may enter into contracts and incur obligations for fuel in sufficient quantities to meet the requirements for one year without regard to the current fiscal year. Amounts appropriated for the fiscal year in which the contract is made or amounts appropriated or which may be appropriated for the following fiscal year may be used to pay for supplies delivered under a contract made pursuant to this section.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3804</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6303.</num>
<heading> Certain contracts limited to appropriated amounts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A contract to erect, repair, or furnish a public building, or to make any public improvement, shall not be made on terms requiring the Federal Government to pay more than the amount specifically appropriated for the activity covered by the contract.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3804</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6304.</num>
<heading> Certain contracts limited to one-year term</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided, an executive department shall not make a contract for stationery or other supplies for a term longer than one year from the time the contract is made.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3804</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6305.</num>
<heading> Prohibition on transfer of contract and certain allowable assignments</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General Prohibition on Transfer of Contracts</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The party to whom the Federal Government gives a contract or order may not transfer the contract or order, or any interest in the contract or order, to another party. A purported transfer in violation of this subsection annuls the contract or order so far as the Federal Government is concerned, except that all rights of action for breach of contract are reserved to the Federal Government.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Assignment.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding subsection (a) and in accordance with the requirements of this subsection, amounts due from the Federal Government under a contract may be assigned to a bank, trust company, Federal lending agency, or other financing institution.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Minimum amount</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This subsection applies only to a contract under which the aggregate amounts due from the Federal Government total at least $1,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Accord with contract terms</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Assignment may not be made under this subsection if the contract forbids the assignment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Full balance due</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Unless otherwise expressly permitted by the contract, an assignment under this subsection must cover the balance of all amounts due from the Federal Government under the contract.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Single assignment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Unless otherwise expressly permitted by the contract, an assignment under this subsection may not be made to more than one party or be subject to further assignment, except that assignment may be made to one party as agent or trustee for 2 or more parties participating in the financing.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Written notice</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The assignee of an assignment under this subsection shall file written notice of the assignment and a true copy of the instrument of assignment with—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the contracting officer or head of the officer’s department or agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the surety on any bond connected with the contract; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the disbursing officer, if any, designated in the contract to make payment.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Validity</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding any law to the contrary governing the validity of assignments, an assignment under this subsection is a valid assignment for all purposes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">No refund to cover assignor’s liability</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The assignee of an assignment under this subsection is not liable to make any refund to the Federal Government because of an assignor’s liability to the Federal Government, whether that liability arises from the contract or independently.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Avoiding reduction or setoff with certain contracts.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contract provision</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A contract of the Department of Defense, the General Services Administration, the Department of Energy, or another department or agency of the Federal Government designated by the President may, on a determination of need by the President, provide or be amended without consideration to provide that payments made to an assignee under the contract are not subject to reduction or setoff. Each determination of need by the President under this subparagraph shall be published in the Federal Register.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Carrying out contract provision</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>When a “no reduction or setoff” provision as described in subparagraph (A) is included in a contract, payments to the assignee are not subject to reduction or setoff for an assignor’s liability arising—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> independently of the contract;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> on account of renegotiation under a renegotiation statute or under a statutory renegotiation article in the contract;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> on account of fines;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> on account of penalties; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> on account of taxes, social security contributions, or the withholding or non-withholding of taxes or social security contributions, whether arising from or independently of the contract.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subparagraph (B)(iv) does not apply to amounts which may be collected or withheld from the assignor in accordance with or for failure to comply with the terms of the contract.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3804</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6306.</num>
<heading> Prohibition on Members of Congress making contracts with Federal Government</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A Member of Congress may not enter into or benefit from a contract or agreement or any part of a contract or agreement with the Federal Government.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Exemptions.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subsection (a) does not apply to contracts that the Secretary of Agriculture may enter into with farmers.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Certain acts</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subsection (a) does not apply to a contract entered into under—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Agricultural Adjustment Act (<ref>7 U.S.C. 601</ref> et seq.);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Farm Credit Act of 1971 (<ref>12 U.S.C. 2001</ref> et seq.); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Home Owners’ Loan Act (<ref>12 U.S.C. 1461</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Public record</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An exemption under this subsection shall be made a matter of public record.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3805</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6307.</num>
<heading> Contracts with Federal Government-owned establishments and availability of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An order or contract placed with a Federal Government-owned establishment for work, material, or the manufacture of material pertaining to an approved project is deemed to be an obligation in the same manner that a similar order or contract placed with a commercial manufacturer or private contractor is an obligation. Appropriations remain available to pay an obligation to a Federal Government-owned establishment just as appropriations remain available to pay an obligation to a commercial manufacturer or private contractor.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3806</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6308.</num>
<heading> Contracts for transportation of Federal Government securities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">When practicable, a contract for transporting bullion, cash, or securities of the Federal Government shall be awarded to the lowest responsible bidder after notice to all parties with means of transportation.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3806</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6309.</num>
<heading> Honorable discharge certificate in lieu of birth certificate</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An employer described in subsection (b) may not deny employment, on account of failure to produce a birth certificate, to an individual who submits, in lieu of the birth certificate, an honorable discharge certificate (or certificate issued in lieu of an honorable discharge certificate) from the Army, Air Force, Navy, Marine Corps, Space Force, or Coast Guard of the United States, unless the honorable discharge certificate shows on its face that the individual may have been an alien at the time of its issuance.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Employers to Which Section Applies</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An employer referred to in subsection (a) is an employer—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> engaged in—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the production, maintenance, or storage of arms, armament, ammunition, implements of war, munitions, machinery, tools, clothing, food, fuel, or any articles or supplies, or parts or ingredients of any articles or supplies; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the construction, reconstruction, repair, or installation of a building, plant, structure, or facility; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> engaged in the activity described in paragraph (1) under—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a contract with the Federal Government; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any contract that the President, the Secretary of the Army, the Secretary of the Air Force, the Secretary of the Navy, or the Secretary of the Department in which the Coast Guard is operating certifies to the employer to be necessary to the national defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3806</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 927(e)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3832</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6310.</num>
<heading> Requirement for agencies to buy domestically made United States flags</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in subsections (b) through (d), funds appropriated or otherwise available to an agency may not be used for the procurement of any flag of the United States, unless such flag has been 100 percent manufactured in the United States from articles, materials, or supplies that have been grown or 100 percent produced or manufactured in the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Availability Exception</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subsection (a) does not apply to the extent that the head of the agency concerned determines that satisfactory quality and sufficient quantity of a flag described in such subsection cannot be procured as and when needed at United States market prices.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception for Certain Procurements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subsection (a) does not apply to the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Procurements by vessels in foreign waters.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Procurements for resale purposes in any military commissary, military exchange, or nonappropriated fund instrumentality operated by an agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Procurements for amounts less than the simplified acquisition threshold.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Presidential Waiver.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The President may waive the requirement in subsection (a) if the President determines a waiver is necessary to comply with any trade agreement to which the United States is a party.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice of waiver</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 30 days after granting a waiver under paragraph (1), the President shall publish a notice of the waiver in the Federal Register.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Agency</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “agency” has the meaning given the term “executive agency” in <ref>section 102 of title 40</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Simplified acquisition threshold</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “simplified acquisition threshold” has the meaning given that term in section 134.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 118–74, § 2(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2024-07-30">July 30, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1505</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>