<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 65—</num>
<heading>CONTRACTS FOR MATERIALS, SUPPLIES, ARTICLES, AND EQUIPMENT EXCEEDING $10,000</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6501.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Agency of the united states</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “agency of the United States” means an executive department, independent establishment, or other agency or instrumentality of the United States, the District of Columbia, or a corporation in which all stock is beneficially owned by the Federal Government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Person</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “person” includes one or more individuals, partnerships, associations, corporations, legal representatives, trustees, trustees in cases under title 11, or receivers.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Secretary</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Labor.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3807</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6502.</num>
<heading> Required contract terms</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A contract made by an agency of the United States for the manufacture or furnishing of materials, supplies, articles, or equipment, in an amount exceeding $10,000, shall include the following representations and stipulations:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Minimum wages to be paid</inline>.—</heading>
<content>All individuals employed by the contractor in the manufacture or furnishing of materials, supplies, articles, or equipment under the contract will be paid, without subsequent deduction or rebate on any account, not less than the prevailing minimum wages, as determined by the Secretary, for individuals employed in similar work or in the particular or similar industries or groups of industries currently operating in the locality in which the materials, supplies, articles, or equipment are to be manufactured or furnished under the contract, except that this paragraph applies only to purchases or contracts relating to industries that have been the subject matter of a determination by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Maximum number of hours to be worked in a week</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No individual employed by the contractor in the manufacture or furnishing of materials, supplies, articles, or equipment under the contract shall be permitted to work in excess of 40 hours in any one week, except that this paragraph does not apply to an employer who has entered into an agreement with employees pursuant to paragraph (1) or (2) of section 7(b) of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 207(b)(1)</ref> or (2)).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Ineligible employees</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No individual under 16 years of age and no incarcerated individual will be employed by the contractor in the manufacture or furnishing of materials, supplies, articles, or equipment under the contract, except that this section, or other law or executive order containing similar prohibitions against the purchase of goods by the Federal Government, does not apply to convict labor that satisfies the conditions of <ref>section 1761(c) of title 18</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Standards of places and working conditions where contract performed</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No part of the contract will be performed, and no materials, supplies, articles, or equipment will be manufactured or fabricated under the contract, in plants, factories, buildings, or surroundings, or under working conditions, that are unsanitary, hazardous, or dangerous to the health and safety of employees engaged in the performance of the contract. Compliance with the safety, sanitary, and factory inspection laws of the State in which the work or part of the work is to be performed is prima facie evidence of compliance with this paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3807</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6503.</num>
<heading> Breach or violation of required contract terms</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Applicable Breach or Violation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section applies in case of breach or violation of a representation or stipulation included in a contract under <ref>section 6502 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Liquidated Damages</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In addition to damages for any other breach of the contract, the party responsible for a breach or violation described in subsection (a) is liable to the Federal Government for the following liquidated damages:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> An amount equal to the sum of $10 per day for each individual under 16 years of age and each incarcerated individual knowingly employed in the performance of the contract.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> An amount equal to the sum of each underpayment of wages due an employee engaged in the performance of the contract, including any underpayments arising from deductions, rebates, or refunds.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Cancellation and Alternative Completion</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In addition to the Federal Government being entitled to damages described in subsection (b), the agency of the United States that made the contract may cancel the contract and make open-market purchases or make other contracts for the completion of the original contract, charging any additional cost to the original contractor.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Recovery of Amounts Due</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An amount due the Federal Government because of a breach or violation described in subsection (a) may be withheld from any amounts owed the contractor under any contract under <ref>section 6502 of this title</ref> or may be recovered in a suit brought by the Attorney General.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Employee Reimbursement for Underpayment of Wages</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An amount withheld or recovered under subsection (d) that is based on an underpayment of wages as described in subsection (b)(2) shall be held in a special deposit account. On order of the Secretary, the amount shall be paid directly to the underpaid employee on whose account the amount was withheld or recovered. However, an employee’s claim for payment under this subsection may be entertained only if made within one year from the date of actual notice to the contractor of the withholding or recovery.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3808</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6504.</num>
<heading> Three-year prohibition on new contracts in case of breach or violation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Distribution of List</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Comptroller General shall distribute to each agency of the United States a list containing the names of persons found by the Secretary to have breached or violated a representation or stipulation included in a contract under <ref>section 6502 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Three-Year Prohibition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Unless the Secretary recommends otherwise, a contract described in <ref>section 6502 of this title</ref> may not be awarded to a person named on the list under subsection (a), or to a firm, corporation, partnership, or association in which the person has a controlling interest, until 3 years have elapsed from the date of the determination by the Secretary that a breach or violation occurred.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3808</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6505.</num>
<heading> Exclusions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Items Available in the Open Market</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This chapter does not apply to the purchase of materials, supplies, articles, or equipment that may usually be bought in the open market.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Perishables and Agricultural Products</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>This chapter does not apply to any of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Perishables, including dairy, livestock and nursery products.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Agricultural or farm products processed for first sale by the original producers.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Contracts made by the Secretary of Agriculture for the purchase of agricultural commodities or products of agricultural commodities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Carriage of Freight or Personnel</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>This chapter may not be construed to apply to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the carriage of freight or personnel by vessel, airplane, bus, truck, express, or railway line where published tariff rates are in effect; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> common carriers subject to the Communications Act of 1934 (<ref>47 U.S.C. 151</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3809</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6506.</num>
<heading> Administrative provisions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall administer this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may make, amend, and rescind regulations as necessary to carry out this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of Government Officers and Employees</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall use Federal officers and employees and, with a State’s consent, State and local officers and employees as the Secretary finds necessary to assist in the administration of this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appointments</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall appoint an administrative officer and attorneys, experts, and other employees from time to time as the Secretary finds necessary for the administration of this chapter. The appointments are subject to chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5 and other law applicable to the employment and compensation of officers and employees of the Federal Government.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Investigations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary, or an authorized representative of the Secretary, may make investigations and findings as provided in this chapter and may, in any part of the United States, prosecute an inquiry necessary to carry out this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3809</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6507.</num>
<heading> Hearing authority and procedures</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Record and Hearing Requirements for Wage Determinations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A wage determination under <ref>section 6502(1) of this title</ref> shall be made on the record after opportunity for a hearing.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority To Hold Hearings</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary or an impartial representative designated by the Secretary may hold hearings when there is a complaint of breach or violation of a representation or stipulation included in a contract under <ref>section 6502 of this title</ref>. The Secretary may initiate hearings on the Secretary’s own motion or on the application of a person affected by the ruling of an agency of the United States relating to a proposal or contract under this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Orders To Compel Testimony</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary or an impartial representative designated by the Secretary may issue orders requiring witnesses to attend hearings held under this section and to produce evidence and testify under oath. Witnesses shall be paid fees and mileage at the same rates as witnesses in courts of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Enforcement of Orders</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If a person refuses or fails to obey an order issued under subsection (c), the Secretary or an impartial representative designated by the Secretary may bring an action to enforce the order in a district court of the United States or in the district court of a territory or possession of the United States. A court has jurisdiction to enforce the order if the inquiry is being carried out within the court’s judicial district or if the person is found or resides or transacts business within the court’s judicial district. The court may issue an order requiring the person to obey the order issued under subsection (c), and the court may punish any further refusal or failure as contempt of court.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Findings of Fact</inline>.—</heading>
<content>After notice and a hearing, the Secretary or an impartial representative designated by the Secretary shall make findings of fact. The findings are conclusive for agencies of the United States. If supported by a preponderance of the evidence, the findings are conclusive in any court of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Decisions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary or an impartial representative designated by the Secretary may make decisions, based on findings of fact, that are considered necessary to enforce this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3809</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6508.</num>
<heading> Authority to make exceptions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duty of the Secretary To Make Exceptions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>When the head of an agency of the United States makes a written finding that the inclusion of representations or stipulations under <ref>section 6502 of this title</ref> in a proposal or contract will seriously impair the conduct of Federal Government business, the Secretary shall make exceptions, in specific cases or otherwise, when justice or the public interest will be served.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority of the Secretary To Modify Existing Contracts</inline>.—</heading>
<content>When an agency of the United States and a contractor jointly recommend, the Secretary may modify the terms of an existing contract with respect to minimum wages and maximum hours of labor as the Secretary finds necessary and proper in the public interest or to prevent injustice and undue hardship.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority of the Secretary To Allow Limitations, Variations, Tolerances, and Exemptions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may provide reasonable limitations and may prescribe regulations to allow reasonable variations, tolerances, and exemptions in the application of this chapter to contractors, including with respect to minimum wages and maximum hours of labor.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rate of Pay for Overtime</inline>.—</heading>
<content>When the Secretary permits an increase in the maximum hours of labor stipulated in a contract, the Secretary shall set a rate of pay for overtime. The overtime rate must be at least one and one-half times the basic hourly rate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority of the President To Suspend</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The President may suspend any of the representations and stipulations contained in <ref>section 6502 of this title</ref> whenever, in the President’s judgment, suspension is in the public interest.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3810</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6509.</num>
<heading> Other procedures</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Applicability of Certain Administrative Provisions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding <ref>section 553 of title 5</ref>, subchapter II of chapter 5 and chapter 7 of title 5 are applicable in the administration of sections 6501 to 6507 and 6511 of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Judicial Review in General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding the inclusion of representations and stipulations in a contract under <ref>section 6502 of this title</ref>, an interested person has the right of judicial review of any legal question which might otherwise be raised, including wage determinations and the interpretation of the terms “locality” and “open market”.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Judicial Review of Wage Determinations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A person adversely affected or aggrieved by a wage determination under <ref>section 6502(1) of this title</ref> has the right of judicial review of the determination, or of the applicability of the determination, within 90 days after the determination is made, in the manner provided by chapter 7 of title 5. A person adversely affected or aggrieved by a wage determination is deemed to include a person in an industry to which the determination applies that is a supplier of materials, supplies, articles, or equipment that are purchased or intended to be purchased by the Federal Government from any source.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3810</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6510.</num>
<heading> Manufacturers and regular dealers</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prescribing Standards</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may prescribe, in regulations, standards for determining whether a contractor is a manufacturer or regular dealer with respect to materials, supplies, articles, or equipment to be manufactured or furnished under, or used in the performance of, a contract entered into by an agency of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Judicial Review</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An interested person has the right of judicial review of any legal question relating to interpretation of the terms “regular dealer” and “manufacturer” as defined pursuant to subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3811</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6511.</num>
<heading> Effect on other law</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">This chapter may not be construed to modify or amend the following provisions:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Chapter 83 of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Sections 3141 to 3144, 3146, and 3147 of title 40.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Chapter 307 of title 18.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3811</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>