<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 12—</num>
<heading>FEDERAL ACQUISITION INSTITUTE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1201.</num>
<heading> Federal Acquisition Institute</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>There is established a Federal Acquisition Institute (FAI) in order to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> foster and promote the development of a professional acquisition workforce Government-wide;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> promote and coordinate Government-wide research and studies to improve the procurement process and the laws, policies, methods, regulations, procedures, and forms relating to acquisition by the executive agencies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> collect data and analyze acquisition workforce data from the Office of Personnel Management, the heads of executive agencies, and, through periodic surveys, from individual employees;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> periodically analyze acquisition career fields to identify critical competencies, duties, tasks, and related academic prerequisites, skills, and knowledge;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> coordinate and assist agencies in identifying and recruiting highly qualified candidates for acquisition fields;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> develop instructional materials for acquisition personnel in coordination with private and public acquisition colleges and training facilities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> evaluate the effectiveness of training and career development programs for acquisition personnel;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> promote the establishment and utilization of academic programs by colleges and universities in acquisition fields;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> facilitate, to the extent requested by agencies, interagency intern and training programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> collaborate with other civilian agency acquisition training programs to leverage training supporting all members of the civilian agency acquisition workforce;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> assist civilian agencies with their acquisition and capital planning efforts; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> perform other career management or research functions as directed by the Administrator.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Budget Resources and Authority.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall recommend to the Administrator of General Services sufficient budget resources and authority for the Federal Acquisition Institute to support Government-wide training standards and certification requirements necessary to enhance the mobility and career opportunities of the Federal acquisition workforce.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Acquisition workforce training fund</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to the availability of funds, the Administrator of General Services shall provide the Federal Acquisition Institute with amounts from the acquisition workforce training fund established under <ref>section 1703(i) of this title</ref> sufficient to meet the annual budget for the Federal Acquisition Institute requested by the Administrator under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Federal Acquisition Institute Board of Directors.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reporting to administrator</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Federal Acquisition Institute shall report through its Board of Directors directly to the Administrator.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Composition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Board shall be composed of not more than 8 individuals from the Federal Government representing a mix of acquisition functional areas, all of whom shall be appointed by the Administrator.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duties</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Board shall provide general direction to the Federal Acquisition Institute to ensure that the Institute—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> meets its statutory requirements;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> meets the needs of the Federal acquisition workforce;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> implements appropriate programs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> coordinates with appropriate organizations and groups that have an impact on the Federal acquisition workforce;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> develops and implements plans to meet future challenges of the Federal acquisition workforce; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> works closely with the Defense Acquisition University.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Recommendations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Board shall make recommendations to the Administrator regarding the development and execution of the annual budget of the Federal Acquisition Institute.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Director</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Director of the Federal Acquisition Institute shall be appointed by, be subject to the direction and control of, and report directly to the Administrator.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Report</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate and the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives an annual report on the projected budget needs and expense plans of the Federal Acquisition Institute to fulfill its mandate.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title VIII, § 864(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1523</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>