<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 23—</num>
<heading>MISCELLANEOUS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2301.</num>
<heading> Use of electronic commerce in Federal procurement</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For the purposes of this section, the term “electronic commerce” means electronic techniques for accomplishing business transactions, including electronic mail or messaging, World Wide Web technology, electronic bulletin boards, purchase cards, electronic funds transfers, and electronic data interchange.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment, Maintenance, and Use of Electronic Commerce Procedures and Processes</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The head of each executive agency, after consulting with the Administrator, shall establish, maintain, and use, to the maximum extent that is practicable and cost-effective, procedures and processes that employ electronic commerce in the conduct and administration of the procurement system of the agency.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Applicable Standards</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In conducting electronic commerce, the head of an executive agency shall apply nationally and internationally recognized standards that broaden interoperability and ease the electronic interchange of information.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirements of Systems, Technologies, Procedures, and Processes</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The head of each executive agency shall ensure that systems, technologies, procedures, and processes established pursuant to this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> are implemented with uniformity throughout the agency, to the extent practicable;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> are implemented only after granting due consideration to the use or partial use, as appropriate, of existing electronic commerce and electronic data interchange systems and infrastructures such as the Federal acquisition computer network architecture known as FACNET;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> facilitate access to Federal Government procurement opportunities, including opportunities for small business concerns, socially and economically disadvantaged small business concerns, and business concerns owned predominantly by women; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> ensure that any notice of agency requirements or agency solicitation for contract opportunities is provided in a form that allows convenient and universal user access through a single, Government-wide point of entry.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Implementation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In carrying out the requirements of this section, the Administrator shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> issue policies to promote, to the maximum extent practicable, uniform implementation of this section by executive agencies, with due regard for differences in program requirements among agencies that may require departures from uniform procedures and processes in appropriate cases, when warranted because of the agency mission;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> ensure that the head of each executive agency complies with the requirements of subsection (d); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> consult with the heads of appropriate Federal agencies with applicable technical and functional expertise, including the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs, the National Institute of Standards and Technology, the General Services Administration, and the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inapplicability to Department of Defense</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “executive agency” does not include the Department of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3732</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title VIII, § 833(b)(5)(A)(ii)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2285</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2302.</num>
<heading> Rights in technical data</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Where Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The legitimate proprietary interest of the Federal Government and of a contractor in technical or other data shall be defined in regulations prescribed as part of the Federal Acquisition Regulation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">General Extent of Regulations.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Other rights not impaired</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Regulations prescribed under subsection (a) may not impair a right of the Federal Government or of a contractor with respect to a patent or copyright or another right in technical data otherwise established by law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on requiring data be provided to the government</inline>.—</heading>
<content>With respect to executive agencies subject to division C, regulations prescribed under subsection (a) shall provide that the Federal Government may not require a person that has developed a product (or process offered or to be offered for sale to the public) to provide to the Federal Government technical data relating to the design (or development or manufacture of the product or process) as a condition of procurement by the Federal Government of the product or process. This paragraph does not apply to data that may be necessary for the Federal Government to operate and maintain the product or use the process if the Federal Government obtains it as an element of performance under the contract.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Technical Data Developed With Federal Funds.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use by government and agencies</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Except as otherwise expressly provided by Federal statute, with respect to executive agencies subject to division C, regulations prescribed under subsection (a) shall provide that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> the Federal Government has unlimited rights in technical data developed exclusively with Federal funds if delivery of the data—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> was required as an element of performance under a contract; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> is needed to ensure the competitive acquisition of supplies or services that will be required in substantial quantities in the future; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Federal Government and each agency of the Federal Government has an unrestricted, royalty-free right to use, or to have its contractors use, for governmental purposes (excluding publication outside the Federal Government) technical data developed exclusively with Federal funds.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirements in addition to other rights of the government</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The requirements of paragraph (1) are in addition to and not in lieu of any other rights the Federal Government may have pursuant to law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Factors To Be Considered in Prescribing Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The following factors shall be considered in prescribing regulations under subsection (a):</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Whether the item or process to which the technical data pertains was developed—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> exclusively with Federal funds;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> exclusively at private expense; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> in part with Federal funds and in part at private expense.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The statement of congressional policy and objectives in <ref>section 200 of title 35</ref>, the statement of purposes in section 2(b) of the Small Business Innovation Development Act of 1982 (<ref>Public Law 97–219</ref>, <ref>15 U.S.C. 638</ref> note), and the declaration of policy in section 2 of the Small Business Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 631</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The interest of the Federal Government in increasing competition and lowering costs by developing and locating alternative sources of supply and manufacture.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Provisions Required in Contracts</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Regulations prescribed under subsection (a) shall require that a contract for property or services entered into by an executive agency contain appropriate provisions relating to technical data, including provisions—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> defining the respective rights of the Federal Government and the contractor or subcontractor (at any tier) regarding technical data to be delivered under the contract;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> specifying technical data to be delivered under the contract and schedules for delivery;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> establishing or referencing procedures for determining the acceptability of technical data to be delivered under the contract;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> establishing separate contract line items for technical data to be delivered under the contract;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to the maximum practicable extent, identifying, in advance of delivery, technical data which is to be delivered with restrictions on the right of the Federal Government to use the data;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> requiring the contractor to revise any technical data delivered under the contract to reflect engineering design changes made during the performance of the contract and affecting the form, fit, and function of the items specified in the contract and to deliver the revised technical data to an agency within a time specified in the contract;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> requiring the contractor to furnish written assurance, when technical data is delivered or is made available, that the technical data is complete and accurate and satisfies the requirements of the contract concerning technical data;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> establishing remedies to be available to the Federal Government when technical data required to be delivered or made available under the contract is found to be incomplete or inadequate or to not satisfy the requirements of the contract concerning technical data; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> authorizing the head of the agency to withhold payments under the contract (or exercise another remedy the head of the agency considers appropriate) during any period if the contractor does not meet the requirements of the contract pertaining to the delivery of technical data.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3733</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2303.</num>
<heading> Ethics safeguards related to contractor conflicts of interest</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “relevant acquisition function” means an acquisition function closely associated with inherently governmental functions.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Policy on Personal Conflicts of Interest by Contractor Employees.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Development and issuance of policy</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall develop and issue a standard policy to prevent personal conflicts of interest by contractor employees performing relevant acquisition functions (including the development, award, and administration of Federal Government contracts) for or on behalf of a Federal agency or department.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Elements of policy</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The policy shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> define “personal conflict of interest” as it relates to contractor employees performing relevant acquisition functions; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> require each contractor whose employees perform relevant acquisition functions to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> identify and prevent personal conflicts of interest for the employees;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> prohibit contractor employees who have access to non-public government information obtained while performing relevant acquisition functions from using the information for personal gain;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> report any personal conflict-of-interest violation by an employee to the applicable contracting officer or contracting officer’s representative as soon as it is identified;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> maintain effective oversight to verify compliance with personal conflict-of-interest safeguards;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> have procedures in place to screen for potential conflicts of interest for all employees performing relevant acquisition functions; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> take appropriate disciplinary action in the case of employees who fail to comply with policies established pursuant to this section.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Contract clause.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contents</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Administrator shall develop a personal conflicts-of-interest clause or a set of clauses for inclusion in solicitations and contracts (and task or delivery orders) for the performance of relevant acquisition functions that sets forth—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the personal conflicts-of-interest policy developed under this subsection; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the contractor’s responsibilities under the policy.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Effective date</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subparagraph (A) shall take effect 300 days after <date date="2008-10-14">October 14, 2008</date>, and shall apply to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> contracts entered into on or after that effective date; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> task or delivery orders awarded on or after that effective date, regardless of whether the contracts pursuant to which the task or delivery orders are awarded are entered before, on, or after <date date="2008-10-14">October 14, 2008</date>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Applicability.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contracts in excess of the simplified acquisition threshold</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This subsection shall apply to any contract for an amount in excess of the simplified acquisition threshold (as defined in <ref>section 134 of this title</ref>) if the contract is for the performance of relevant acquisition functions.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Partial applicability</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If only a portion of a contract described in subparagraph (A) is for the performance of relevant acquisition functions, then this subsection applies only to that portion of the contract.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Best Practices</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall, in consultation with the Director of the Office of Government Ethics, develop and maintain a repository of best practices relating to the prevention and mitigation of organizational and personal conflicts of interest in Federal contracting.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3735</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2304.</num>
<heading> Conflict of interest standards for consultants</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Content of Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Administrator shall prescribe under this division Government-wide regulations that set forth—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> conflict of interest standards for persons who provide consulting services described in subsection (b); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> procedures, including registration, certification, and enforcement requirements as may be appropriate, to promote compliance with the standards.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Services Subject to Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Regulations required by subsection (a) apply to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> advisory and assistance services provided to the Federal Government to the extent necessary to identify and evaluate the potential for conflicts of interest that could be prejudicial to the interests of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> services related to support of the preparation or submission of bids and proposals for Federal contracts to the extent that inclusion of the services in the regulations is necessary to identify and evaluate the potential for conflicts of interest that could be prejudicial to the interests of the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> other services related to Federal contracts as specified in the regulations prescribed under subsection (a) to the extent necessary to identify and evaluate the potential for conflicts of interest that could be prejudicial to the interests of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Intelligence Activities Exemption.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Activities that may be exempt</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Intelligence activities as defined in section 3.4(e) of Executive Order No. 12333 or a comparable definitional section in any successor order may be exempt from the regulations required by subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Director of National Intelligence shall report to the Intelligence and Appropriations Committees of Congress each January 1, delineating the activities and organizations that have been exempted under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Presidential Determination</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Before the regulations required by subsection (a) are prescribed, the President shall determine if prescribing the regulations will have a significantly adverse effect on the accomplishment of the mission of the Defense Department or another Federal agency. If the President determines that the regulations will have such an adverse effect, the President shall so report to the appropriate committees of the Senate and the House of Representatives, stating in full the reasons for the determination. If such a report is submitted, the requirement for the regulations shall be null and void.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3736</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2305.</num>
<heading> Authority of Director of Office of Management and Budget not affected</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This division does not limit the authorities and responsibilities of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget in effect on <date date="1983-12-01">December 1, 1983</date>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3737</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2306.</num>
<heading> Openness of meetings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Administrator by regulation shall require that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> formal meetings of the Office of Federal Procurement Policy, as designated by the Administrator, for developing procurement policies and regulations be open to the public; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> public notice of each meeting be given not less than 10 days prior to the meeting.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3737</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2307.</num>
<heading> Comptroller General’s access to information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator and personnel in the Office of Federal Procurement Policy shall furnish information the Comptroller General may require to discharge the responsibilities of the Comptroller General. For this purpose, the Comptroller General or representatives of the Comptroller General shall have access to all books, documents, papers, and records of the Office of Federal Procurement Policy.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3737</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2308.</num>
<heading> Modular contracting for information technology</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use</inline>.—</heading>
<content>To the maximum extent practicable, the head of an executive agency should use modular contracting for an acquisition of a major system of information technology.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Modular Contracting Described</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Under modular contracting, an executive agency’s need for a system is satisfied in successive acquisitions of interoperable increments. Each increment complies with common or commercially accepted standards applicable to information technology so that the increments are compatible with other increments of information technology comprising the system.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Provisions in Federal Acquisition Regulation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Federal Acquisition Regulation shall provide that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> under the modular contracting process, an acquisition of a major system of information technology may be divided into several smaller acquisition increments that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> are easier to manage individually than would be one comprehensive acquisition;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> address complex information technology objectives incrementally in order to enhance the likelihood of achieving workable solutions for attaining those objectives;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> provide for delivery, implementation, and testing of workable systems or solutions in discrete increments, each of which comprises a system or solution that is not dependent on a subsequent increment in order to perform its principal functions; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> provide an opportunity for subsequent increments of the acquisition to take advantage of any evolution in technology or needs that occurs during conduct of the earlier increments;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to the maximum extent practicable, a contract for an increment of an information technology acquisition should be awarded within 180 days after the solicitation is issued and, if the contract for that increment cannot be awarded within that period, the increment should be considered for cancellation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the information technology provided for in a contract for acquisition of information technology should be delivered within 18 months after the solicitation resulting in award of the contract was issued.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3737</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2309.</num>
<heading> Protection of constitutional rights of contractors</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition on Requiring Waiver of Rights</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A contractor may not be required, as a condition for entering into a contract with the Federal Government, to waive a right under the Constitution for a purpose relating to the Chemical Weapons Convention Implementation Act of 1998 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 6701</ref> et seq.) or the Chemical Weapons Convention (as defined in section 3 of that Act (<ref>22 U.S.C. 6701</ref>)).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Permissible Contract Clauses</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subsection (a) does not prohibit an executive agency from including in a contract a clause that requires the contractor to permit inspections to ensure that the contractor is performing the contract in accordance with the provisions of the contract.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3738</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2310.</num>
<heading> Performance-based contracts or task orders for services to be treated as contracts for the procurement of commercial items</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Criteria</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A performance-based contract for the procurement of services entered into by an executive agency or a performance-based task order for services issued by an executive agency may be treated as a contract for the procurement of commercial items if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the value of the contract or task order is estimated not to exceed $25,000,000;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the contract or task order sets forth specifically each task to be performed and, for each task—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> defines the task in measurable, mission-related terms;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> identifies the specific end products or output to be achieved; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> contains firm, fixed prices for specific tasks to be performed or outcomes to be achieved; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the source of the services provides similar services to the general public under terms and conditions similar to those offered to the Federal Government.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Regulations implementing this section shall require agencies to collect and maintain reliable data sufficient to identify the contracts or task orders treated as contracts for commercial items using the authority of this section. The data may be collected using the Federal Procurement Data System or other reporting mechanism.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 2 years after <date date="2003-11-24">November 24, 2003</date>, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall prepare and submit to the Committees on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committees on Oversight and Government Reform and on Armed Services of the House of Representatives a report on the contracts or task orders treated as contracts for commercial items using the authority of this section. The report shall include data on the use of the authority, both government-wide and for each department and agency.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Expiration</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The authority under this section expires 10 years after <date date="2003-11-24">November 24, 2003</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3738</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2311.</num>
<heading> Enhanced transparency on interagency contracting and other transactions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall direct appropriate revisions to the Federal Procurement Data System or any successor system to facilitate the collection of complete, timely, and reliable data on interagency contracting actions and on transactions other than contracts, grants, and cooperative agreements issued pursuant to <ref>section 4021 of title 10</ref> or similar authorities. The Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall ensure that data, consistent with what is collected for contract actions, is obtained on—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> interagency contracting actions, including data at the task or delivery-order level; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> other transactions, including the initial award and any subsequent modifications awarded or orders issued (other than transactions that are reported through the Federal Assistance Awards Data System).</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3739</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1702(h)(11)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2158</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2312.</num>
<heading> Contingency Contracting Corps</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “Corps” means the Contingency Contracting Corps established in subsection (b).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator of General Services, pursuant to policies established by the Office of Management and Budget, and in consultation with the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Homeland Security, shall establish a Government-wide Contingency Contracting Corps.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Function</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The members of the Corps shall be available for deployment in responding to an emergency or major disaster, or a contingency operation, both within or outside the continental United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Applicability</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The authorities provided in this section apply with respect to any procurement of property or services by or for an executive agency that, as determined by the head of the executive agency, are to be used—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in support of a contingency operation as defined in <ref>section 101(a)(13) of title 10</ref>; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to respond to an emergency or major disaster as defined in section 102 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 5122</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Membership</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Membership in the Corps shall be voluntary and open to all Federal employees and members of the Armed Forces who are members of the Federal acquisition workforce.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Education and Training</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator of General Services may, in consultation with the Director of the Federal Acquisition Institute and the Chief Acquisition Officers Council, establish educational and training requirements for members of the Corps. Education and training carried out pursuant to the requirements shall be paid for from funds available in the acquisition workforce training fund established pursuant to <ref>section 1703(i) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Salary</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The salary for a member of the Corps shall be paid—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in the case of a member of the Armed Forces, out of funds available to the Armed Force concerned; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in the case of a Federal employee, out of funds available to the employing agency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Authority to Deploy the Corps.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Director of the Office of Management and Budget</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall have the authority, upon request by an executive agency, to determine when members of the Corps shall be deployed, with the concurrence of the head of the agency or agencies employing the members to be deployed.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Secretary of Defense</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section shall preclude the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary’s designee from deploying members of the Armed Forces or civilian personnel of the Department of Defense in support of a contingency operation as defined in <ref>section 101(a)(13) of title 10</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Annual Report.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator of General Services shall provide to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives an annual report on the status of the Corps as of September 30 of each fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Content</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each report under paragraph (1) shall include the number of members of the Corps, the total cost of operating the program, the number of deployments of members of the program, and the performance of members of the program in deployment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3739</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2313.</num>
<heading> Database for Federal agency contract and grant officers and suspension and debarment officials</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to the authority, direction, and control of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, the Administrator of General Services shall establish and maintain a database of information regarding the integrity and performance of certain persons awarded Federal agency contracts and grants for use by Federal agency officials having authority over contracts and grants.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Persons Covered</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The database shall cover the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Any person awarded a Federal agency contract or grant in excess of $500,000, if any information described in subsection (c) exists with respect to the person.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any person awarded such other category or categories of Federal agency contract as the Federal Acquisition Regulation may provide, if any information described in subsection (c) exists with respect to the person.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Information Included</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>With respect to a covered person, the database shall include information (in the form of a brief description) for the most recent 5-year period regarding the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Each civil or criminal proceeding, or any administrative proceeding, in connection with the award or performance of a contract or grant with the Federal Government with respect to the person during the period to the extent that the proceeding results in the following dispositions:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> In a criminal proceeding, a conviction.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> In a civil proceeding, a finding of fault and liability that results in the payment of a monetary fine, penalty, reimbursement, restitution, or damages of $5,000 or more.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> In an administrative proceeding, a finding of fault and liability that results in—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the payment of a monetary fine or penalty of $5,000 or more; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the payment of a reimbursement, restitution, or damages in excess of $100,000.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> To the maximum extent practicable and consistent with applicable laws and regulations, in a criminal, civil, or administrative proceeding, a disposition of the matter by consent or compromise with an acknowledgment of fault by the person if the proceeding could have led to any of the outcomes specified in subparagraph (A), (B), or (C).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<chapeau> In an administrative proceeding—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a final determination of contractor fault by the Secretary of Defense pursuant to section 823(d) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2010 (<ref>10 U.S.C. 2302</ref> note; <ref>Public Law 111–84</ref>); or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a substantiated allegation, pursuant to section 1704(b) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2013, that the contractor, a subcontractor, or an agent of the contractor or subcontractor engaged in any of the activities described in section 106(g) of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 7104(g)</ref>).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Each Federal contract and grant awarded to the person that was terminated in the period due to default.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Each Federal suspension and debarment of the person.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Each Federal administrative agreement entered into by the person and the Federal Government in the period to resolve a suspension or debarment proceeding.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Each final finding by a Federal official in the period that the person has been determined not to be a responsible source under paragraph (3) or (4) of <ref>section 113 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Other information that shall be provided for purposes of this section in the Federal Acquisition Regulation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> To the maximum extent practicable, information similar to the information covered by paragraphs (1) to (4) in connection with the award or performance of a contract or grant with a State government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<chapeau> Whether the person is included on any of the following lists maintained by the Office of Foreign Assets Control of the Department of the Treasury:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The specially designated nationals and blocked persons list (commonly known as the “SDN list”).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The sectoral sanctions identification list.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The foreign sanctions evaders list.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The list of persons sanctioned under the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996 (<ref>Public Law 104–172</ref>; <ref>50 U.S.C. 1701</ref> note) that do not appear on the SDN list (commonly known as the “Non-SDN Iranian Sanctions Act list”).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The list of foreign financial institutions subject to part 561 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Requirements Relating to Database Information.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Direct input and update</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator of General Services shall design and maintain the database in a manner that allows the appropriate Federal agency officials to directly input and update information in the database relating to actions that the officials have taken with regard to contractors or grant recipients.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Timeliness and accuracy</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Administrator of General Services shall develop policies to require—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the timely and accurate input of information into the database;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the timely notification of any covered person when information relevant to the person is entered into the database; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> opportunities for any covered person to submit comments pertaining to information about the person for inclusion in the database.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Information on corporations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The information in the database on a person that is a corporation shall, to the extent practicable, include information on any parent, subsidiary, or successor entities to the corporation, and an identification of any beneficial owner of such corporation, in a manner designed to give the acquisition officials using the database a comprehensive understanding of the performance and integrity of the corporation in carrying out Federal contracts and grants.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this subsection:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Beneficial ownership</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “beneficial ownership” has the meaning given under section 847 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2020 (<ref>Public Law 116–92</ref>; <ref>133 Stat. 1505</ref>; <ref>10 U.S.C. 2509</ref> note).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Corporation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “corporation” means any corporation, company, limited liability company, limited partnership, business trust, business association, or other similar entity.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Use of Database.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Availability to government officials</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator of General Services shall ensure that the information in the database is available to appropriate acquisition officials of Federal agencies, other government officials as the Administrator of General Services determines appropriate, and, on request, the Chairman and Ranking Member of the committees of Congress having jurisdiction.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Review and assessment of data.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Before awarding a contract or grant in excess of the simplified acquisition threshold under <ref>section 134 of this title</ref>, the Federal agency official responsible for awarding the contract or grant shall review the database and consider all information in the database with regard to any offer or proposal, and in the case of a contract, shall consider other past performance information available with respect to the offeror in making any responsibility determination or past performance evaluation for the offeror.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Documentation in contract file</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The contract file for each contract of a Federal agency in excess of the simplified acquisition threshold shall document the manner in which the material in the database was considered in any responsibility determination or past performance evaluation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Disclosure in Applications</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Federal Acquisition Regulation shall require that persons with Federal agency contracts and grants valued in total greater than $10,000,000 shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> submit to the Administrator of General Services, in a manner determined appropriate by the Administrator of General Services, the information subject to inclusion in the database as listed in subsection (c) current as of the date of submittal of the information under this subsection; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> update the information submitted under paragraph (1) on a semiannual basis.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rulemaking</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator of General Services shall prescribe regulations that may be necessary to carry out this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3740</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–212, title III, § 3010</ref>, <date date="2010-07-29">July 29, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2340</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title VIII, § 834(d)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4279</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title VIII, § 852</ref>, title XVII, § 1704(d)(2), <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1856</ref>, 2096; <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title XII, § 1270</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3587</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title VIII, § 885</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3791</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>