<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 305—</num>
<heading>BLUE STAR MOTHERS OF AMERICA, INC.</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 30501.</num>
<heading> Definition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this chapter, “Armed Forces” includes the United States Army, United States Navy, United States Marines, United States Air Force, United States Coast Guard, National Guard, United States Army Reserves, United States Navy Reserves, United States Marine Reserves, United States Air Force Reserves, United States Coast Guard Reserves, United States Naval Militia, merchant marines, and armed home guards who have served on active duty.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1319</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 30502.</num>
<heading> Organization</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Federal Charter</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Blue Star Mothers of America, Inc. (in this chapter, the “corporation”), is a federally chartered corporation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Place of Incorporation and Domicile</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The corporation is declared to be incorporated and domiciled in the District of Columbia.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Perpetual Existence</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as otherwise provided, the corporation has perpetual existence.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1320</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 30503.</num>
<heading> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes of the corporation are patriotic, educational, social, and for service, and include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> perpetuating the Blue Star Mothers of America, Inc., and the memory of all the men and women who have served our country as members of the Armed Forces;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> maintaining true allegiance to the Government of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> educating members of the corporation and others not to divulge military, naval, or other Government information;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> assisting in veterans’ ceremonies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> attending patriotic rallies and meetings;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> fostering true democracy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> caring for unsupported mothers who gave their sons to the service of the Nation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> aiding in bringing about recognition of the need for permanent civilian defense in each community and the need to be always alert against invasion of un-American activities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> upholding the American institutions of freedom, justice, and equal rights; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> defending the United States from all enemies.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1320</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 30504.</num>
<heading> Membership</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">An individual is eligible for membership in the corporation if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> she is a mother (meaning a woman who filled the role of birthmother, adoptive mother, step-mother, foster-mother, grandmother, or legal guardian) of a person who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is serving in the Armed Forces; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> has served in, or has been honorably discharged from, the Armed Forces; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> she is living in the United States or is a citizen of the United States living outside the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1320</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–65, § 1</ref>, <date date="2011-12-13">Dec. 13, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 767</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 30505.</num>
<heading> Governing body</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">National Convention</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The national convention is the supreme governing authority of the corporation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The national convention is composed of officers and elected representatives from the States and other local subdivisions of the corporation as provided in the constitution and bylaws. However, the form of government of the corporation must be representative of the membership at large and may not permit concentration of control in a limited number of members or in a self-perpetuating group not representative of the membership at large.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The meetings of the national convention may be held in the District of Columbia or any State, territory, or possession of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Officers</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The officers of the corporation and their manner of selection, term of office, and duties are as provided in the constitution and bylaws of the corporation.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1320</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 30506.</num>
<heading> Powers</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The corporation may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> adopt and amend a constitution and bylaws for the management of its property and the regulation of its affairs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> adopt and alter a corporate seal;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> choose officers, managers, employees, and agents as the activities of the corporation require;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> make contracts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> acquire, own, lease, encumber, and transfer property as necessary or convenient to carry out the purposes of the corporation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> borrow money, issue instruments of indebtedness, and secure its obligations by granting security interests in its property;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> sue and be sued; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> do any other act necessary and proper to carry out the purposes of the corporation.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1321</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 30507.</num>
<heading> Exclusive right to name, seals, emblems, and badges</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The corporation and its subordinate divisions have the exclusive right to use the name “Blue Star Mothers of America, Inc.”. The corporation has the exclusive right to use, and to allow others to use, seals, emblems, and badges the corporation adopts.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1321</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 30508.</num>
<heading> Restrictions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Stock and Dividends</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The corporation may not issue stock or declare or pay a dividend.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Political Activities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The corporation or an officer or agent as such may not contribute to a political party or candidate for public office.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Distribution of Income or Assets</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The income or assets of the corporation may not inure to the benefit of, or be distributed to, an officer or member as such during the life of the corporation or on its dissolution or final liquidation. This subsection does not prevent the payment of compensation to an officer or reimbursement for actual necessary expenses in amounts approved by the council of administration of the corporation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Loans</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The corporation may not make a loan or advance to an officer or employee. Members of the council of administration who vote for or assent to making a loan or advance to an officer or employee, and officers who participate in making the loan or advance, are jointly and severally liable to the corporation for the amount of the loan or advance until it is repaid.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1321</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 30509.</num>
<heading> Principal office</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The principal office of the corporation shall be in the District of Columbia.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1321</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 30510.</num>
<heading> Records and inspection</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Records</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The corporation shall keep—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> correct and complete records of account; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> minutes of the proceedings of its national conventions and council of administration.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inspection</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A member, or an agent or attorney of the member, may inspect the records of the corporation for any proper purpose, at any reasonable time.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1321</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 30511.</num>
<heading> Service of process</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The corporation shall have a designated agent in the District of Columbia to receive service of process, notice, or demand for the corporation. Designation of the agent shall be filed in the office of the Mayor of the District of Columbia or another office designated by the Mayor. Notice to or service on the agent is notice to or service on the corporation.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1322</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 30512.</num>
<heading> Liability for acts of officers and agents</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The corporation is liable for the acts of its officers and agents acting within the scope of their authority.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1322</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 30513.</num>
<heading> Annual report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than March 1 of each year, the corporation shall submit a report to Congress on the activities of the corporation during the prior fiscal year. The report may consist of a report of the proceedings of the national convention. The report may not be printed as a public document.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1322</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 30514.</num>
<heading> Distribution of assets on dissolution or final liquidation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On dissolution or final liquidation of the corporation, any assets remaining after the discharge of all liabilities shall be distributed as provided by the national executive board, but in compliance with the constitution and bylaws of the corporation.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1322</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>