<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 1541—</num>
<heading>NAVAL SEA CADET CORPS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 154101.</num>
<heading> Organization</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Federal Charter</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Naval Sea Cadet Corps (in this chapter, the “corporation”) is a federally chartered corporation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Perpetual Existence</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as otherwise provided, the corporation has perpetual existence.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1432</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 154102.</num>
<heading> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes of the corporation are, through organization and cooperation with the Department of the Navy—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to encourage and aid American young people to develop an interest and skill in basic seamanship and in its naval adaptations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to train them in seagoing skills; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to teach them patriotism, courage, self-reliance, and kindred virtues.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1432</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 154103.</num>
<heading> Membership</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as provided in this chapter, eligibility for membership in the corporation and the rights, privileges, and designation of classes of members are as provided in the constitution and bylaws of the corporation.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1432</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 154104.</num>
<heading> Governing body</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Board of Directors</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The board of directors is the governing body of the corporation. The board is responsible for the general policies and program of the corporation and the control of all funds of the corporation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The number of directors, their manner of selection (including the filling of vacancies), and their term of office are as provided in the constitution and bylaws. However, the board shall have at least 10 but not more than 25 directors.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Officers</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The officers of the corporation are a president, one or more vice presidents as provided in the constitution and bylaws, a secretary, a treasurer, and other officers as provided in the constitution and bylaws.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The manner of election, term of office, and duties of the officers are as provided in the constitution and bylaws.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1432</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 154105.</num>
<heading> Powers</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The corporation may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> adopt and amend a constitution and bylaws for the management of its property and the regulation of its affairs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> adopt and alter a corporate seal;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> choose officers, managers, employees, and agents as the activities of the corporation require;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> make contracts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> acquire, own, lease, encumber, and transfer property as necessary or convenient to carry out the purposes of the corporation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> borrow money, issue instruments of indebtedness, and secure its obligations by granting security interests in its property; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> sue and be sued.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1432</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 154106.</num>
<heading> Exclusive right to name, insignia, emblems, badges, marks, and words</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The corporation has the exclusive right to use the name “Naval Sea Cadet Corps” and distinctive insignia, emblems, and badges, descriptive or designating marks, and words or phrases required to carry out the duties and powers of the corporation. This section does not affect any vested rights.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1433</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 154107.</num>
<heading> Restrictions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Stock and Dividends</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The corporation may not issue stock or declare or pay a dividend.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Political Activities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The corporation or a director or officer as such may not contribute to, support, or assist a political party or candidate for public office.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Distribution of Income or Assets</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The income or assets of the corporation may not inure to the benefit of, or be distributed to, a director, officer, or member during the life of the corporation or on its dissolution or final liquidation. This subsection does not prevent the payment of compensation to an officer in an amount approved by the board of directors.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Loans</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The corporation may not make a loan or advance to a director, officer, or employee. Directors who vote for or assent to making a loan or advance to a director, officer, or employee, and officers who participate in making the loan or advance, are jointly and severally liable to the corporation for the amount of the loan or advance until it is repaid.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1433</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 154108.</num>
<heading> Principal office</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The principal office of the corporation shall be in Tacoma, Washington, or another place decided by the board of directors. However, the activities of the corporation are not confined to the place where the principal office is located but may be conducted throughout the States, territories, and possessions of the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1433</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 154109.</num>
<heading> Records and inspection</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Records</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The corporation shall keep—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> correct and complete records of account;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> minutes of the proceedings of its members, board of directors, and committees having any of the authority of its board of directors; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> at its principal office, a record of the names and addresses of its members entitled to vote.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inspection</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A member entitled to vote, or an agent or attorney of the member, may inspect the records of the corporation for any proper purpose, at any reasonable time.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1433</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 154110.</num>
<heading> Service of process</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The corporation shall have a designated agent in the District of Columbia to receive service of process for the corporation. Notice to or service on the agent, or mailed to the business address of the agent, is notice to or service on the corporation.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1433</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 154111.</num>
<heading> Liability for acts of officers and agents</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The corporation is liable for the acts of its officers and agents acting within the scope of their authority.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1433</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 154112.</num>
<heading> Annual report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The corporation shall submit an annual report to the Secretary of the Navy on the activities of the corporation during the prior calendar year. The Secretary shall communicate to Congress any part of the report that the Secretary considers appropriate.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1434</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 154113.</num>
<heading> Distribution of assets on dissolution or final liquidation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On dissolution or final liquidation of the corporation, any assets remaining after the discharge of all liabilities shall be distributed as provided by the board of directors, but in compliance with the constitution and bylaws of the corporation.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1434</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>