<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 709—</num>
<heading>FUTURE FARMERS OF AMERICA</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 70901.</num>
<heading> Organization</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Federal Charter</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Future Farmers of America (in this chapter, the “FFA”) is a federally chartered corporation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Perpetual Existence</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as otherwise provided, the FFA has perpetual existence.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1356</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–7, § 2</ref>, <date date="2019-02-21">Feb. 21, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 478</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 70902.</num>
<heading> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes of the FFA are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to be an integral component of instruction in agricultural education, including instruction relating to agriculture, food, and natural resources;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to advance comprehensive agricultural education in the United States, including in public schools, by supporting contextual classroom and laboratory instruction and work-based experiential learning;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to prepare students for successful entry into productive careers in fields relating to agriculture, food, and natural resources, including by connecting students to relevant postsecondary educational pathways and focusing on the complete delivery of classroom and laboratory instruction, work-based experiential learning, and leadership development;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to be a resource and support organization that does not select, control, or supervise State association, local chapter, or individual member activities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to develop educational materials, programs, services, and events as a service to State and local agricultural education agencies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> to seek and promote inclusion and diversity in its membership, leadership, and staff to reflect the belief of the FFA in the value of all human beings;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> to create, foster, and assist subsidiary chapters) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002008">1</ref> and associations of those chapters in the States, territories, and possessions of the United States as such chapters and associations carry out agricultural education programs that are approved by States, territories, or possessions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> to build character,<sup>1</sup> and develop competent and assertive agricultural leadership;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> to increase awareness of the global and technological importance of agriculture, food, and natural resources, and the way agriculture contributes to our well-being;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> to promote the intelligent choice and establishment of a career in fields relating to agriculture, food, and natural resources;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> to make available to State associations, local chapters, and members all official supplies, programs, services, and equipment of the FFA;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> to cooperate with others, including State boards and officials for career and technical education, in accomplishing these purposes; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> to engage in other activities, consistent with these purposes, determined by the governing body to be for the best interests of the FFA.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1356</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–7, § 3</ref>, <date date="2019-02-21">Feb. 21, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 478</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 70903.</num>
<heading> Membership</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Eligibility</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in this chapter, eligibility for membership in the FFA and the rights and privileges of members are as provided in the constitution or bylaws of the FFA.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Voting</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In matters of official business of a local chapter, each member has one vote. In matters of official business of a State association, each qualified delegate of a local chapter has one vote.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1356</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–7, § 4</ref>, <date date="2019-02-21">Feb. 21, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 479</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 70904.</num>
<heading> Governing body</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Board of Directors</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The board of directors is the governing body of the FFA. The board shall exercise the powers granted to the FFA.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The board—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> shall consist of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Education, or the Secretary of Education’s designee who has experience in agricultural education, the FFA, or career and technical education; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> other individuals—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> representing the fields of education, agriculture, food, and natural resources; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> with experience working closely with the FFA; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> shall not include any individual who is a current employee of the National FFA Organization.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The number of directors, terms of office of the directors, and the method of selecting the directors, are as provided in the constitution or bylaws of the FFA.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The board shall meet at least annually at the time and place provided in the constitution or bylaws of the FFA. The annual report of the board shall be presented at that meeting. Special meetings of the board may be called at any time by the chair.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Officers</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The officers of the FFA, the terms of officers, and the election of officers, are as provided in the constitution or bylaws of the FFA, except that such officers shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a national advisor;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an executive secretary; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a treasurer.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Governing Committee.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The board may designate a governing committee. The terms and method of selecting the governing committee members are as provided in the constitution or bylaws of the FFA, except that all members of the governing committee shall be members of the board of directors and at all times the governing committee shall be comprised of not less than 3 individuals.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> When the board is not in session, the governing committee has the powers of the board subject to the board’s direction and may authorize the seal of the FFA to be affixed to all papers that require it.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The board shall designate to such committee—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the chair of the board;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the executive secretary of the board; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the treasurer of the board.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1357</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–7, § 5</ref>, <date date="2019-02-21">Feb. 21, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 479</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 70905.</num>
<heading> National officers</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Composition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There shall be not less than 6 national student officers of the FFA, including a student president, 4 student vice presidents (each representing regions as provided in the constitution or bylaws of the corporation), and a student secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Election</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The national officers of the corporation shall be elected annually by a majority vote of the delegates assembled in the annual national convention from among qualified members of the corporation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Vote at National Convention</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each qualified delegate has one vote at the annual national convention.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1357</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–7, § 6</ref>, <date date="2019-02-21">Feb. 21, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 480</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 70906.</num>
<heading> Powers</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The FFA may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> adopt and amend bylaws and regulations for the management of its property and the regulation of its affairs, including the establishment and maintenance of local chapters and State associations of chapters;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> adopt and alter a seal;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> adopt emblems and badges;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> choose officers, managers, agents, and employees as the activities of the FFA require;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> make contracts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> acquire, own, lease, encumber, and transfer property as necessary or convenient to carry out the purposes of the FFA;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> borrow money, issue instruments of indebtedness, and secure its obligations by granting security interests in its property;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> use FFA funds to give prizes, awards, loans, and grants to deserving members, local FFA chapters, and State FFA associations to carry out the purposes of the FFA;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> produce publications, websites, and other media;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> make available to State associations, local chapters, and members all official FFA supplies and equipment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> sue and be sued; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> do any other act necessary and proper to carry out the purposes of the FFA.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1357</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–7, § 7</ref>, <date date="2019-02-21">Feb. 21, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 481</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 70907.</num>
<heading> Exclusive right to name,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002009">1</ref> seals, emblems, and badges</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The FFA and its authorized chapters and associations of chapters have the exclusive right to use the names “Future Farmers of America” and “National FFA Organization,” <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002010">2</ref> and the initials FFA as representing an agricultural education membership organization and seals, emblems, and badges the FFA adopts.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1358</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–7, § 8</ref>, <date date="2019-02-21">Feb. 21, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 481</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 70908.</num>
<heading> Restrictions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Stock and Dividends</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The FFA may not issue stock or declare or pay a dividend.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Political Activities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The FFA or a director, officer, or member acting on behalf of the FFA may not contribute to, support, or assist a political party or candidate for elective public office.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Distribution of Income or Assets</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The income or assets of the FFA may not inure to the benefit of, or be distributed to, a director, officer, or member, except on dissolution or final liquidation of the FFA.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Loans</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The FFA may not make a loan to a director, officer, or employee. Directors who vote for or assent to making a loan to a director, officer, or employee, and officers who participate in making the loan, are jointly and severally liable to the corporation for the amount of the loan until it is repaid.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prizes, Awards, Grants, or Loans to Student Officers and Members Meeting Criteria</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section does not preclude prizes, awards, grants, or loans to student officers and members meeting the criteria established by the board of directors for selecting recipients of those benefits.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1358</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–7, § 9</ref>, <date date="2019-02-21">Feb. 21, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 481</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 70909.</num>
<heading> Relationship to Federal agencies</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>On request of the board of directors, the FFA may collaborate with Federal agencies, including the Department of Education and the Department of Agriculture on matters of mutual interest and benefit.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Agency Assistance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Those Federal agencies may make personnel, services, and facilities available to administer or assist in the administration of the activities of the FFA.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Agency Compensation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Personnel of the Federal agencies may not receive compensation from the FFA for their services, except that travel and other legitimate expenses as defined by the Federal agencies and approved by the board may be paid.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Cooperation With State Boards</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Federal agencies also may cooperate with State boards and other organizations for career and technical education to assist in the promotion of activities of the FFA.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1358</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–7, § 10</ref>, <date date="2019-02-21">Feb. 21, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 481</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 70910.</num>
<heading> Headquarters and principal office</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The headquarters and principal office of the FFA shall be as provided in the constitution or bylaws of the FFA. The activities of the FFA may be conducted throughout the States, territories, and possessions of the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1359</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–7, § 11</ref>, <date date="2019-02-21">Feb. 21, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 482</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 70911.</num>
<heading> Records and inspection</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Records</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The FFA shall keep—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> correct and complete records of account;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> minutes of the proceedings of its members, board of directors, and committees having any of the authority of its board of directors; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a record of the names and addresses of its members.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inspection</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A member, or an agent or attorney of the member, may inspect the records of the FFA at any reasonable time.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1359</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–7, § 12</ref>, <date date="2019-02-21">Feb. 21, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 482</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 70912.</num>
<heading> Service of process</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The FFA shall have a designated agent to receive service of process for the FFA..<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002011">1</ref> Notice to or service on the agent, or mailed to the business address of the agent, is notice to or service on the FFA.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">States, Territories, and Possessions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>As a condition to the exercise of any power or privilege granted by this chapter, the FFA shall file, with the Secretary of State or other designated official of each State, territory, or possession of the United States in which a subordinate association or chapter of the FFA is organized, the name and address of an agent in that State, territory, or possession on whom legal process or demands against the FFA may be served.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1359</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–284, § 5(7)</ref>, <date date="2006-09-27">Sept. 27, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1212</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–7, § 13</ref>, <date date="2019-02-21">Feb. 21, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 482</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 70913.</num>
<heading> Liability for acts of officers and agents</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The FFA is liable for the acts of its officers and agents acting within the scope of their authority.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1359</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–7, § 14</ref>, <date date="2019-02-21">Feb. 21, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 482</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 70914.</num>
<heading> Distribution of assets on dissolution or final liquidation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On dissolution or final liquidation of the FFA, any assets remaining after the discharge of all liabilities shall be used by the board of directors for the benefit of students of agricultural education or be transferred to a recognized educational foundation.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1359</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–7, § 15</ref>, <date date="2019-02-21">Feb. 21, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 482</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>