<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 205—</num>
<heading>AMERICAN CHEMICAL SOCIETY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 20501.</num>
<heading> Organization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">American Chemical Society (in this chapter, the “corporation”) is a federally chartered corporation.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1287</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20502.</num>
<heading> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes of the corporation are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to encourage in the broadest and most liberal manner the advancement of chemistry in all its branches;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to promote research in chemical science and industry;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to improve the qualifications and usefulness of chemists through high standards of professional ethics, education, and attainments;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to increase and diffuse chemical knowledge; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> by its meetings, professional contacts, reports, papers, discussions, and publications, to promote scientific interests and inquiry to foster public welfare and education, aid the development of our country’s industries, and add to the material prosperity and happiness of our people.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1287</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20503.</num>
<heading> Powers</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The corporation may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> adopt a constitution, bylaws, and regulations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> fill vacancies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> provide for the election of members and the division of those members into classes;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> receive property, hold the property absolutely or in trust, invest and manage the property, and use the property and income arising from it to carry out the purposes of the corporation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> do any other act necessary and proper to carry out the purposes of the corporation.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1287</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20504.</num>
<heading> Cooperation with the military</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Investigations, Examinations, Experiments, and Reports</inline>.—</heading>
<content>When requested by the Secretary of the Army, Air Force, or Navy, the corporation shall investigate, examine, experiment, and report on any subject in pure or applied chemistry connected with the national defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Payments</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The actual expense of those investigations, examinations, experiments, and reports shall be paid from amounts appropriated for those purposes, but the corporation may not receive compensation for any services performed for the United States Government.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Title and License</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Title to inventions and discoveries made in the course of those investigations, examinations, and experiments that the appropriate Secretary believes involve the national defense vest in the Government. The Government shall have unlimited license under other inventions and discoveries made in the course of those investigations, examinations, and experiments.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1288</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20505.</num>
<heading> Annual meeting</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The corporation shall hold an annual meeting at a place in the United States as may from time to time be designated.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1288</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20506.</num>
<heading> Annual report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than December 1 of each year, the corporation shall submit a report to Congress on the activities of the corporation during the prior calendar year, including a complete statement of its receipts and expenditures. The report may not be printed as a public document.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1288</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>