<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 2201—</num>
<heading>UNITED SERVICE ORGANIZATIONS, INCORPORATED</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 220101.</num>
<heading> Organization</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Federal Charter</inline>.—</heading>
<content>United Service Organizations, Incorporated (in this chapter, the “corporation”), is a federally chartered corporation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Perpetual Existence</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as otherwise provided, the corporation has perpetual existence.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1459</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 220102.</num>
<heading> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes of the corporation are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to provide a voluntary civilian agency through which the people of this Nation may, in peace or war, serve the religious, spiritual, social, welfare, educational, and entertainment needs of men and women in the Armed Forces, within or without the territorial limits of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to contribute to the maintenance of morale of men and women in the Armed Forces;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to solicit funds to maintain the organization and accomplish its responsibility;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to accept the cooperation of, and provide an organization and means through which, the National Board of Young Men’s Christian Associations, the National Board of Young Women’s Christian Associations, the National Catholic Community Service, the Salvation Army, the National Jewish Welfare Board, the Travelers Aid-International Social Service of America, and other civilian agencies experienced in specialized types of related work, which may be needed adequately to meet the particular needs of the members of the Armed Forces, may carry on their historic work of serving the religious, spiritual, social, welfare, educational, and entertainment needs of men and women in the Armed Forces and be afforded an appropriate means of participation and financial assistance;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to coordinate their programs; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> other consonant purposes.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1459</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 220103.</num>
<heading> Membership</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except as provided in this chapter, the rights, privileges, and designation of classes of members are as provided in the bylaws. The membership of the corporation consists of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> nine individuals designated by the President; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> representatives of the civilian organizations listed in <ref>section 220102(4) of this title</ref>, and of the public at large, as provided in the bylaws.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1459</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 220104.</num>
<heading> Governing body</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Board of Governors</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The board of governors is the governing body of the corporation. The board is responsible for the general policies and program of the corporation and for the control of the affairs and property of the corporation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The board shall be elected by the members of the corporation for the term and in the classes provided in the bylaws of the corporation. The board includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> six members appointed by the President;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary’s designee; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> representatives of the civilian organizations listed in <ref>section 220102(4) of this title</ref>, and of the public at large, as provided in the bylaws.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The corporation may have other governing bodies or committees as provided in the bylaws.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Officers</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The office of honorary chairman of the corporation shall be offered to the President. On acceptance, the honorary chairman shall be invited to preside at meetings of the corporation that the honorary chairman deems appropriate and convenient.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The corporation may have other officers as provided in the bylaws.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1460</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–284, § 5(11)</ref>, <date date="2006-09-27">Sept. 27, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1212</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 220105.</num>
<heading> Powers</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The corporation has all the powers necessary and proper to carry out the purposes stated in <ref>section 220102 of this title</ref>, including the power—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to adopt and amend bylaws and regulations for the management of its property and the regulation of its affairs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to adopt and alter a corporate seal;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to adopt and alter emblems and marks;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to establish and maintain offices to conduct the affairs of the corporation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to choose officers, representatives, and agents as the activities of the corporation require;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> to make contracts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> to acquire, own, lease, encumber, and transfer property as necessary or convenient to carry out the purposes of the corporation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> to borrow money, issue instruments of indebtedness, and secure its obligations by granting security interests in its property;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> to publish a magazine, newspaper, and other publications;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> to establish, regulate, and terminate councils, organizations, chapters, or affiliates as needed to carry out the purposes stated in <ref>section 220102 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> to solicit funds;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> to sue and be sued; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> to do any other act necessary and proper to carry out the purposes stated in <ref>section 220102 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1460</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 220106.</num>
<heading> Exclusive right to name, seals, emblems, and badges</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The corporation and its councils, organizations, chapters, and affiliates have the exclusive right to use the names “United Service Organizations, Incorporated” and “USO” and seals, emblems, and badges the corporation adopts.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1461</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 220107.</num>
<heading> Assistance by Department of Defense</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Defense may make the resources of the Department of Defense, including access to General Services Administration supplies and services through the Federal Supply Schedule of the General Services Administration, available to the corporation to the extent compatible with the primary mission of the Department and in accordance with guidelines issued by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1461</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title VIII, § 820</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2016</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 220108.</num>
<heading> Restrictions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Profit</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The corporation may not engage in business activity for profit unless the activity is substantially related to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the purposes stated in <ref>section 220102 of this title</ref>; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> raising funds to accomplish those purposes.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Stock and Dividends</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The corporation may not issue stock or declare or pay a dividend.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Political Activities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The corporation shall be nonpolitical and may not provide financial aid or assistance to, or otherwise promote the candidacy of, an individual seeking elective public office. A substantial part of the activities of the corporation may not involve carrying on propaganda or otherwise attempting to influence legislation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Distribution of Income or Assets</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The income or assets of the corporation may not inure to the benefit of a governor, officer, member, or employee or be distributed to any person during the life of the corporation or on its dissolution or final liquidation. This subsection does not prevent the payment of reasonable compensation to an officer, employee, or other person or reimbursement for actual necessary expenses in amounts approved by the board of governors.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Loans</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The corporation may not make a loan to a governor, officer, member, or employee.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1461</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 220109.</num>
<heading> Duty to maintain corporate status</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The corporation shall maintain its status as a corporation incorporated under the laws of New York, another State, or the District of Columbia.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1461</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 220110.</num>
<heading> Principal office</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The principal office of the corporation shall be in New York, New York, or another place decided by the board of governors. However, the activities of the corporation are not confined to the place where the principal office is located but may be conducted throughout the States, territories, and possessions of the United States and in foreign countries.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1461</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 220111.</num>
<heading> Records and inspection</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Records</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The corporation shall keep—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> correct and complete records of account;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> minutes of the proceedings of its members, board of governors, and committees having any of the authority of its board of governors; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> at its principal office, a record of the names and addresses of its members entitled to vote.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inspection</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A member, or an agent or attorney of the member, may inspect the records of the corporation for any proper purpose, at any reasonable time.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1461</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 220112.</num>
<heading> Service of process</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">District of Columbia</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The corporation shall have a designated agent in the District of Columbia to receive service of process for the corporation. Notice to or service on the agent, or mailed to the business address of the agent, is notice to or service on the corporation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">States, Territories, and Possessions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The corporation shall file, with the secretary of state or other designated official of each State, territory, or possession of the United States in which the corporation or a council, organization, chapter, or affiliate may have activities, the name and address of an agent in that State, territory, or possession on whom legal process or demands against the corporation may be served.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1462</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 220113.</num>
<heading> Annual report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The corporation shall make public an annual report on its activities for the prior calendar year.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1462</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 220114.</num>
<heading> Distribution of assets on dissolution or final liquidation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On dissolution or final liquidation of the corporation, any assets remaining after the discharge of all liabilities shall be distributed as provided by the board of governors, but in compliance with the bylaws. However, the assets of the corporation are irrevocably dedicated to charitable purposes and may not inure to the benefit of a private person except a fund, foundation, or organization operated exclusively for charitable purposes.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1462</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>