<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 803—</num>
<heading>GIRL SCOUTS OF THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 80301.</num>
<heading> Organization</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Federal Charter</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Girl Scouts of the United States of America (in this chapter, the “corporation”) is a body corporate and politic of the District of Columbia.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Domicile</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The domicile of the corporation is the District of Columbia.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Perpetual Existence</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as otherwise provided, the corporation has perpetual existence.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1361</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 80302.</num>
<heading> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes of the corporation are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to promote the qualities of truth, loyalty, helpfulness, friendliness, courtesy, purity, kindness, obedience, cheerfulness, thriftiness, and kindred virtues among girls, as a preparation for their responsibilities in the home and for service to the community;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to direct and coordinate the Girl Scout movement in the United States and territories and possessions of the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to fix and maintain standards for the movement that will inspire the rising generation with the highest ideals of character, patriotism, conduct, and attainment.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1361</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 80303.</num>
<heading> Governing body</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">National Council</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> There shall be a National Council of Girl Scouts. The number, qualifications, and term of office of members of the Council are as provided in the constitution of the corporation, except that members of the Council must be citizens of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Council may adopt and amend a constitution and bylaws and elect a board of directors, officers, and agents.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The constitution may prescribe the number of members of the Council necessary for a quorum. That number may be less than a majority of the entire Council.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Meetings of the Council shall be held as provided in the constitution to hold elections and receive reports of the officers and board of directors. Special meetings may be called as provided in the constitution.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Board of Directors</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> To the extent provided in the constitution and bylaws, the board of directors shall have the powers of the Council and manage the activities of the corporation between meetings of the Council. The number, qualifications, and term of office of directors are as provided in the constitution.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The constitution may prescribe the number of directors necessary for a quorum. That number shall be at least 20 or two-fifths of the entire board.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Executive and Other Committees</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The bylaws may provide for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an executive committee to carry out the powers of the board of directors between meetings of the board; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> other committees to operate under the general supervision of the board of directors.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Location of Meetings and Records</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Council and the board of directors may hold meetings and keep the seal and records of the corporation in or outside the District of Columbia.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1361</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 80304.</num>
<heading> Powers</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The corporation may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> adopt and amend a constitution, bylaws, and regulations, including regulations for the election of associates and successors;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> adopt and alter a seal;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> have offices and conduct its activities in the District of Columbia and in the States, territories, and possessions of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> acquire, own, lease, encumber, and transfer property, and use any income from the property, as necessary to carry out the purposes of the corporation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> sue and be sued within the jurisdiction of the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> do any other act necessary to carry out this chapter and the purposes of the corporation.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1362</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 80305.</num>
<heading> Exclusive right to emblems, badges, marks, and words</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The corporation has the exclusive right to use all emblems and badges, descriptive or designating marks, and words or phrases the corporation adopts, including the badge of the Girl Scouts, Incorporated, referred to in the Act of <date date="1937-08-12">August 12, 1937</date> (ch. 590, <ref>50 Stat. 623</ref>), and to authorize their use, during the life of the corporation, in connection with the manufacture, advertisement, and sale of equipment and merchandise. This section does not affect any vested rights.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1362</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 80306.</num>
<heading> Restrictions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Profit</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The corporation may not operate for profit.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Political Activities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The corporation shall be nonpolitical and nonsectarian.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1362</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 80307.</num>
<heading> Annual report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than April 1 of each year, the corporation shall submit a report to Congress on the activities of the corporation during the prior fiscal year. The report shall be printed each year, with accompanying illustrations, as a separate House document of the session of the Congress to which the report is submitted.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1362</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>