<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 5—</num>
<heading>PRESIDENTIAL INAUGURAL CEREMONIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 501.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “Inaugural Committee” means the committee appointed by the President-elect to be in charge of the Presidential inaugural ceremony and functions and activities connected with the ceremony; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> “inaugural period” means the period that includes the day on which the Presidential inaugural ceremony is held, the 5 calendar days immediately preceding that day, and the 4 calendar days immediately following that day.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1263</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 502.</num>
<heading> Regulations, licenses, and registration tags</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations and Licenses</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For each inaugural period, the Council of the District of Columbia shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> prescribe reasonable regulations necessary to preserve public order and protect life, health, and property;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> prescribe special regulations related to the standing, movement, and operation of vehicles; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> grant special licenses to peddlers and vendors to sell merchandise in places the Council considers proper, subject to conditions and fees for the licenses the Council considers proper.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Registration Tags</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Mayor of the District of Columbia may issue, for any motor vehicle made available for the use of the Inaugural Committee, special registration tags, valid for not more than 90 days, designed to celebrate the inauguration of the President and Vice President.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1264</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 503.</num>
<heading> Use of reservations, grounds, and public spaces</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Permit for Use</inline>.—</heading>
<content>With the approval of the officer having jurisdiction over any of the Federal reservations or grounds in the District of Columbia, the Secretary of the Interior may grant to the Inaugural Committee a permit to use the reservations or grounds during the inaugural period, including a reasonable time before and after the inaugural period. The Mayor of the District of Columbia may grant a similar permit to use public space under the Mayor’s jurisdiction. Each permit granted under this subsection is subject to conditions the grantor of the permit prescribes.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reviewing Stands and Commercial Stands and Structures</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A reviewing stand or a stand or structure for the sale of merchandise, food, or drink may be built on public grounds in the District of Columbia only if approved by the Inaugural Committee and by the Secretary or the Mayor, as appropriate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Restoration After Inaugural Period</inline>.—</heading>
<content>After the inaugural period, the reservation, ground, or public space occupied by a stand or structure shall be restored promptly to its prior condition.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Indemnification</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Inaugural Committee shall indemnify and save harmless the District of Columbia and the appropriate department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States Government against any loss or damage to, and against any liability arising from the use of, the reservation, ground, or public space, by the Inaugural Committee or a licensee of the Inaugural Committee.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1264</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 504.</num>
<heading> Installation and removal of electrical facilities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Installation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Mayor of the District of Columbia may allow the Inaugural Committee to install suitable overhead conductors and electrical facilities, with adequate supports. The official in charge of a park or reservation in the District of Columbia in which it is necessary to place wires shall supervise the placing and removal of those wires.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Removal</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The conductors and supports shall be removed not later than 5 days after the end of the inaugural period.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Indemnification</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The United States Government and the District of Columbia may not incur any expense or damage from the installation, operation, or removal of a temporary overhead conductor or electrical facility. The Inaugural Committee shall indemnify and hold harmless the District of Columbia and the appropriate department, agency, or instrumentality of the Government against any loss or damage, and against any liability arising, from any act of the Inaugural Committee or any agent, licensee, servant, or employee of the Inaugural Committee in connection with the installation, operation, or removal of a temporary overhead conductor or electrical facility.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1264</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 505.</num>
<heading> Extension of wires along parade routes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Mayor of the District of Columbia, the Secretary of the Interior, and the Inaugural Committee may allow communications companies to extend overhead wires to places along a parade route that are considered convenient for use in connection with the parade and other inaugural purposes. The wires shall be removed not later than 10 days after the inaugural period ends.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1265</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 506.</num>
<heading> Duration of regulations and licenses and publication of regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Regulations prescribed and licenses authorized under this chapter are effective only during the inaugural period. The regulations shall be published in at least one daily newspaper published in the District of Columbia. A penalty prescribed for violating such a regulation may not be enforced until 5 days after publication.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1265</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 507.</num>
<heading> Application to other property</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This chapter does not apply to the United States Capitol Buildings or Grounds or other property under the jurisdiction of Congress or a committee, commission, or officer of Congress. A service or facility authorized by or under this chapter is available for the property on request or approval of the joint committee of the Senate and House of Representatives appointed by the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives to arrange for the inauguration of the President-elect and the Vice President-elect.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1265</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 508.</num>
<heading> Enforcement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Mayor of the District of Columbia, or other official having jurisdiction in the premises, shall enforce this chapter, take necessary precautions to protect the public, and ensure that the pavement of any street, sidewalk, avenue, or alley disturbed or damaged is restored to its prior condition.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1265</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 509.</num>
<heading> Penalty</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A person violating a regulation prescribed under this chapter shall be fined under title 18 or imprisoned for not more than 30 days. A separate violation occurs under this section for each day the violation continues.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1265</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 510.</num>
<heading> Disclosure of and prohibition on certain donations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A committee shall not be considered to be the Inaugural Committee for purposes of this chapter unless the committee agrees to, and meets, the requirements of subsections (b) and (c).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Disclosure.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than the date that is 90 days after the date of the Presidential inaugural ceremony, the committee shall file a report with the Federal Election Commission disclosing any donation of money or anything of value made to the committee in an aggregate amount equal to or greater than $200.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contents of report</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A report filed under paragraph (1) shall contain—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the amount of the donation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the date the donation is received; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the name and address of the person making the donation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The committee shall not accept any donation from a foreign national (as defined in section 319(b) of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (<ref>2 U.S.C. 441e(b)</ref>)).<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002004">1</ref></content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 107–155, title III, § 308(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2002-03-27">Mar. 27, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 103</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 511.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authorization</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Necessary amounts are authorized to be appropriated—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> to enable the Mayor of the District of Columbia to provide additional municipal services in the District of Columbia during the inaugural period, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> employment of personal services without regard to chapters 33 and 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> travel expenses of enforcement personnel, including sanitarians, from other jurisdictions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the hiring of the means of transportation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> meals for policemen, firemen, and other municipal employees;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the cost of removing and relocating streetcar loading platforms, construction, rent, maintenance, and expenses incident to the operation of temporary public comfort stations, first-aid stations, and information booths; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> other incidental expenses in the discretion of the Mayor; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to enable the Secretary of the Interior to provide meals for the members of the United States Park Police during the inaugural period.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Payment</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Amounts appropriated under—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> subsection (a)(1) of this section are payable in the same way as other appropriations for the expenses of the District of Columbia; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> subsection (a)(2) of this section are payable in the same way as other appropriations for the expenses of the Department of the Interior.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1265</ref>, § 510; renumbered § 511, <ref>Pub. L. 107–155, title III, § 308(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-03-27">Mar. 27, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 103</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>