<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 1301—</num>
<heading>LADIES OF THE GRAND ARMY OF THE REPUBLIC</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 130101.</num>
<heading> Organization</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Federal Charter</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Ladies of the Grand Army of the Republic (in this chapter, the “corporation”) is a federally chartered corporation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Place of Incorporation and Domicile</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The corporation is declared to be incorporated and domiciled in the District of Columbia.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Perpetual Existence</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as otherwise provided, the corporation has perpetual existence.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1371</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 130102.</num>
<heading> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes of the corporation are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to perpetuate the memory of the Grand Army of the Republic and of the men who saved the Union in 1861 to 1865;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to assist in every practicable way in preserving, and making available for research, documents and records pertaining to the Grand Army of the Republic and its members;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to cooperate in doing honor to all those who have served our country patriotically in any way;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to teach patriotism, the duties of citizenship, the true history of our country, and the love and honor of our flag;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to oppose every tendency or movement that would weaken loyalty to, destroy, or impair our constitutional Union; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> to inculcate and broadly sustain the American principles of representative government, equal rights, and impartial justice for all.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1371</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 130103.</num>
<heading> Membership</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Eligibility</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in this chapter, eligibility for membership in the corporation and the rights, privileges, and designation of classes of members are as provided in the constitution and bylaws of the corporation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Eligibility for membership is limited to female blood relatives of an individual who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> served at any time during the period <date date="1861-04-12">April 12, 1861</date>, through <date date="1865-04-09">April 9, 1865</date>, as a soldier or sailor in—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the United States Army, Navy, Marine Corps, or Revenue-Cutter Service; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a State regiment that was called into active service and was subject to orders of United States general officers during that period; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> was honorably discharged from, or died in, that service.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Voting</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each member has one vote on each matter submitted to a vote at a meeting of the members.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1371</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 130104.</num>
<heading> Governing body</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">National Convention</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The national convention is the supreme governing authority of the corporation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The national convention is composed of officers and elected representatives from the States and other local subdivisions of the corporation as provided in the constitution and bylaws. However, the form of government of the corporation must be representative of the membership at large and may not permit concentration of control in a limited number of members or in a self-perpetuating group not representative of the membership at large.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The meetings of the national convention may be held in the District of Columbia or in any State, territory, or possession of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Officers</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The titles, manner of selection, term of office, and duties of the officers are as provided in the constitution and bylaws of the corporation.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1372</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 130105.</num>
<heading> Powers</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The corporation may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> adopt and amend a constitution and bylaws for the management of its property and the regulation of its affairs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> adopt and alter a corporate seal;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> choose officers, managers, agents, and employees as the activities of the corporation require;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> make contracts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> acquire, own, lease, encumber, and transfer property as necessary or convenient to carry out the purposes of the corporation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> borrow money, issue instruments of indebtedness, and secure its obligations by granting security interests in its property;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> sue and be sued; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> do any other act necessary and proper to carry out the purposes of the corporation.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1372</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 130106.</num>
<heading> Exclusive right to name, seals, emblems, and badges</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The corporation and its subordinate divisions have the exclusive right to use the name “Ladies of the Grand Army of the Republic”. The corporation has the exclusive right to use and to allow others to use seals, emblems, and badges the corporation adopts.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1372</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 130107.</num>
<heading> Restrictions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Stock and Dividends</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The corporation may not issue stock or declare or pay a dividend.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Political Activities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The corporation or an officer or agent as such may not contribute to a political party or candidate for public office.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Distribution of Income or Assets</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The income or assets of the corporation may not inure to the benefit of, or be distributed to, an officer or member during the life of the corporation or on its dissolution or final liquidation. This subsection does not prevent the payment of compensation to an officer or reimbursement for actual necessary expenses in amounts approved by the council of administration of the corporation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Loans</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The corporation may not make a loan or advance to an officer or employee. Members of the council of administration who vote for or assent to making a loan or advance to an officer or employee, and officers who participate in making the loan or advance, are jointly and severally liable to the corporation for the amount of the loan or advance until it is repaid.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1372</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 130108.</num>
<heading> Principal office</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The principal office of the corporation shall be in the District of Columbia or another place decided by the corporation. However, the activities of the corporation are not confined to the place where the principal office is located but may be conducted throughout the States, territories, and possessions of the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1373</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 130109.</num>
<heading> Records and inspection</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Records</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The corporation shall keep—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> correct and complete records of account; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> minutes of the proceedings of its national conventions and council of administration.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inspection</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A member, or an agent or attorney of the member, may inspect the records of the corporation for any proper purpose, at any reasonable time.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1373</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 130110.</num>
<heading> Service of process</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The corporation shall have a designated agent in the District of Columbia to receive service of process for the corporation. Notice to or service on the agent, or mailed to the business address of the agent, is notice to or service on the corporation.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1373</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 130111.</num>
<heading> Liability for acts of officers and agents</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The corporation is liable for the acts of its officers and agents acting within the scope of their authority.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1373</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 130112.</num>
<heading> Annual report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than March 1 of each year, the corporation shall submit a report to Congress on the activities of the corporation during the prior fiscal year. The report may consist of a report on the proceedings of the national convention. The report may not be printed as a public document.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1373</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 130113.</num>
<heading> Distribution of assets on dissolution or final liquidation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On dissolution or final liquidation of the corporation, any assets remaining after the discharge of all liabilities shall be distributed as provided by the council of administration, but in compliance with the constitution and bylaws of the corporation.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1373</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>