<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 3001—</num>
<heading>THE AMERICAN NATIONAL RED CROSS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 300101.</num>
<heading> Organization</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Federal Charter</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The American National Red Cross (in this chapter, the “corporation”) is a Federally chartered instrumentality of the United States and a body corporate and politic in the District of Columbia.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Name</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The name of the corporation is “The American National Red Cross”. The corporation may conduct its business and affairs, and otherwise hold itself out, as the “American Red Cross” in any jurisdiction.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Perpetual Existence</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as otherwise provided, the corporation has perpetual existence.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1490</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–26, § 3</ref>, <date date="2007-05-11">May 11, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 105</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 300102.</num>
<heading> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes of the corporation are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> to provide volunteer aid in time of war to the sick and wounded of the Armed Forces, in accordance with the spirit and conditions of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the conference of Geneva of October 1863;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the treaties of the Red Cross, or the treaties of Geneva, <date date="1864-08-22">August 22, 1864</date>, <date date="1929-07-27">July 27, 1929</date>, and <date date="1949-08-12">August 12, 1949</date>, to which the United States of America has given its adhesion; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any other treaty, convention, or protocol similar in purpose to which the United States of America has given or may give its adhesion;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in carrying out the purposes described in paragraph (1) of this section, to perform all the duties devolved on a national society by each nation that has acceded to any of those treaties, conventions, or protocols;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to act in matters of voluntary relief and in accordance with the military authorities as a medium of communication between the people of the United States and the Armed Forces of the United States and to act in those matters between similar national societies of governments of other countries through the International Committee of the Red Cross and the Government, the people, and the Armed Forces of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to carry out a system of national and international relief in time of peace, and to apply that system in mitigating the suffering caused by pestilence, famine, fire, floods, and other great national calamities, and to devise and carry out measures for preventing those calamities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to conduct other activities consistent with the foregoing purposes.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1490</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–26, § 4</ref>, <date date="2007-05-11">May 11, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 105</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 300103.</num>
<heading> Membership and chapters</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Membership</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Membership in the corporation is open to all the people of the United States and its territories and possessions, on payment of an amount specified, or as otherwise provided, in the bylaws.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Chapters</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The chapters of the corporation are the local units of the corporation. The corporation shall prescribe policies and regulations related to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> granting charters to the chapters and revoking those charters;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the territorial jurisdiction of the chapters;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the relationship of the chapters to the corporation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> compliance by the chapters with the policies and regulations of the corporation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The policies and regulations shall require that each chapter adhere to the democratic principles of election specified in the bylaws in electing the governing body of the chapter and selecting delegates to the annual meeting of the corporation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1491</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–26, § 5</ref>, <date date="2007-05-11">May 11, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 106</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 300104.</num>
<heading> Board of governors</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Board of Governors.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The board of governors is the governing body of the corporation with all powers of governing and directing, and of overseeing the management of the business and affairs of, the corporation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Number</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The board of governors shall fix by resolution, from time to time, the number of members constituting the entire board of governors, provided that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> as of <date date="2009-03-31">March 31, 2009</date>, and thereafter, there shall be no fewer than 12 and no more than 25 members; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> as of <date date="2012-03-31">March 31, 2012</date>, and thereafter, there shall be no fewer than 12 and no more than 20 members constituting the entire board.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">Procedures to implement the preceding sentence shall be provided in the bylaws.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appointment</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The governors shall be appointed or elected in the following manner:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Chairman.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The board of governors, in accordance with procedures provided in the bylaws, shall recommend to the President an individual to serve as chairman of the board of governors. If such recommendation is approved by the President, the President shall appoint such individual to serve as chairman of the board of governors.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Vacancies</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Vacancies in the office of the chairman, including vacancies resulting from the resignation, death, or removal by the President of the chairman, shall be filled in the same manner described in clause (i).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duties</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The chairman shall be a member of the board of governors and, when present, shall preside at meetings of the board of governors and shall have such other duties and responsibilities as may be provided in the bylaws or a resolution of the board of governors.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Other members.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Members of the board of governors other than the chairman shall be elected at the annual meeting of the corporation in accordance with such procedures as may be provided in the bylaws.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Vacancies</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Vacancies in any such elected board position and in any newly created board position may be filled by a vote of the remaining members of the board of governors in accordance with such procedures as may be provided in the bylaws.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Terms of Office.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term of office of each member of the board of governors shall be 3 years, except that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the board of governors may provide under the bylaws that the terms of office of members of the board of governors elected to the board of governors before <date date="2012-03-31">March 31, 2012</date>, may be less than 3 years in order to implement the provisions of subparagraphs (A) and (B) of subsection (a)(2); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any member of the board of governors elected by the board to fill a vacancy in a board position arising before the expiration of its term may, as determined by the board, serve for the remainder of that term or until the next annual meeting of the corporation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Staggered terms</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The terms of office of members of the board of governors (other than the chairman) shall be staggered such that, by <date date="2012-03-31">March 31, 2012</date>, and thereafter, ⅓ of the entire board (or as near to ⅓ as practicable) shall be elected at each successive annual meeting of the corporation with the term of office of each member of the board of governors elected at an annual meeting expiring at the third annual meeting following the annual meeting at which such member was elected.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Term limits</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No person may serve as a member of the board of governors for more than such number of terms of office or years as may be provided in the bylaws.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Committees and Officers</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The board—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> may appoint, from its own members, an executive committee to exercise such powers of the board when the board is not in session as may be provided in the bylaws;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> may appoint such other committees or advisory councils with such powers as may be provided in the bylaws or a resolution of the board of governors;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> shall appoint such officers of the corporation, including a chief executive officer, with such duties, responsibilities, and terms of office as may be provided in the bylaws or a resolution of the board of governors; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> may remove members of the board of governors (other than the chairman), officers, and employees under such procedures as may be provided in the bylaws or a resolution of the board of governors.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Advisory Council.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There shall be an advisory council to the board of governors.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Membership; appointment by president.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The advisory council shall be composed of no fewer than 8 and no more than 10 members, each of whom shall be appointed by the President from principal officers of the executive departments and senior officers of the Armed Forces whose positions and interests qualify them to contribute to carrying out the programs and purposes of the corporation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Members from the armed forces</inline>.—</heading>
<content>At least 1, but not more than 3, of the members of the advisory council shall be selected from the Armed Forces.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duties</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The advisory council shall advise, report directly to, and meet, at least 1 time per year with the board of governors, and shall have such name, functions and be subject to such procedures as may be provided in the bylaws.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Action Without Meeting</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any action required or permitted to be taken at any meeting of the board of governors or of any committee thereof may be taken without a meeting if all members of the board or committee, as the case may be, consent thereto in writing, or by electronic transmission and the writing or writings or electronic transmission or transmissions are filed with the minutes of proceedings of the board or committee. Such filing shall be in paper form if the minutes are maintained in paper form and shall be in electronic form if the minutes are maintained in electronic form.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Voting by Proxy.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Voting by proxy is not allowed at any meeting of the board, at the annual meeting, or at any meeting of a chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The board may allow the election of governors by proxy during any emergency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Bylaws.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The board of governors may—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> at any time adopt bylaws; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> at any time adopt bylaws to be effective only in an emergency.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Emergency bylaws</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any bylaws adopted pursuant to paragraph (1)(B) may provide special procedures necessary for managing the corporation during the emergency. All provisions of the regular bylaws consistent with the emergency bylaws remain effective during the emergency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “entire board” means the total number of members of the board of governors that the corporation would have if there were no vacancies; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “emergency” shall have such meaning as may be provided in the bylaws.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1491</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–26, § 6</ref>, <date date="2007-05-11">May 11, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 106</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 300105.</num>
<heading> Powers</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The corporation may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> adopt policies and regulations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> adopt, alter, and destroy a seal;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> own and dispose of property to carry out the purposes of the corporation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> accept gifts, devises, and bequests of property to carry out the purposes of the corporation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> sue and be sued in courts of law and equity, State or Federal, within the jurisdiction of the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> do any other act necessary to carry out this chapter and promote the purposes of the corporation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The corporation is designated as the organization authorized to act in matters of relief under the treaties of Geneva, <date date="1864-08-22">August 22, 1864</date>, <date date="1929-07-27">July 27, 1929</date>, and <date date="1949-08-12">August 12, 1949</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1492</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–26, § 7</ref>, <date date="2007-05-11">May 11, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 108</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 300106.</num>
<heading> Emblem, badge, and brassard</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Emblem and Badge</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In carrying out its purposes under this chapter, the corporation may have and use, as an emblem and badge, a Greek red cross on a white ground, as described in the treaties of Geneva, <date date="1864-08-22">August 22, 1864</date>, <date date="1929-07-27">July 27, 1929</date>, and <date date="1949-08-12">August 12, 1949</date>, and adopted by the nations acceding to those treaties.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Delivery of Brassard</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In accordance with those treaties, the delivery of the brassard allowed for individuals neutralized in time of war shall be left to military authority.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1492</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 300107.</num>
<heading> Annual meeting</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The annual meeting of the corporation is the annual meeting of delegates of the chapters.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Time of Meeting</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The annual meeting shall be held as determined by the board of governors.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Place of Meeting</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The board of governors is authorized to determine that the annual meeting shall not be held at any place, but may instead be held solely by means of remote communication subject to such procedures as are provided in the bylaws.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Voting.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In matters requiring a vote at the annual meeting, each chapter is entitled to at least 1 vote, and voting on all matters may be conducted by mail, telephone, telegram, cablegram, electronic mail, or any other means of electronic or telephone transmission, provided that the person voting shall state, or submit information from which it can be determined, that the method of voting chosen was authorized by such person.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Establishment of number of votes.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The board of governors shall determine on an equitable basis the number of votes that each chapter is entitled to cast, taking into consideration the size of the membership of the chapters, the populations served by the chapters, and such other factors as may be determined by the board.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Periodic review</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The board of governors shall review the allocation of votes at least every 5 years.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1493</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–26, § 8</ref>, <date date="2007-05-11">May 11, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 108</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 300108.</num>
<heading> Buildings</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Ownership</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The United States Government shall retain ownership of the corporation’s permanent headquarters, comprised of buildings erected on square 172 in the District of Columbia, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the memorial building to commemorate the service and sacrifice of the women of the United States, North and South, during the Civil War, erected for the use of the corporation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the memorial building to commemorate the service and sacrifice of the patriotic women of the United States, its territories and possessions, and the District of Columbia during World War I, erected for the use of the corporation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the permanent building erected for the use of the corporation in connection with its work in cooperation with the Government.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Maintenance and Expenses</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Those buildings shall remain under the supervision of the Administrator of General Services. However, the corporation shall care for and maintain the buildings without expense to the Government.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1493</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 300109.</num>
<heading> Endowment fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The endowment fund of the corporation shall be kept and invested under the management and control of a board of trustees elected by the board of governors. The corporation shall prescribe policies and regulations on terms and tenure of office, accountability, and expenses of the board of trustees.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1493</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–26, § 9</ref>, <date date="2007-05-11">May 11, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 109</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 300110.</num>
<heading> Annual report and audit</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Submission of Report</inline>.—</heading>
<content>As soon as practicable after the end of the corporation’s fiscal year, which may be changed from time to time by the board of governors, the corporation shall submit a report to the Secretary of Defense on the activities of the corporation during such fiscal year, including a complete, itemized report of all receipts and expenditures.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Auditing of Report and Submission to Congress</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall audit the report and submit a copy of the audited report to Congress.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Payment of Audit Expenses</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The corporation shall reimburse the Secretary each year for auditing its accounts. The amount paid shall be deposited in the Treasury of the United States as a miscellaneous receipt.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1493</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–26, § 10</ref>, <date date="2007-05-11">May 11, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 109</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 300111.</num>
<heading> Authority of the Comptroller General of the United States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Comptroller General of the United States is authorized to review the corporation’s involvement in any Federal program or activity the Government carries out under law.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–26, § 11(a)</ref>, <date date="2007-05-11">May 11, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 109</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 300112.</num>
<heading> Office of the Ombudsman</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The corporation shall establish an Office of the Ombudsman with such duties and responsibilities as may be provided in the bylaws or a resolution of the board of governors.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Report.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Office of the Ombudsman shall submit annually to the appropriate Congressional committees a report concerning any trends and systemic matters that the Office of the Ombudsman has identified as confronting the corporation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appropriate congressional committees</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For purposes of paragraph (1), the appropriate Congressional committees are the following committees of Congress:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Senate committees</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The appropriate Congressional committees of the Senate are—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Committee on Finance;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the Committee on Foreign Relations;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> the Committee on the Judiciary.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">House committees</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The appropriate Congressional committees of the House of Representatives are—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Committee on Energy and Commerce;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the Committee on Foreign Affairs;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the Committee on Homeland Security;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the Committee on the Judiciary; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> the Committee on Ways and Means.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–26, § 11(a)</ref>, <date date="2007-05-11">May 11, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 110</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 300113.</num>
<heading> Reservation of right to amend or repeal</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Congress reserves the right to amend or repeal the provisions of this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1494</ref>, § 300111; renumbered § 300113, <ref>Pub. L. 110–26, § 11(a)</ref>, <date date="2007-05-11">May 11, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 109</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>