<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 309—</num>
<heading>BOY SCOUTS OF AMERICA</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 30901.</num>
<heading> Organization</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Federal Charter</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Boy Scouts of America (in this chapter, the “corporation”) is a body corporate and politic of the District of Columbia.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Domicile</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The domicile of the corporation is the District of Columbia.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Perpetual Existence</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as otherwise provided, the corporation has perpetual existence.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1325</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 30902.</num>
<heading> Purposes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The purposes of the corporation are to promote, through organization, and cooperation with other agencies, the ability of boys to do things for themselves and others, to train them in scoutcraft, and to teach them patriotism, courage, self-reliance, and kindred virtues, using the methods that were in common use by boy scouts on <date date="1916-06-15">June 15, 1916</date>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1325</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 30903.</num>
<heading> Governing body</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Executive Board</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An executive board composed of citizens of the United States is the governing body of the corporation. The number, qualifications, and term of office of members of the board are as provided in the bylaws. A vacancy on the board shall be filled by a majority vote of the remaining members of the board.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Quorum</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The bylaws may prescribe the number of members of the board necessary for a quorum. That number may be less than a majority of the entire board.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Committees</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The board, by resolution passed by a majority of the entire board, may designate 3 or more members of the board as an executive or governing committee. A majority of the committee is a quorum. The committee, to the extent provided in the resolution or bylaws, may—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> exercise the powers of the executive board in managing the activities of the corporation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> authorize the seal of the corporation to be affixed to papers that may require it.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The board, by majority vote of the entire board, may appoint other standing committees. The standing committees may exercise powers as provided in the bylaws.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1325</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 30904.</num>
<heading> Powers</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The corporation may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> adopt and amend bylaws and regulations, including regulations for the election of associates and successors;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> adopt and alter a corporate seal;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> have offices and conduct its activities in the District of Columbia and the States, territories, and possessions of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> acquire and own property as necessary to carry out the purposes of the corporation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> sue and be sued within the jurisdiction of the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> do any other act necessary to carry out this chapter and promote the purpose of the corporation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitations on Exercising Certain Powers</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The corporation may execute mortgages and liens on the property of the corporation only if approved by a two-thirds vote of the entire executive board at a meeting called for that purpose.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The corporation may dispose in any manner of the whole property of the corporation only with the written consent and affirmative vote of a majority of the members of the corporation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1325</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 30905.</num>
<heading> Exclusive right to emblems, badges, marks, and words</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The corporation has the exclusive right to use emblems, badges, descriptive or designating marks, and words or phrases the corporation adopts. This section does not affect any vested rights.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1326</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 30906.</num>
<heading> Restrictions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Profit</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The corporation may not operate for pecuniary profit to its members.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Stocks and Dividends</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The corporation may not issue stock or declare or pay a dividend.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1326</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 30907.</num>
<heading> Annual and special meetings</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Meetings</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The corporation shall hold an annual meeting at a time and place as provided in the bylaws. At the meeting, the annual reports of the officers and executive board shall be presented, and members of the board shall be elected for the next year.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Special Meetings</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Special meetings of the corporation may be called on notice as provided in the bylaws.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Quorum</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The number of members necessary for a quorum at an annual or special meeting shall be prescribed in the bylaws.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Locations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The members and the executive board may hold meetings and keep the seal and records of the corporation in or outside the District of Columbia.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1326</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 30908.</num>
<heading> Annual report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than April 1 of each year, the corporation shall submit a report to Congress on the activities of the corporation during the prior calendar year.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1326</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>