<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 25—</num>
<heading>PRESIDENT’S COMMITTEE ON EMPLOYMENT OF PEOPLE WITH DISABILITIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2501.</num>
<heading> Acceptance of voluntary services and money or property</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President’s Committee on Employment of People With Disabilities—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> notwithstanding <ref>section 1342 of title 31</ref>, may accept voluntary and uncompensated services; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> may solicit, accept, use, and dispose of any money or property the Committee receives.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1280</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–354, § 1(3)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-03">Nov. 3, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3239</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2502.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Amounts necessary for the work of the President’s Committee on Employment of People With Disabilities are authorized to be appropriated for the fiscal year ending <date date="1997-09-30">September 30, 1997</date>, to be expended in the manner and by agencies the President may direct.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Uses</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Amounts appropriated under this section are to be used to carry out the purposes of the National Disability Employment Awareness Month and to enable the President to provide the Committee with adequate personnel to assist in its activities, and otherwise to provide the Committee with the means of carrying out a program to promote the employment of individuals with disabilities, by—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> creating interest throughout the United States in the rehabilitation and employment of such individuals; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> obtaining and maintaining cooperation from all public and private groups in the field.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1280</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>