<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 1303—</num>
<heading>LEGION OF VALOR OF THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA, INCORPORATED</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 130301.</num>
<heading> Organization</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Federal Charter</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Legion of Valor of the United States of America, Incorporated (in this chapter, the “corporation”), is a federally chartered corporation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Place of Incorporation and Domicile</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The corporation is declared to be incorporated and domiciled in the District of Columbia.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Perpetual Existence</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as otherwise provided, the corporation has perpetual existence.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">References to Army and Navy Legion of Valor of the United States of America, Incorporated</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any reference to the Army and Navy Legion of Valor of the United States of America, Incorporated, is deemed to refer to the Legion of Valor of the United States of America, Incorporated.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1374</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 130302.</num>
<heading> Principles and purposes</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Principles</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The principles underlying the corporation are patriotic allegiance to the United States of America, fidelity to the constitution and laws of the United States, the security of civil liberty, and the permanence of free institutions.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Purposes</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The purposes of the corporation are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to cherish the memories of the valiant deeds in arms for which the Congressional Medal of Honor, the Distinguished Service Cross, the Navy Cross, and the Air Force Cross are the insignia;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to promote true fellowship among its members;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to advance the best interests of members of the Armed Forces of the United States of America;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to extend all possible relief to needy members of the corporation and their widows and children; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to stimulate patriotism in the minds of our youth by encouraging the study of the patriotic, military, and naval history of our Nation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1374</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 130303.</num>
<heading> Membership</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Eligibility</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An individual is eligible for active membership in the corporation if the individual—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> is of good moral character; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> has received a Congressional Medal of Honor, a Distinguished Service Cross, a Navy Cross, or an Air Force Cross awarded for acts of extraordinary heroism in connection with military or naval operations against an armed enemy, or for heroism of a specially distinguished character, as a member of the Armed Forces of the United States or any foreign country.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Extension of Eligibility to Parents and Descendants</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The corporation may extend eligibility for membership, either active or associate, to parents and lineal descendants of an individual described in subsection (a) of this section on terms provided in its constitution and bylaws.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Voting</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each member (except an associate member) has one vote on each matter submitted to a vote at a meeting of the members.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1374</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 130304.</num>
<heading> Governing body</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Board of Directors</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The board of directors is the governing body of the corporation. Between meetings of the corporation, the board is responsible for the general policies and program of the corporation. The board is responsible for all funds of the corporation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The number of directors, their manner of selection (including the filling of vacancies), and their term of office are as provided in the constitution and bylaws of the corporation. However, the board shall have at least 10 directors.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Officers</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The officers of the corporation are a commander, a senior vice commander, a junior vice commander, a chaplain, an adjutant and quartermaster, a judge advocate, an inspector, a surgeon, a historian, and any aides-de-camp provided in the constitution and bylaws.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The manner of election, term of office, and duties of the officers are as provided in the constitution and bylaws.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1375</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 130305.</num>
<heading> Powers</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The corporation may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> adopt and amend a constitution and bylaws for the management of its property and the regulation of its affairs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> adopt and alter a corporate seal;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> make contracts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> acquire, own, lease, encumber, and transfer property as necessary or convenient to carry out the purposes of the corporation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> borrow money, issue instruments of indebtedness, and secure its obligations by granting security interests in its property;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> charge and collect membership dues; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> sue and be sued.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1375</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 130306.</num>
<heading> Restrictions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Stock and Dividends</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The corporation may not issue stock or declare or pay a dividend.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Political Activities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The corporation or a director or officer as such may not contribute to, support, or assist a political party or candidate for public office.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Distribution of Income or Assets</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The income or assets of the corporation may not inure to the benefit of, or be distributed to, a director, officer, or member except on dissolution or final liquidation of the corporation. This subsection does not prevent the payment of compensation to an officer in an amount approved by the executive committee of the corporation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Loans</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The corporation may not make a loan to a director, officer, or employee. Directors who vote for or assent to making a loan to a director, officer, or employee, and officers who participate in making the loan, are jointly and severally liable to the corporation for the amount of the loan until it is repaid.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1375</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 130307.</num>
<heading> Principal office</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The principal office of the corporation shall be in a place decided by the board of directors. However, the activities of the corporation are not confined to the place where the principal office is located but may be conducted throughout the States, territories, and possessions of the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1376</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 130308.</num>
<heading> Records and inspection</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Records</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The corporation shall keep—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> correct and complete records of account;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> minutes of the proceedings of its members, board of directors, and committees having any of the authority of its board of directors; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> at its principal office, a record of the names and addresses of its members entitled to vote.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inspection</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A member entitled to vote, or an agent or attorney of the member, may inspect the records of the corporation for any proper purpose, at any reasonable time.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1376</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 130309.</num>
<heading> Service of process</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The corporation shall have a designated agent in the District of Columbia to receive service of process for the corporation. Notice to or service on the agent, or mailed to the business address of the agent, is notice to or service on the corporation.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1376</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 130310.</num>
<heading> Liability for acts of officers and agents</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The corporation is liable for the acts of its officers and agents acting within the scope of their authority.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1376</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 130311.</num>
<heading> Distribution of assets on dissolution or final liquidation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On dissolution or final liquidation of the corporation, any assets remaining after the discharge of all liabilities shall be distributed as provided by the board of directors, but in compliance with the constitution and bylaws of the corporation.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1376</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>