<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 1—</num>
<heading>PATRIOTIC AND NATIONAL OBSERVANCES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 101.</num>
<heading> American Heart Month</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President is requested to issue each year a proclamation—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> designating February as American Heart Month;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> inviting the chief executive officers of the States, territories, and possessions of the United States to issue proclamations designating February as American Heart Month; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> urging the people of the United States to recognize the nationwide problem of heart and blood vessel diseases and to support all essential programs required to solve the problem.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1254</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 102.</num>
<heading> Asian/Pacific American Heritage Month</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>May is Asian/Pacific American Heritage Month.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Proclamations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The President is requested to issue each year a proclamation calling on the people of the United States, and the chief executive officers of each State of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Virgin Islands, Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the Northern Mariana Islands, the Marshall Islands, Micronesia, and Palau are requested to issue each year proclamations calling on the people of their respective jurisdictions, to observe Asian/Pacific American Heritage Month with appropriate programs, ceremonies, and activities.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1254</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 103.</num>
<heading> Cancer Control Month</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The President is requested—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to issue each year a proclamation designating April as Cancer Control Month; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to invite each year the chief executive officers of the States, territories, and possessions of the United States to issue proclamations designating April as Cancer Control Month.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contents of Proclamations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>As part of those proclamations, the chief executive officers and President are requested to invite the medical profession, the press, and all agencies and individuals interested in a national program for the control of cancer by education and other cooperative means to unite during Cancer Control Month in a public dedication to the program and in a concerted effort to make the people of the United States aware of the need for the program.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1255</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 104.</num>
<heading> Carl Garner Federal Lands Cleanup Day</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The first Saturday after Labor Day is Carl Garner Federal Lands Cleanup Day.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Proclamation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The President shall issue a proclamation calling on the people of the United States to observe Carl Garner Federal Lands Cleanup Day with appropriate programs, ceremonies, and activities. However, activities may be undertaken in individual States on a day other than the first Saturday after Labor Day if a manager of Federal land decides that an alternative date is more appropriate because of climatological or other factors.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1255</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 105.</num>
<heading> Child Health Day</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President is requested to issue each year a proclamation—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> designating the first Monday in October as Child Health Day; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> inviting all agencies and organizations interested in child welfare to unite on Child Health Day in observing exercises that will make the people of the United States aware of the fundamental necessity of a year-round program to protect and develop the health of the children of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1255</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 106.</num>
<heading> Constitution Day and Citizenship Day</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>September 17 is designated as Constitution Day and Citizenship Day.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Purpose</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Constitution Day and Citizenship Day commemorate the formation and signing on <date date="1787-09-17">September 17, 1787</date>, of the Constitution and recognize all who, by coming of age or by naturalization, have become citizens.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Proclamation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The President may issue each year a proclamation calling on United States Government officials to display the flag of the United States on all Government buildings on Constitution Day and Citizenship Day and inviting the people of the United States to observe Constitution Day and Citizenship Day, in schools and churches, or other suitable places, with appropriate ceremonies.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">State and Local Observances</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The civil and educational authorities of States, counties, cities, and towns are urged to make plans for the proper observance of Constitution Day and Citizenship Day and for the complete instruction of citizens in their responsibilities and opportunities as citizens of the United States and of the State and locality in which they reside.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1255</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–447, div. J, title I, § 111(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2004-12-08">Dec. 8, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3344</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 107.</num>
<heading> Columbus Day</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President is requested to issue each year a proclamation—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> designating the second Monday in October as Columbus Day;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> calling on United States Government officials to display the flag of the United States on all Government buildings on Columbus Day; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> inviting the people of the United States to observe Columbus Day, in schools and churches, or other suitable places, with appropriate ceremonies that express the public sentiment befitting the anniversary of the discovery of America.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1256</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 108.</num>
<heading> Constitution Week</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President is requested to issue each year a proclamation—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> designating September 17 through September 23 as Constitution Week; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> inviting the people of the United States to observe Constitution Week, in schools, churches, and other suitable places, with appropriate ceremonies and activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1256</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 109.</num>
<heading> Father’s Day</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The third Sunday in June is Father’s Day.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Proclamation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The President is requested to issue a proclamation—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> calling on United States Government officials to display the flag of the United States on all Government buildings on Father’s Day;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> inviting State and local governments and the people of the United States to observe Father’s Day with appropriate ceremonies; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> urging the people of the United States to offer public and private expressions of Father’s Day to the abiding love and gratitude they have for their fathers.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1256</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 110.</num>
<heading> Flag Day</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>June 14 is Flag Day.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Proclamation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The President is requested to issue each year a proclamation—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> calling on United States Government officials to display the flag of the United States on all Government buildings on Flag Day; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> urging the people of the United States to observe Flag Day as the anniversary of the adoption on <date date="1777-06-14">June 14, 1777</date>, by the Continental Congress of the Stars and Stripes as the official flag of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1256</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 111.</num>
<heading> Gold Star Mother’s Day</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The last Sunday in September is Gold Star Mother’s Day.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Proclamation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The President is requested to issue a proclamation calling on United States Government officials to display the flag of the United States on all Government buildings, and the people of the United States to display the flag and hold appropriate meetings at homes, churches, or other suitable places, on Gold Star Mother’s Day as a public expression of the love, sorrow, and reverence of the people for Gold Star Mothers.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1256</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 112.</num>
<heading> Honor America Days</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The 21 days from Flag Day through Independence Day is a period to honor America.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Congressional Declaration</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Congress declares that there be public gatherings and activities during that period at which the people of the United States can celebrate and honor their country in an appropriate way.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1257</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 113.</num>
<heading> Law Day, U.S.A.</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>May 1 is Law Day, U.S.A.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Purpose</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Law Day, U.S.A., is a special day of celebration by the people of the United States—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in appreciation of their liberties and the reaffirmation of their loyalty to the United States and of their rededication to the ideals of equality and justice under law in their relations with each other and with other countries; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> for the cultivation of the respect for law that is so vital to the democratic way of life.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Proclamation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The President is requested to issue a proclamation—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> calling on all public officials to display the flag of the United States on all Government buildings on Law Day, U.S.A.; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> inviting the people of the United States to observe Law Day, U.S.A., with appropriate ceremonies and in other appropriate ways, through public entities and private organizations and in schools and other suitable places.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1257</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 114.</num>
<heading> Leif Erikson Day</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President may issue each year a proclamation designating October 9 as Leif Erikson Day.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1257</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 115.</num>
<heading> Loyalty Day</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>May 1 is Loyalty Day.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Purpose</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Loyalty Day is a special day for the reaffirmation of loyalty to the United States and for the recognition of the heritage of American freedom.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Proclamation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The President is requested to issue a proclamation—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> calling on United States Government officials to display the flag of the United States on all Government buildings on Loyalty Day; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> inviting the people of the United States to observe Loyalty Day with appropriate ceremonies in schools and other suitable places.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1257</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 116.</num>
<heading> Memorial Day</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The last Monday in May is Memorial Day.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Proclamation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The President is requested to issue each year a proclamation—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> calling on the people of the United States to observe Memorial Day by praying, according to their individual religious faith, for permanent peace;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> designating a period of time on Memorial Day during which the people may unite in prayer for a permanent peace;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> calling on the people of the United States to unite in prayer at that time; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> calling on the media to join in observing Memorial Day and the period of prayer.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1257</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 117.</num>
<heading> Mother’s Day</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The second Sunday in May is Mother’s Day.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Proclamation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The President is requested to issue a proclamation calling on United States Government officials to display the flag of the United States on all Government buildings, and on the people of the United States to display the flag at their homes or other suitable places, on Mother’s Day as a public expression of love and reverence for the mothers of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1258</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 118.</num>
<heading> National Aviation Day</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President may issue each year a proclamation—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> designating August 19 as National Aviation Day;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> calling on United States Government officials to display the flag of the United States on all Government buildings on National Aviation Day; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> inviting the people of the United States to observe National Aviation Day with appropriate exercises to further stimulate interest in aviation in the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1258</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 119.</num>
<heading> National Day of Prayer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall issue each year a proclamation designating the first Thursday in May as a National Day of Prayer on which the people of the United States may turn to God in prayer and meditation at churches, in groups, and as individuals.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1258</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 120.</num>
<heading> National Defense Transportation Day</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President is requested to issue each year a proclamation—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> designating the third Friday in May as National Defense Transportation Day; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> urging the people of the United States, including labor, management, users, and investors, in all communities served by the various forms of transportation to observe National Defense Transportation Day by appropriate ceremonies that will give complete recognition to the importance to each community and its people of the transportation system of the United States and the maintenance of the facilities of the system in the most modern state of adequacy to serve the needs of the United States in times of peace and in national defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1258</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 121.</num>
<heading> National Disability Employment Awareness Month</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>October is National Disability Employment Awareness Month.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Ceremonies</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Appropriate ceremonies shall be held throughout the United States during National Disability Employment Awareness Month to enlist public support for, and interest in, the employment of workers with disabilities who are otherwise qualified. Governors, mayors, heads of other governmental entities, and interested organizations and individuals are invited to participate in the ceremonies.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Proclamation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The President is requested to issue each year a suitable proclamation.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1258</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 122.</num>
<heading> National Flag Week</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President is requested to issue each year a proclamation—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> designating the week in which June 14 falls as National Flag Week; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> calling on citizens to display the flag of the United States during National Flag Week.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1259</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 123.</num>
<heading> National Forest Products Week</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The week beginning on the third Sunday in October is National Forest Products Week.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Proclamation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The President is requested to issue each year a proclamation calling on the people of the United States to observe National Forest Products Week with appropriate ceremonies and activities.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1259</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 124.</num>
<heading> National Freedom Day</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President may issue each year a proclamation designating February 1 as National Freedom Day to commemorate the signing by Abraham Lincoln on <date date="1865-02-01">February 1, 1865</date>, of the joint resolution adopted by the Senate and the House of Representatives that proposed the 13th amendment to the Constitution.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1259</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 125.</num>
<heading> National Grandparents Day</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President is requested to issue each year a proclamation—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> designating the first Sunday in September after Labor Day as National Grandparents Day; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> calling on the people of the United States and interested groups and organizations to observe National Grandparents Day with appropriate ceremonies and activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1259</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 126.</num>
<heading> National Hispanic Heritage Month</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President is requested to issue each year a proclamation—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> designating September 15 through October 15 as National Hispanic Heritage Month; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> calling on the people of the United States, especially the educational community, to observe National Hispanic Heritage Month with appropriate ceremonies and activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1259</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 127.</num>
<heading> National Korean War Veterans Armistice Day</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>July 27 of each year until 2003 is National Korean War Veterans Armistice Day.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Proclamation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The President is requested to issue each year a proclamation calling on—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the people of the United States to observe National Korean War Veterans Armistice Day with appropriate ceremonies and activities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> all departments, agencies, and instrumentalities of the United States Government, and interested organizations, groups, and individuals, to fly the flag of the United States at halfstaff on July 27 of each year until 2003 in honor of the individuals who died as a result of their service in Korea.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1259</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 128.</num>
<heading> National Maritime Day</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>May 22 is National Maritime Day.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Proclamation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The President is requested to issue each year a proclamation calling on—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the people of the United States to observe National Maritime Day by displaying the flag of the United States at their homes or other suitable places; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> United States Government officials to display the flag on all Government buildings on National Maritime Day.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1260</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 129.</num>
<heading> National Pearl Harbor Remembrance Day</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>December 7 is National Pearl Harbor Remembrance Day.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Proclamation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The President is requested to issue each year a proclamation calling on—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the people of the United States to observe National Pearl Harbor Remembrance Day with appropriate ceremonies and activities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> all departments, agencies, and instrumentalities of the United States Government, and interested organizations, groups, and individuals, to fly the flag of the United States at halfstaff each December 7 in honor of the individuals who died as a result of their service at Pearl Harbor.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1260</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 130.</num>
<heading> National Poison Prevention Week</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President is requested to issue each year a proclamation designating the third week in March as National Poison Prevention Week to aid in encouraging the people of the United States to learn of the dangers of accidental poisoning and to take preventive measures that are warranted by the seriousness of the danger.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1260</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 131.</num>
<heading> National Safe Boating Week</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President is requested to issue each year a proclamation designating the 7-day period ending on the last Friday before Memorial Day as National Safe Boating Week.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1260</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 132.</num>
<heading> National School Lunch Week</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The week beginning on the second Sunday in October is National School Lunch Week.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Proclamation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The President is requested to issue each year a proclamation calling on the people of the United States to observe National School Lunch Week with appropriate ceremonies and activities.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1260</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 133.</num>
<heading> National Transportation Week</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President is requested to issue each year a proclamation—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> designating the week that includes the third Friday of May as National Transportation Week; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> inviting the people of the United States to observe National Transportation Week with appropriate ceremonies and activities as a tribute to the men and women who, night and day, move goods and individuals throughout the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1260</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 134.</num>
<heading> Pan American Aviation Day</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President may issue each year a proclamation—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> designating December 17 as Pan American Aviation Day; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> calling on all officials of the United States Government, the chief executive offices of the States, territories, and possessions of the United States, and all citizens to participate in the observance of Pan American Aviation Day to further, and stimulate interest in, aviation in the American countries as an important stimulus to the further development of more rapid communications and a cultural development between the countries of the Western Hemisphere.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1261</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 135.</num>
<heading> Parents’ Day</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The fourth Sunday in July is Parents’ Day.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Recognition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>All private citizens, organizations, and Federal, State, and local governmental and legislative entities are encouraged to recognize Parents’ Day through proclamations, activities, and educational efforts in furtherance of recognizing, uplifting, and supporting the role of parents in bringing up their children.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1261</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 136.</num>
<heading> Peace Officers Memorial Day</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President is requested to issue each year a proclamation—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> designating May 15 as Peace Officers Memorial Day in honor of Federal, State, and local officers killed or disabled in the line of duty;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> directing United States Government officials to display the flag of the United States at halfstaff on all Government buildings on Peace Officers Memorial Day, as provided by <ref>section 7(m) of title 4</ref>, United States Code; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> inviting State and local governments and the people of the United States to observe Peace Officers Memorial Day with appropriate ceremonies and activities, including the display of the flag at halfstaff.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1261</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 137.</num>
<heading> Police Week</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President is requested to issue each year a proclamation—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> designating the week in which May 15 occurs as Police Week in recognition of the service given by men and women who stand guard to protect the people of the United States through law enforcement; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> inviting State and local governments and the people of the United States to observe Police Week with appropriate ceremonies and activities, including the display of the flag at halfstaff.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1261</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 138.</num>
<heading> Save Your Vision Week</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President is requested to issue each year a proclamation—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> designating the first week in March as Save Your Vision Week;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> inviting the governors and mayors of State and local governments to issue proclamations designating the first week in March as Save Your Vision Week;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> inviting the communications media, health care professions, and other agencies and individuals concerned with programs for the improvement of vision to unite during Save Your Vision Week in public activities to convince the people of the United States of the importance of vision to their welfare and the welfare of the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> urging the media, health care professions, and other agencies and individuals to support programs to improve and protect the vision of the people of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1261</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 139.</num>
<heading> Steelmark Month</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>May is Steelmark Month.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Purpose</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Steelmark Month recognizes the tremendous contribution made by the steel industry in the United States to national security and defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Proclamation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The President is requested to issue a proclamation calling on the people of the United States to observe Steelmark Month with appropriate ceremonies and activities.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1262</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 140.</num>
<heading> Stephen Foster Memorial Day</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President may issue each year a proclamation—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> designating January 13 as Stephen Foster Memorial Day; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> calling on the people of the United States to observe Stephen Foster Memorial Day with appropriate ceremonies, pilgrimages to his shrines, and musical programs featuring his compositions.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1262</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 141.</num>
<heading> Thomas Jefferson’s birthday</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President shall issue each year a proclamation—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> calling on officials of the United States Government to display the flag of the United States on all Government buildings on April 13; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> inviting the people of the United States to observe April 13 in schools and churches, or other suitable places, with appropriate ceremonies in commemoration of Thomas Jefferson’s birthday.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1262</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 142.</num>
<heading> White Cane Safety Day</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President may issue each year a proclamation—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> designating October 15 as White Cane Safety Day; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> calling on the people of the United States to observe White Cane Safety Day with appropriate ceremonies and activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1262</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 143.</num>
<heading> Wright Brothers Day</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>December 17 is Wright Brothers Day.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Purpose</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Wright Brothers Day commemorates the first successful flights in a heavier than air, mechanically propelled airplane, that were made by Orville and Wilbur Wright on <date date="1903-12-17">December 17, 1903</date>, near Kitty Hawk, North Carolina.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Proclamation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The President is requested to issue each year a proclamation inviting the people of the United States to observe Wright Brothers Day with appropriate ceremonies and activities.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1262</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 144.</num>
<heading> Patriot Day</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>September 11 is Patriot Day.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Proclamation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The President is requested to issue each year a proclamation calling on—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> State and local governments and the people of the United States to observe Patriot Day with appropriate programs and activities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> all departments, agencies, and instrumentalities of the United States and interested organizations and individuals to display the flag of the United States at halfstaff on Patriot Day in honor of the individuals who lost their lives as a result of the terrorist attacks against the United States that occurred on <date date="2001-09-11">September 11, 2001</date>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the people of the United States to observe a moment of silence on Patriot Day in honor of the individuals who lost their lives as a result of the terrorist attacks against the United States that occurred on <date date="2001-09-11">September 11, 2001</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 107–89, § 1</ref>, <date date="2001-12-18">Dec. 18, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 876</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 145.</num>
<heading> Veterans Day</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President shall issue each year a proclamation calling on the people of the United States to observe two minutes of silence on Veterans Day in honor of the service and sacrifice of veterans throughout the history of the Nation, beginning at—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> 3:11 p.m. Atlantic standard time;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> 2:11 p.m. eastern standard time;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> 1:11 p.m. central standard time;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> 12:11 p.m. mountain standard time;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> 11:11 a.m. Pacific standard time;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> 10:11 a.m. Alaska standard time; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> 9:11 a.m. Hawaii-Aleutian standard time.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–240, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-10-07">Oct. 7, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 974</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 146.</num>
<heading> National Atomic Veterans Day</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President shall issue each year a proclamation calling on the people of the United States to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> observe Atomic Veterans Day with appropriate ceremonies and activities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> remember and honor the atomic veterans of the United States whose brave service and sacrifice played an important role in the defense of the Nation.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title X, § 1084(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1924</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 147.</num>
<heading> Choose Respect Day</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>October 1 is Choose Respect Day.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Recognition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>All private citizens, organizations, and Federal, State, and local governmental and legislative entities are encouraged to recognize Choose Respect Day through proclamations, activities, and educational efforts in furtherance of changing the culture around the tolerance of violence against women.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–103, div. W, title XIII, § 1310(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2022-03-15">Mar. 15, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 931</ref>, § 146; renumbered § 147, <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XVIII, § 1804(a)(1)(A)(i)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 686</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 148.</num>
<heading> U.S. Hostage and Wrongful Detainee Day</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>March 9 is U.S. Hostage and Wrongful Detainee Day.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Proclamation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The President is requested to issue each year a proclamation calling on the people of the United States to observe U.S. Hostage and Wrongful Detainee Day with appropriate ceremonies and activities.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XVIII, § 1804(a)(1)(A)(ii)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 686</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>