<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 1401—</num>
<heading>MARINE CORPS LEAGUE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 140101.</num>
<heading> Organization</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Federal Charter</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Marine Corps League (in this chapter, the “corporation”) is a federally chartered corporation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Perpetual Existence</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as otherwise provided, the corporation has perpetual existence.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1379</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 140102.</num>
<heading> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes of the corporation are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to preserve the traditions and to promote the interests of the United States Marine Corps;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to band those who, on <date date="1937-08-04">August 4, 1937</date>, were serving in the United States Marine Corps and those who have been honorably discharged from that service together in fellowship that they may effectively promote the ideals of American freedom and democracy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to fit its members for the duties of citizenship and to encourage them to serve as ably as citizens as they have served the Nation under arms;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to hold sacred the history and memory of the men who have given their lives to the Nation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to foster love for the principles which they have supported by blood and valor since the founding of the Republic;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> to maintain true allegiance to American institutions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> to create a bond of comradeship between those in service and those who have returned to civil life;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> to aid voluntarily and to render assistance to all marines and former marines as well as to their widows and orphans; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> to perpetuate the history of the United States Marine Corps and by fitting acts to observe the anniversaries of historical occasions of peculiar interest to marines.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1379</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 140103.</num>
<heading> Powers</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The corporation may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> adopt and amend bylaws;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> adopt and alter a corporate seal;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> appoint or elect officers and agents;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> choose a board of trustees, consisting of at least 5 but not more than 15 individuals, to conduct the business and exercise the powers of the corporation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> establish and maintain offices to conduct its activities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> acquire, own, lease, encumber, and transfer property as necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of the corporation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> charge and collect membership dues and receive contributions of money or property to be devoted to carrying out the purposes of the corporation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> sue and be sued; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> do any other act necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of the corporation.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1380</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 140104.</num>
<heading> Annual report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than December 1 of each year, the corporation shall submit a report to Congress on the activities of the corporation during the prior calendar year. The report may not be printed as a public document.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1380</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>