<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 21—</num>
<heading>AMERICAN BATTLE MONUMENTS COMMISSION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2101.</num>
<heading> Membership</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Composition and Terms</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The American Battle Monuments Commission has not more than 11 members appointed by the President. The President also shall appoint one officer of the Regular Army to serve as secretary of the Commission. The members and secretary serve at the pleasure of the President. The President shall fill any vacancies that occur. Notwithstanding any other law, members of the Armed Forces may be appointed members of the Commission.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Pay and Expenses</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The members of the Commission serve without compensation. However, the members of the Commission may receive, from an amount appropriated to carry out this chapter or acquired by another authorized way—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> their actual expenses related to the work of the Commission;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> when in a travel status outside the continental United States, a per diem at the rate authorized to be paid for members of the uniformed services under <ref>section 405 of title 37</ref> instead of subsistence; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> when in a travel status in the continental United States, a per diem at the rate authorized to be paid under sections 5702 and 5703 of title 5 instead of subsistence.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Expenses of Officers of Armed Forces Serving on Commission</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An officer of the Armed Forces serving as a member or as secretary of the Commission may be reimbursed for expenses when traveling on business of the Commission in the same way as civilian members of the Commission.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1269</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–117, title VI, § 604(1)</ref>, <date date="1999-11-30">Nov. 30, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1580</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title VI, § 631(f)(4)(B)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1465</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title X, § 1076(a)(9)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1948</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title VI, § 626(g)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2629</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2102.</num>
<heading> Employment of personnel</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Within the limits of an appropriation made to employ personnel, the American Battle Monuments Commission may employ personnel necessary to carry out this chapter. To ensure adequate care and maintenance of cemeteries, monuments, and memorials, the Commission, subject to the availability of appropriations, shall employ—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> at least 50 individuals in the competitive service (as defined in <ref>section 2102 of title 5</ref>), of whom at least 43 shall be assigned to duty in foreign countries where the cemeteries, monuments, and memorials are located; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> at least 348 individuals who are citizens of the countries where the cemeteries, monuments, and memorials are located.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Detailed Personnel</inline>.—</heading>
<content>On request of the Commission, the heads of departments, agencies, and instrumentalities of the United States Government may make available to the Commission their personnel and facilities to assist in carrying out this chapter, and may expend for that purpose amounts appropriated to the department, agency, and instrumentality. The Commission shall reimburse the department, agency, or instrumentality for the pay and allowances of personnel made available to the Commission.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Station Allowance for Officers Assigned to the Commission</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For officers of the Armed Forces assigned to the Commission, the same station allowance shall be authorized for serving at foreign stations as the Secretary of the Army has authorized for officers of the Army.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Citizenship Requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An individual may be employed as the superintendent, or as an assistant superintendent, of a cemetery operated by the Commission only if the individual is a citizen of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1269</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–354, § 1(2)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-03">Nov. 3, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3239</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–117, title VI, § 604(2)</ref>, <date date="1999-11-30">Nov. 30, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1580</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2103.</num>
<heading> Administrative</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subject to appropriations made to carry out this chapter, the American Battle Monuments Commission may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> acquire land or an interest in land in a foreign country to carry out the purposes of this chapter, or an executive order conferring duties and powers on the Commission, without submission to the Attorney General under <ref>section 3111 of title 40</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> maintain, repair, and operate motor-propelled passenger-carrying vehicles and other property that another department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States Government provides to the Commission;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> establish offices in the District of Columbia and elsewhere in or outside the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> rent office and garage space, which may be paid for in advance, in foreign countries; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> procure printing, binding, engraving, lithographing, photographing, and typewriting, including the publication of information on United States activities, battlefields, memorials, and cemeteries with respect to which the Commission may exercise any duties and powers.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Disposition of Land</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Under conditions and in the manner the Commission decides is proper, the Commission may dispose of land or an interest in land in a foreign country that the Commission acquires in connection with its work.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contracting Out</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding the requirements of existing laws or regulations, the Commission, under conditions the Commission decides are necessary and proper, may contract for work, supplies, materials, and equipment outside or for use outside the United States and engage the services of architects and other technical and professional personnel.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Delegation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Under conditions the Commission may prescribe, the Commission may delegate to its Chairman, secretary, or officials in charge of any of its offices any of its authority it considers necessary and proper.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Solicitation and Receipt of Contributions</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Commission may solicit and receive funds and in-kind donations and gifts from any State, municipal, or private source to carry out the purposes of this chapter. The Commission shall deposit such funds in a separate account in the Treasury. Funds from that account shall be disbursed upon vouchers approved by the Chairman of the Commission.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Commission shall establish written guidelines setting forth the criteria to be used in determining whether the acceptance of funds and in-kind donations and gifts under paragraph (1) would—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> reflect unfavorably on the ability of the Commission, or any member or employee of the Commission, to carry out the responsibilities or official duties of the Commission in a fair and objective manner; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> compromise the integrity or the appearance of the integrity of the programs of the Commission or any official involved in those programs.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Use of Contributions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commission may not obligate, withdraw, or expend amounts received as contributions before <date date="1998-03-01">March 1, 1998</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Statements to President</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commission shall transmit to the President on October 1 of each year a statement of all its financial and other transactions during the prior fiscal year.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Financial Statements and Audits</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commission shall have a system of financial controls to enable the Commission to comply with the requirements of <ref>section 3515 of title 31</ref> and with <ref>section 2106(d)(4) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Disposition of Records and Archives</inline>.—</heading>
<content>When no longer required by the Commission, the records and archives of the Commission shall be deposited with the National Archives in accordance with <ref>section 2107 of title 44</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Seal</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commission shall have a seal that shall be judicially noticed.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(k)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Disbursements Outside Continental United States</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Disbursements for expenditures outside the continental United States may be made by a special disbursing agent designated by the Commission under regulations it prescribes.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1270</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–117, title VI</ref>, §§ 602, 604(3), <date date="1999-11-30">Nov. 30, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1578</ref>, 1580; <ref>Pub. L. 107–217, § 3(i)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1300</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–234, § 2(g)</ref>, <date date="2012-12-28">Dec. 28, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1625</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2104.</num>
<heading> Military cemeteries in foreign countries</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">When, as a result of combat operations, the Armed Forces establish military cemeteries in zones of operations outside the United States and the territories and possessions of the United States, the American Battle Monuments Commission and the Secretary of the Army, immediately on the cessation of hostilities, shall decide which of the cemeteries will become permanent cemeteries or, if they decide it is desirable, shall select new sites for the cemeteries at any other location. The Commission is solely responsible for the design and construction of the permanent cemeteries, and of all buildings, plantings, headstones, and other permanent improvements incidental to the cemeteries, except that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Armed Forces are responsible for maintaining the permanent cemeteries until the Commission declares its readiness to assume the authorized administrative duties and powers;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> all construction undertaken by the Armed Forces in establishing and maintaining the cemetery prior to its transfer to the Commission shall be nonpermanent;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> burials and reburials by the Armed Forces shall be carried out in accordance with plans prepared by the Commission; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the Armed Forces have the right to re-enter a cemetery transferred to the Commission to exhume or re-inter a body if they decide it is necessary.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1271</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2105.</num>
<heading> Monuments built by the United States Government</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Memorials</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The American Battle Monuments Commission shall prepare plans and estimates to build suitable memorials commemorating the service of American Armed Forces, and shall build and maintain memorials in the United States and, as the Commission decides, at any place outside the United States where the Armed Forces have served since <date date="1917-04-06">April 6, 1917</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Architecture and Art</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commission shall build and maintain works of architecture and art in United States cemeteries located outside the United States and the territories and possessions of the United States that are permanent cemeteries. The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall maintain works of architecture and art built by the Commission in the National Cemetery Administration, as described in <ref>section 2400(b) of title 38</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Control and Supervision of Materials, Design, and Building</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Commission shall control the materials and design and prescribe regulations for, and supervise the building of, all memorial monuments and buildings in United States cemeteries located outside the United States and the territories and possessions of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Commission shall control the design and prescribe regulations for the building of all memorial monuments and buildings commemorating the service of American Armed Forces that are built in a foreign country or political division of the foreign country that authorizes the Commission to carry out those duties and powers.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Approval by National Commission of Fine Arts</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A design for a memorial must be approved by the National Commission of Fine Arts before the Commission can accept it.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1271</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–368, title IV, § 403(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-11">Nov. 11, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3339</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2106.</num>
<heading> War memorials not built by the United States Government</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Cooperation With Others</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The American Battle Monuments Commission may cooperate with citizens of the United States, States, municipalities, or associations desiring to build war memorials outside the continental limits of the United States in the way the Commission decides. An administrative agency of the United States Government may give assistance to build the memorial only if a plan for the memorial has been approved under this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Control, Administration, and Maintenance of War Memorials</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Commission may assume responsibility for the control, administration, and maintenance of any war memorial built outside the United States by a citizen of the United States, a State, a political subdivision of a State, a governmental authority (except a department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States Government), a foreign agency, or a private association to commemorate the services of any of the Armed Forces in hostilities occurring since <date date="1917-04-06">April 6, 1917</date>, if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the memorial is not built on the territory of the applicable former enemy; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the sponsors of the memorial consent to the Commission assuming those responsibilities and transfer to the Commission all their rights and interests in the memorial.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If reasonable effort fails to locate the sponsors of a memorial, the Commission may assume responsibility for the memorial under this subsection by agreement with the appropriate foreign authorities. A decision of the Commission to assume responsibility for a war memorial under this subsection is final.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Sponsors of a war memorial for which the Commission assumes responsibility under this subsection may transfer amounts accumulated to maintain and repair the memorial to the Commission for use in carrying out this chapter. Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, the Commission shall deposit transferred amounts as provided in <ref>section 2103(e) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Arrangements for Repair or Long-Term Maintenance of Memorials</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In assuming responsibility for a war memorial under subsection (b)(1) or (2) of this section, the Commission may arrange with the sponsors of the memorial to provide for repair or long-term maintenance of the memorial. An amount transferred to the Commission for the purpose of this subsection shall be deposited by the Commission in the fund established under subsection (d) of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Fund for Arrangements for Repair or Long-Term Maintenance of Memorials</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> There is a fund in the Treasury that is available to the Commission for expenses of repair and long-term maintenance of memorials for which the Commission has made arrangements under subsection (c) of this section. The fund consists of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> amounts deposited into, and interest and proceeds credited to, the fund under paragraph (2) of this subsection; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> obligations obtained under paragraph (3) of this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Commission shall deposit into the fund the amounts that are accepted under subsection (c) of this section. The Secretary of the Treasury shall credit to the fund the interest on, and the proceeds from the sale or redemption of, obligations held in the fund.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall invest any part of the fund that the Commission decides is not required to meet current expenses. Each investment shall be made in an interest-bearing obligation of the United States Government, or an obligation that has its principal and interest guaranteed by the Government, that the Commission decides has a maturity suitable for the fund.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Commission shall separately account for all amounts deposited in and expended from the fund for each war memorial for which an arrangement for repair or long-term maintenance is made under subsection (c) of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Demolition of War Memorial Built in a Foreign Country and Disposition of Site</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Commission may take necessary action to demolish any war memorial built outside the United States by a citizen of the United States, a State, a political subdivision of a State, a governmental authority (except a department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States Government), a foreign agency, or a private association and to dispose of the site of the memorial in a way the Commission decides is proper, if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the appropriate foreign authorities agree to the demolition; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the sponsor of the memorial consents to the demolition; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> the memorial has fallen into disrepair and a reasonable effort by the Commission has failed—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> to persuade the sponsor to maintain the memorial at a standard acceptable to the Commission; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> to locate the sponsor.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1272</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2107.</num>
<heading> National Memorial Cemetery of the Pacific</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">With the consent of the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, the American Battle Monuments Commission may build works of architecture and art in the National Memorial Cemetery of the Pacific.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1274</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2108.</num>
<heading> Pacific War Memorial and other historical and memorial sites on Corregidor</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>After an agreement is made between the Government of the Republic of the Philippines and the United States Government, the American Battle Monuments Commission shall restore, operate, and maintain the Pacific War Memorial and other historical and memorial sites on Corregidor.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Personnel</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commission may employ necessary personnel to carry out this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of Other Departments, Agencies, and Instrumentalities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Departments, agencies, and instrumentalities of the United States Government may assist the Commission, on a reimbursable basis, in carrying out this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority To Solicit Contributions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>To carry out this section, the Commission may solicit and accept private contributions and shall deposit the contributions in the fund established by subsection (f) of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of Private Amounts</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commission shall carry out this section with private amounts except to the extent amounts are appropriated under subsection (g) of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Fund</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> There is a fund in the Treasury that is available to the Commission only to carry out this section. The fund consists of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> amounts deposited into, and interest and proceeds credited to, the fund under paragraph (2) of this subsection; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> obligations obtained under paragraph (3) of this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Chairman of the Commission shall deposit into the fund the amounts that are accepted under subsection (d) of this section. The Secretary of the Treasury shall credit to the fund the interest on, and the proceeds from the sale or redemption of, obligations held in the fund.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall invest any part of the fund that the Chairman decides is not required to meet current expenses. Each investment shall be made in an interest-bearing obligation of the United States Government, or an obligation that has its principal and interest guaranteed by the Government, that the Chairman decides has a maturity suitable for the fund.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Amounts in the fund exceeding the cost of carrying out this section, as decided by the Chairman, shall be deposited in the Treasury as miscellaneous receipts to reimburse the United States Government for amounts appropriated under subsection (g) of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authorization of Appropriations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>There are authorized to be appropriated—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> $6,000,000 for site preparation, design, planning, construction, and associated administrative costs for the restoration of the Memorial and other historical and memorial sites referred to in subsection (a) of this section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> amounts necessary to operate and maintain the Memorial and those other historical and memorial sites.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1274</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2109.</num>
<heading> Foreign Currency Fluctuations Account</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment and Purpose</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is an account in the Treasury known as the “Foreign Currency Fluctuations, American Battle Monuments Commission, Account”. The Account shall be used to provide amounts, in addition to amounts appropriated for salaries and expenses of the Commission, to pay the cost of salaries and expenses that exceeds the amount appropriated for salaries and expenses because of fluctuations in currency exchange rates of foreign countries occurring after a budget request for the Commission is submitted to Congress. The Account may not be used for any other purpose.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Increase in Permissible Obligations of Amounts</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A provision of law limiting the amounts the Commission may obligate in a fiscal year shall be increased to the extent necessary to reflect fluctuations in exchange rates from those used in preparing the budget submission.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transferred Amounts</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Amounts in the Account may be transferred to amounts appropriated for salaries and expenses of the Commission. Transferred amounts shall be merged with, and are available for the same time period as, the appropriation to which they are applied.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading> Amounts transferred from the Account may be transferred back—</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> if the amounts are not needed to pay obligations incurred because of fluctuations in currency exchange rates of foreign countries in the appropriation to which the amounts were originally transferred; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> because of subsequent favorable fluctuations in the rates or because other amounts are, or become, available to pay the obligations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Amounts transferred to an appropriation under this subsection may not be transferred back to the Account after the end of the 2d fiscal year after the fiscal year in which the appropriation was available for obligation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Recording of Obligations and Fluctuations in Exchange Rates</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An obligation of the Commission payable in the currency of a foreign country may be recorded as an obligation based on exchange rates used in preparing a budget submission. A change reflecting fluctuations in exchange rates may be recorded as a disbursement is made.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Unobligated Balances</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The unobligated balance of an appropriation for salaries and expenses may be transferred to the Account not later than the end of the second fiscal year following the fiscal year for which the appropriation was made. The unobligated balance shall be merged with, and be available for the same period and purposes as, the Account.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Report</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commission each year shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on amounts transferred under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authorization of Appropriations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is authorized to be appropriated $3,000,000 to the Account.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1275</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2110.</num>
<heading> Claims against the Commission</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A claim against the American Battle Monuments Commission that is similar to a claim described in <ref>section 2734 of title 10</ref>, that is based on damage to, or loss or destruction of, property, or personal injury or death of an individual, and that is caused by the negligent or wrongful act or omission of an officer or civilian employee of the Commission acting within the scope of the officer’s or employee’s office or employment, may be settled, decided, and paid as provided in section 2734 for the settlement of Army claims. However, the Secretary of the Army may appoint an officer or employee of the Commission to a claims commission or as an officer to approve settlements of claims made by the claims commission. All payments in settlement of a claim shall be made out of appropriations made to carry out this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1276</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2111.</num>
<heading> Presidential duties and powers</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Arrangements With Foreign Countries</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The President is requested to make the necessary arrangements with the proper authorities of the appropriate foreign countries to enable the American Battle Monuments Commission to carry out this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transfer of Administrative Duties and Powers and Supplies, Material, and Equipment to Commission</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The President by executive order may transfer to the Commission—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the same administrative duties and powers related to a permanent military cemetery located outside the United States and the territories and possessions of the United States that were transferred to the Commission by Executive Order 6614, <date date="1934-02-26">February 26, 1934</date>, and Executive Order 10057, <date date="1949-05-14">May 14, 1949</date>, as amended by Executive Order 10087, <date date="1949-12-03">December 3, 1949</date>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> supplies, material, and equipment located in the permanent military cemetery or in a military depot overseas that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Department of Defense does not need; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the Commission requests to carry out the duties and powers specified in clause (A) of this paragraph.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> After a transfer under this subsection, the Commission shall maintain the cemetery and all improvements in it.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1276</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2112.</num>
<heading> Care and maintenance of Surrender Tree site</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The American Battle Monuments Commission is responsible for the care and maintenance of the Surrender Tree site in Santiago, Cuba.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1276</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2113.</num>
<heading> World War II memorial in the District of Columbia</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Solicitation and Acceptance of Contributions</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Consistent with its authority under <ref>section 2103(e) of this title</ref>, the American Battle Monuments Commission shall solicit and accept contributions for the World War II memorial.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In this section, the term “World War II memorial” means the memorial authorized by <ref>Public Law 103–32</ref> (<ref>40 U.S.C. 8903</ref> note) to be established by the Commission on Federal land in the District of Columbia or its environs to honor members of the Armed Forces who served in World War II and to commemorate the participation of the United States in that war.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Creation of Memorial Fund</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> There is hereby created in the Treasury a fund for the World War II memorial, which shall consist of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Amounts deposited, and interest and proceeds credited, under paragraph (2).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Obligations obtained under paragraph (3).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The amount of surcharges paid to the Commission for the World War II memorial under the World War II 50th Anniversary Commemorative Coins Act (<ref>31 U.S.C. 5112</ref> note).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Amounts borrowed using the authority provided under subsection (d).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Any funds received by the Commission under <ref>section 2114 of this title</ref> in exchange for use of, or the right to use, any mark, copyright or patent.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Chairman of the Commission shall deposit in the fund the amounts accepted as contributions under subsection (a). The Secretary of the Treasury shall credit to the fund the interest on, and the proceeds from sale or redemption of, obligations held in the fund.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Treasury shall invest any portion of the fund that, as determined by the Chairman, is not required to meet current expenses. Each investment shall be made in an interest-bearing obligation of the United States or an obligation guaranteed as to principal and interest by the United States that, as determined by the Chairman, has a maturity suitable for the fund.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of Fund</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The fund shall be available to the Commission—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> for the expenses of establishing the World War II memorial, including the maintenance and preservation amount provided for in <ref>section 8906(b) of title 40</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> for such other expenses, other than routine maintenance, with respect to the World War II memorial as the Commission considers warranted; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to secure, obtain, register, enforce, protect, and license any mark, copyright, or patent that is owned by, assigned to, or licensed to the Commission under <ref>section 2114 of this title</ref> to aid or facilitate the construction of the World War II memorial.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Special Borrowing Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> To assure that groundbreaking, construction, and dedication of the World War II memorial are carried out on a timely basis, the Commission may borrow money from the Treasury of the United States in such amounts as the Commission considers necessary, but not to exceed a total of $65,000,000. Borrowed amounts shall bear interest at a rate determined by the Secretary of the Treasury, taking into consideration the average market yield on outstanding marketable obligations of the United States of comparable maturities during the month preceding the month in which the obligations of the Commission are issued. The interest payments on such obligations may be deferred with the approval of the Secretary, but any interest payment so deferred shall also bear interest.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The borrowing of money by the Commission under paragraph (1) shall be subject to such maturities, terms, and conditions as may be agreed upon by the Commission and the Secretary, except that the maturities may not exceed 20 years and such borrowings may be redeemable at the option of the Commission before maturity.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The obligations of the Commission shall be issued in amounts and at prices approved by the Secretary. The authority of the Commission to issue obligations under this subsection shall remain available without fiscal year limitation. The Secretary of the Treasury shall purchase any obligations of the Commission to be issued under this subsection, and for such purpose the Secretary of the Treasury may use as a public debt transaction of the United States the proceeds from the sale of any securities issued under chapter 31 of title 31. The purposes for which securities may be issued under such chapter are extended to include any purchase of the Commission’s obligations under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Repayment of the interest and principal on any funds borrowed by the Commission under paragraph (1) shall be made from amounts in the fund. The Commission may not use for such purpose any funds appropriated for any other activities of the Commission.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Treatment of Borrowing Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In determining whether the Commission has sufficient funds to complete construction of the World War II memorial, as required by <ref>section 8906 of title 40</ref>, the Secretary of the Interior shall consider the funds that the Commission may borrow from the Treasury under subsection (d) as funds available to complete construction of the memorial, whether or not the Commission has actually exercised the authority to borrow such funds.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Voluntary Services</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding <ref>section 1342 of title 31</ref>, the Commission may accept from any person voluntary services to be provided in furtherance of the fund-raising activities of the Commission relating to the World War II memorial.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A person providing voluntary services under this subsection shall be considered to be a Federal employee for purposes of chapter 81 of title 5, relating to compensation for work-related injuries, and chapter 171 of title 28, relating to tort claims. A volunteer who is not otherwise employed by the United States shall not be considered to be a Federal employee for any other purpose by reason of the provision of such voluntary service, except that any volunteer given responsibility for the handling of funds or the carrying out of a Federal function is subject to the conflict of interest laws contained in chapter 11 of title 18 and the administrative standards of conduct contained in part 2635 of title 5 of the Code of Federal Regulations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Commission may provide for reimbursement of incidental expenses that are incurred by a person providing voluntary services under this subsection. The Commission shall determine those expenses that are eligible for reimbursement under this paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to require any Federal employee to work without compensation or to allow the use of volunteer services to displace or replace any Federal employee.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Treatment of Certain Contracts</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A contract entered into by the Commission for the design or construction of the World War II memorial is not a funding agreement as that term is defined in <ref>section 201 of title 35</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Extension of Authority To Establish Memorial</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding <ref>section 8903(e) of title 40</ref>, the authority for the construction of the World War II memorial provided by <ref>Public Law 103–32</ref> (<ref>40 U.S.C. 8903</ref> note) expires on <date date="2005-12-31">December 31, 2005</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–117, title VI, § 601(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1999-11-30">Nov. 30, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1576</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–178, § 4(h)</ref>, <date date="2003-12-15">Dec. 15, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2641</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2114.</num>
<heading> Intellectual property and related items</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority To Use and Register Intellectual Property</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The American Battle Monuments Commission may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> adopt, use, register, and license trademarks, service marks, and other marks;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> obtain, use, register, and license the use of copyrights consistent with <ref>section 105 of title 17</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> obtain, use, and license patents; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> accept gifts of marks, copyrights, patents, and licenses for use by the Commission.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority To Grant Licenses</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commission may grant exclusive and nonexclusive licenses in connection with any mark, copyright, patent, or license for the use of such mark, copyright or patent, except to the extent the grant of such license by the Commission would be contrary to any contract or license by which the use of the mark, copyright, or patent was obtained.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Enforcement Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commission may enforce any mark, copyright, or patent by an action in the district courts under any law providing for the protection of such marks, copyrights, or patents.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Legal Representation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Attorney General shall furnish the Commission with such legal representation as the Commission may require under subsection (c). The Secretary of Defense shall provide representation for the Commission in administrative proceedings before the Patent and Trademark Office and Copyright Office.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Irrevocability of Transfers of Copyrights to Commission</inline>.—</heading>
<content><ref>Section 203 of title 17</ref> shall not apply to any copyright transferred in any manner to the Commission.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–117, title VI, § 603(a)</ref>, <date date="1999-11-30">Nov. 30, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1579</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2115.</num>
<heading> Acquisition, operation, and maintenance of Lafayette Escadrille Memorial</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The American Battle Monuments Commission may enter into an agreement with the Lafayette Escadrille Memorial Foundation to acquire, operate, and maintain the Lafayette Escadrille Memorial in Marnes-la-Coquette, France. Under such an agreement, the Commission shall make necessary arrangements to ensure the ongoing maintenance of the memorial, including the cemetery at the memorial that contains the remains of 49 aviators of the United States who died during World War I.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–227, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-09-29">Sept. 29, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 934</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>