<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 1531—</num>
<heading>THE NATIONAL SOCIETY OF THE DAUGHTERS OF THE AMERICAN REVOLUTION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 153101.</num>
<heading> Organization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The National Society of the Daughters of the American Revolution (in this chapter, the “corporation”) is a body corporate and politic in the District of Columbia.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1422</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 153102.</num>
<heading> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes of the corporation are patriotic, historical, and educational, and include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> perpetuating the memory and spirit of the men and women who achieved American independence by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> acquiring and protecting historical spots and erecting monuments;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> encouraging historical research in relation to the Revolution and publishing its results;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> preserving documents and relics and the records of the individual services of Revolutionary soldiers and patriots; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> promoting celebrations of all patriotic anniversaries;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> carrying out the injunction of Washington, in his farewell address to the American people, “to promote, as an object of primary importance, institutions for the general diffusion of knowledge,” thus developing an enlightened public opinion and affording to young and old such advantages as shall develop in them the largest capacity for performing the duties of American citizens;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> cherishing, maintaining, and extending the institutions of American freedom;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> fostering true patriotism and love of country; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> aiding in securing for mankind all the blessings of liberty.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1422</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 153103.</num>
<heading> Powers</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The corporation may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> adopt a constitution and bylaws;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> adopt a seal; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> acquire, own, lease, encumber, and transfer property as necessary or convenient to carry out its purposes.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1423</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 153104.</num>
<heading> Exclusive right to name, seals, emblems, and badges</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The corporation and its subordinate divisions have the exclusive right to use the name “National Society of the Daughters of the American Revolution”. The corporation has the exclusive right to use and to allow others to use seals, emblems, and badges the corporation adopts.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1423</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 153105.</num>
<heading> Principal office</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The corporation shall have its headquarters or principal office in the District of Columbia.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1423</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 153106.</num>
<heading> Deposit of historical material in Smithsonian Institution</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Regents of the Smithsonian Institution may permit the corporation to deposit its collections, manuscripts, books, pamphlets, and other material for history in the Smithsonian Institution or in the National Museum, on conditions and under rules they prescribe.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1423</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 153107.</num>
<heading> Annual report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The corporation shall submit an annual report to the Secretary of the Smithsonian Institution on the activities of the corporation. The Secretary shall communicate to Congress any part of the report that the Secretary considers of national interest and importance.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1423</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>