<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 1103—</num>
<heading>JEWISH WAR VETERANS, U.S.A., NATIONAL MEMORIAL, INCORPORATED</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 110301.</num>
<heading> Organization</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Federal Charter</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Jewish War Veterans, U.S.A., National Memorial, Incorporated (in this chapter, the “corporation”), is a federally chartered corporation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Place of Incorporation and Domicile</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The corporation is declared to be a nonprofit corporation incorporated and domiciled in the District of Columbia.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Perpetual Existence</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as otherwise provided, the corporation has perpetual existence.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1369</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 110302.</num>
<heading> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes of the corporation are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to maintain and conduct a national memorial and museum dedicated to and commemorating the service and sacrifice by Americans of the Jewish faith in the Armed Forces of the United States during the period of war;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to gather, collate, edit, publish, and exhibit memorabilia, information, records, military awards, decorations, citations, and similar items, to preserve the memories and records of patriotic service performed by men and women of the Jewish faith while in the Armed Forces of the United States in time of war; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to stimulate patriotism in the minds of all Americans by encouraging the study of the military and naval history of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1369</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 110303.</num>
<heading> Governing body</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Board of Directors</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The board of directors is the governing body of the corporation. Between meetings of the corporation, the board is responsible for the general policies and program of the corporation. The board is responsible for the control of all funds of the corporation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The number of directors, their manner of selection (including the filling of vacancies), and their term of office are as provided in the constitution and bylaws of the corporation. However, the board shall have at least 36 directors.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Officers</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The officers of the corporation are a president, one or more vice presidents as provided in the constitution and bylaws, a secretary, and a treasurer.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The manner of election, term of office, and duties of the officers are as provided in the constitution and bylaws.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1369</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 110304.</num>
<heading> Powers</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The corporation may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> adopt and amend a constitution and bylaws for the management of its property and the regulation of its affairs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> adopt and alter a corporate seal;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> make contracts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> acquire, own, lease, encumber, and transfer property as necessary or convenient to carry out the purposes of the corporation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> borrow money, issue instruments of indebtedness, and secure its obligations by granting security interests in its property; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> sue and be sued.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1369</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 110305.</num>
<heading> Restrictions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Stock and Dividends</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The corporation may not issue stock or declare or pay a dividend.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Political Activities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The corporation or a director or officer as such may not contribute to, support, or assist a political party or candidate for public office.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Distribution of Income or Assets</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The income or assets of the corporation may not inure to the benefit of, or be distributed to, a director or officer. This subsection does not prevent the payment of compensation to an officer or employee in an amount approved by the executive committee of the corporation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Loans</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The corporation may not make a loan to a director, officer, or employee. Directors who vote for or assent to making a loan to a director, officer, or employee, and officers who participate in making the loan, are jointly and severally liable to the corporation for the amount of the loan until it is repaid.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1370</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 110306.</num>
<heading> Principal office</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The principal office of the corporation shall be in the District of Columbia. However, the activities of the corporation are not confined to the District of Columbia but may be conducted throughout the States, territories, and possessions of the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1370</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 110307.</num>
<heading> Records and inspection</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Records</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The corporation shall keep—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> correct and complete records of account;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> minutes of the proceedings of its members, board of directors, and committees having any of the authority of its board of directors; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> at its principal office, a record of the names and addresses of its members entitled to vote.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inspection</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A member entitled to vote, or an agent or attorney of the member, may inspect the records of the corporation for any proper purpose, at any reasonable time.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1370</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 110308.</num>
<heading> Service of process</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The corporation shall have a designated agent in its headquarters in the District of Columbia to receive service of process for the corporation. Notice to or service on the agent, or mailed to the headquarters of the corporation in the District of Columbia, is notice to or service on the corporation.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1370</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 110309.</num>
<heading> Liability for acts of officers and agents</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The corporation is liable for the acts of its officers and agents acting within the scope of their authority.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1370</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 110310.</num>
<heading> Distribution of assets on dissolution or final liquidation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On dissolution or final liquidation of the corporation, any assets remaining after the discharge of all liabilities shall be distributed as provided by the board of directors, but in compliance with the constitution and bylaws of the corporation. This section does not allow assets to be distributed to an officer or employee or to inure to the benefit of a private person.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1370</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>