<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 401—</num>
<heading>CATHOLIC WAR VETERANS OF THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA, INCORPORATED</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 40101.</num>
<heading> Definition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this chapter, “State” includes the District of Columbia and the territories and possessions of the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1329</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40102.</num>
<heading> Organization</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Federal Charter</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Catholic War Veterans of the United States of America, Incorporated (in this chapter, the “corporation”), incorporated in New York, is a federally chartered corporation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Expiration of Charter</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the corporation does not comply with any provision of this chapter, the charter granted by this chapter expires.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1329</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40103.</num>
<heading> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes of the corporation are as provided in the articles of incorporation and include a continuing commitment, on a national basis, to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> preserve, protect, and defend the Constitution of the United States and the laws of the States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> commemorate the wars, campaigns, and military actions of the United States to reflect profound respect, high honor, and great tribute on the glorious dead and the surviving veterans of those wars, campaigns, and actions and to give all Americans a greater understanding of and appreciation for the sacrifices of those who participated in them for all Americans;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> stimulate to the highest degree possible the interests of the entire Nation in the problems of veterans, their widows, and orphans;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> cooperate to the fullest extent and in a harmonious manner with all veterans’ organizations in common projects designed to serve the interests of all veterans of all wars in which the United States has participated;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> collate, preserve, and encourage the study of historical episodes, chronicles, mementos, and events pertaining to the wars, campaigns, and military actions of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> inculcate an enduring love of country, a deep and abiding sense of patriotism, and a profound commitment to Americanism among all the people of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> encourage, among the youth of our Nation, respect for our national flag, our anthem, and the traditions of America;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> preserve the freedoms of all the people, national peace, prosperity, tranquility, good will, the permanence of free institutions, and the defense of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> foster the association of veterans of the Catholic faith who have served in the Armed Forces of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> encourage morality in government, labor, management, economic, social, fraternal, and all other phases of American life;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> promote the realization that the family is the basic unit of society;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> increase our love, honor, and service to God and to our fellow man without regard to race, creed, color, or national origin; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> function as a veterans’ and patriotic organization as authorized by the laws of each State in which it is incorporated.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1329</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–284, § 5(6)</ref>, <date date="2006-09-27">Sept. 27, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1212</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40104.</num>
<heading> Membership</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Eligibility for membership in the corporation and the rights and privileges of members are as provided in the bylaws.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1330</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40105.</num>
<heading> Governing body</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Board of Directors</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The board of directors and the responsibilities of the board are as provided in the articles of incorporation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Officers</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The officers and the election of officers are as provided in the articles of incorporation.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1330</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40106.</num>
<heading> Powers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The corporation has only the powers provided in its bylaws and articles of incorporation filed in each State in which it is incorporated.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1330</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40107.</num>
<heading> Restrictions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Stock and Dividends</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The corporation may not issue stock or declare or pay a dividend.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Distribution of Income or Assets</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The income or assets of the corporation may not inure to the benefit of, or be distributed to, a director, officer, or member during the life of the charter granted by this chapter. This subsection does not prevent the payment of reasonable compensation to an officer or employee in an amount approved by the board of directors.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Loans</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The corporation may not make a loan to a director, officer, or employee.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Claim of Governmental Approval or Authorization</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The corporation may not claim congressional approval or the authority of the United States Government for any of its activities.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1330</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40108.</num>
<heading> Duty to maintain tax-exempt status</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The corporation shall maintain its status as an organization exempt from taxation under the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (<ref>26 U.S.C. 1</ref> et seq.).</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1330</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40109.</num>
<heading> Records and inspection</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Records</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The corporation shall keep—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> correct and complete records of account;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> minutes of the proceedings of its members, board of directors, and committees having any of the authority of its board of directors; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> at its principal office, a record of the names and addresses of its members entitled to vote.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inspection</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A member entitled to vote, or an agent or attorney of the member, may inspect the records of the corporation for any proper purpose, at any reasonable time.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1331</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40110.</num>
<heading> Service of process</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The corporation shall comply with the law on service of process of each State in which it is incorporated and each State in which it carries on activities.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1331</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40111.</num>
<heading> Liability for acts of officers and agents</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The corporation is liable for the acts of its officers and agents acting within the scope of their authority.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1331</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40112.</num>
<heading> Annual report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The corporation shall submit an annual report to Congress on the activities of the corporation during the prior fiscal year. The report shall be submitted at the same time as the report of the audit required by <ref>section 10101 of this title</ref>. The report may not be printed as a public document.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1331</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>