<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 1543—</num>
<heading>NAVY CLUB OF THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 154301.</num>
<heading> Organization</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Federal Charter</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Navy Club of the United States of America (in this chapter, the “corporation”) is a federally chartered corporation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Perpetual Existence</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as otherwise provided, the corporation has perpetual existence.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1434</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 154302.</num>
<heading> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes of the corporation are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to encourage, promote, and maintain comradeship among individuals who are or have been in the active service of the United States Navy, the United States Marine Corps, or the United States Coast Guard;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to revere, honor, and perpetuate the memory of individuals described in paragraph (1) of this section who have departed this life;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to promote and encourage further public interest in the United States Navy, the United States Marine Corps, and the United States Coast Guard, and the history of those organizations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to uphold the spirit and ideals of the United States Navy, the United States Marine Corps, and the United States Coast Guard;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to promote the ideals of American freedom and democracy and to fit its members for the duties of citizenship and to encourage them to serve as ably as citizens as they have served the Nation under arms; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> to maintain true allegiance to American institutions.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1434</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 154303.</num>
<heading> Powers</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The corporation may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> adopt and amend bylaws;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> adopt and alter a corporate seal;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> appoint or elect officers and agents;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> choose a board of trustees, consisting of at least 5 but not more than 15 individuals, to conduct the business and exercise the powers of the corporation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> establish and maintain offices to conduct its activities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> acquire, own, lease, encumber, and transfer property as necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of the corporation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> charge and collect membership dues and receive contributions of money or property to be devoted to carrying out the purposes of the corporation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> sue and be sued; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> do any other act necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of the corporation.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1434</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 154304.</num>
<heading> Annual report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than December 1 of each year, the corporation shall submit a report to Congress on the activities of the corporation during the prior calendar year. The report may not be printed as a public document.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1435</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>