<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 201—</num>
<heading>AGRICULTURAL HALL OF FAME</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 20101.</num>
<heading> Organization</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Federal Charter</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Agricultural Hall of Fame (in this chapter, the “corporation”) is a federally chartered corporation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Perpetual Existence</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as otherwise provided, the corporation has perpetual existence.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1284</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20102.</num>
<heading> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes of the corporation are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to receive and maintain one or more funds and to use any part of the principal or interest only for charitable, scientific, literary, or educational purposes either directly or by contributing to organizations authorized to carry on similar activities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to honor farmers, farm women, farm leaders, teachers, scientists, inventors, governmental leaders, and other individuals who have helped make this Nation great by their outstanding contributions to the establishment, development, advancement, or improvement of agriculture in the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to perpetuate the memory of those individuals and record their contributions and achievements by the erection and maintenance of buildings and monuments as may be appropriate as a lasting memorial;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to promote a greater sense of appreciation of the dignity and importance of agriculture, historically carried out through owner-operated farms, and the part it has played in developing those social, economic, and spiritual values which are essential in maintaining the free and democratic institutions of our Republic;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to establish and maintain a library and museum for the collection and preservation for posterity of agricultural tools, implements, machines, vehicles, pictures, paintings, books, papers, documents, data, relics, mementos, artifacts, and other items relating to agriculture;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> to cooperate with other organizations interested in similar projects; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> to engage in other activities appropriate to carry out its purposes.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1284</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20103.</num>
<heading> Membership</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Eligibility</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in this chapter, eligibility for membership in the corporation and the rights, privileges, and designation of classes of members are as provided in the bylaws.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Voting</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each member given voting rights by the bylaws has one vote on each matter submitted to a vote at a meeting of the voting members. The vote may be cast in the manner provided in the bylaws.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1284</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20104.</num>
<heading> Governing body</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Board of Governors</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The board of governors is the governing body of the corporation. Between meetings of the members of the corporation, the board is responsible for the general policies and program of the corporation and for the control of all funds of the corporation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The number of governors, their manner of selection (including the filling of vacancies), and their term of office are as provided in the bylaws. However, the board shall have at least 15 members.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The board may appoint committees. Each committee has the powers provided in the bylaws or by resolution of the board. The powers of a committee may include all the powers of the board.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Officers</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The officers of the corporation are a president, one or more one vice presidents as provided in the bylaws, a secretary, a treasurer, one or more assistant secretaries and assistant treasurers, and other officers as provided in the bylaws.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The manner of election, term of office, and duties of the officers are as provided in the bylaws.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1284</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20105.</num>
<heading> Powers</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The corporation may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> adopt and amend bylaws for the management of its property and the regulation of its affairs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> adopt and alter a corporate seal;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> choose officers, managers, agents, and employees as the activities of the corporation require;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> make contracts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> acquire, own, lease, encumber, and transfer property as necessary or convenient to carry out the purposes of the corporation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> borrow money, issue instruments of indebtedness, and secure its obligations by granting security interests in its property; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> sue and be sued.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1285</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20106.</num>
<heading> Restrictions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Stock and Dividends</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The corporation may not issue stock or declare or pay a dividend.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Political Activities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The corporation or a governor, officer, employee, or member as such may not contribute to, support, or assist a political party or candidate for public office.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Distribution of Income or Assets</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The income or assets of the corporation may not inure to the benefit of, or be distributed to, a governor, officer, or member as such during the life of the corporation or on its dissolution or final liquidation. This subsection does not prevent the payment of compensation to an officer or employee in an amount approved by the board of governors.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Loans</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The corporation may not make a loan or advance to a governor, officer, employee, or member. Governors who vote for or assent to making a loan or advance to a governor, officer, employee, or member, and officers who participate in making the loan or advance, are jointly and severally liable to the corporation for the amount of the loan or advance until it is repaid.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contributions to Certain Organizations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>None of the principal or interest of a fund referred to in <ref>section 20102(1) of this title</ref> may be contributed to an organization if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a substantial part of its activities is carrying on propaganda or attempting to influence legislation; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any part of its net earnings benefits a private shareholder or individual.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1285</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20107.</num>
<heading> Principal office</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The principal office of the corporation shall be in Kansas City, Kansas, or another place decided by the board of governors. However, the activities of the corporation are not confined to the place where the principal office is located but may be conducted throughout the States, territories, and possessions of the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1285</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20108.</num>
<heading> Records and inspection</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Records</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The corporation shall keep—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> correct and complete records of account;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> minutes of the proceedings of its members, board of governors, and committees having any of the authority of its board of governors; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> at its principal office, a record of the names and addresses of its members entitled to vote.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inspection</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A member entitled to vote, or an agent or attorney of the member, may inspect the records of the corporation for any proper purpose, at any reasonable time.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1286</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20109.</num>
<heading> Service of process</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The corporation shall have a designated agent in the District of Columbia to receive service of process for the corporation. Notice to or service on the agent is notice to or service on the corporation.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1286</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20110.</num>
<heading> Liability for acts of officers and agents</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The corporation is liable for the acts of its officers and agents acting within the scope of their authority.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1286</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20111.</num>
<heading> Use of assets on dissolution or final liquidation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On dissolution or final liquidation of the corporation, any assets of the corporation remaining after the discharge of all liabilities shall be distributed as provided by the board of governors, but in compliance with the charter and bylaws.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1286</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>