<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 1535—</num>
<heading>NATIONAL TROPICAL BOTANICAL GARDEN</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 153501.</num>
<heading> Organization</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Federal Charter</inline>.—</heading>
<content>National Tropical Botanical Garden (in this chapter, the “corporation”) is a federally chartered corporation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Perpetual Existence</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as otherwise provided, the corporation has perpetual existence.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1425</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 153502.</num>
<heading> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes of the corporation are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to establish, develop, operate, and maintain for the benefit of the people of the United States an educational and scientific center in the form of one or more tropical botanical gardens, together with facilities such as libraries, herbaria, laboratories, and museums that are appropriate and necessary for encouraging and conducting research in basic and applied tropical botany;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to foster and encourage fundamental research about tropical plant life and to encourage research and study of the uses of tropical flora in agriculture, forestry, horticulture, medicine, and other sciences;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to disseminate through publications and other media the knowledge about basic and applied tropical botany acquired at the gardens;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to collect and cultivate tropical flora of every nature and origin and to preserve for the people of the United States species of tropical plant life threatened with extinction; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to provide a beneficial facility that will contribute to the education, instruction, and recreation of the people of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1425</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 153503.</num>
<heading> Membership</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Eligibility</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in this chapter, eligibility for membership in the corporation and the rights and privileges of members are as provided in the constitution and bylaws of the corporation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Voting</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each member (except an honorary or associate member) has one vote on each matter submitted to a vote at a meeting of the members.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1425</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 153504.</num>
<heading> Governing body</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Board of Trustees</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The board of trustees is the governing body of the corporation. The duties and powers of the board are as provided in the bylaws.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The manner of selection and term of office of the trustees are as provided in the bylaws.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Officers</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The officers of the corporation are a president, one or more vice presidents, a secretary, a treasurer, and other officers as provided in the bylaws.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The manner of election, term of office, and duties of the officers are as provided in the bylaws.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1425</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 153505.</num>
<heading> Powers</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The corporation may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> adopt and amend bylaws for the management of its property and the regulation of its affairs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> adopt and alter a corporate seal;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> choose officers, trustees, managers, employees, and agents as the activities of the corporation require;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> make contracts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> acquire, own, lease, encumber, and transfer property as necessary or proper to carry out the purposes of the corporation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> borrow money, issue instruments of indebtedness, and secure its obligations by granting security interests in its property;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> sue and be sued; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> do any other act necessary and proper to carry out the purposes of the corporation.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1426</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 153506.</num>
<heading> Exclusive right to name</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The corporation has the exclusive right to use and to allow others to use the name “National Tropical Botanical Garden”.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1426</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 153507.</num>
<heading> Restrictions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Stock and Dividends</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The corporation may not issue stock or declare or pay a dividend.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Political Activities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The corporation or a trustee or officer as such may not contribute to, support, or assist a political party or candidate for elective public office.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Distribution of Income or Assets</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The income or assets of the corporation may not inure to the benefit of, or be distributed to, a trustee, officer, or member during the life of the corporation or on its dissolution or final liquidation. This subsection does not prevent the payment of reasonable compensation to an officer or reimbursement for actual necessary expenses in amounts approved by the board of trustees.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Loans</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The corporation may not make a loan to a trustee, officer, or employee. Trustees who vote for or assent to making a loan to a trustee, officer, or employee, and officers who participate in making the loan, are jointly and severally liable to the corporation for the amount of the loan until it is repaid.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1426</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 153508.</num>
<heading> Principal office and location of activities and gardens</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Principal Office</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The principal office of the corporation shall be in the District of Columbia or another place decided by the board of trustees.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Location of Activities and Gardens</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The activities of the corporation may be conducted anywhere. However, the corporation may establish tropical botanical gardens only in the United States and its territories and possessions.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1426</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 153509.</num>
<heading> Records and inspection</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Records</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The corporation shall keep—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> correct and complete records of account;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> minutes of the proceedings of its board of trustees and committees having any of the authority of its board of trustees; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> at its principal office, a record of the names and addresses of its members entitled to vote.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inspection</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A member entitled to vote, or an agent or attorney of the member, may inspect the records of the corporation for any proper purpose, at any reasonable time.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1426</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 153510.</num>
<heading> Statement required in audit report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The corporation shall include in the audit report statement required under <ref>section 10101(b)(1)(B) of this title</ref> a schedule of all contracts requiring payments greater than $10,000 and all payments of compensation or fees at a rate of greater than $10,000 a year.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1427</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 153511.</num>
<heading> Service of process</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The corporation shall have a designated agent in the District of Columbia to receive service of process for the corporation. Notice to or service on the agent, or mailed to the business address of the agent, is notice to or service on the corporation.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1427</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 153512.</num>
<heading> Liability for acts of officers and agents</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The corporation is liable for the acts of its officers and agents acting within the scope of their authority.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1427</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 153513.</num>
<heading> Distribution of assets on dissolution or final liquidation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Allowable Recipients</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>On dissolution or final liquidation of the corporation, any assets remaining after the discharge of all liabilities shall be distributed, as decided by the board of trustees, to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the United States Government, to be administered by the Secretary of the Interior under section 100101(a), chapter 1003, and sections 100751(a), 100752, 100753, and 102101 of title 54, United States Code; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a State or local government to be used for a public purpose.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Restriction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A distribution under subsection (a) of this section shall be consistent with the purposes of the corporation and in compliance with the charter and bylaws.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1427</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–284, § 5(10)</ref>, <date date="2006-09-27">Sept. 27, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1212</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 5(i)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3269</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 153514.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to subsection (b), there is authorized to be appropriated to the corporation for operation and maintenance expenses $500,000 for each of fiscal years 2008 through 2017.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any Federal funds made available under subsection (a) shall be matched on a 1-to-1 basis by non-Federal funds.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–11, title XIII, § 13006</ref>, <date date="2009-03-30">Mar. 30, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1452</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>