<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 177—</num>
<heading>ALASKA COMMUNICATIONS DISPOSAL</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 17701.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter, the following definitions apply:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Agency concerned</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “agency concerned” means a department, agency, wholly owned corporation, or instrumentality of the Federal Government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Long-lines communication facilities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “long-lines communication facilities” means the transmission systems connecting points inside the State with each other and with points outside the State by radio or wire, and includes all kinds of property and rights of way necessary to accomplish this interconnection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transfer</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “transfer” means the conveyance by the Government of any element of ownership, including any estate or interest in property, and franchise rights, by sale, exchange, lease, easement, or permit, for cash, credit, or other property with or without warranty.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1286</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 17702.</num>
<heading> Transfer of Government-owned long-lines communication facilities in and to Alaska</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">In General.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Authority of the secretary of defense.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirements prior to transfer</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to <ref>section 17703 of this title</ref> and with the advice, assistance, and, in the case of an agency not under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of Defense, the consent of the agency concerned, and after approval of the President, the Secretary of Defense shall transfer for adequate consideration any or all long-lines communication facilities in or to Alaska under the jurisdiction of the Federal Government to any person qualifying under section 17703.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority to carry out chapter</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may take action and exercise powers as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consent of secretary concerned</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An interest in public lands, withdrawn or otherwise appropriated, shall not be transferred under this chapter without the prior consent of the Secretary of the Interior, or, with respect to lands in a national forest, of the Secretary of Agriculture.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Procedures and methods</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall carry out a transfer under this chapter in accordance with the procedures and methods required of the Administrator of General Services by section 545(a) and (b) of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Documents of Title or Other Property Interests</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The head of the agency concerned (or a designee of the head) shall execute documents for the transfer of title or other interest in property, except any mineral rights in the property, and take other action that the Secretary of Defense decides is necessary or proper to transfer the property under this chapter. A copy of a deed, lease, or other instrument executed by or on behalf of the head of the agency concerned purporting to transfer title or another interest in public land shall be provided to the Secretary of the Interior.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Solicitation of Offers To Purchase Certain Facilities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In connection with soliciting offers to purchase long-lines facilities of the Alaska Communication System, the Secretary of Defense shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> provide any prospective purchaser who requests it data on—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the facilities available for purchase;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the amounts considered to be the current fair and reasonable value of those facilities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the initial rates that will be charged to the purchaser for capacity in facilities retained by the Government and available for commercial use;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provide in the request for offers to purchase that offerors must specify the rates the offerors propose to charge for service and the improvements in service the offerors propose to initiate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> provide an opportunity for prospective purchasers to meet as a group with Department of Defense representatives to ensure that the data and public interest requirements described in clauses (1) and (2) are fully understood; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> seek the advice and assistance of the Federal Communications Commission and the Governor of Alaska (or a designee of the Governor) to ensure consideration of all public interest factors associated with the transfer.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Applicability of Antitrust Provisions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The requirements of <ref>section 559 of this title</ref> apply to transfers under this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1286</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 17703.</num>
<heading> National defense considerations and qualification of transferee</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A transfer under this chapter shall not be made unless the Secretary of Defense determines that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Federal Government does not need to retain the property involved in the transfer for national defense purposes;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the transfer is in the public interest;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the person to whom the transfer is made is prepared and qualified to provide the communication service involved in the transfer without interruption; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the long-lines communication facilities will not directly or indirectly be owned, operated, or controlled by a person that would legally be disqualified from holding a radio station license by section 310(a) of the Communications Act of 1934 (<ref>47 U.S.C. 310(a)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1287</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 17704.</num>
<heading> Contents of agreements for transfer</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">An agreement by which a transfer is made under this chapter shall provide that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> subject to regulations of the Federal Communications Commission and of any body or commission established by Alaska to govern and regulate communications services to the public and all applicable statutes, treaties, and conventions, the person to whom the transfer is made shall provide the communication services involved in the transfer without interruption, except those services reserved by the Federal Government in the transfer;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the rates and charges for those services applicable at the time of transfer shall not be changed for a period of one year from the date of the transfer unless approved by a governmental body or commission having jurisdiction; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the transfer will not be final until the transferee receives the requisite license and certificate of convenience and necessity to operate interstate and intrastate commercial communications in Alaska from the appropriate governmental regulatory bodies.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1288</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 17705.</num>
<heading> Approval of Federal Communications Commission</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A transfer under this chapter does not require the approval of the Federal Communications Commission except to the extent that the approval of the Commission is necessary under <ref>section 17704(3) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1288</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 17706.</num>
<heading> Gross proceeds as miscellaneous receipts in the Treasury</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The gross proceeds of each transfer shall be deposited in the Treasury as miscellaneous receipts.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1288</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 17707.</num>
<heading> Reports</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of Defense shall report to the Congress and the President—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in January of each year, the actions taken under this chapter during the preceding 12 months; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> not later than 90 days after completion of each transfer under this chapter, a full account of that transfer.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1288</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 17708.</num>
<heading> Nonapplication</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This chapter does not modify in any manner the Communications Act of 1934 (<ref>47 U.S.C. 151</ref> et seq.).</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1288</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>