<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 61—</num>
<heading>UNITED STATES SUPREME COURT BUILDING AND GROUNDS</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>GENERAL</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6101.</num>
<heading> Definitions and application</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this chapter, the following definitions apply:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Official guest of the supreme court</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “official guest of the Supreme Court” means an individual who is a guest of the Supreme Court, as determined by the Chief Justice of the United States or any Associate Justice of the Supreme Court;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">State</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “State” means a State of the United States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, the Northern Mariana Islands, the Federated States of Micronesia, the Marshall Islands, Palau, and any territory or possession of the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Application</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For purposes of <ref>section 6102 of this title</ref> and subchapters III and IV, the Supreme Court grounds—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> extend to the line of the face of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the east curb of First Street Northeast, between Maryland Avenue Northeast and East Capitol Street;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the south curb of Maryland Avenue Northeast, between First Street Northeast and Second Street Northeast;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the west curb of Second Street Northeast, between Maryland Avenue Northeast and East Capitol Street; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the north curb of East Capitol Street between First Street Northeast and Second Street Northeast; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> comprise any property under the custody and control of the Supreme Court as part of the Supreme Court grounds, including property acquired as provided by law on behalf of the Federal Government in lots 2, 3, 800, 801, and 802 in square 758 in the District of Columbia as an addition to the grounds of the Supreme Court Building and that parcel transferred under the Supreme Court Grounds Transfer Act of 2005.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1180</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–214, § 1(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2006-04-11">Apr. 11, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 326</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6102.</num>
<heading> Regulations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority of the Marshal</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In addition to the restrictions and requirements specified in subchapter IV, the Marshal of the Supreme Court may prescribe regulations, approved by the Chief Justice of the United States, that are necessary for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the adequate protection of the Supreme Court Building and grounds and of individuals and property in the Building and grounds; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the maintenance of suitable order and decorum within the Building and grounds.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Posting Requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>All regulations prescribed under this section shall be posted in a public place at the Building and shall be made reasonably available to the public in writing.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1180</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>BUILDINGS AND GROUNDS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6111.</num>
<heading> Supreme Court Building</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">In General.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Structural and mechanical care</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Architect of the Capitol shall have charge of the structural and mechanical care of the Supreme Court Building, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the care and maintenance of the grounds; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the supplying of all mechanical furnishings and mechanical equipment for the Building.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Operation and maintenance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Architect shall direct the operation and maintenance of the mechanical equipment and repair of the building.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contract authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Architect may enter into all necessary contracts to carry out this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Availability of Appropriations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Amounts appropriated under—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> subsection (a) and sections 6112 and 6113 of this title are available for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> expenses of heating and air-conditioning refrigeration supplied by the Capitol Power Plant, advancements for which shall be made and deposited in the Treasury to the credit of appropriations provided for the Capitol Power Plant; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the purchase of electrical energy; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the heading “Supreme Court of the United States” and “care of the building and grounds” are available for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> improvements, maintenance, repairs, equipment, supplies, materials, and appurtenances;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> special clothing for workers;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> personal and other services (including temporary labor without regard to chapter 51, subchapter III of chapter 53, and subchapter III of chapter 83, of title 5); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> without compliance with section 6101(b) to (d) of title 41—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> for snow removal (by hire of personnel and equipment or under contract); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> for the replacement of electrical transformers containing polychlorinated biphenyls.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1180</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–284, § 6(18)</ref>, <date date="2006-09-27">Sept. 27, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1213</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 5</ref>(<i>l</i>)(22), <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3852</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6112.</num>
<heading> Supreme Court Building and grounds employees</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Employees required to carry out <ref>section 6111(a) of this title</ref> shall be—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> appointed by the Architect of the Capitol with the approval of the Chief Justice of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> compensated in accordance with chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> subject to subchapter III of chapter 83 of title 5.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1181</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6113.</num>
<heading> Duties of the Superintendent of the Supreme Court Building</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as provided in <ref>section 6111(a) of this title</ref>, all duties and work required for the operation, domestic care, and custody of the Supreme Court Building shall be performed under the direction of the Marshal of the Supreme Court. The Marshal serves as the superintendent of the Building.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1181</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6114.</num>
<heading> Oliver Wendell Holmes Garden</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Architect of the Capitol shall maintain and care for the Oliver Wendell Holmes Garden in accordance with the provisions of law on the maintenance and care of the grounds of the Supreme Court Building.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1181</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>POLICING AUTHORITY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6121.</num>
<heading> General</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority of Marshal of the Supreme Court and Supreme Court Police</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In accordance with regulations prescribed by the Marshal of the Supreme Court and approved by the Chief Justice of the United States, the Marshal and the Supreme Court Police shall have authority—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to police the Supreme Court Building and grounds and adjacent streets to protect individuals and property;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> in any location, to protect—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Chief Justice, any Associate Justice of the Supreme Court, and any official guest of the Supreme Court;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any officer or employee of the Supreme Court while that officer or employee is performing official duties; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any member of the immediate family of the Chief Justice, any Associate Justice, or any officer of the Supreme Court if the Marshal determines such protection is necessary.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002026">1</ref></content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> while performing duties necessary to carry out paragraph (1) or (2), to make arrests for any violation of Federal or State law and any regulation under Federal or State law; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to carry firearms as may be required while performing duties under <ref>section 6102 of this title</ref>, this subchapter, and subchapter IV.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authorization To Carry Firearms</inline>—</heading>
<content> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002027">2</ref> Duties under subsection (a)(2)(A) with respect to an official guest of the Supreme Court in any location (other than the District of Columbia, Maryland, and Virginia) shall be authorized in writing by the Chief Justice or an Associate Justice, if those duties require the carrying of firearms under subsection (a)(4).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1182</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–356, § 1</ref>, <date date="2004-10-21">Oct. 21, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1416</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–402, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-10-13">Oct. 13, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4254</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–62, § 1</ref>, <date date="2013-12-20">Dec. 20, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 666</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–75, § 2</ref>, <date date="2019-11-27">Nov. 27, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1160</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–148, § 2</ref>, <date date="2022-06-16">June 16, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 1288</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6122.</num>
<heading> Designation of members of the Supreme Court Police</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Under the general supervision and direction of the Chief Justice of the United States, the Marshal of the Supreme Court may designate employees of the Supreme Court as members of the Supreme Court Police, without additional compensation.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1182</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6123.</num>
<heading> Authority of Metropolitan Police of the District of Columbia</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Metropolitan Police of the District of Columbia may make arrests within the Supreme Court Building and grounds for a violation of federal or state law or any regulation under federal or state law. This section does not authorize the Metropolitan Police to enter the Supreme Court Building to make an arrest in response to a complaint, serve a warrant, or patrol the Supreme Court Building or grounds, unless the Metropolitan Police have been requested to do so by, or have received the consent of, the Marshal of the Supreme Court or an assistant to the Marshal.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1182</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>PROHIBITIONS AND PENALTIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6131.</num>
<heading> Public travel in Supreme Court grounds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Public travel in, and occupancy of, the Supreme Court grounds is restricted to the sidewalks and other paved surfaces.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1182</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6132.</num>
<heading> Sale of articles, signs, and solicitation in Supreme Court Building and grounds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is unlawful—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to offer or expose any article for sale in the Supreme Court Building or grounds;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to display a sign, placard, or other form of advertisement in the Building or grounds; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to solicit fares, alms, subscriptions, or contributions in the Building or grounds.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1183</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6133.</num>
<heading> Property in the Supreme Court Building and grounds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is unlawful to step or climb on, remove, or in any way injure any statue, seat, wall, fountain, or other erection or architectural feature, or any tree, shrub, plant, or turf, in the Supreme Court Building or grounds.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1183</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6134.</num>
<heading> Firearms, fireworks, speeches, and objectionable language in the Supreme Court Building and grounds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is unlawful to discharge a firearm, firework or explosive, set fire to a combustible, make a harangue or oration, or utter loud, threatening, or abusive language in the Supreme Court Building or grounds.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1183</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6135.</num>
<heading> Parades, assemblages, and display of flags in the Supreme Court Building and grounds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is unlawful to parade, stand, or move in processions or assemblages in the Supreme Court Building or grounds, or to display in the Building and grounds a flag, banner, or device designed or adapted to bring into public notice a party, organization, or movement.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1183</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6136.</num>
<heading> Suspension of prohibitions against use of Supreme Court grounds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">To allow the observance of authorized ceremonies in the Supreme Court Building and grounds, the Marshal of the Supreme Court may suspend for those occasions any of the prohibitions contained in this subchapter as may be necessary for the occasion if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> responsible officers have been appointed; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the Marshal determines that adequate arrangements have been made—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to maintain suitable order and decorum in the proceedings; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to protect the Supreme Court Building and grounds and individuals and property in the Building and grounds.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1183</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6137.</num>
<heading> Penalties</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An individual who violates this subchapter, or a regulation prescribed under <ref>section 6102 of this title</ref>, shall be fined under title 18, imprisoned not more than 60 days, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Venue and Procedure</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Prosecution for a violation described in subsection (a) shall be in the United States District Court for the District of Columbia or in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia, on information by the United States Attorney or an Assistant United States Attorney.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Offenses Involving Property Damage Over</inline> $100.—</heading>
<content>If during the commission of a violation described in subsection (a), public property is damaged in an amount exceeding $100, the period of imprisonment for the offense may be not more than five years.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1183</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–356, § 2</ref>, <date date="2004-10-21">Oct. 21, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1416</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>