<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 81—</num>
<heading>ADMINISTRATIVE</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>GENERAL</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 8101.</num>
<heading> Supervision of public buildings and grounds in District of Columbia not otherwise provided for by law</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Under regulations the President prescribes, the Administrator of General Services shall have charge of the public buildings and grounds in the District of Columbia, except those buildings and grounds which otherwise are provided for by law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice of Unlawful Occupancy</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the Administrator, or the officer under the direction of the Administrator who is in immediate charge of those public buildings and grounds, decides that an individual is unlawfully occupying any part of that public land, the Administrator or officer in charge shall notify the United States marshal for the District of Columbia in writing of the unlawful occupation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Ejection of Trespasser</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The marshal shall have the trespasser ejected from the public land and shall restore possession of the land to the officer charged by law with the custody of the land.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1204</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8102.</num>
<heading> Protection of Federal Government buildings in District of Columbia</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Attorney General and the Secretary of the Treasury may prohibit—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> a vehicle from parking or standing on a street or roadway adjacent to a building in the District of Columbia—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> at least partly owned or possessed by, or leased to, the Federal Government; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> used by law enforcement authorities subject to their jurisdiction; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a person or entity from conducting business on property immediately adjacent to a building described in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1205</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8103.</num>
<heading> Application of District of Columbia laws to public buildings and grounds</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Application of Laws</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Laws and regulations of the District of Columbia for the protection of public or private property and the preservation of peace and order are extended to all public buildings and public grounds belonging to the Federal Government in the District of Columbia.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Penalties</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A person shall be fined under title 18, imprisoned for not more than six months, or both if the person—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> is guilty of disorderly and unlawful conduct in or about those public buildings or public grounds;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> willfully injures the buildings or shrubs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> pull downs, impairs, or otherwise injures any fence, wall, or other enclosure;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> injures any sink, culvert, pipe, hydrant, cistern, lamp, or bridge; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> removes any stone, gravel, sand, or other property of the Government, or any other part of the public grounds or lots belonging to the Government in the District of Columbia.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1205</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8104.</num>
<heading> Regulation of private and semipublic buildings adjacent to public buildings and grounds</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Factors for Development</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In view of the provisions of the Constitution respecting the establishment of the seat of the National Government, the duties it imposed on Congress in connection with establishing the seat of the National Government, and the solicitude shown and the efforts exerted by President Washington in the planning and development of the Capital City, the development should proceed along the lines of good order, good taste, and with due regard to the public interests involved, and a reasonable degree of control should be exercised over the architecture of private or semipublic buildings adjacent to public buildings and grounds of major importance.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Submission of Application to Commission of Fine Arts</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Mayor of the District of Columbia shall submit to the Commission of Fine Arts an application for a permit to erect or alter any building, a part of which fronts or abuts on the grounds of the Capitol, the grounds of the White House, the part of Pennsylvania Avenue extending from the Capitol to the White House, Lafayette Park, Rock Creek Park, the Zoological Park, the Rock Creek and Potomac Parkway, Potomac Park, or The Mall Park System and public buildings adjacent to the System, or abuts on any street bordering any of those grounds or parks, so far as the plans relate to height and appearance, color, and texture of the materials of exterior construction.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report to Mayor</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commission shall report promptly its recommendations to the Mayor, including any changes the Commission decides are necessary to prevent reasonably avoidable impairment of the public values belonging to the public building or park. If the Commission fails to report its approval or disapproval of a plan within 30 days, the report is deemed approved and a permit may be issued.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Action by the Mayor</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Mayor shall take action the Mayor decides is necessary to effect reasonable compliance with the recommendation under subsection (c).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1205</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–284, § 6(22)</ref>, <date date="2006-09-27">Sept. 27, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1213</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8105.</num>
<heading> Approval by Administrator of General Services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to applicable provisions of existing law relating to the functions in the District of Columbia of the National Capital Planning Commission and the Commission of Fine Arts, only the Administrator of General Services is required to approve sketches, plans, and estimates for buildings to be constructed by the Administrator, except that the Administrator and the United States Postal Service must approve buildings designed for post office purposes.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1206</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–284, § 6(23)</ref>, <date date="2006-09-27">Sept. 27, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1213</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8106.</num>
<heading> Buildings on reservations, parks, or public grounds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A building or structure shall not be erected on any reservation, park, or public grounds of the Federal Government in the District of Columbia without express authority of Congress.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1206</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8107.</num>
<heading> Advertisements and sales in or around Washington Monument</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except on the written authority of the Director of the National Park Service, advertisements of any kind shall not be displayed, and articles of any kind shall not be sold, in or around the Washington Monument.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1206</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8108.</num>
<heading> Use of public buildings for public ceremonies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as expressly authorized by law, public buildings in the District of Columbia (other than the Capitol Building and the White House), and the approaches to those public buildings, shall not be used or occupied in connection with ceremonies for the inauguration of the President or other public functions.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1206</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>JURISDICTION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 8121.</num>
<heading> Improper appropriation of streets</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of the Interior shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> prevent the improper appropriation or occupation of any public street, avenue, square, or reservation in the District of Columbia that belongs to the Federal Government;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> reclaim the street, avenue, square, or reservation if unlawfully appropriated;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> prevent the erection of any permanent building on property reserved to or for the use of the Government, unless plainly authorized by law; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> report to Congress at the beginning of each session on the Secretary’s proceedings in the premises, together with a full statement of all property described in this subsection, and how, and by what authority, the property is occupied or claimed.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Application</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section does not interfere with the temporary and proper occupation of any part of the property described in subsection (a), by lawful authority, for the legitimate purposes of the Government.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1206</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8122.</num>
<heading> Jurisdiction over portion of Constitution Avenue</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director of the National Park Service has jurisdiction over that part of Constitution Avenue west of Virginia Avenue that was under the control of the Commissioners of the District of Columbia prior to <date date="1908-05-27">May 27, 1908</date>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1207</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8123.</num>
<heading> Record of transfer of jurisdiction between Director of National Park Service and Mayor of District of Columbia</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">When in accordance with law or mutual legal agreement, spaces or portions of public land are transferred between the jurisdiction of the Director of the National Park Service, as established by the Act of <date date="1898-07-01">July 1, 1898</date> (ch. 543, <ref>30 Stat. 570</ref>), and the Mayor of the District of Columbia, the letters of transfer and acceptance exchanged between them are sufficient authority for the necessary change in the official maps and for record when necessary.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1207</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8124.</num>
<heading> Transfer of jurisdiction between Federal and District of Columbia authorities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transfer of Jurisdiction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Federal and District of Columbia authorities administering properties in the District that are owned by the Federal Government or by the District may transfer jurisdiction over any part of the property among or between themselves for purposes of administration and maintenance under conditions the parties agree on. The National Capital Planning Commission shall recommend the transfer before it is completed.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report to Congress</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The District authorities shall report all transfers and agreements to Congress.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Certain Laws Not Repealed</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subsection (a) does not repeal any law in effect on <date date="1932-05-20">May 20, 1932</date>, which authorized the transfer of jurisdiction of certain land among and between federal and District authorities.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1207</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8125.</num>
<heading> Public spaces resulting from filling of canals</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director of the National Park Service has jurisdiction over all public spaces resulting from the filling of canals in the original city of Washington that were not under the jurisdiction of the Chief of Engineers of the United States Army as of <date date="1914-08-01">August 1, 1914</date>, except spaces included in the navy yard or in actual use as roadways and sidewalks and spaces assigned by law to the District of Columbia for use as a property yard and the location of a sewage pumping station. The spaces shall be laid out as reservations as a part of the park system of the District of Columbia.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1207</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8126.</num>
<heading> Temporary occupancy of Potomac Park by Secretary of Agriculture</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Not More Than</inline> 75 <inline class="small-caps">Acres</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Director of the National Park Service may allow the Secretary of Agriculture to temporarily occupy as a testing ground not more than 75 acres of Potomac Park not needed in any one season for reclamation or park improvement. The Secretary shall vacate the area at the close of any season on the request of the Director.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Continue as Public Park Under Director</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section does not change the essential character of the land used, which shall continue to be a public park under the charge of the Director.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1207</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8127.</num>
<heading> Part of Washington Aqueduct for playground purposes</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Jurisdiction of Mayor</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Mayor of the District of Columbia has possession, control, and jurisdiction of the land of the Washington Aqueduct adjacent to the Champlain Avenue pumping station and lying outside of the fence around the pumping station as it—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> existed on <date date="1918-08-31">August 31, 1918</date>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> was transferred by the Chief of Engineers for playground purposes.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Jurisdiction of Secretary of the Army Not Affected</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section does not affect the superintendence and control of the Secretary of the Army over the Washington Aqueduct and the rights, appurtenances, and fixtures connected with the Aqueduct.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1208</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>SERVICES FOR FACILITIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 8141.</num>
<heading> Contract to rent buildings in the District of Columbia not to be made until appropriation enacted</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A contract shall not be made for the rent of a building, or part of a building, to be used for the purposes of the Federal Government in the District of Columbia until Congress enacts an appropriation for the rent. This section is deemed to be notice to all contractors or lessors of the building or a part of the building.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1208</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8142.</num>
<heading> Rent of other buildings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An executive department of the Federal Government renting a building for public use in the District of Columbia may rent a different building instead if it is in the public interest to do so. This section does not authorize an increase in the number of buildings in use or in the amount paid for rent.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1208</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8143.</num>
<heading> Heat</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Corcoran Gallery of Art</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Administrator of General Services may furnish heat from the central heating plant to the Corcoran Gallery of Art, if the Corcoran Gallery of Art agrees to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> pay for heat furnished at rates the Administrator determines; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> connect the building with the Federal Government mains in a manner satisfactory to the Administrator.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Administrator may furnish steam from the central heating plant for the use of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System on the property which the Board acquired in squares east of 87 and east of 88 in the District of Columbia if the Board agrees to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> pay for the steam furnished at reasonable rates the Administrator determines but that are at least equal to cost; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provide the necessary connections with the Government mains at its own expense and in a manner satisfactory to the Administrator.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Non-Federal Public Buildings</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall determine the rates to be paid for steam furnished to the Corcoran Gallery of Art, the Pan American Union Buildings, the American Red Cross Buildings, and other non-federal public buildings authorized to receive steam from the central heating plant.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1208</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8144.</num>
<heading> Delivery of fuel for use during ensuing fiscal year</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">During April, May, and June of each year, the Administrator of General Services may deliver to all branches of the Federal Government and the government of the District of Columbia as much fuel for their use during the following fiscal year as may be practicable to store at the points of consumption. The branches of the Federal Government and the government of the District of Columbia shall pay for the fuel from their applicable appropriations for that fiscal year.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1209</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>MISCELLANEOUS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 8161.</num>
<heading> Reservation of parking spaces for Members of Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Council of the District of Columbia shall designate, reserve, and properly mark appropriate and sufficient parking spaces on the streets adjacent to all public buildings in the District for the use of Members of Congress engaged in public business.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1209</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8162.</num>
<heading> Ailanthus trees prohibited</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Ailanthus trees shall not be purchased for, or planted in, the public grounds.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1209</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8163.</num>
<heading> Use of greenhouses and nursery for trees, shrubs, and plants</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The greenhouses and nursery shall be used only for the propagation of trees, shrubs, and plants suitable for planting in the public reservations. Only those trees, shrubs, and plants shall be planted in the public reservations.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1209</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8164.</num>
<heading> E. Barrett Prettyman United States Courthouse</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Operation, Maintenance, and Repair</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The operation, maintenance, and repair of the E. Barrett Prettyman United States Courthouse, used by the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia and the United States District Court for the District of Columbia, is under the control of the Administrator of General Services.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Allocation of Space</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The allocation of space in the Courthouse is vested in the chief judge of the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia and the chief judge of the United States District Court for the District of Columbia.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1209</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8165.</num>
<heading> Services for Office of Personnel Management</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For carrying out the work of the Director of the Office of Personnel Management and the examinations provided for in sections 3304 and 3305 of title 5, the Administrator of General Services shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> assign or provide suitable and convenient rooms and accommodations, which are furnished, heated, and lighted, in Washington, D.C.;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> supply necessary stationery and other articles; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> arrange for or provide necessary printing.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1210</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>