<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 63—</num>
<heading>SMITHSONIAN INSTITUTION, NATIONAL GALLERY OF ART, AND JOHN F. KENNEDY CENTER FOR THE PERFORMING ARTS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6301.</num>
<heading> Definition</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter, the term “specified buildings and grounds” means—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Smithsonian institution</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Smithsonian Institution and its grounds, which include the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Smithsonian buildings and grounds on the national mall</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Smithsonian Building, the Arts and Industries Building, the Freer Gallery of Art, the National Air and Space Museum, the National Museum of Natural History, the National Museum of American History, the National Museum of the American Indian, the Hirshhorn Museum and Sculpture Garden, the Arthur M. Sackler Gallery, the National Museum of African Art, the S. Dillon Ripley Center, and all other buildings of the Smithsonian Institution within the Mall, including the entrance walks, unloading areas, and other pertinent service roads and parking areas.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">National zoological park</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The National Zoological Park comprising all the buildings, streets, service roads, walks, and other areas within the boundary fence of the National Zoological Park in the District of Columbia and including the public space between that fence and the face of the curb lines of the adjacent city streets.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Other smithsonian buildings and grounds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>All other buildings, service roads, walks, and other areas within the exterior boundaries of any real estate or land or interest in land (including temporary use) that the Smithsonian Institution acquires and that the Secretary of the Smithsonian Institution determines to be necessary for the adequate protection of individuals or property in the Smithsonian Institution and suitable for administration as a part of the Smithsonian Institution.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">National gallery of art</inline>.—</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> The National Gallery of Art and its grounds, which extend—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> to the line of the face of the south curb of Constitution Avenue Northwest, between Seventh Street Northwest, and Fourth Street Northwest, to the line of the face of the west curb of Fourth Street Northwest, between Constitution Avenue Northwest, and Madison Drive Northwest; to the line of the face of the north curb of Madison Drive Northwest, between Fourth Street Northwest, and Seventh Street Northwest; and to the line of the face of the east curb of Seventh Street Northwest, between Madison Drive Northwest, and Constitution Avenue Northwest;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> to the line of the face of the south curb of Pennsylvania Avenue Northwest, between Fourth Street and Third Street Northwest, to the line of the face of the west curb of Third Street Northwest, between Pennsylvania Avenue and Madison Drive Northwest, to the line of the face of the north curb of Madison Drive Northwest, between Third Street and Fourth Street Northwest, and to the line of the face of the east curb of Fourth Street Northwest, between Pennsylvania Avenue and Madison Drive Northwest; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> to the line of the face of the south curb of Constitution Avenue Northwest, between Ninth Street Northwest and Seventh Street Northwest; to the line of the face of the west curb of Seventh Street Northwest, between Constitution Avenue Northwest and Madison Drive Northwest; to the line of the face of the north curb of Madison Drive Northwest, between Seventh Street Northwest and the line of the face of the east side of the east retaining wall of the Ninth Street Expressway Northwest; and to the line of the face of the east side of the east retaining wall of the Ninth Street Expressway Northwest, between Madison Drive Northwest and Constitution Avenue Northwest.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> All other buildings, service roads, walks, and other areas within the exterior boundaries of any real estate or land or interest in land (including temporary use) that the National Gallery of Art acquires and that the Director of the National Gallery of Art determines to be necessary for the adequate protection of individuals or property in the National Gallery of Art and suitable for administration as a part of the National Gallery of Art.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">John f. kennedy center for the performing arts</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The John F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts, which extends to the line of the west face of the west retaining walls and curbs of the Inner Loop Freeway on the east, the north face of the north retaining walls and curbs of the Theodore Roosevelt Bridge approaches on the south, the east face of the east retaining walls and curbs of Rock Creek Parkway on the west, and the south curbs of New Hampshire Avenue and F Street on the north, as generally depicted on the map entitled “Transfer of John F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts”, numbered 844/82563 and dated <date date="1994-04-20">April 20, 1994</date> (as amended by the map entitled “Transfer of John F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts”, numbered 844/82563A and dated <date date="1997-05-22">May 22, 1997</date>), which shall be on file and available for public inspection in the office of the National Capital Region, National Park Service.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1184</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–31, div. G, title IV, § 426</ref>, <date date="2017-05-05">May 5, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 500</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6302.</num>
<heading> Public use of grounds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Public travel in, and occupancy of, the grounds specified under <ref>section 6301 of this title</ref> are restricted to the sidewalks and other paved surfaces, except in the National Zoological Park.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1185</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6303.</num>
<heading> Unlawful activities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Displays and Solicitations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>It is unlawful for anyone other than an authorized employee or concessionaire to carry out any of the following activities within the specified buildings and grounds:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Offer or expose any article for sale.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Display any sign, placard, or other form of advertisement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Solicit alms, subscriptions, or contributions.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Touching of, or Injuries to, Property</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>It is unlawful for anyone—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> other than an authorized employee, to touch or handle objects of art or scientific or historical objects on exhibition within the specified buildings or grounds; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to step or climb on, remove, or in any way injure any object of art, exhibit (including an exhibit animal), equipment, seat, wall, fountain, or other erection or architectural feature, or any tree, shrub, plant, or turf, within the specified buildings or grounds.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1185</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6304.</num>
<heading> Additional regulations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority To Prescribe Additional Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In addition to the restrictions and requirements specified in sections 6302 and 6303 of this title, the Secretary of the Smithsonian Institution, the Trustees of the National Gallery of Art, and the Trustees of the John F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts may prescribe for their respective agencies regulations necessary for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the adequate protection of the specified buildings and grounds and individuals and property in those buildings and grounds; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the maintenance of suitable order and decorum within the specified buildings and grounds, including the control of traffic and parking of vehicles in the National Zoological Park and all other areas in the District of Columbia under their control.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Publication in Federal Register</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A regulation prescribed under this section shall be published in the Federal Register and is not effective until the expiration of 10 days after the date of publication.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1186</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6305.</num>
<heading> Suspension of regulations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">To allow authorized services, training programs, and ceremonies in the specified buildings and grounds, the Secretary of the Smithsonian Institution, the Trustees of the National Gallery of Art, and the Trustees of the John F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts (or their designees) may suspend for their respective agencies any of the prohibitions contained in sections 6302 and 6303 of this title as may be necessary for the occasion or circumstance if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> responsible officers have been appointed; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the Secretary of the Smithsonian Institution, the Trustees of the National Gallery of Art, and the Trustees of the John F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts (or their designees) determine that adequate arrangements have been made—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to maintain suitable order and decorum in the proceedings; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to protect the specified buildings and grounds and persons and property in those buildings and on those grounds.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1186</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6306.</num>
<heading> Policing of buildings and grounds</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designation of Employees as Special Police</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to <ref>section 5375 of title 5</ref>, the Secretary of the Smithsonian Institution, the Trustees of the National Gallery of Art, and the Trustees of the John F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts (or their designees) may designate employees of their respective agencies as special police, without additional compensation, for duty in connection with the policing of their respective specified buildings and grounds.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Powers</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The employees designated as special police under subsection (a)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> may, within the specified buildings and grounds, enforce, and make arrests for violations of, sections 6302 and 6303 of this title, any regulation prescribed under <ref>section 6304 of this title</ref>, federal or state law, or any regulation prescribed under federal or state law; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> may enforce concurrently with the United States Park Police the laws and regulations applicable to the National Capital Parks, and may make arrests for violations of sections 6302 and 6303 of this title, within the several areas located within the exterior boundaries of the face of the curb lines of the squares within which the specified buildings and grounds are located.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Uniforms and Other Equipment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The employees designated as special police under subsection (a) may be provided, without charge, with uniforms and other equipment as may be necessary for the proper performance of their duties, including badges, revolvers, and ammunition.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1186</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6307.</num>
<heading> Penalties</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">In General.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Penalty</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A person violating section 6302 or 6303 of this title, or a regulation prescribed under <ref>section 6304 of this title</ref>, shall be fined under title 18, imprisoned for not more than 60 days, or both.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Procedure</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Prosecution for an offense under this subsection shall be in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia, by information by the United States Attorney or an Assistant United States Attorney.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Offenses Involving Property Damage Over</inline> $100.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Penalty</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If in the commission of a violation described in subsection (a), property is damaged in an amount exceeding $100, the period of imprisonment for the offense may be not more than five years.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Venue and procedure</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Prosecution of an offense under this subsection shall be in the United States District Court for the District of Columbia by indictment. Prosecution may be on information by the United States Attorney or an Assistant United States Attorney if the defendant, after being advised of the nature of the charge and of rights of the defendant, waives in open court prosecution by indictment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1187</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>