<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 69—</num>
<heading>UNION STATION REDEVELOPMENT</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>UNION STATION COMPLEX</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6901.</num>
<heading> Definition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this subchapter, the term “Union Station complex” means real property, air rights, and improvements the Secretary of the Interior leased under sections 101–110 of the National Visitors Center Facilities Act of 1968 (<ref>Public Law 90–264</ref>, <ref>82 Stat. 43</ref>) and property acquired and improvements made in accordance with this subchapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1201</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6902.</num>
<heading> Assignment of right, title, and interest in the Union Station complex to the Secretary of Transportation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Transportation has the right, title, and interest in and to the Union Station complex, including all agreements and leases made under sections 101–110 of the National Visitors Center Facilities Act of 1968 (<ref>Public Law 90–264</ref>, <ref>82 Stat. 43</ref>). To the extent the Secretary of Transportation and the Secretary of the Interior agree, the Secretary of the Interior may lease space for visitor services.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1201</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6903.</num>
<heading> Agreements and contracts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Transportation may make agreements and contracts, except an agreement or contract to sell property rights at the Union Station complex, with a person, a federal, regional, or local agency, or the Architect of the Capitol that the Secretary considers necessary or desirable to carry out the purposes of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1201</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6904.</num>
<heading> Acquisition, maintenance, and use of property</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Acquisition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Transportation may acquire for the Federal Government an interest in real property (including easements or reservations) and any other property interest (including contract rights) in or relating or adjacent to the Union Station complex that the Secretary considers necessary to carry out the purposes of this subchapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Maintenance and Use</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may maintain, use, operate, manage, and lease, either directly, by contract, or through development agreements, any property interest the Secretary holds or acquires for the Government under this subchapter in the manner and subject to the terms, conditions, covenants, and easements that the Secretary considers necessary or desirable to carry out the purposes of this subchapter.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1201</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6905.</num>
<heading> Service on board of directors of Union Station Redevelopment Corporation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To further the rehabilitation, redevelopment, and operation of the Union Station complex, the Secretary of Transportation and the Administrator of the Federal Railroad Administration may serve as ex officio members of the board of directors of the Union Station Redevelopment Corporation.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1202</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6906.</num>
<heading> Union Station Fund</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is a special deposit account in the Treasury known as the “Union Station Fund”, which shall be administered as a revolving fund.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Content</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The account shall be credited with receipts of the Secretary of Transportation from activities authorized by this subchapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of Amounts</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may use income and proceeds received from activities authorized by this subchapter, including operating and leasing income and payments made to the Federal Government under development agreements, to pay expenses the Secretary incurs in carrying out the purposes of this subchapter, including construction, acquisition, leasing, operation, and maintenance expenses and payments made to developers under development agreements.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Availability of Amounts</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The balance in the account is available in amounts specified in annual appropriation laws for making expenditures authorized by this subchapter.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1202</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6907.</num>
<heading> Use of other appropriated amounts</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Waiver of Cost Sharing Requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Transportation may use amounts appropriated under <ref>section 24909(a)(2)(A) of title 49</ref> to carry out the purposes of this subchapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Ban on Using Amounts for Heliport</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Amounts appropriated under <ref>section 24909 of title 49</ref> may not be used for design, construction, or operation of a heliport at or near Union Station.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1202</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6908.</num>
<heading> Parking facility</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Title</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Federal Government has the right, title, and interest in and to the parking facility at Union Station.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Fees</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The rate of fees charged for use of the facility may exceed the rate required for maintenance and operation of the facility. The rate shall be established in a manner that encourages use of the facility by rail passengers and participants in activities in the Union Station complex and area.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1202</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6909.</num>
<heading> Supplying steam or chilled water to Union Station complex</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Architect of the Capitol may make agreements with the Secretary of Transportation to furnish steam, chilled water, or both from the Capitol Power Plant to the Union Station complex, at no expense to the legislative branch.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1202</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6910.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Amounts necessary to meet lease and other obligations, including maintenance requirements, incurred by the Secretary of the Interior and assigned to the Secretary of Transportation under this subchapter may be appropriated to the Secretary of Transportation.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1202</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>NATIONAL VISITOR FACILITIES ADVISORY COMMISSION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6921.</num>
<heading> Establishment, composition, and meetings</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is a National Visitor Facilities Advisory Commission.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Composition.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Membership</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Commission is composed of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Secretary of the Interior;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Administrator of General Services;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Secretary of the Smithsonian Institution;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Chairman of the National Capital Planning Commission;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the Chairman of the Commission of Fine Arts;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> six Members of the Senate, three from each party, to be appointed by the President of the Senate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> six Members of the House of Representatives, three from each party, to be appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> three individuals appointed by the President, at least two of whom shall not be officers of the Federal Government, and one member of whom shall be a representative of the District of Columbia government.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Chairman</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the Interior serves as the Chairman of the Commission.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Service of non-federal members</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Non-federal members serve at the pleasure of the President.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Meetings</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commission shall meet at the call of the Chairman.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1203</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6922.</num>
<heading> Duties</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The National Visitor Facilities Advisory Commission shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> conduct continuing investigations and studies of sites and plans to provide additional facilities and services for visitors and students coming to the Nation’s Capital; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> advise the Secretary of the Interior and the Administrator of General Services on the planning, construction, acquisition, and operation of those visitor facilities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Staff and Facilities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Director of the National Park Service, in consultation with the Administrator, shall provide the necessary staff and facilities to assist the Commission in carrying out its duties under this subchapter.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1203</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6923.</num>
<heading> Compensation and expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Members of the National Visitor Facilities Advisory Commission who are not officers or employees of the Federal Government or the government of the District of Columbia are entitled to receive compensation under <ref>section 3109 of title 5</ref> and expenses under <ref>section 5703 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1203</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6924.</num>
<heading> Reports and recommendations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The National Visitor Facilities Advisory Commission shall report to the Secretary of the Interior and the Administrator of General Services the results of its studies and investigations. A report recommending additional facilities for visitors shall include the Commission’s recommendations as to sites for the facilities to be provided, preliminary plans, specifications, and architectural drawings for the facilities, and the estimated cost of the recommended sites and facilities.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1203</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>