<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 117—</num>
<heading>ADDITIONAL INFORMATION RESOURCES MANAGEMENT MATTERS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 11701.</num>
<heading> Identification of excess and surplus computer equipment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In accordance with chapter 5 of this title, the head of an executive agency shall maintain an inventory of all computer equipment under the control of that official that is excess or surplus property.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1252</ref>, § 11702; renumbered § 11701, <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title VIII, § 825(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2616</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11702.</num>
<heading> Index of certain information in information systems included in directory established under <ref>section 4101 of title 44</ref></heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If in designing an information technology system pursuant to this subtitle, the head of an executive agency determines that a purpose of the system is to disseminate information to the public, then the head of that executive agency shall reasonably ensure that an index of information disseminated by the system is included in the directory created pursuant to <ref>section 4101 of title 44</ref>. This section does not authorize the dissemination of information to the public unless otherwise authorized.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1252</ref>, § 11703; renumbered § 11702, <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title VIII, § 825(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2616</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11703.</num>
<heading> Procurement procedures</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To the maximum extent practicable, the Federal Acquisition Regulatory Council shall ensure that the process for acquisition of information technology is a simplified, clear, and understandable process that specifically addresses the management of risk, incremental acquisitions, and the need to incorporate commercial information technology in a timely manner.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1252</ref>, § 11704; renumbered § 11703, <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title VIII, § 825(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2616</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 11704.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 11703]</heading>
</section>
</chapter>