<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 151—</num>
<heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 15101.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this subtitle, the following definitions apply:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Commission</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “Commission” means a Commission or Authority established under section 15301.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Local development district</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “local development district” means an entity that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> is an economic development district that is—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> in existence on the date of the enactment of this chapter; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> located in the region; or</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> if an entity described in clause (i) does not exist—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> is organized and operated in a manner that ensures broad-based community participation and an effective opportunity for local officials, community leaders, and the public to contribute to the development and implementation of programs in the region;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<chapeau> is governed by a policy board with at least a simple majority of members consisting of—</chapeau>
<item class="indent4">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> elected officials; or</content>
</item>
<item class="indent4">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> designees or employees of a general purpose unit of local government that have been appointed to represent the unit of local government; and</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> is certified by the Governor or appropriate State officer as having a charter or authority that includes the economic development of counties, portions of counties, or other political subdivisions within the region; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> has not, as certified by the Federal Cochairperson—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> inappropriately used Federal grant funds from any Federal source; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> appointed an officer who, during the period in which another entity inappropriately used Federal grant funds from any Federal source, was an officer of the other entity.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Federal grant program</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “Federal grant program” means a Federal grant program to provide assistance in carrying out economic and community development activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Indian tribe</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “Indian tribe” has the meaning given the term in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<ref>25 U.S.C. 450b</ref>).<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002038">1</ref></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Nonprofit entity</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “nonprofit entity” means any organization described in section 501(c) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and exempt from taxation under 501(a) of that Code that has been formed for the purpose of economic development.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Region</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “region” means the area covered by a Commission as described in subchapter II of chapter 157.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002039">2</ref></content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title XIV, § 14217(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1468</ref>, and <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title XIV, § 14217(a)(2), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2230; amended <ref>Pub. L. 117–328, div. O, title IV, § 401(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 5228</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>