<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 175—</num>
<heading>FEDERAL MOTOR VEHICLE EXPENDITURE CONTROL</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 17501.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter, the following definitions apply:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Executive agency</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “executive agency”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> means an executive agency (as that term is defined in <ref>section 105 of title 5</ref>) that operates at least 300 motor vehicles; but</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> does not include the Tennessee Valley Authority.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Motor vehicle</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “motor vehicle” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a vehicle self-propelled or drawn by mechanical power; but not</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a vehicle designed or used for military field training, combat, or tactical purposes, or any other special purpose vehicle exempted from the requirements of this chapter by the Administrator of General Services.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1283</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 17502.</num>
<heading> Monitoring system</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The head of each executive agency shall designate one office, officer, or employee of the agency—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to establish and operate a central monitoring system for the motor vehicle operations of the agency, related activities, and related reporting requirements; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provide oversight of those operations, activities, and requirements.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1283</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 17503.</num>
<heading> Data collection</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Cost Identification and Analysis</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The head of each executive agency shall develop a system to identify, collect, and analyze data with respect to all costs (including obligations and outlays) the agency incurs in the operation, maintenance, acquisition, and disposition of motor vehicles, including vehicles owned or leased by the Federal Government and privately owned vehicles used for official purposes.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Requirements for Data Systems.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Scope of requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In cooperation with the Comptroller General of the United States and the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, the Administrator of General Services shall prescribe requirements governing the establishment and operation by executive agencies of the systems required by subsection (a), including requirements with respect to data on the costs and uses of motor vehicles and with respect to the uniform collection and submission of the data.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Conformity with principles and standards</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Requirements prescribed under this section shall conform to accounting principles and standards issued by the Comptroller General. Each executive agency shall comply with those requirements.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1284</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 17504.</num>
<heading> Agency statements with respect to motor vehicle use</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contents of Statement</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The head of each executive agency shall include with the appropriation request the agency submits under <ref>section 1108 of title 31</ref> for each fiscal year, a statement—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> specifying—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the total motor vehicle acquisition, maintenance, leasing, operation, and disposal costs (including obligations and outlays) the agency incurred in the most recently completed fiscal year; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an estimate of those costs for the fiscal year in which the request is submitted and for the succeeding fiscal year; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> justifying why the existing and any new motor vehicle acquisition, maintenance, leasing, operation, and disposal requirements of the agency cannot be met through the Interagency Fleet Management System the Administrator of General Services operates, a qualified private fleet management firm, or any other method which is less costly to the Federal Government.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Compliance With Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The head of each executive agency shall comply with the requirements prescribed under <ref>section 17503(b) of this title</ref> in preparing each statement required under subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1284</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–284, § 6(32)</ref>, <date date="2006-09-27">Sept. 27, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1214</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 17505.</num>
<heading> Presidential report</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Summary and Analysis of Agency Statements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The President shall include with the budget transmitted under <ref>section 1105 of title 31</ref> for each fiscal year, or in a separate written report to Congress for that fiscal year, a summary and analysis of the statements most recently submitted by the heads of executive agencies pursuant to <ref>section 17504(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contents of Summary and Analysis</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each summary and analysis shall include a review, for the fiscal year preceding the fiscal year in which the budget is submitted, the current fiscal year, and the fiscal year for which the budget is submitted, of the cost savings that have been achieved, that are estimated will be achieved, and that could be achieved, in the acquisition, maintenance, leasing, operation, and disposal of motor vehicles by executive agencies through—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the use of a qualified private fleet management firm or another private contractor;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> increased reliance by executive agencies on the Interagency Fleet Management System the Administrator of General Services operates; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> other existing motor vehicle management systems.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1284</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 17506.</num>
<heading> Reduction of storage and disposal costs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator of General Services shall take such actions as may be necessary to reduce motor vehicle storage and disposal costs and to improve the rate of return on motor vehicle sales through a program of vehicle reconditioning prior to sale.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1285</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 17507.</num>
<heading> Savings</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Actions by President Required</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The President shall establish, for each executive agency, goals to reduce outlays for the operation, maintenance, leasing, acquisition, and disposal of motor vehicles in order to reduce, by fiscal year 1988, the total amount of outlays by all executive agencies for the operation, maintenance, leasing, acquisition, and disposal of motor vehicles to an amount which is $150,000,000 less than the amount for the operation, maintenance, leasing, acquisition, and disposal of motor vehicles requested by the President in the budget submitted under <ref>section 1105 of title 31</ref> for fiscal year 1986.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Monitoring of Compliance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall monitor compliance by executive agencies with the goals established by the President under subsection (a) and shall include, in each summary and analysis required under <ref>section 17505 of this title</ref>, a statement specifying the reductions in expenditures by executive agencies, including the Department of Defense, achieved under those goals.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1285</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 17508.</num>
<heading> Compliance</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Administrator of General Services</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator of General Services shall comply with and be subject to this chapter with regard to all motor vehicles that are used within the General Services Administration for official purposes.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Managers of Other Motor Pools</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This chapter with respect to motor vehicles from the Interagency Fleet Management System shall be complied with by the executive agencies to which such motor vehicles are assigned.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1285</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 17509.</num>
<heading> Applicability</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Priority in Reducing Headquarters Use</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The heads of executive agencies shall give first priority to meeting the goals established by the President under <ref>section 17507(a) of this title</ref> by reducing the costs of administrative motor vehicles used at the headquarters and regional headquarters of executive agencies, rather than by reducing the costs of motor vehicles used by line agency personnel working in agency field operations or activities.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations, Standards, and Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The President shall require the Administrator of General Services, in cooperation with the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, to prescribe appropriate regulations, standards, and definitions to ensure that executive agencies meet the goals established under <ref>section 17507(a) of this title</ref> in the manner prescribed by subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1285</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 17510.</num>
<heading> Cooperation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director of the Office of Management and Budget and the Administrator of General Services shall cooperate closely in the implementation of this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1286</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>