<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 11—</num>
<heading>SELECTION OF ARCHITECTS AND ENGINEERS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1101.</num>
<heading> Policy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The policy of the Federal Government is to publicly announce all requirements for architectural and engineering services and to negotiate contracts for architectural and engineering services on the basis of demonstrated competence and qualification for the type of professional services required and at fair and reasonable prices.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1129</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1102.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter, the following definitions apply:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Agency head</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “agency head” means the head of a department, agency, or bureau of the Federal Government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Architectural and engineering services</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “architectural and engineering services” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> professional services of an architectural or engineering nature, as defined by state law, if applicable, that are required to be performed or approved by a person licensed, registered, or certified to provide the services described in this paragraph;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> professional services of an architectural or engineering nature performed by contract that are associated with research, planning, development, design, construction, alteration, or repair of real property; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> other professional services of an architectural or engineering nature, or incidental services, which members of the architectural and engineering professions (and individuals in their employ) may logically or justifiably perform, including studies, investigations, surveying and mapping, tests, evaluations, consultations, comprehensive planning, program management, conceptual designs, plans and specifications, value engineering, construction phase services, soils engineering, drawing reviews, preparation of operating and maintenance manuals, and other related services.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Firm</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “firm” means an individual, firm, partnership, corporation, association, or other legal entity permitted by law to practice the profession of architecture or engineering.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1129</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1103.</num>
<heading> Selection procedure</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>These procedures apply to the procurement of architectural and engineering services by an agency head.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Statements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The agency head shall encourage firms to submit annually a statement of qualifications and performance data.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Evaluation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For each proposed project, the agency head shall evaluate current statements of qualifications and performance data on file with the agency, together with statements submitted by other firms regarding the proposed project. The agency head shall conduct discussions with at least 3 firms to consider anticipated concepts and compare alternative methods for furnishing services.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Selection</inline>.—</heading>
<content>From the firms with which discussions have been conducted, the agency head shall select, in order of preference, at least 3 firms that the agency head considers most highly qualified to provide the services required. Selection shall be based on criteria established and published by the agency head.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1130</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1104.</num>
<heading> Negotiation of contract</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The agency head shall negotiate a contract for architectural and engineering services at compensation which the agency head determines is fair and reasonable to the Federal Government. In determining fair and reasonable compensation, the agency head shall consider the scope, complexity, professional nature, and estimated value of the services to be rendered.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Order of Negotiation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The agency head shall attempt to negotiate a contract, as provided in subsection (a), with the most highly qualified firm selected under <ref>section 1103 of this title</ref>. If the agency head is unable to negotiate a satisfactory contract with the firm, the agency head shall formally terminate negotiations and then undertake negotiations with the next most qualified of the selected firms, continuing the process until an agreement is reached. If the agency head is unable to negotiate a satisfactory contract with any of the selected firms, the agency head shall select additional firms in order of their competence and qualification and continue negotiations in accordance with this section until an agreement is reached.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1130</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>