<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 95—</num>
<heading>WASHINGTON AQUEDUCT AND OTHER PUBLIC WORKS IN THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 9501.</num>
<heading> Chief of Engineers</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Superintendence Duties.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Washington aqueduct and other public works and improvements in the district of columbia</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Chief of Engineers has the immediate superintendence of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Washington Aqueduct, together with all rights, appurtenances, and fixtures connected with the Aqueduct and belonging to the Federal Government; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> all other public works and improvements in the District of Columbia in which the Government has an interest and which are not otherwise specially provided for by law.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Obeying regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In carrying out paragraph (1), the Chief of Engineers shall obey regulations the President prescribes, through the Secretary of the Army.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">No Increase in Compensation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Chief of Engineers shall not receive additional compensation for the services required under this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Office</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Chief of Engineers shall be furnished an office in one of the public buildings in the District of Columbia, as the Administrator of General Services directs, and shall be supplied by the Federal Government with stationery, instruments, books, and furniture which may be required for the performance of the duties of the Chief of Engineers.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1233</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9502.</num>
<heading> Authority of Chief of Engineers</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Chief of Engineers and necessary assistants may use all lawful means to carry out their duties.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Supply of Water in District of Columbia.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Providing water</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Chief of Engineers has complete control over the Washington Aqueduct to regulate the manner in which the authorities of the District of Columbia may tap the supply of water to the inhabitants of the District of Columbia.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Stoppage of water flow</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Chief of Engineers shall stop the authorities of the District of Columbia from tapping the supply of water when the supply is no more than adequate to the wants of the public buildings and grounds.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appeal of decision</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The decision of the Chief of Engineers on all questions concerning the supply of water under this subsection may be appealed only to the Secretary of the Army.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1234</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9503.</num>
<heading> Record of property</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Chief of Engineers shall keep in the office a complete record of all land and other property connected with or belonging to the Washington Aqueduct and other public works under the charge of the Chief of Engineers, together with accurate plans and surveys of the public grounds and reservations in the District of Columbia.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1234</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9504.</num>
<heading> Reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As superintendent of the Washington Aqueduct, the Chief of Engineers annually shall submit to the Secretary of the Army, within nine months after the end of the fiscal year, a report of the Chief of Engineers’ operations for that year and a report of the condition, progress, repairs, casualties, and expenditures of the Washington Aqueduct and other public works under the charge of the Chief of Engineers.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1234</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9505.</num>
<heading> Paying for main pipes</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Federal Government</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Federal Government shall only pay for the number of main pipes of the Washington Aqueduct needed to furnish public buildings, offices, and grounds with the necessary supply of water.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">District of Columbia</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The District of Columbia shall pay the cost of any main pipe of the Washington Aqueduct which supplies water to the inhabitants of the District of Columbia, in the manner provided by law.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1234</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9506.</num>
<heading> Civil penalty</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A person that, without the consent of the Chief of Engineers, taps or opens the mains or pipes laid by the Federal Government is liable to the Government for a civil penalty of at least $50 and not more than $500.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1234</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9507.</num>
<heading> Control of expenditures</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Unless expressly provided for by law, the Secretary of the Army shall direct the expenditure of amounts appropriated for the Washington Aqueduct and for other public works in the District of Columbia.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1235</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>