<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 153—</num>
<heading>REGIONAL COMMISSIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 15301.</num>
<heading> Establishment, membership, and employees</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>There are established the following regional Commissions:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Southeast Crescent Regional Commission.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Southwest Border Regional Commission.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Northern Border Regional Commission.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Great Lakes Authority.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The Mid-Atlantic Regional Commission.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The Southern New England Regional Commission.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Membership.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Federal and state members</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each Commission shall be composed of the following members:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A Federal Cochairperson, to be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Governor of each participating State in the region of the Commission.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Alternate members.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Alternate federal cochairperson</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The President shall appoint an alternate Federal Cochairperson for each Commission. The alternate Federal Cochairperson, when not actively serving as an alternate for the Federal Cochairperson, shall perform such functions and duties as are delegated by the Federal Cochairperson.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">State alternates</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The State member of a participating State may have a single alternate, who shall be appointed by the Governor of the State from among the members of the Governor’s cabinet or personal staff.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Voting.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An alternate member shall vote in the case of the absence, death, disability, removal, or resignation of the Federal or State member for which the alternate member is an alternate.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">State alternates</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the alternate State member is unable to vote in accordance with clause (i), the alternate State member may delegate voting authority to a designee, subject to the condition that the executive director shall be notified, in writing, of the designation not less than 1 week before the applicable vote is to take place.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Cochairpersons</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A Commission shall be headed by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Federal Cochairperson, who shall serve as a liaison between the Federal Government and the Commission; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a State Cochairperson, who shall be a Governor of a participating State in the region and shall be elected by the State members for a term of not less than 1 year.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consecutive terms</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A State member may not be elected to serve as State Cochairperson for more than 2 consecutive terms.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Compensation.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Federal cochairpersons</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each Federal Cochairperson shall be compensated by the Federal Government at level III of the Executive Schedule as set out in <ref>section 5314 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Alternate federal cochairpersons</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each Federal Cochairperson’s alternate shall be compensated by the Federal Government at level V of the Executive Schedule as set out in <ref>section 5316 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">State members and alternates</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each State member and alternate shall be compensated by the State that they represent at the rate established by the laws of that State.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Executive Director and Staff.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A Commission shall appoint and fix the compensation of an executive director and such other personnel as are necessary to enable the Commission to carry out its duties. Compensation under this paragraph may not exceed the maximum rate of basic pay established for the Senior Executive Service under <ref>section 5382 of title 5</ref>, including any applicable locality-based comparability payment that may be authorized under section 5304(h)(2)(C) of that title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Executive director</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The executive director shall be responsible for carrying out the administrative duties of the Commission, directing the Commission staff, and such other duties as the Commission may assign.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">No Federal Employee Status</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No member, alternate, officer, or employee of a Commission (other than the Federal Cochairperson, the alternate Federal Cochairperson, staff of the Federal Cochairperson, and any Federal employee detailed to the Commission) shall be considered to be a Federal employee for any purpose.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Succession</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to the time limitations under <ref>section 3346 of title 5</ref>, the Federal Cochairperson may designate an employee of the Commission to perform the functions and duties of the office of the Federal Cochairperson temporarily in an acting capacity if both the Federal Cochairperson and the alternate Federal Cochairperson die, resign, or otherwise are unable to perform the functions and duties of their offices.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title XIV, § 14217(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1469</ref>, and <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title XIV, § 14217(a)(2), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2231; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title VI, § 6304(f)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4752</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–328, div. O, title IV, § 401(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 5228</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–272, div. B, title II</ref>, §§ 2242(a), 2249(a), 2250(a), <date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 3202</ref>, 3209.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 15302.</num>
<heading> Decisions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirements for Approval</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in section 15304(c)(3), decisions by the Commission shall require the affirmative vote of the Federal Cochairperson and a majority of the State members or alternate State members, including designees (exclusive of members representing States delinquent under section 15304(c)(3)(C)).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consultation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In matters coming before the Commission, the Federal Cochairperson shall, to the extent practicable, consult with the Federal departments and agencies having an interest in the subject matter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Quorums.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to paragraph (2), a Commission shall determine what constitutes a quorum for meetings of the Commission.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Any quorum for meetings of a Commission shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Federal Cochairperson or the alternate Federal Cochairperson; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a majority of State members or alternate State members, including designees (exclusive of members representing States delinquent under section 15304(c)(3)(C)).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Projects and Grant Proposals</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The approval of project and grant proposals shall be a responsibility of each Commission and shall be carried out in accordance with section 15503.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title XIV, § 14217(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1470</ref>, and <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title XIV, § 14217(a)(2), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2232; amended <ref>Pub. L. 118–272, div. B, title II, § 2242(b)</ref>, <date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 3202</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 15303.</num>
<heading> Functions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A Commission shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> assess the needs and assets of its region based on available research, demonstration projects, investigations, assessments, and evaluations of the region prepared by Federal, State, and local agencies, universities, local development districts, and other nonprofit groups;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> develop, on a continuing basis, comprehensive and coordinated economic and infrastructure development strategies to establish priorities and approve grants for the economic development of its region, giving due consideration to other Federal, State, and local planning and development activities in the region;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this section, and after taking into account State plans developed under section 15502, establish priorities in an economic and infrastructure development plan for its region, including 5-year regional outcome targets;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> enhance the capacity of, and provide support for, local development districts in its region; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> if no local development district exists in an area in a participating State in the region, foster the creation of a local development district;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> encourage private investment in industrial, commercial, and other economic development projects in its region;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> cooperate with and assist State governments with the preparation of economic and infrastructure development plans and programs for participating States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> formulate and recommend to the Governors and legislatures of States that participate in the Commission forms of interstate cooperation and, where appropriate, international cooperation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> work with State and local agencies in developing appropriate model legislation to enhance local and regional economic development.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title XIV, § 14217(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1470</ref>, and <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title XIV, § 14217(a)(2), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2232.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 15304.</num>
<heading> Administrative powers and expenses</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Powers</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In carrying out its duties under this subtitle, a Commission may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> hold such hearings, sit and act at such times and places, take such testimony, receive such evidence, and print or otherwise reproduce and distribute a description of the proceedings and reports on actions by the Commission as the Commission considers appropriate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> authorize, through the Federal or State Cochairperson or any other member of the Commission designated by the Commission, the administration of oaths if the Commission determines that testimony should be taken or evidence received under oath;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> request from any Federal, State, or local agency such information as may be available to or procurable by the agency that may be of use to the Commission in carrying out the duties of the Commission;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> adopt, amend, and repeal bylaws and rules governing the conduct of business and the performance of duties by the Commission;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> request the head of any Federal agency, State agency, or local government to detail to the Commission such personnel as the Commission requires to carry out its duties, each such detail to be without loss of seniority, pay, or other employee status, which may be done without a requirement for the Commission to reimburse the agency or local government;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> provide for coverage of Commission employees in a suitable retirement and employee benefit system by making arrangements or entering into contracts with any participating State government or otherwise providing retirement and other employee coverage;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> accept, use, and dispose of gifts or donations or services or real, personal, tangible, or intangible property;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> collect fees for services provided and retain and expend such fees;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> enter into and perform such contracts, cooperative agreements, or other transactions as are necessary to carry out Commission duties, including any contracts or cooperative agreements with a department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States, a State (including a political subdivision, agency, or instrumentality of the State), or a person, firm, association, or corporation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> establish and maintain a central office at such location in its region as the Commission may select.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Federal Agency Cooperation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A Federal agency shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> cooperate with a Commission; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provide, to the extent practicable, on request of the Federal Cochairperson, appropriate assistance in carrying out this subtitle, in accordance with applicable Federal laws (including regulations).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Administrative Expenses.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subject to paragraph (2), the administrative expenses of a Commission shall be paid—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> by the Federal Government, in an amount equal to 50 percent of the administrative expenses of the Commission; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> by the States participating in the Commission, in an amount equal to 50 percent of the administrative expenses.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Expenses of the federal cochairperson</inline>.—</heading>
<content>All expenses of the Federal Cochairperson, including expenses of the alternate and staff of the Federal Cochairperson, shall be paid by the Federal Government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">State share.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to subparagraph (B), the share of administrative expenses of a Commission to be paid by each State of the Commission shall be determined by a majority vote of the State members of the Commission.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">No federal participation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Federal Cochairperson shall not participate or vote in any decision under subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Delinquent states</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>During any period in which a State is more than 1 year delinquent in payment of the State’s share of administrative expenses of the Commission under this subsection—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> no assistance under this subtitle shall be provided to the State (including assistance to a political subdivision or a resident of the State) for any project not approved as of the date of the commencement of the delinquency; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> no member of the Commission from the State shall participate or vote in any action by the Commission.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Effect on assistance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A State’s share of administrative expenses of a Commission under this subsection shall not be taken into consideration when determining the amount of assistance provided to the State under this subtitle.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title XIV, § 14217(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1471</ref>, and <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title XIV, § 14217(a)(2), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2233; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title VI, § 6304(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4749</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–272, div. B, title II, § 2242(c)</ref>, <date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 3203</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 15305.</num>
<heading> Meetings</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Initial Meeting</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each Commission shall hold an initial meeting not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Meeting</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each Commission shall conduct at least 1 meeting each year with—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Federal Cochairperson; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> at least a majority of the State members or alternate State members (including designees) present in-person or via electronic means.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Additional Meetings</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each Commission shall conduct additional meetings at such times as it determines and may conduct such meetings by electronic means.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title XIV, § 14217(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1473</ref>, and <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title XIV, § 14217(a)(2), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2235; amended <ref>Pub. L. 118–272, div. B, title II, § 2242(d)</ref>, <date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 3203</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 15306.</num>
<heading> Personal financial interests</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Conflicts of Interest.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">No role allowed</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Except as permitted by paragraph (2), an individual who is a State member or alternate, or an officer or employee of a Commission, shall not participate personally and substantially as a member, alternate, officer, or employee of the Commission, through decision, approval, disapproval, recommendation, request for a ruling, or other determination, contract, claim, controversy, or other matter in which, to the individual’s knowledge, any of the following has a financial interest:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The individual.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The individual’s spouse, minor child, or partner.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> An organization (except a State or political subdivision of a State) in which the individual is serving as an officer, director, trustee, partner, or employee.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Any person or organization with whom the individual is negotiating or has any arrangement concerning prospective employment.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Paragraph (1) shall not apply if the individual, in advance of the proceeding, application, request for a ruling or other determination, contract, claim controversy, or other particular matter presenting a potential conflict of interest—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> advises the Commission of the nature and circumstances of the matter presenting the conflict of interest;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> makes full disclosure of the financial interest; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> receives a written decision of the Commission that the interest is not so substantial as to be considered likely to affect the integrity of the services that the Commission may expect from the individual.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Violation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An individual violating this subsection shall be fined under title 18, imprisoned for not more than 1 year, or both.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">State Member or Alternate</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A State member or alternate member may not receive any salary, or any contribution to, or supplementation of, salary, for services on a Commission from a source other than the State of the member or alternate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Detailed Employees.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No person detailed to serve a Commission shall receive any salary, or any contribution to, or supplementation of, salary, for services provided to the Commission from any source other than the State, local, or intergovernmental department or agency from which the person was detailed to the Commission.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Violation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any person that violates this subsection shall be fined under title 18, imprisoned not more than 1 year, or both.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Federal Cochairman, Alternate to Federal Cochairman, and Federal Officers and Employees</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Federal Cochairman, the alternate to the Federal Cochairman, and any Federal officer or employee detailed to duty with the Commission are not subject to this section but remain subject to sections 202 through 209 of title 18.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rescission</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A Commission may declare void any contract, loan, or grant of or by the Commission in relation to which the Commission determines that there has been a violation of any provision under subsection (a)(1), (b), or (c), or any of the provisions of sections 202 through 209 of title 18.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title XIV, § 14217(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1473</ref>, and <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title XIV, § 14217(a)(2), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2235.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 15307.</num>
<heading> Tribal participation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Governments of Indian tribes in the region of the Southwest Border Regional Commission shall be allowed to participate in matters before that Commission in the same manner and to the same extent as State agencies and instrumentalities in the region.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title XIV, § 14217(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1474</ref>, and <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title XIV, § 14217(a)(2), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2236.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 15308.</num>
<heading> Transfer of funds among Federal agencies</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to subsection (c), for purposes of this subtitle, each Commission may transfer funds to and accept transfers of funds from other Federal agencies.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transfer of Funds to Other Federal Agencies</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Funds made available to a Commission may be transferred to other Federal agencies if the funds are used consistently with the purposes for which the funds were specifically authorized and appropriated.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transfer of Funds From Other Federal Agencies</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Funds may be transferred to any Commission under this section if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the statutory authority for the funds provided by the Federal agency does not expressly prohibit use of funds for authorities being carried out by a Commission; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Federal agency that provides the funds determines that the activities for which the funds are to be used are otherwise eligible for funding under such a statutory authority.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 118–272, div. B, title II, § 2243(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 3203</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 15309.</num>
<heading> Annual report</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 180 days after the last day of each fiscal year, each Commission shall submit to the President and Congress a report on the activities carried out by the Commission under this subtitle in the fiscal year.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contents</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The report shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a description of the criteria used by the Commission to designate counties under section 15702 and a list of the counties designated in each category;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an evaluation of the progress of the Commission in meeting the goals identified in the Commission’s economic and infrastructure development plan under section 15303 and State economic and infrastructure development plans under section 15502; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> any policy recommendations approved by the Commission.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title XIV, § 14217(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1474</ref>, and <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title XIV, § 14217(a)(2), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2236, § 15308; renumbered § 15309 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 118–272, div. B, title II</ref>, §§ 2242(e), 2243(a)(1), <date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 3203</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>