<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 171—</num>
<heading>SAFETY STANDARDS FOR MOTOR VEHICLES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 17101.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter, the following definitions apply:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Federal government</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “Federal Government” includes the government of the District of Columbia.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Motor vehicle</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “motor vehicle” means a vehicle, self-propelled or drawn by mechanical power, designed for use on the highways principally for the transportation of passengers, except a vehicle designed or used for military field training, combat, or tactical purposes.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1279</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 17102.</num>
<heading> Prohibition on acquisition or purchase of motor vehicles by Federal Government</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Federal Government shall not purchase a motor vehicle for use by the Government unless that motor vehicle is equipped with reasonable passenger safety devices that the Administrator of General Services requires. Those devices shall conform with standards the Administrator prescribes under <ref>section 17103 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1279</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 17103.</num>
<heading> Commercial standards for passenger safety devices</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator of General Services shall prescribe and publish in the Federal Register commercial standards for passenger safety devices the Administrator requires under <ref>section 17102 of this title</ref>. Changes in the standards take effect one year and 90 days after the publication of the standards in the Federal Register.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1279</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>