<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 33—</num>
<heading>ACQUISITION, CONSTRUCTION, AND ALTERATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3301.</num>
<heading> Definitions and nonapplication</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Alter</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “alter” includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> preliminary planning, engineering, architectural, legal, fiscal, and economic investigations and studies, surveys, designs, plans, working drawings, specifications, procedures, and other similar actions necessary for the alteration of a public building; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> repairing, remodeling, improving, or extending, or other changes in, a public building.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Construct</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “construct” includes preliminary planning, engineering, architectural, legal, fiscal, and economic investigations and studies, surveys, designs, plans, working drawings, specifications, procedures, and other similar actions necessary for the construction of a public building.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Executive agency</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “executive agency” means an executive department or independent establishment in the executive branch of the Federal Government, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any wholly owned Government corporation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Central-Bank for Cooperatives and the regional banks for cooperatives;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> federal land banks;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> federal intermediate credit banks;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the Government National Mortgage Association.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Federal agency</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “federal agency” means an executive agency or an establishment in the legislative or judicial branch of the Government (except the Senate, the House of Representatives, and the Architect of the Capitol and any activities under the direction of the Architect).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Public building</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “public building”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> means a building, whether for single or multitenant occupancy, and its grounds, approaches, and appurtenances, which is generally suitable for use as office or storage space or both by one or more federal agencies or mixed-ownership Government corporations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> includes—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> federal office buildings;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> post offices;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> customhouses;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> courthouses;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> appraisers stores;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> border inspection facilities;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> warehouses;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> record centers;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ix)</num>
<content> relocation facilities;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(x)</num>
<content> telecommuting centers;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(xi)</num>
<content> similar federal facilities; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(xii)</num>
<content> any other buildings or construction projects the inclusion of which the President considers to be justified in the public interest; but</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> does not include a building or construction project described in subparagraphs (A) and (B)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> that is on the public domain (including that reserved for national forests and other purposes);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> that is on property of the Government in foreign countries;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> that is on Indian and native Eskimo property held in trust by the Government;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> that is on land used in connection with federal programs for agricultural, recreational, and conservation purposes, including research in connection with the programs;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> that is on or used in connection with river, harbor, flood control, reclamation or power projects, for chemical manufacturing or development projects, or for nuclear production, research, or development projects;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> that is on or used in connection with housing and residential projects;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> that is on military installations (including any fort, camp, post, naval training station, airfield, proving ground, military supply depot, military school, or any similar facility of the Department of Defense);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> that is on installations of the Department of Veterans Affairs used for hospital or domiciliary purposes; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ix)</num>
<content> the exclusion of which the President considers to be justified in the public interest.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">United states</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “United States” includes the States of the United States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, and the territories and possessions of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Nonapplication</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This chapter does not apply to the construction of any public building to which section 241(g) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<ref>8 U.S.C. 1231(g)</ref>) or <ref>section 1 of the Act of June 26, 1930</ref> (<ref>19 U.S.C. 68</ref>) applies.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1156</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3302.</num>
<heading> Prohibition on construction of buildings except by Administrator of General Services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Only the Administrator of General Services may construct a public building. The Administrator shall construct a public building in accordance with this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1158</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3303.</num>
<heading> Continuing investigation and survey of public buildings</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Conducted by Administrator</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Administrator of General Services shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> make a continuing investigation and survey of the public buildings needs of the Federal Government so that the Administrator may carry out the duties of the Administrator under this chapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> submit to Congress prospectuses of proposed projects in accordance with section 3307(a) and (b) of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Cooperation with Federal Agencies.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duties of administrator</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In carrying out the duties of the Administrator under this chapter, the Administrator—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall cooperate with all federal agencies in order to keep informed of their needs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> shall advise each federal agency of the program with respect to the agency; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> may request the cooperation and assistance of each federal agency in carrying out duties under this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duty of federal agencies</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each federal agency shall cooperate with, advise, and assist the Administrator in carrying out the duties of the Administrator under this chapter as determined necessary by the Administrator to carry out the purposes of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Request for Identification of Existing Buildings of Historical, Architectural, or Cultural Significance</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>When the Administrator undertakes a survey of the public buildings needs of the Government within a geographical area, the Administrator shall request that, within 60 days, the Advisory Council on Historic Preservation established by <ref>section 304101 of title 54</ref> identify any existing buildings in the geographical area that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> are of historical, architectural, or cultural significance (as defined in <ref>section 3306(a) of this title</ref>); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> whether or not in need of repair, alteration, or addition, would be suitable for acquisition to meet the public buildings needs of the Government.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Standard for Construction and Acquisition of Public Buildings</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In carrying out the duties of the Administrator under this chapter, the Administrator shall provide for the construction and acquisition of public buildings equitably throughout the United States with due regard to the comparative urgency of the need for each particular building. In developing plans for new buildings, the Administrator shall give due consideration to excellence of architecture and design.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1158</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 5(j)(5)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3269</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3304.</num>
<heading> Acquisition of buildings and sites</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator of General Services may acquire, by purchase, condemnation, donation, exchange, or otherwise, any building and its site which the Administrator decides is necessary to carry out the duties of the Administrator under this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Acquisition of Land or Interest in Land for Use as Sites</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator may acquire, by purchase, condemnation, donation, exchange, or otherwise, land or an interest in land the Administrator considers necessary for use as sites, or additions to sites, for public buildings authorized to be constructed or altered under this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Public Buildings Used for Post Office Purposes</inline>.—</heading>
<content>When any part of a public building is to be used for post office purposes, the Administrator shall act jointly with the United States Postal Service in selecting the town or city where the building is to be constructed, and in selecting the site in the town or city for the building.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Solicitation of Proposals for Sale, Donation, or Exchange of Real Property</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>When the Administrator is to acquire a site under subsection (b), the Administrator, if the Administrator considers it necessary, by public advertisement may solicit proposals for the sale, donation, or exchange of real property to the Federal Government to be used as the site. In selecting a site under subsection (b) the Administrator (with the concurrence of the United States Postal Service if any part of the public building to be constructed on the site is to be used for post office purposes) may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> select the site that the Administrator believes is the most advantageous to the Government, all factors considered; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> acquire the site without regard to division C (except sections 3302, 3501(b), 3509, 3906, 4710, and 4711) of subtitle I of title 41.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1158</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–178, § 3(1)</ref>, <date date="2003-12-15">Dec. 15, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2640</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 5</ref>(<i>l</i>)(15), <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3852</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3305.</num>
<heading> Construction and alteration of buildings</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Construction.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Replacement of existing buildings</inline>.—</heading>
<content>When the Administrator of General Services considers it to be in the best interest of the Federal Government to construct a new public building to take the place of an existing public building, the Administrator may demolish the existing building and use the site on which it is located for the site of the proposed public building. If the Administrator believes that it is more advantageous to construct the public building on a different site in the same city, the Administrator may exchange the building and site, or the site, for another site, or may sell the building and site in accordance with subtitle I of this title and division C (except sections 3302, 3501(b), 3509, 3906, 4710, and 4711) of subtitle I of title 41.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Sale or exchange of sites</inline>.—</heading>
<content>When the Administrator decides that a site acquired for the construction of a public building is not suitable for that purpose, the Administrator may exchange the site for another site, or may sell it in accordance with subtitle I of this title and division C (except sections 3302, 3501(b), 3509, 3906, 4710, and 4711) of subtitle I of title 41.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Committee approval required</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This subsection does not permit the Administrator to use any land as a site for a public building if the project has not been approved in accordance with <ref>section 3307 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Alteration of Buildings.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority to alter buildings and acquire land</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Administrator may—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> alter any public building; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> acquire in accordance with section 3304(b)–(d) of this title land necessary to carry out the alteration.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Committee approval not required.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Threshold amount</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Approval under <ref>section 3307 of this title</ref> is not required for any alteration and acquisition authorized by this subsection for which the estimated maximum cost does not exceed $1,500,000.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Dollar amount adjustment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator annually may adjust the dollar amount referred to in subparagraph (A) to reflect a percentage increase or decrease in construction costs during the prior calendar year, as determined by the composite index of construction costs of the Department of Commerce. Any adjustment shall be expeditiously reported to the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Construction or Alteration by Contract</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator may carry out any construction or alteration authorized by this chapter by contract if the Administrator considers it to be most advantageous to the Government.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1159</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 5</ref>(<i>l</i>)(16), <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3852</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3306.</num>
<heading> Accommodating federal agencies</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Commercial activities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “commercial activities” includes the operations of restaurants, food stores, craft stores, dry goods stores, financial institutions, and display facilities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Cultural activities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “cultural activities” includes film, dramatic, dance, and musical presentations, and fine art exhibits, whether or not those activities are intended to make a profit.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Educational activities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The terms “educational activities” includes the operations of libraries, schools, day care centers, laboratories, and lecture and demonstration facilities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Historical, architectural, or cultural significance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “historical, architectural, or cultural significance” includes buildings listed or eligible to be listed on the National Register established under chapter 3021 of title 54.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Recreational activities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “recreational activities” includes the operations of gymnasiums and related facilities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Unit of general local government</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “unit of general local government” means a city, county, town, parish, village, or other general-purpose political subdivision of a State.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duties of Administrator</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>To carry out the duties of the Administrator of General Services under sections 581(h), 584(b), 3303(c), and 3307(b)(3) and (5) of this title and under any other authority with respect to constructing, operating, maintaining, altering, and otherwise managing or acquiring space necessary to accommodate federal agencies and to accomplish the purposes of sections 581(h), 584(b), 3303(c), and 3307(b)(3) and (5), the Administrator shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> acquire and utilize space in suitable buildings of historical, architectural, or cultural significance, unless use of the space would not prove feasible and prudent compared with available alternatives;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> encourage the location of commercial, cultural, educational, and recreational facilities and activities in public buildings;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> provide and maintain space, facilities, and activities, to the extent practicable, that encourage public access to, and stimulate public pedestrian traffic around, into, and through, public buildings, permitting cooperative improvements to and uses of the area between the building and the street, so that the activities complement and supplement commercial, cultural, educational, and recreational resources in the neighborhood of public buildings; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> encourage the public use of public buildings for cultural, educational, and recreational activities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consultation and Solicitation of Comments</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In carrying out the duties under subsection (b), the Administrator shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> consult with chief executive officers of the States, areawide agencies established pursuant to title II of the Demonstration Cities and Metropolitan Development Act of 1966 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 3331</ref> et seq.) and <ref>section 6506 of title 31</ref>, and chief executive officers of those units of general local government in each area served by an existing or proposed public building; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> solicit the comments of other community leaders and members of the general public as the Administrator considers appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1160</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 5(j)(6)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3269</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3307.</num>
<heading> Congressional approval of proposed projects</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Resolutions Required Before Appropriations May Be Made</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The following appropriations may be made only if the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives adopt resolutions approving the purpose for which the appropriation is made:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> An appropriation to construct, alter, or acquire any building to be used as a public building which involves a total expenditure in excess of $1,500,000, so that the equitable distribution of public buildings throughout the United States with due regard for the comparative urgency of need for the buildings, except as provided in <ref>section 3305(b) of this title</ref>, is ensured.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> An appropriation to lease any space at an average annual rental in excess of $1,500,000 for use for public purposes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> An appropriation to alter any building, or part of the building, which is under lease by the Federal Government for use for a public purpose if the cost of the alteration will exceed $750,000.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transmission to Congress of Prospectus of Proposed Project</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>To secure consideration for the approval referred to in subsection (a), the Administrator of General Services (referred to in this section as the “Administrator”) shall transmit to Congress a prospectus of the proposed facility, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a brief description of the building to be constructed, altered, or acquired, or the space to be leased, under this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the location of the building or space to be leased and an estimate of the maximum cost to the Government of the facility to be constructed, altered, or acquired, or the space to be leased;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a comprehensive plan for providing space for all Government officers and employees in the locality of the proposed facility or the space to be leased, having due regard for suitable space which may continue to be available in existing Government-owned or occupied buildings, especially those buildings that enhance the architectural, historical, social, cultural, and economic environment of the locality;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> with respect to any project for the construction, alteration, or acquisition of any building, a statement by the Administrator that suitable space owned by the Government is not available and that suitable rental space is not available at a price commensurate with that to be afforded through the proposed action;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> a statement by the Administrator of the economic and other justifications for not acquiring a building identified to the Administrator under <ref>section 3303(c) of this title</ref> as suitable for the public building needs of the Government;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> a statement of rents and other housing costs currently being paid by the Government for federal agencies to be housed in the building to be constructed, altered, or acquired, or the space to be leased;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> with respect to any prospectus for the construction, alteration, or acquisition of any building or space to be leased, an estimate of the future energy performance of the building or space and a specific description of the use of energy efficient and renewable energy systems, including photovoltaic systems, in carrying out the project;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> a statement of how the proposed project is consistent with the standards and criteria developed under section 11(b) of the Federal Assets Sale and Transfer Act of 2016;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> information on any space occupied by the relevant agency in the geographical area of the proposed facility, including uses, utilization rates, any proposed consolidations, and, if not proposed to be consolidated, a justification for such determination;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> a statement by the Administrator of whether the public building needs of the Government for the proposed space to be leased were formerly met by a federally owned building, including any building identified for disposal or sale; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> details on actual utilization rates, including number of personnel assigned to the facility, number of personnel expected to work in-person at the facility and whether all personnel identified reflect filled and authorized positions.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Increase of Estimated Maximum Cost</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The estimated maximum cost of any project approved under this section as set forth in any prospectus may be increased by an amount equal to any percentage increase, as determined by the Administrator, in construction or alteration costs from the date the prospectus is transmitted to Congress. The increase authorized by this subsection may not exceed 10 percent of the estimated maximum cost. The Administrator shall notify, in writing, the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate of any increase of more than 5 percent of an estimated maximum cost or of any increase or decrease in the scope or size of a project of 5 or more percent. Such notification shall include an explanation regarding any such increase or decrease. The scope or size of a project shall not increase or decrease by more than 10 percent unless an amended prospectus is submitted and approved pursuant to this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rescission of Approval</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If an appropriation is not made within one year after the date a project for construction, alteration, or acquisition is approved under subsection (a), the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate or the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives by resolution may rescind its approval before an appropriation is made.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Emergency Leases by the Administrator</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section does not prevent the Administrator from entering into emergency leases during any period declared by the President to require emergency leasing authority. An emergency lease may not be for more than 180 days without approval of a prospectus for the lease in accordance with subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Minimum Performance Requirements for Leased Space</inline>.—</heading>
<content>With respect to space to be leased, the Administrator shall include, to the maximum extent practicable, minimum performance requirements requiring energy efficiency and the use of renewable energy.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Leasing Certain Space.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Administrator may not lease space to accommodate any of the following if the average rental cost of leasing the space will exceed $1,500,000:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Computer and telecommunications operations.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Secure or sensitive activities related to the national defense or security, except when it would be inappropriate to locate those activities in a public building or other facility identified with the Government.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> A permanent courtroom, judicial chamber, or administrative office for any United States court.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Administrator may lease space with respect to which paragraph (1) applies if the Administrator—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> decides, for reasons set forth in writing, that leasing the space is necessary to meet requirements which cannot be met in public buildings; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> submits the reasons to the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Dollar Amount Adjustment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator annually may adjust any dollar amount referred to in this section to reflect a percentage increase or decrease in construction costs during the prior calendar year, as determined by the composite index of construction costs of the Department of Commerce. Any adjustment shall be expeditiously reported to the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notification Required</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For each project approved under this section, the Administrator shall notify, in writing, the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate of any project milestones that are accomplished, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the solicitation and award of design and construction services;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the completion of any actions required for the project pursuant to the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> any ceremonies for the beginning or completion of the project;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> a naming ceremony for the project; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the completion of the project.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Expiration of Committee Resolutions.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Unless a lease is awarded or a construction, alteration, repair, design, or acquisition project is initiated not later than 5 years after the resolution approvals adopted by the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate pursuant to subsection (a), the resolutions shall be deemed expired.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Application</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This subsection shall only apply to resolutions approved after the date of enactment of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1161</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–140, title III, § 323(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2007-12-19">Dec. 19, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 1589</ref>, 1590; <ref>Pub. L. 114–287, § 17</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1476</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–272, div. B, title III</ref>, §§ 2304(a), (c), (f), 2310, <date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 3223</ref>, 3224, 3227.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3308.</num>
<heading> Architectural or engineering services</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Employment by Administrator</inline>.—</heading>
<content>When the Administrator of General Services decides it to be necessary, the Administrator may employ, by contract or otherwise, without regard to chapters 33 and 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5, civil service rules and regulations, or section 6101(b) to (d) of title 41, the services of established architectural or engineering corporations, firms, or individuals, to the extent the Administrator may require those services for any public building authorized to be constructed or altered under this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Employment on Permanent Basis Not Permitted</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A corporation, firm, or individual shall not be employed under authority of subsection (a) on a permanent basis.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Responsibility of Administrator</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, the Administrator is responsible for all construction authorized by this chapter, including the interpretation of construction contracts, approval of material and workmanship supplied under a construction contract, approval of changes in the construction contract, certification of vouchers for payments due the contractor, and final settlement of the contract.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1163</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 5</ref>(<i>l</i>)(17), <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3852</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3309.</num>
<heading> Buildings and sites in the District of Columbia</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The purposes of this chapter shall be carried out in the District of Columbia as nearly as may be practicable in harmony with the plan of Peter Charles L’Enfant. Public buildings shall be constructed or altered to combine architectural beauty with practical utility.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Closing of Streets and Alleys</inline>.—</heading>
<content>When the Administrator of General Services decides that constructing or altering a public building under this chapter in the District of Columbia requires using contiguous squares as a site for the building, parts of streets that lie between the squares, and alleys that intersect the squares, may be closed and vacated if agreed to by the Administrator, the Council of the District of Columbia, and the National Capital Planning Commission. Those streets and alleys become part of the site.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Consultations Prior to Acquisitions.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">With house office building commission</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator must consult with the House Office Building Commission created by the Act of <date date="1907-03-04">March 4, 1907</date> (ch. 2918, <ref>34 Stat. 1365</ref>), before the Administrator may acquire land located south of Independence Avenue, between Third Street SW and Eleventh Street SE, in the District of Columbia, for use as a site or an addition to a site.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">With architect of capitol</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator must consult with the Architect of the Capitol before the Administrator may acquire land located in the area extending from the United States Capitol Grounds to Eleventh Street NE and SE and bounded by Independence Avenue on the south and G Street NE on the north, in the District of Columbia, for use as a site or an addition to a site.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contracts for Events in Stadium</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding the District of Columbia Stadium Act of 1957 (<ref>Public Law 85–300</ref>, <ref>71 Stat. 619</ref>) or any other provision of law, the Armory Board may make contracts to conduct events in Robert F. Kennedy Stadium.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1163</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3310.</num>
<heading> Special rules for leased buildings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For any building to be constructed for lease to, and for predominant use by, the Federal Government, the Administrator of General Services—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> notwithstanding <ref>section 585(a)(1) of this title</ref>, shall not make any agreement or undertake any commitment which will result in the construction of the building until the Administrator has established detailed specification requirements for the building;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> may acquire a leasehold interest in the building only by the use of competitive procedures required by sections 3105, 3301, and 3303 to 3305 of title 41;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> shall include in the solicitation for any lease requiring a prospectus under section 3307 an evaluation factor considering the extent to which the offeror will promote energy efficiency and the use of renewable energy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> shall inspect every building during construction to establish that the specifications established for the building are complied with;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> on completion of the building, shall evaluate the building to determine the extent of failure to comply with the specifications referred to in clause (1); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> shall ensure that any contract entered into for the building shall contain provisions permitting a reduction of rent during any period when the building is not in compliance with the specifications.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1164</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–140, title III, § 323(d)</ref>, <date date="2007-12-19">Dec. 19, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 1591</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 5</ref>(<i>l</i>)(18), <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3852</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3311.</num>
<heading> State administration of criminal and health and safety laws</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">When the Administrator of General Services considers it desirable, the Administrator may assign to a State or a territory or possession of the United States any part of the authority of the Federal Government to administer criminal laws and health and safety laws with respect to land or an interest in land under the control of the Administrator and located in the State, territory, or possession. Assignment of authority under this section may be accomplished by filing with the chief executive officer of the State, territory, or possession a notice of assignment to take effect on acceptance, or in another manner as may be prescribed by the laws of the State, territory, or possession in which the land or interest is located.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1164</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3312.</num>
<heading> Compliance with nationally recognized codes</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Application.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section applies to any project for construction or alteration of a building for which amounts are first appropriated for a fiscal year beginning after <date date="1989-09-30">September 30, 1989</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">National security waiver</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section does not apply to a building for which the Administrator of General Services or the head of the federal agency authorized to construct or alter the building decides that the application of this section to the building would adversely affect national security. A decision under this subsection is not subject to administrative or judicial review.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Building Codes</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each building constructed or altered by the General Services Administration or any other federal agency shall be constructed or altered, to the maximum extent feasible as determined by the Administrator or the head of the federal agency, in compliance with one of the nationally recognized model building codes and with other applicable nationally recognized codes, including electrical codes, fire and life safety codes, and plumbing codes, as the Administrator decides is appropriate. In carrying out this subsection, the Administrator or the head of the federal agency shall use the latest edition of the nationally recognized codes.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Zoning Laws</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each building constructed or altered by the Administration or any other federal agency shall be constructed or altered only after consideration of all requirements (except procedural requirements) of the following laws of a State or a political subdivision of a State, which would apply to the building if it were not a building constructed or altered by a federal agency:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Zoning laws.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Laws relating to landscaping, open space, minimum distance of a building from the property line, maximum height of a building, historic preservation, esthetic qualities of a building, and other similar laws.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Cooperation With State and Local Officials.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">State and local government consultation, review, and inspections</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>To meet the requirements of subsections (b) and (c), the Administrator or the head of the federal agency authorized to construct or alter the building—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in preparing plans for the building, shall consult with appropriate officials of the State or political subdivision of a State, or both, in which the building will be located;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> on request shall submit the plans in a timely manner to the officials for review by the officials for a reasonable period of time not exceeding 30 days; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> shall permit inspection by the officials during construction or alteration of the building, in accordance with the customary schedule of inspections for construction or alteration of buildings in the locality, if the officials provide to the Administrator or the head of the federal agency—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a copy of the schedule before construction of the building is begun; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> reasonable notice of their intention to conduct any inspection before conducting the inspection.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on responsibilities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section does not impose an obligation on any State or political subdivision to take any action under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">State and Local Government Recommendations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Appropriate officials of a State or political subdivision of a State may make recommendations to the Administrator or the head of the federal agency authorized to construct or alter a building concerning measures necessary to meet the requirements of subsections (b) and (c). The officials also may make recommendations to the Administrator or the head of the federal agency concerning measures which should be taken in the construction or alteration of the building to take into account local conditions. The Administrator or the head of the agency shall give due consideration to the recommendations.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Effect of Noncompliance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An action may not be brought against the Federal Government and a fine or penalty may not be imposed against the Government for failure to meet the requirements of subsection (b), (c), or (d) or for failure to carry out any recommendation under subsection (e).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Liability</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Government and its contractors shall not be required to pay any amount for any action a State or a political subdivision of a State takes to carry out this section, including reviewing plans, carrying out on-site inspections, issuing building permits, and making recommendations.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1165</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3313.</num>
<heading> Procurement of life-cycle cost effective and energy efficient lighting systems</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Administrator</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “Administrator” means the Administrator of General Services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Lighting system</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “lighting system” means the elements required to maintain a desired light level, including lamps, light fixtures, fixture distribution, sensors and control technologies, interior design elements, and daylighting sources.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Procurement.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>To the maximum extent practicable, the Administrator shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> procure the most life-cycle cost effective and energy efficient lighting systems; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> ensure that procurements after the date of enactment of the BRIGHT Act of lighting systems or the individual components of lighting systems maximize life-cycle cost effectiveness and energy efficiency.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each public building constructed, altered, acquired, or leased by the Administrator shall be equipped, to the maximum extent practicable as determined by the Administrator, with the most life-cycle cost effective and energy efficient lighting systems for each application.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Maintenance of Public Buildings</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each individual component of a lighting system, including a lamp or fixture, that is replaced by the Administrator in the normal course of maintenance of public buildings shall be replaced, to the maximum extent practicable, with the most life-cycle cost effective and energy efficient lighting system possible for the application.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Considerations.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contracting options</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In carrying out this section, the Administrator shall consider appropriate contracting options for the procurement of the most life-cycle cost effective and energy efficient lighting systems.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Procurement and use</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In making a determination under this section concerning the practicability of procuring and installing the most life-cycle cost effective and energy efficient lighting system, the Administrator shall consider—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the compatibility of the lighting system with existing equipment, including consideration of a cost effective retrofit;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> whether procurement and use of the lighting system could result in interference with productivity;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the aesthetics relating to the use of the lighting system; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> such other factors as the Administrator determines to be appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Life-Cycle Cost Effective</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall use the procedures and methods established under section 544(a) of the National Energy Conservation Policy Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 8254(a)</ref>) in determining whether a lighting system is life-cycle cost effective.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Energy Star</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A lighting system shall be treated as being energy efficient for purposes of this section if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the lighting system or the individual components of the lighting system are certified under the Energy Star program established by section 324A of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 6294a</ref>);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in the case of all light-emitting diode (LED) luminaires, lamps, and systems whose efficacy (lumens per watt) and Color Rendering Index (CRI) meet the Department of Energy requirements for minimum luminaire efficacy and CRI for the Energy Star certification, as verified by an independent third-party testing laboratory that the Administrator and the Secretary of Energy determine conducts its tests according to the procedures and recommendations of the Illuminating Engineering Society of North America, even if the luminaires, lamps, and systems have not received such certification; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the Administrator and the Secretary of Energy have otherwise determined that the lighting system is energy efficient.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Additional Energy Efficient Lighting Designations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency and the Secretary of Energy shall give priority to establishing Energy Star performance criteria or Federal Energy Management Program designations for additional lighting product categories that are appropriate for procurement and use in public buildings.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Guidelines</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall develop guidelines for the procurement and use of energy efficient lighting technologies that contain mercury in child care centers in public buildings.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Applicability of Buy American Act</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Acquisitions carried out pursuant to this section shall be subject to the requirements of the Buy American Act <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002018">1</ref> (<ref>41 U.S.C. 10c</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–140, title III, § 323(c)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="2007-12-19">Dec. 19, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 1590</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 117–202, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-10-17">Oct. 17, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2224</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3314.</num>
<heading> Baby changing facilities in restrooms</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Additional Requirement for the Construction, Alteration, and Acquisition of Public Buildings</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in subsection (b) and subject to any reasonable accommodations that may be made for individuals in accordance with the Americans with Disabilities Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 12101</ref> et seq.) restrooms in a public building shall be equipped with baby changing facilities that the Administrator determines are physically safe, sanitary, and appropriate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exceptions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The requirement under subsection (a) shall not apply—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to a restroom in a public building that is not available or accessible for public use;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to a restroom in a public building that contains clear and conspicuous signage indicating where a restroom with a baby changing table is located on the same floor of such public building;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> if new construction would be required to install a baby changing facility in the public building and the cost of such construction is unfeasible; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to a building not subject to an alteration as set forth in section 3307.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Baby changing facility</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “baby changing facility” means a table or other device suitable for changing the diaper of a child age 3 or under.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Pubic </inline><ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002019">1</ref><inline class="small-caps"> building</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “public building” means a public building as defined in section 3301 and controlled by the Public Building Service of the General Services Administration.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–235, § 2(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2016-10-07">Oct. 7, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 964</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3315.</num>
<heading> Delegation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">When Allowed</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The carrying out of the duties and powers of the Administrator of General Services under this chapter, in accordance with standards the Administrator prescribes—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall, except for the authority contained in <ref>section 3305(b) of this title</ref>, be delegated on request to the appropriate executive agency when the estimated cost of the project does not exceed $100,000; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> may be delegated to the appropriate executive agency when the Administrator determines that delegation will promote efficiency and economy.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">No Exemption From Other Provisions of Chapter</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Delegation under subsection (a) does not exempt the person to whom the delegation is made, or the carrying out of the delegated duty or power, from any other provision of this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1166</ref>, § 3313; <ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 17(g)(3)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1709</ref>; renumbered § 3314, <ref>Pub. L. 110–140, title III, § 323(c)(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="2007-12-19">Dec. 19, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 1590</ref>; renumbered § 3315, <ref>Pub. L. 114–235, § 2(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2016-10-07">Oct. 7, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 964</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3316.</num>
<heading> Report to Congress</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Request by Either House of Congress or Any Committee</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Within a reasonable time after a request of either House of Congress or any committee of Congress, the Administrator of General Services shall submit a report showing the location, space, cost, and status of each public building the construction, alteration, or acquisition of which—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> is to be under authority of this chapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> was uncompleted as of the date of the request, or as of another date the request may designate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Request of Committee on Public Works and Environment or Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator and the United States Postal Service shall make building project surveys requested by resolution by the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate or the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives, and within a reasonable time shall make a report on the survey to Congress. The report shall contain all other information required to be included in a prospectus of the proposed public building project under <ref>section 3307(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1166</ref>, § 3314; renumbered § 3315, <ref>Pub. L. 110–140, title III, § 323(c)(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="2007-12-19">Dec. 19, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 1590</ref>; renumbered § 3316, <ref>Pub. L. 114–235, § 2(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2016-10-07">Oct. 7, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 964</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3317.</num>
<heading> Certain authority not affected</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This chapter does not limit or repeal the authority conferred by law on the United States Postal Service.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1167</ref>, § 3315; renumbered § 3316, <ref>Pub. L. 110–140, title III, § 323(c)(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="2007-12-19">Dec. 19, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 1590</ref>; renumbered § 3317, <ref>Pub. L. 114–235, § 2(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2016-10-07">Oct. 7, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 964</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3318.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002020">1</ref></num>
<heading> Lactation room in public buildings</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appropriate authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “appropriate authority” means the head of a Federal agency, the Architect of the Capitol, or other official authority responsible for the operation of a public building.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered public building</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “covered public building” means a public building (as defined in section 3301) that is open to the public and contains a public restroom, and includes a building listed in section 6301 or 5101.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Lactation room</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “lactation room” means a hygienic place, other than a bathroom, that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is shielded from view;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is free from intrusion; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> contains a chair, a working surface, and, if the public building is otherwise supplied with electricity, an electrical outlet.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Lactation Room Required</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in subsection (c), the appropriate authority of a covered public building shall ensure that the building contains a lactation room that is made available for use by members of the public to express breast milk.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exceptions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A covered public building may be excluded from the requirement in subsection (b) at the discretion of the appropriate authority if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the public building—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> does not contain a lactation room for employees who work in the building; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> does not have a room that could be repurposed as a lactation room or a space that could be made private using portable materials, at a reasonable cost; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> new construction would be required to create a lactation room in the public building and the cost of such construction is unfeasible.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">No Unauthorized Entry</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section shall be construed to authorize an individual to enter a public building or portion thereof that the individual is not otherwise authorized to enter.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–30, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-07-25">July 25, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1032</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3318.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002021">1</ref></num>
<heading> Availability of Federal building project information</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this section, and, at a minimum, on a quarterly basis thereafter, the Administrator shall make publicly available on a subpage of the website of the General Services Administration all prospectuses submitted pursuant to sections 3307 and 3316, and associated information subject to the following requirements:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Administrator shall maintain such information in an easily accessible and readable, organized, downloadable, and searchable format.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Administrator shall ensure the information is current and prospectuses and associated information updated on a regular basis.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The information required under this section shall be inclusive for a period of not less than 10 years.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> The information shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the last date on which the relevant webpage was updated;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> approval dates of respective authorizing resolutions by each committee of jurisdiction, if applicable;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> copies of respective committee of jurisdiction resolutions authorizing such prospectuses, as appropriate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> cross-references to any resubmitted or amended prospectuses and associated resolutions; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> such other information as determined by the Administrator.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the following definitions apply:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prospectus</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “prospectus” means prospectuses, building surveys, and factsheets submitted to the committees of jurisdiction pursuant to sections 3307 and 3316.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Committees of jurisdiction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “committees of jurisdiction” means the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Associated information</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “associated information” means resolutions approved by the committees of jurisdiction and other information as required pursuant to subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–333, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-13">Jan. 13, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 5113</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3319.</num>
<heading> Interagency space coordination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Unless a Federal agency specifically restricts the sharing of the information described in this section for national security purposes, the Administrator of General Services shall share with tenant Federal agencies pursuing new or replacement office space information on any other Federal agencies located in the same geographical area for purposes of determining opportunities for consolidations, collocations, or other space sharing to reduce the costs of space and maximize space utilization.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 118–272, div. B, title III, § 2304(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 3224</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>