<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 5—</num>
<heading>PROPERTY MANAGEMENT</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>PROCUREMENT AND WAREHOUSING</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 501.</num>
<heading> Services for executive agencies</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Authority of Administrator of General Services.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Administrator of General Services shall take action under this subchapter for an executive agency—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to the extent that the Administrator of General Services determines that the action is advantageous to the Federal Government in terms of economy, efficiency, or service; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> with due regard to the program activities of the agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exemption for defense</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may exempt the Department of Defense from an action taken by the Administrator of General Services under this subchapter, unless the President directs otherwise, whenever the Secretary determines that an exemption is in the best interests of national security.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Procurement and Supply.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Functions.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator of General Services shall procure and supply personal property and nonpersonal services for executive agencies to use in the proper discharge of their responsibilities, and perform functions related to procurement and supply including contracting, inspection, storage, issue, property identification and classification, transportation and traffic management, management of public utility services, and repairing and converting.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Public utility contracts</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A contract for public utility services may be made for a period of not more than 10 years.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Policies and methods.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator of General Services shall prescribe policies and methods for executive agencies regarding the procurement and supply of personal property and nonpersonal services and related functions.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Controlling regulation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Policies and methods prescribed by the Administrator of General Services under this paragraph are subject to regulations prescribed by the Administrator for Federal Procurement Policy under division B (except sections 1704 and 2303) of subtitle I of title 41.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Representation</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> For transportation and other public utility services used by executive agencies, the Administrator of General Services shall represent the agencies—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in negotiations with carriers and other public utilities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in proceedings involving carriers or other public utilities before federal and state regulatory bodies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Prior to representing any installation of the Department of Defense in any proceeding under this subsection, the Administrator or any persons or entities acting on behalf of the Administrator shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> notify the senior mission commander of the installation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> solicit and represent the interests of the installation as determined by the installation’s senior mission commander.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Facilities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator of General Services shall operate, for executive agencies, warehouses, supply centers, repair shops, fuel yards, and other similar facilities. After consultation with the executive agencies affected, the Administrator of General Services shall consolidate, take over, or arrange for executive agencies to operate the facilities.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1079</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 5</ref>(<i>l</i>)(6), <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3851</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2826</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2270</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 502.</num>
<heading> Services for other entities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Federal Agencies, Mixed-Ownership Government Corporations, and the District of Columbia</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>On request, the Administrator of General Services shall provide, to the extent practicable, any of the services specified in <ref>section 501 of this title</ref> to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a federal agency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a mixed-ownership Government corporation (as defined in <ref>section 9101 of title 31</ref>); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the District of Columbia.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Qualified Nonprofit Agencies.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>On request, the Administrator may provide, to the extent practicable, any of the services specified in <ref>section 501 of this title</ref> to an agency that is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a qualified nonprofit agency for the blind (as defined in <ref>section 8501(7) of title 41</ref>); or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a qualified nonprofit agency for other severely disabled (as defined in <ref>section 8501(6) of title 41</ref>); and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> providing a commodity or service to the Federal Government under chapter 85 of title 41.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of services</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A nonprofit agency receiving services under this subsection shall use the services directly in making or providing to the Government a commodity or service that has been determined by the Committee for Purchase From People Who Are Blind or Severely Disabled under <ref>section 8503 of title 41</ref> to be suitable for procurement by the Government.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Use of Certain Supply Schedules.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Administrator may provide for the use by State or local governments of Federal supply schedules of the General Services Administration for the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Automated data processing equipment (including firmware), software, supplies, support equipment, and services (as contained in Federal supply classification code group 70).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Alarm and signal systems, facility management systems, firefighting and rescue equipment, law enforcement and security equipment, marine craft and related equipment, special purpose clothing, and related services (as contained in Federal supply classification code group 84 or any amended or subsequent version of that Federal supply classification group).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Voluntary use</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In any case of the use by a State or local government of a Federal supply schedule pursuant to paragraph (1), participation by a firm that sells to the Federal Government through the supply schedule shall be voluntary with respect to a sale to the State or local government through such supply schedule.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this subsection:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The term “State or local government” includes any State, local, regional, or tribal government, or any instrumentality thereof (including any local educational agency or institution of higher education).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> The term “tribal government” means—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the governing body of any Indian tribe, band, nation, or other organized group or community located in the continental United States (excluding the State of Alaska) that is recognized as eligible for the special programs and services provided by the United States to Indians because of their status as Indians, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any Alaska Native regional or village corporation established pursuant to the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<ref>43 U.S.C. 1601</ref> et seq.).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The term “local educational agency” has the meaning given that term in section 7013 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The term “institution of higher education” has the meaning given that term in section 101(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<ref>20 U.S.C. 1001(a)</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Use of Supply Schedules for Certain Goods and Services.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator may provide for the use by State or local governments of Federal supply schedules of the General Services Administration for goods or services that are to be used to facilitate recovery from a major disaster declared by the President under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 5121</ref> et seq.), to facilitate disaster preparedness or response, or to facilitate recovery from terrorism or nuclear, biological, chemical, or radiological attack.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Determination by secretary of homeland security</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall determine which goods and services qualify as goods and services described in paragraph (1) before the Administrator provides for the use of the Federal supply schedule relating to such goods and services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Voluntary use</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In the case of the use by a State or local government of a Federal supply schedule pursuant to paragraph (1), participation by a firm that sells to the Federal Government through the supply schedule shall be voluntary with respect to a sale to the State or local government through such supply schedule.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The definitions in subsection (c)(3) shall apply for purposes of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Use of Supply Schedules by the Red Cross and Other Qualified Organizations.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator may provide for the use by the American National Red Cross and other qualified organizations of Federal supply schedules. Purchases under this authority by the American National Red Cross shall be used in furtherance of the purposes of the American National Red Cross set forth in <ref>section 300102 of title 36</ref>, United States Code. Purchases under this authority by other qualified organizations shall be used in furtherance of purposes determined to be appropriate to facilitate emergency preparedness and disaster relief and set forth in guidance by the Administrator of General Services, in consultation with the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The authority under this subsection may not be used to purchase supplies for resale.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Qualified organization</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this subsection, the term “qualified organization” means a relief or disaster assistance organization as described in section 309 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 5152</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duty of Users Regarding Use of Supply Schedules</inline>.—</heading>
<content>All users of Federal supply schedules, including non-Federal users, shall use the schedules in accordance with the ordering guidance provided by the Administrator of General Services.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1080</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–347, title II, § 211(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-17">Dec. 17, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2939</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title VIII, § 833(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2332</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–248, § 2</ref>, <date date="2008-06-26">June 26, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2316</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–263</ref>, §§ 2–4, <date date="2010-10-08">Oct. 8, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2787</ref>, 2788; <ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 5</ref>(<i>l</i>)(7), <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3851</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–95, title IX, § 9215(www)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-10">Dec. 10, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 2191</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 503.</num>
<heading> Exchange or sale of similar items</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority of Executive Agencies</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In acquiring personal property, an executive agency may exchange or sell similar items and may apply the exchange allowance or proceeds of sale in whole or in part payment for the property acquired.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Applicable Regulation and Law.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations prescribed by administrator of general services</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A transaction under subsection (a) must be carried out in accordance with regulations the Administrator of General Services prescribes, subject to regulations prescribed by the Administrator for Federal Procurement Policy under division B (except sections 1704 and 2303) of subtitle I of title 41.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In writing</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A transaction under subsection (a) must be evidenced in writing.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Section 6101(</inline>b<inline class="small-caps">) to (</inline>d<inline class="small-caps">) of title 41</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Section 6101(b) to (d) of title 41 applies to a sale of property under subsection (a), except that fixed price sales may be conducted in the same manner and subject to the same conditions as are applicable to the sale of property under <ref>section 545(d) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1081</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 5</ref>(<i>l</i>)(8), <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3851</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 504.</num>
<heading> Agency cooperation for inspection</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Receiving Assistance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An executive agency may use the services, work, materials, and equipment of another executive agency, with the consent of the other executive agency, to inspect personal property incident to procuring the property.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Providing Assistance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding <ref>section 1301(a) of title 31</ref> or any other law, an executive agency may provide services, work, materials, and equipment for purposes of this section without reimbursement or transfer of amounts.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Policies and Methods</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The use or provision of services, work, materials, and equipment under this section must be in conformity with policies and methods the Administrator of General Services prescribes under <ref>section 501 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1081</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 505.</num>
<heading> Exchange or transfer of medical supplies</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Excess Property Determination.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Medical materials or supplies an executive agency holds for national emergency purposes are considered excess property for purposes of subchapter II when the head of the agency determines that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the remaining storage or shelf life is too short to justify continued retention for national emergency purposes; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> transfer or other disposal is in the national interest.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Timing</inline>.—</heading>
<content>To the greatest extent practicable, the head of the agency shall make the determination in sufficient time to allow for the transfer or other disposal and use of medical materials or supplies before their shelf life expires and they are rendered unfit for human use.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Transfer or Exchange.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In accordance with regulations the Administrator of General Services prescribes, medical materials or supplies considered excess property may be transferred to another federal agency or exchanged with another federal agency for other medical materials or supplies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of proceeds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any proceeds derived from a transfer under this section may be credited to the current applicable appropriation or fund of the transferor agency and shall be available only to purchase medical materials or supplies to be held for national emergency purposes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Disposal as surplus property</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the materials or supplies are not transferred to or exchanged with another federal agency, they shall be disposed of as surplus property.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1081</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 506.</num>
<heading> Inventory controls and systems</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Activities of the Administrator of General Services.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subject to paragraph (2), and after adequate advance notice to affected executive agencies, the Administrator of General Services may undertake the following activities as necessary to carry out functions under this chapter:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Surveys and reports</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Survey and obtain executive agency reports on Federal Government property and property management practices.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inventory levels</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Cooperate with executive agencies to establish reasonable inventory levels for property stocked by them, and report any excessive inventory levels to Congress and to the Director of the Office of Management and Budget.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Federal supply catalog system</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Establish and maintain a uniform federal supply catalog system that is appropriate to identify and classify personal property under the control of federal agencies.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Standard purchase specifications and standard forms and procedures</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Prescribe standard purchase specifications and standard forms and procedures (except forms and procedures that the Comptroller General prescribes by law) subject to regulations the Administrator for Federal Procurement Policy prescribes under division B (except sections 1704 and 2303) of subtitle I of title 41.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Capitalization thresholds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Establish thresholds for acquisitions of personal property for which executive agencies shall capitalize the personal property.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Accountability thresholds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding section 121(b), for the management and accountability of personal property, establish thresholds for acquisitions of personal property for which executive agencies shall establish and maintain property records in a centralized system.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Special considerations regarding department of defense.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator of General Services shall carry out activities under paragraph (1) with due regard to the requirements of the Department of Defense, as determined by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Federal supply catalog system</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In establishing and maintaining a uniform federal supply catalog system under paragraph (1)(C), the Administrator of General Services and the Secretary shall coordinate to avoid unnecessary duplication.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Activities of Federal Agencies</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each federal agency shall use the uniformed federal supply catalog system, the standard purchase specifications, and the standard forms and procedures established under subsection (a), except as the Administrator of General Services, considering efficiency, economy, or other interests of the Government, may otherwise provide.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Audit of Property Accounts</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Comptroller General shall audit all types of property accounts and transactions. Audits shall be conducted at the time and in the manner the Comptroller General decides and as far as practicable at the place where the property or records of the executive agencies are kept. Audits shall include an evaluation of the effectiveness of internal controls and audits, and a general audit of the discharge of accountability for Government-owned or controlled property, based on generally accepted principles of auditing.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1082</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 5</ref>(<i>l</i>)(9), <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3852</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–419, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="2019-01-03">Jan. 3, 2019</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5443</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>USE OF PROPERTY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 521.</num>
<heading> Policies and methods</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subject to <ref>section 523 of this title</ref>, in order to minimize expenditures for property, the Administrator of General Services shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> prescribe policies and methods to promote the maximum use of excess property by executive agencies; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> provide for the transfer of excess property—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> among federal agencies; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to the organizations specified in <ref>section 321(c)(2) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1083</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 522.</num>
<heading> Reimbursement for transfer of excess property</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to subsections (b) and (c), the Administrator of General Services, with the approval of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, shall prescribe the amount of reimbursement required for a transfer of excess property.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reimbursement at Fair Value</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The amount of reimbursement required for a transfer of excess property is the fair value of the property, as determined by the Administrator, if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> net proceeds are requested under <ref>section 574(a) of this title</ref>; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> either the transferor or the transferee agency (or the organizational unit affected) is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> subject to chapter 91 of title 31; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an organization specified in <ref>section 321(c)(2) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Distribution Through General Services Administration Supply Centers</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Excess property determined by the Administrator to be suitable for distribution through the supply centers of the General Services Administration shall be retransferred at prices set by the Administrator with due regard to prices established under <ref>section 321(d) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1083</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–284, § 6(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="2006-09-27">Sept. 27, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1212</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 523.</num>
<heading> Excess real property located on Indian reservations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Procedures for Transfer</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator of General Services shall prescribe procedures necessary to transfer to the Secretary of the Interior, without compensation, excess real property located within the reservation of any group, band, or tribe of Indians that is recognized as eligible for services by the Bureau of Indian Affairs.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Property Held in Trust.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the Secretary shall hold excess real property transferred under this section in trust for the benefit and use of the group, band, or tribe of Indians, within whose reservation the excess real property is located.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Special requirement for oklahoma</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall hold excess real property that is located in Oklahoma and transferred under this section in trust for Oklahoma Indian tribes recognized by the Secretary if the real property—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is located within boundaries of former reservations in Oklahoma, as defined by the Secretary, and was held in trust by the Federal Government for an Indian tribe when the Government acquired it; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is contiguous to real property presently held in trust by the Government for an Oklahoma Indian tribe and was held in trust by the Government for an Indian tribe at any time.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1083</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 524.</num>
<heading> Duties of executive agencies</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Required</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each executive agency shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> maintain adequate inventory controls and accountability systems for property under its control;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> continuously survey property under its control to identify excess property;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> promptly report excess property to the Administrator of General Services;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> perform the care and handling of excess property;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> transfer or dispose of excess property as promptly as possible in accordance with authority delegated and regulations prescribed by the Administrator;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> develop current and future workforce projections so as to have the capacity to assess the needs of the Federal workforce regarding the use of real property;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> establish goals and policies that will lead the executive agency to reduce excess property and underutilized property in the inventory of the executive agency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<chapeau> submit to the Federal Real Property Council an annual report on all excess property that is real property and underutilized property in the inventory of the executive agency, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> whether underutilized property can be better utilized, including through collocation with other executive agencies or consolidation with other facilities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the extent to which the executive agency believes that retention of the underutilized property serves the needs of the executive agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> adopt workplace practices, configurations, and management techniques that can achieve increased levels of productivity and decrease the need for real property assets;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> assess leased space to identify space that is not fully used or occupied;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<chapeau> on an annual basis and subject to the guidance of the Federal Real Property Council—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> conduct an inventory of real property under control of the executive agency; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> make an assessment of each property, which shall include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the age and condition of the property;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the size of the property in square footage and acreage;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the geographical location of the property, including an address and description;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the extent to which the property is being utilized;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> the actual annual operating costs associated with the property;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> the total cost of capital expenditures incurred by the Federal Government associated with the property;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> sustainability metrics associated with the property;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> the number of Federal employees and contractor employees and functions housed at the property;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ix)</num>
<content> the extent to which the mission of the executive agency is dependent on the property;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(x)</num>
<content> the estimated amount of capital expenditures projected to maintain and operate the property during the 5-year period beginning on the date of enactment of this paragraph; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(xi)</num>
<content> any additional information required by the Administrator of General Services to carry out section 623;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> provide to the Federal Real Property Council and the Administrator of General Services the information described in paragraph (11)(B) to be used for the establishment and maintenance of the database described in section 21 of the Federal Assets Sale and Transfer Act of 2016; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<chapeau> in accordance with guidance from the Administrator of General Services—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> on an annual basis, conduct an inventory and assessment of capitalized personal property to identify excess capitalized personal property under its control, including evaluating—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the age and condition of the personal property;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the extent to which the executive agency utilizes the personal property;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the extent to which the mission of the executive agency is dependent on the personal property; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> any other aspect of the personal property that the Administrator determines is useful or necessary for the executive agency to evaluate; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> on a regular basis, conduct an inventory and assessment of accountable personal property under its control, including evaluating—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the age and condition of the personal property;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the extent to which the executive agency utilizes the personal property;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the extent to which the mission of the executive agency is dependent on the personal property; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> any other aspect of the personal property that the Administrator determines is useful or necessary for the executive agency to evaluate.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Required as Far as Practicable</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each executive agency, as far as practicable, shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> reassign property to another activity within the agency when the property is no longer required for the purposes of the appropriation used to make the purchase;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> transfer excess property under its control to other federal agencies and to organizations specified in <ref>section 321(c)(2) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> obtain excess property from other federal agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition of Executive Agency</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For the purpose of paragraphs (6) through (12) of subsection (a), the term “executive agency” shall have the meaning given the term “Federal agency” in section 621.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1084</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–318, § 6</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1615</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–419, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-01-03">Jan. 3, 2019</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5442</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 525.</num>
<heading> Excess personal property for federal agency grantees</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General Prohibition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A federal agency is prohibited from obtaining excess personal property for the purpose of furnishing the property to a grantee of the agency, except as provided in this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Exception for Public Agencies and Tax-exempt Nonprofit Organizations.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Under regulations the Administrator of General Services may prescribe, a federal agency may obtain excess personal property for the purpose of furnishing it to a public agency or an organization that is nonprofit and exempt from taxation under section 501 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (<ref>26 U.S.C. 501</ref>), if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the agency or organization is conducting a federally sponsored project pursuant to a grant made for a specific purpose with a specific termination provision;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the property is to be furnished for use in connection with the grant; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the sponsoring federal agency pays an amount equal to 25 percent of the original acquisition cost (except for costs of care and handling) of the excess property; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the amount is deposited in the Treasury as miscellaneous receipts.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Title</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Title to excess property obtained under this subsection vests in the grantee. The grantee shall account for and dispose of the property in accordance with procedures governing accountability for personal property acquired under grant agreements.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Exception for Certain Property Furnished by Secretary of Agriculture.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this subsection, the term “State” means a State of the United States, Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the Northern Mariana Islands, the Federated States of Micronesia, the Marshall Islands, Palau, the Virgin Islands, and the District of Columbia.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Under regulations and restrictions the Administrator may prescribe, subsection (a) does not apply to property furnished by the Secretary of Agriculture to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a state <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002006">1</ref> or county extension service engaged in cooperative agricultural extension work under the Smith-Lever Act (<ref>7 U.S.C. 341</ref> et seq.);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a state <sup>1</sup> experiment station engaged in cooperative agricultural research work under the Hatch Act of 1887 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 361a</ref> et seq.); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> an institution engaged in cooperative agricultural research or extension work under section 1433, 1434, 1444, or 1445 of the National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act of 1977 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 3195</ref>, 3196, 3221, or 3222), or the Act of <date date="1962-10-10">October 10, 1962</date> (<ref>16 U.S.C. 582a</ref> et seq.), if the Federal Government retains title.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Other Exceptions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Under regulations and restrictions the Administrator may prescribe, subsection (a) does not apply to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> property furnished under section 608 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2358</ref>), to the extent that the Administrator determines that the property is not needed for donation under <ref>section 549 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> scientific equipment furnished under section 11(e) of the National Science Foundation Act of 1950 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 1870(e)</ref>);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> property furnished under section 203 of the Department of Agriculture Organic Act of 1944 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 580a</ref>), in connection with the Cooperative Forest Fire Control Program, if the Government retains title; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> property furnished in connection with a grant to a tribe, as defined in section 3(c) of the Indian Financing Act of 1974 (<ref>25 U.S.C. 1452(c)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1084</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 526.</num>
<heading> Temporary assignment of excess real property</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Assignment of Space</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator of General Services may temporarily assign or reassign space in excess real property to a federal agency, for use as office or storage space or for a related purpose, if the Administrator determines that assignment or reassignment is more advantageous than permanent transfer. The Administrator shall determine the duration of the assignment or reassignment.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reimbursement for Maintenance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If there is no appropriation available to the Administrator for the expense of maintaining the space, the Administrator may obtain appropriate reimbursement from the federal agency.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1085</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 527.</num>
<heading> Abandonment, destruction, or donation of property</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Administrator of General Services may authorize the abandonment or destruction of property, or the donation of property to a public body, if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the property has no commercial value; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the estimated cost of continued care and handling exceeds the estimated proceeds from sale.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1086</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 528.</num>
<heading> Utilization of excess furniture</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A department or agency of the Federal Government may not use amounts provided by law to purchase furniture if the Administrator of General Services determines that requirements can reasonably be met by transferring excess furniture, including rehabilitated furniture, from other departments or agencies pursuant to this subtitle.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1086</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 529.</num>
<heading> Annual executive agency reports on excess personal property</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>During the calendar quarter following the close of each fiscal year, each executive agency shall submit to the Administrator of General Services and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Oversight and Accountability of the House of Representatives a report on personal property—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> obtained as—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> excess property; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> personal property determined to be no longer required for the purpose of the appropriation used to make the purchase; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> furnished within the United States to a recipient other than a federal agency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Required Information</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The report must set out the categories of equipment and show—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the acquisition cost of the property;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the recipient of the property; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> other information the Administrator may require.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Compilation of Data</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not later than 180 days following the close of a fiscal year, the Administrator shall compile the data in the reports submitted under subsection (a) and submit to the Committee on Homeland Security <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002007">1</ref> Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Oversight and Accountability of the House of Representatives and publish on a centralized online website a publicly available report, which shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the complete data provided in each report in a user-friendly format;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a summary of the findings of each report, including the aggregate dollar amount of personal property determined to be no longer required for the purpose of the appropriation used to make the purchase; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> any other recommendations from the Administrator.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1086</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–99, § 2(a)(1)</ref>, (e)(1), <date date="2024-10-01">Oct. 1, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1578</ref>, 1579.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 530.</num>
<heading> Internal guidance on excess personal property</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Initial Report</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this section, each executive agency shall submit to the Administrator of General Services and make publicly available on the website of the executive agency the internal guidance of the executive agency on considering using excess personal property to meet the needs of the executive agency, which shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a requirement to consider excess personal property before buying new;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> when it is practicable to check for and obtain excess personal property;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> how to evaluate the suitability of excess personal property for use; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> defined roles and responsibilities relevant to considering the use of excess personal property, including the designation of an employee as responsible for searching through available excess personal property for items that meet the needs of the executive agency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Updates</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each executive agency shall submit to the Administrator of General Services and update on the website of the executive agency any changes to the internal guidance submitted and made available under subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 118–99, § 2(a)(2)</ref>, (e)(2), <date date="2024-10-01">Oct. 1, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1578</ref>, 1579.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>DISPOSING OF PROPERTY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 541.</num>
<heading> Supervision and direction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided in this subchapter, the Administrator of General Services shall supervise and direct the disposition of surplus property in accordance with this subtitle.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1086</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 542.</num>
<heading> Care and handling</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The disposal of surplus property, and the care and handling of the property pending disposition, may be performed by the General Services Administration or, when the Administrator of General Services decides, by the executive agency in possession of the property or by any other executive agency that agrees.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1086</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 543.</num>
<heading> Method of disposition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An executive agency designated or authorized by the Administrator of General Services to dispose of surplus property may do so by sale, exchange, lease, permit, or transfer, for cash, credit, or other property, with or without warranty, on terms and conditions that the Administrator considers proper. The agency may execute documents to transfer title or other interest in the property and may take other action it considers necessary or proper to dispose of the property under this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1086</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 544.</num>
<heading> Validity of transfer instruments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A deed, bill of sale, lease, or other instrument executed by or on behalf of an executive agency purporting to transfer title or other interest in surplus property under this chapter is conclusive evidence of compliance with the provisions of this chapter concerning title or other interest of a bona fide grantee or transferee for value and without notice of lack of compliance.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1087</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 545.</num>
<heading> Procedure for disposal</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Public Advertising for Bids.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Requirement.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the Administrator of General Services may make or authorize a disposal or a contract for disposal of surplus property only after public advertising for bids, under regulations the Administrator prescribes.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exceptions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>This subsection does not apply to disposal or a contract for disposal of surplus property—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> under subsection (b) or (d); or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> by abandonment, destruction, or donation or through a contract broker.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Time, method, and terms</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The time, method, and terms and conditions of advertisement must permit full and free competition consistent with the value and nature of the property involved.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Public disclosure</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Bids must be publicly disclosed at the time and place stated in the advertisement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Awards</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An award shall be made with reasonable promptness by notice to the responsible bidder whose bid, conforming to the invitation for bids, is most advantageous to the Federal Government, price and other factors considered. However, all bids may be rejected if it is in the public interest to do so.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Negotiated Disposal</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Under regulations the Administrator prescribes, disposals and contracts for disposal may be negotiated without regard to subsection (a), but subject to obtaining competition that is feasible under the circumstances, if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> necessary in the public interest—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> during the period of a national emergency declared by the President or Congress, with respect to a particular lot of personal property; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for a period not exceeding three months, with respect to a specifically described category of personal property as determined by the Administrator;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the public health, safety, or national security will be promoted by a particular disposal of personal property;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> public exigency will not allow delay incident to advertising certain personal property;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the nature and quantity of personal property involved are such that disposal under subsection (a) would impact an industry to an extent that would adversely affect the national economy, and the estimated fair market value of the property and other satisfactory terms of disposal can be obtained by negotiation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the estimated fair market value of the property involved does not exceed $15,000;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> after advertising under subsection (a), the bid prices for the property, or part of the property, are not reasonable or have not been independently arrived at in open competition;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> with respect to real property, the character or condition of the property or unusual circumstances make it impractical to advertise publicly for competitive bids and the fair market value of the property and other satisfactory terms of disposal can be obtained by negotiation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> the disposal will be to a State, territory, or possession of the United States, or to a political subdivision of, or a tax-supported agency in, a State, territory, or possession, and the estimated fair market value of the property and other satisfactory terms of disposal are obtained by negotiation; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> otherwise authorized by law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Disposal Through Contract Brokers</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Disposals and contracts for disposal of surplus real and related personal property through contract realty brokers employed by the Administrator shall be made in the manner followed in similar commercial transactions under regulations the Administrator prescribes. The regulations must require that brokers give wide public notice of the availability of the property for disposal.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Negotiated Sale at Fixed Price.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authorization</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator may make a negotiated sale of personal property at a fixed price, either directly or through the use of a disposal contractor, without regard to subsection (a). However, the sale must be publicized to an extent consistent with the value and nature of the property involved and the price established must reflect the estimated fair market value of the property. Sales under this subsection are limited to categories of personal property for which the Administrator determines that disposal under this subsection best serves the interests of the Government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">First offer</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Under regulations and restrictions the Administrator prescribes, an opportunity to purchase property at a fixed price under this subsection may be offered first to an entity specified in subsection (b)(8) that has expressed an interest in the property.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Explanatory Statements for Negotiated Disposals.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Requirement.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), an explanatory statement of the circumstances shall be prepared for each disposal by negotiation of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> personal property that has an estimated fair market value in excess of $15,000;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> real property that has an estimated fair market value in excess of $100,000, except that real property disposed of by lease or exchange is subject only to clauses (iii)–(v) of this subparagraph;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> real property disposed of by lease for a term of not more than 5 years, if the estimated fair annual rent is more than $100,000 for any year;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> real property disposed of by lease for a term of more than 5 years, if the total estimated rent over the term of the lease is more than $100,000; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> real property or real and related personal property disposed of by exchange, regardless of value, or any property for which any part of the consideration is real property.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An explanatory statement is not required for a disposal of personal property under subsection (d), or for a disposal of real or personal property authorized by any other law to be made without advertising.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transmittal to congress</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The explanatory statement shall be transmitted to the appropriate committees of Congress in advance of the disposal, and a copy of the statement shall be preserved in the files of the executive agency making the disposal.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Listing in report</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A report of the Administrator under <ref>section 126 of this title</ref> must include a listing and description of any negotiated disposals of surplus property having an estimated fair market value of more than $15,000, in the case of real property, or $5,000, in the case of any other property, other than disposals for which an explanatory statement has been transmitted under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Applicability of Other Law</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Section 6101(b)–(d) of title 41 does not apply to a disposal or contract for disposal made under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1087</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 5</ref>(<i>l</i>)(10), <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3852</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 546.</num>
<heading> Contractor inventories</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to regulations of the Administrator of General Services, an executive agency may authorize a contractor or subcontractor with the agency to retain or dispose of contractor inventory.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1089</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 547.</num>
<heading> Agricultural commodities, foods, and cotton or woolen goods</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Policies</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator of General Services shall consult with the Secretary of Agriculture to formulate policies for the disposal of surplus agricultural commodities, surplus foods processed from agricultural commodities, and surplus cotton or woolen goods. The policies shall be formulated to prevent surplus agricultural commodities, or surplus foods processed from agricultural commodities, from being dumped on the market in a disorderly manner and disrupting the market prices for agricultural commodities.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Transfers to Department of Agriculture.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall transfer without charge to the Department of Agriculture any surplus agricultural commodities, foods, and cotton or woolen goods for disposal, when the Secretary determines that a transfer is necessary for the Secretary to carry out responsibilities for price support or stabilization.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Deposit of receipts</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Receipts resulting from disposal by the Department under this subsection shall be deposited pursuant to any authority available to the Secretary. When applicable, however, net proceeds from the sale of surplus property transferred under this subsection shall be credited pursuant to <ref>section 572(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation of sales</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Surplus farm commodities transferred under this subsection may not be sold, other than for export, in quantities exceeding, or at prices less than, the applicable quantities and prices for sales of those commodities by the Commodity Credit Corporation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1089</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 548.</num>
<heading> Surplus vessels</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Maritime Administration shall dispose of surplus vessels of 1,500 gross tons or more which the Administration determines to be merchant vessels or capable of conversion to merchant use. The vessels shall be disposed of in accordance with part F of subtitle V of title 46 and other laws authorizing the sale of such vessels.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1090</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 17(g)(1)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1708</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 549.</num>
<heading> Donation of personal property through state agencies</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the following definitions apply:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Public agency</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “public agency” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a State;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a political subdivision of a State (including a unit of local government or economic development district);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a department, agency, or instrumentality of a State (including instrumentalities created by compact or other agreement between States or political subdivisions); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> an Indian tribe, band, group, pueblo, or community located on a state reservation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">State</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “State” means a State of the United States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, the Northern Mariana Islands, and American Samoa.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">State agency</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “state agency” means an agency designated under state law as the agency responsible for fair and equitable distribution, through donation, of property transferred under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Authorization.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator of General Services, in the Administrator’s discretion and under regulations the Administrator may prescribe, may transfer property described in paragraph (2) to a state agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Property.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Property referred to in paragraph (1) is any personal property that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is under the control of an executive agency; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> has been determined to be surplus property.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Special rule</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In determining whether the property is to be transferred for donation under this section, no distinction may be made between property capitalized in a working-capital fund established under <ref>section 2208 of title 10</ref> (or similar fund) and any other property.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">No cost</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Transfer of property under this section is without cost, except for any costs of care and handling.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Allocation and Transfer of Property.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall allocate and transfer property under this section in accordance with criteria that are based on need and use and that are established after consultation with state agencies to the extent feasible. The Administrator shall give fair consideration, consistent with the established criteria, to an expression of need and interest from a public agency or other eligible institution within a State. The Administrator shall give special consideration to an eligible recipient’s request, transmitted through the state agency, for a specific item of property.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Allocation among states</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall allocate property among the States on a fair and equitable basis, taking into account the condition of the property as well as the original acquisition cost of the property.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Recipients and purposes</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Administrator shall transfer to a state agency property the state agency selects for distribution through donation within the State—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to a public agency for use in carrying out or promoting, for residents of a given political area, a public purpose, including conservation, economic development, education, parks and recreation, public health, and public safety;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> for purposes of education or public health (including research), to a nonprofit educational or public health institution or organization that is exempt from taxation under section 501 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (<ref>26 U.S.C. 501</ref>), including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a medical institution, hospital, clinic, health center, or drug abuse treatment center;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a provider of assistance to homeless individuals or to families or individuals whose annual incomes are below the poverty line (as that term is defined in section 673 of the Community Services Block Grant Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 9902</ref>));</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a school, college, or university;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> a school for the mentally retarded or physically handicapped;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> a child care center;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> a radio or television station licensed by the Federal Communications Commission as an educational radio or educational television station;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> a museum attended by the public, and, for purposes of determining whether a museum is attended by the public, the Administrator shall consider a museum to be public if the nonprofit educational or public health institution or organization, at minimum, accedes to any request submitted for access during business hours;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> a library serving free all residents of a community, district, State, or region; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ix)</num>
<content> a historic light station as defined under <ref>section 305101(4) of title 54</ref>, including a historic light station conveyed under <ref>section 305103 of title 54</ref>, notwithstanding the number of hours that the historic light station is open to the public; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> for purposes of providing services to veterans (as defined in <ref>section 101 of title 38</ref>), to an organization whose—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> membership comprises substantially veterans; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> representatives are recognized by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs under <ref>section 5902 of title 38</ref>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This subsection does not apply to property transferred under subsection (d).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Department of Defense Property.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Determination</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall determine whether surplus personal property under the control of the Department of Defense is usable and necessary for educational activities which are of special interest to the armed services, including maritime academies, or military, naval, Air Force, or Coast Guard preparatory schools.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Property usable for special interest activities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the Secretary of Defense determines that the property is usable and necessary for educational activities which are of special interest to the armed services, the Secretary shall allocate the property for transfer by the Administrator to the appropriate state agency for distribution through donation to the educational activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Property not usable for special interest activities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the Secretary of Defense determines that the property is not usable and necessary for educational activities which are of special interest to the armed services, the property may be disposed of in accordance with subsection (c).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">State Plan of Operation.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Before property may be transferred to a state agency, the State shall develop a detailed state plan of operation, in accordance with this subsection and with state law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Procedure.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consideration of needs and resources</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In developing and implementing the state plan of operation, the relative needs and resources of all public agencies and other eligible institutions in the State shall be taken into consideration. The Administrator may consult with interested federal agencies to obtain their views concerning the administration and operation of this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Publication and period for comment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The state plan of operation, and any major amendment to the plan, may not be filed with the Administrator until 60 days after general notice of the proposed plan or amendment has been published and interested persons have been given at least 30 days to submit comments.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Certification</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The chief executive officer of the State shall certify and submit the state plan of operation to the Administrator.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Requirements.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">State agency</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The state plan of operation shall include adequate assurance that the state agency has—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the necessary organizational and operational authority and capability including staff, facilities, and means and methods of financing; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> established procedures for accountability, internal and external audits, cooperative agreements, compliance and use reviews, equitable distribution and property disposal, determination of eligibility, and assistance through consultation with advisory bodies and public and private groups.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Equitable distribution</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The state plan of operation shall provide for fair and equitable distribution of property in the State based on the relative needs and resources of interested public agencies and other eligible institutions in the State and their abilities to use the property.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Management control and accounting systems</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The state plan of operation shall require, for donable property transferred under this section, that the state agency use management control and accounting systems of the same type as systems required by state law for state-owned property. However, with approval from the chief executive officer of the State, the state agency may elect to use other management control and accounting systems that are effective to govern the use, inventory control, accountability, and disposal of property under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Return and redistribution for non-use</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The state plan of operation shall require the state agency to provide for the return and redistribution of donable property if the property, while still usable, has not been placed in use for the purpose for which it was donated within one year of donation or ceases to be used by the donee for that purpose within one year of being placed in use.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Request by recipient</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The state plan of operation shall require the state agency, to the extent practicable, to select property requested by a public agency or other eligible institution in the State and, if requested by the recipient, to arrange shipment of the property directly to the recipient.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Service charges</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the state agency is authorized to assess and collect service charges from participating recipients to cover direct and reasonable indirect costs of its activities, the method of establishing the charges shall be set out in the state plan of operation. The charges shall be fair and equitable and shall be based on services the state agency performs, including screening, packing, crating, removal, and transportation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Terms, conditions, reservations, and restrictions.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The state plan of operation shall provide that the state agency—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> may impose reasonable terms, conditions, reservations, and restrictions on the use of property to be donated under subsection (c); and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> shall impose reasonable terms, conditions, reservations, and restrictions on the use of a passenger motor vehicle and any item of property having a unit acquisition cost of $5,000 or more.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Special limitations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the Administrator finds that an item has characteristics that require special handling or use limitations, the Administrator may impose appropriate conditions on the donation of the property.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Unusable property.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Disposal</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The state plan of operation shall provide that surplus personal property which the state agency determines cannot be used by eligible recipients shall be disposed of—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> subject to the disapproval of the Administrator within 30 days after notice to the Administrator, through transfer by the state agency to another state agency or through abandonment or destruction if the property has no commercial value or if the estimated cost of continued care and handling exceeds estimated proceeds from sale; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> under this subtitle, on terms and conditions and in a manner the Administrator prescribes.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Proceeds from sale</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding subchapter IV of this chapter and <ref>section 702 of this title</ref>, the Administrator, from the proceeds of sale of property described in subsection (b), may reimburse the state agency for expenses that the Administrator considers appropriate for care and handling of the property.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Cooperative Agreements With State Agencies.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Parties to the agreement</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For purposes of carrying out this section, a cooperative agreement may be made between a state surplus property distribution agency designated under this section and—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Administrator;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Education, for property transferred under <ref>section 550(c) of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Health and Human Services, for property transferred under <ref>section 550(d) of this title</ref>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the head of a federal agency designated by the Administrator, the Secretary of Education, or the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Shared resources</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The cooperative agreement may provide that the property, facilities, personnel, or services of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a state agency may be used by a federal agency; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a federal agency may be made available to a state agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reimbursement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The cooperative agreement may require payment or reimbursement for the use or provision of property, facilities, personnel, or services. Payment or reimbursement received from a state agency shall be credited to the fund or appropriation against which charges would otherwise be made.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Surplus property transferred to state agency.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Under the cooperative agreement, surplus property transferred to a state agency for distribution pursuant to subsection (c) may be retained by the state agency for use in performing its functions. Unless otherwise directed by the Administrator, title to the retained property vests in the state agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Conditions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Retention of surplus property under this paragraph is subject to conditions that may be imposed by—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Administrator;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Education, for property transferred under <ref>section 550(c) of this title</ref>; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Health and Human Services, for property transferred under <ref>section 550(d) of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1090</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–313, § 5</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1737</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–338, § 2</ref>, <date date="2010-12-22">Dec. 22, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3590</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–26, § 2</ref>, <date date="2013-08-09">Aug. 9, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 502</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 5(j)(1)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3269</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–287, § 23</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1479</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 549a.</num>
<heading> Donation of personal property through nonprofit refurbishers</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authorization</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 30 days after the date on which the Administrator provides State agencies for surplus property an opportunity to review surplus computer or technology equipment under section 549, the Administrator shall, as appropriate, transfer full title to such surplus computer or technology equipment that is determined to be eligible under subsection (b)(1) to nonprofit computer refurbishers for repair, distribution, and subsequent transfer of full title of the equipment to eligible recipients under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Eligibility, Participation, and Duties.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Eligibility</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Surplus computer or technology equipment is eligible for transfer under this section if a Federal agency determines that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the surplus computer or technology equipment is repairable; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the surplus computer or technology equipment meets the Guidelines for Media Sanitization issued by the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST Special Publication 800–88), or any successor thereto.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Participation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator may establish partnerships with nongovernmental entities, at no cost and through cooperative agreements, to facilitate the identification and participation of nonprofit computer refurbishers under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duties of refurbishers</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A nonprofit computer refurbisher that receives surplus computer or technology equipment under this section shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> make necessary repairs to restore the surplus computer or technology equipment to working order;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> distribute the repaired surplus computer or technology equipment to eligible recipients at no cost, except to the extent—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> necessary to facilitate shipping and handling of such equipment; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> that such cost is consistent with any regulations promulgated by the Administrator under subsection (d);</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> offer training programs on the use of the repaired computers and technology equipment for the recipients of the equipment; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> use recyclers to the maximum extent practicable in the event that surplus computer or technology equipment transferred under this section cannot be repaired or reused.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Reporting Requirements.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Refurbisher reports</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A nonprofit computer refurbisher that receives surplus computer or technology equipment under this section shall provide the Administrator with any information the Administrator determines to be necessary for required reporting—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> including information about the distribution of such equipment; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> which shall not include any personal identifying information about the recipient of such equipment apart from whether a recipient is an educational institution, individual with disabilities, low-income individual, student, senior in need, or veteran for the purposes of eligibility under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Administrator reports</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Annually and consistent with reporting requirements for transfers of Federal personal property to non-Federal entities, the Administrator shall submit to Congress and make publicly available a report that includes, for the period covered by the report—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a description of the efforts of the Administrator under this section;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a list of nongovernmental entities with which the Administrator had a partnership described in subsection (b)(2);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a list of nonprofit computer refurbishers that received, made repairs to, and distributed surplus computer and technology equipment, including disclosure of any foreign ownership interest in a nonprofit computer refurbisher; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> a list of donated and subsequently repaired surplus computer or technology equipment identifying—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Federal agency that donated the surplus computer or technology equipment;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the State and county (or similar unit of local government) where the recipient is located; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> whether the recipient is an educational institution, individual with disabilities, low-income individual, student, senior in need, or veteran.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Agency reports</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 5 years after the date of enactment of this section, and annually thereafter, the head of each Federal agency shall make publicly available a report on the number of pieces of repairable surplus computer or technology equipment that were sent to recycling, abandoned, or destroyed.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Administrator shall issue regulations that are necessary and appropriate to implement this section, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> allowing nonprofit computer refurbishers to assess nominal fees (which shall not exceed fair market value) on recipients of refurbished surplus computer or technology equipment to facilitate shipping and handling of the surplus computer or technology equipment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> determining, in coordination with other relevant Federal agencies, eligibility and certification requirements for nongovernmental entities and nonprofit computer refurbishers to participate in the program established under this section, including whether the participation of a nongovernmental entity or nonprofit computer refurbisher poses any actual or potential harm to the national security interests of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> establishing an efficient process for identifying eligible recipients; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> determining appropriate recyclers to dispose of surplus computer or technology equipment if it cannot be repaired or refurbished under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Judicial Review</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section shall be construed to create any substantive or procedural right or benefit enforceable by law by a party against the United States, its agencies, its officers, or its employees.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rule of Construction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section may be construed to supersede the requirements of the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 (<ref>Public Law 96–480</ref>; <ref>15 U.S.C. 3701</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Administrator</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “Administrator” means the Administrator of General Services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Digital divide</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “digital divide” means the gap between those who have an internet-connected computer and the skills to use the computer and those who do not.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Disability</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “disability” has the meaning given that term in section 3 of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 12102</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Educational institution</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “educational institution” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any public or private child care center, preschool, elementary school, secondary school, accredited institution of vocational or professional education, or institution of higher education;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of an accredited institution of vocational or professional education or an institution of higher education composed of more than 1 school, college, or department that is administratively a separate unit, each such school, college, or department; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a home school (whether treated as a home school or private school for the purposes of applicable State law).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Eligible recipient</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “eligible recipient” means an educational institution, individual with a disability, low-income individual, student, senior in need, or veteran that is residing or based in the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Institution of higher education</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “institution of higher education” has the meaning given that term in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<ref>20 U.S.C. 1001</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Low-income individual</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “low-income individual” has the meaning given that term in section 351 of the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 (<ref>15 U.S.C. 689</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Nongovernmental entity</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “nongovernmental entity” means an organization or group of organizations that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> are not part of a Federal, State, local, Tribal, or territorial government; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> are nonprofit computer refurbishers or other industry participants that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> primarily work to improve access to information and communication technology in their mission to bridge the digital divide through coordination and oversight of computer refurbishment and repair; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> operate in the United States.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Nonprofit computer refurbisher</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “nonprofit computer refurbisher” means a nonprofit organization that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> primarily works to improve access to information and communication technology in their mission to bridge the digital divide; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> operates in the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Nonprofit organization</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “nonprofit organization” means an organization that is described under section 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and is exempt from taxation under section 501(a) of such Code.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Repairable</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “repairable” means property that is unusable in its current state but can be economically repaired.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Secondary school</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “secondary school” has the meaning given that term in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<ref>20 U.S.C. 7801</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Senior</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “senior” means an individual who is 65 years of age or older.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Senior in need</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “senior in need” means a senior who experiences cultural, social, or geographical isolation that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> restricts the ability of the senior to perform normal daily tasks; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> threatens the capacity of the senior to live independently.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">State agency for surplus property</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “State agency for surplus property” has the meaning given the term “state agency” under section 549(a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(16)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Student</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “student” means any individual enrolled in an educational institution, but not a public or private child care center.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(17)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Surplus computer or technology equipment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “surplus computer or technology equipment” means computer or technology equipment that is property described under section 549(b)(2).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(18)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Technology equipment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “technology equipment” means any physical asset related to a computer or information technology, including any peripheral component, tablet, communication device (such as a router, server, or cell phone), printer, scanner, uninterruptible power source, cable, or connection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(19)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Veteran</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “veteran” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 101 of title 38</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–328, div. Z, § 103(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 5524</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 550.</num>
<heading> Disposal of real property for certain purposes</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “State” includes the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, and the territories and possessions of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Enforcement and Revision of Instruments Transferring Property Under This Section.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to disapproval by the Administrator of General Services within 30 days after notice of a proposed action to be taken under this section, except for personal property transferred pursuant to <ref>section 549 of this title</ref>, the official specified in paragraph (2) shall determine and enforce compliance with the terms, conditions, reservations, and restrictions contained in an instrument by which a transfer under this section is made. The official shall reform, correct, or amend the instrument if necessary to correct the instrument or to conform the transfer to the requirements of law. The official shall grant a release from any term, condition, reservation or restriction contained in the instrument, and shall convey, quitclaim, or release to the transferee (or other eligible user) any right or interest reserved to the Federal Government by the instrument, if the official determines that the property no longer serves the purpose for which it was transferred or that a release, conveyance, or quitclaim deed will not prevent accomplishment of that purpose. The release, conveyance, or quitclaim deed may be made subject to terms and conditions that the official considers necessary to protect or advance the interests of the Government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Specified official</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The official referred to in paragraph (1) is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Education, for property transferred under subsection (c) for school, classroom, or other educational use;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Health and Human Services, for property transferred under subsection (d) for use in the protection of public health, including research;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Secretary of the Interior, for property transferred under subsection (e) for public park or recreation area use;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, for property transferred under subsection (f) to provide housing or housing assistance for low-income individuals or families; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the Secretary of the Interior, for property transferred under subsection (h) for use as a historic monument for the benefit of the public.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Property for School, Classroom, or Other Educational Use.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Assignment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator, in the Administrator’s discretion and under regulations that the Administrator may prescribe, may assign to the Secretary of Education for disposal surplus real property, including buildings, fixtures, and equipment situated on the property, that the Secretary recommends as needed for school, classroom, or other educational use.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Sale or lease</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to disapproval by the Administrator within 30 days after notice to the Administrator by the Secretary of Education of a proposed transfer, the Secretary, for school, classroom, or other educational use, may sell or lease property assigned to the Secretary under paragraph (1) to a State, a political subdivision or instrumentality of a State, a tax-supported educational institution, or a nonprofit educational institution that has been held exempt from taxation under section 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (<ref>26 U.S.C. 501(c)(3)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Fixing value</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In fixing the sale or lease value of property disposed of under paragraph (2), the Secretary of Education shall take into consideration any benefit which has accrued or may accrue to the Government from the use of the property by the State, political subdivision or instrumentality, or institution.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Property for Use in the Protection of Public Health, Including Research.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Assignment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator, in the Administrator’s discretion and under regulations that the Administrator may prescribe, may assign to the Secretary of Health and Human Services for disposal surplus real property, including buildings, fixtures, and equipment situated on the property, that the Secretary recommends as needed for use in the protection of public health, including research.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Sale or lease</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to disapproval by the Administrator within 30 days after notice to the Administrator by the Secretary of Health and Human Services of a proposed transfer, the Secretary, for use in the protection of public health, including research, may sell or lease property assigned to the Secretary under paragraph (1) to a State, a political subdivision or instrumentality of a State, a tax-supported medical institution, or a hospital or similar institution not operated for profit that has been held exempt from taxation under section 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (<ref>26 U.S.C. 501(c)(3)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Fixing value</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In fixing the sale or lease value of property disposed of under paragraph (2), the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall take into consideration any benefit which has accrued or may accrue to the Government from the use of the property by the State, political subdivision or instrumentality, or institution.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Property for Use as a Public Park or Recreation Area.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Assignment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator, in the Administrator’s discretion and under regulations that the Administrator may prescribe, may assign to the Secretary of the Interior for disposal surplus real property, including buildings, fixtures, and equipment situated on the property, that the Secretary recommends as needed for use as a public park or recreation area.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Sale or lease</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to disapproval by the Administrator within 30 days after notice to the Administrator by the Secretary of the Interior of a proposed transfer, the Secretary, for public park or recreation area use, may sell or lease property assigned to the Secretary under paragraph (1) to a State, a political subdivision or instrumentality of a State, or a municipality.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Fixing value</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In fixing the sale or lease value of property disposed of under paragraph (2), the Secretary of the Interior shall take into consideration any benefit which has accrued or may accrue to the Government from the use of the property by the State, political subdivision or instrumentality, or municipality.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Deed of conveyance</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The deed of conveyance of any surplus real property disposed of under this subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall provide that all of the property be used and maintained for the purpose for which it was conveyed in perpetuity, and that if the property ceases to be used or maintained for that purpose, all or any portion of the property shall, in its then existing condition, at the option of the Government, revert to the Government; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> may contain additional terms, reservations, restrictions, and conditions the Secretary of the Interior determines are necessary to safeguard the interests of the Government.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Property for Low Income Housing Assistance.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Assignment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator, in the Administrator’s discretion and under regulations that the Administrator may prescribe, may assign to the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development for disposal surplus real property, including buildings, fixtures, and equipment situated on the property, that the Secretary recommends as needed to provide housing or housing assistance for low-income individuals or families.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Sale or lease</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to disapproval by the Administrator within 30 days after notice to the Administrator by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development of a proposed transfer, the Secretary, to provide housing or housing assistance for low-income individuals or families, may sell or lease property assigned to the Secretary under paragraph (1) to a State, a political subdivision or instrumentality of a State, or a nonprofit organization that exists for the primary purpose of providing housing or housing assistance for low-income individuals or families.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Self-help housing.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Administrator shall disapprove a proposed transfer of property under this subsection unless the Administrator determines that the property will be used for low-income housing opportunities through the construction, rehabilitation, or refurbishment of self-help housing, under terms requiring that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> subject to subparagraph (B), an individual or family receiving housing or housing assistance through use of the property shall contribute a significant amount of labor toward the construction, rehabilitation, or refurbishment; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> dwellings constructed, rehabilitated, or refurbished through use of the property shall be quality dwellings that comply with local building and safety codes and standards and shall be available at prices below prevailing market prices.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Guidelines for considering disabilities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of fulfilling self-help requirements under paragraph (3)(A)(i), the Administrator shall ensure that nonprofit organizations receiving property under paragraph (2) develop and use guidelines to consider any disability (as defined in section 3(2) of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 12102(2)</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Fixing value.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In fixing the sale or lease value of property disposed of under paragraph (2), the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall take into consideration and discount the value for any benefit which has accrued or may accrue to the Government from the use of the property by the State, political subdivision or instrumentality, or nonprofit organization.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Amount of discount</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The amount of the discount under subparagraph (A) is 75 percent of the market value of the property, except that the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development may discount by a greater percentage if the Secretary, in consultation with the Administrator, determines that a higher percentage is justified.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Property for National Service Activities.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Assignment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator, in the Administrator’s discretion and under regulations that the Administrator may prescribe, may assign to the Chief Executive Officer of the Corporation for National and Community Service for disposal surplus property that the Chief Executive Officer recommends as needed for national service activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Sale, lease, or donation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to disapproval by the Administrator within 30 days after notice to the Administrator by the Chief Executive Officer of a proposed transfer, the Chief Executive Officer, for national service activities, may sell, lease, or donate property assigned to the Chief Executive Officer under paragraph (1) to an entity that receives financial assistance under the National and Community Service Act of 1990 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 12501</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Fixing value</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In fixing the sale or lease value of property disposed of under paragraph (2), the Chief Executive Officer shall take into consideration any benefit which has accrued or may accrue to the Government from the use of the property by the entity receiving the property.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Property for Use as a Historic Monument.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Conveyance.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Without monetary consideration to the Government, the Administrator may convey to a State, a political subdivision or instrumentality of a State, or a municipality, the right, title, and interest of the Government in and to any surplus real and related personal property that the Secretary of the Interior determines is suitable and desirable for use as a historic monument for the benefit of the public.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Recommendation by national park system advisory board</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Property may be determined to be suitable and desirable for use as a historic monument only in conformity with a recommendation by the National Park System Advisory Board established under <ref>section 102303 of title 54</ref>. Only the portion of the property that is necessary for the preservation and proper observation of the property’s historic features may be determined to be suitable and desirable for use as a historic monument.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Revenue-producing activity.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Administrator may authorize use of any property conveyed under this subsection for revenue-producing activities if the Secretary of the Interior—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> determines that the activities are compatible with use of the property for historic monument purposes;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> approves the grantee’s plan for repair, rehabilitation, restoration, and maintenance of the property;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> approves the grantee’s plan for financing the repair, rehabilitation, restoration, and maintenance of the property; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> examines and approves the accounting and financial procedures used by the grantee.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of excess income</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the Interior may approve a grantee’s financial plan only if the plan provides that the grantee shall use income exceeding the cost of repair, rehabilitation, restoration, and maintenance only for public historic preservation, park, or recreational purposes.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Audits</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the Interior may periodically audit the records of the grantee that are directly related to the property conveyed.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Deed of conveyance</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The deed of conveyance of any surplus real property disposed of under this subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall provide that all of the property be used and maintained for historical monument purposes in perpetuity, and that if the property ceases to be used or maintained for historical monument purposes, all or any portion of the property shall, in its then existing condition, at the option of the Government, revert to the Government; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> may contain additional terms, reservations, restrictions, and conditions the Administrator determines are necessary to safeguard the interests of the Government.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1094</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 5(j)(2)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3269</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 551.</num>
<heading> Donations to American Red Cross</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator of General Services, in the Administrator’s discretion and under regulations that the Administrator may prescribe, may donate to the American National Red Cross for charitable purposes property that the American National Red Cross processed, produced, or donated and that has been determined to be surplus property.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1099</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 552.</num>
<heading> Abandoned or unclaimed property on Government premises</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority To Take Property</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator of General Services may take possession of abandoned or unclaimed property on premises owned or leased by the Federal Government and determine when title to the property vests in the Government. The Administrator may use, transfer, or otherwise dispose of the property.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Claim Filed by Former Owner</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>If a former owner files a proper claim within three years from the date that title to the property vests in the Government, the former owner shall be paid an amount—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> equal to the proceeds realized from the disposition of the property less costs incident to care and handling as determined by the Administrator; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> if the property has been used or transferred, equal to the fair value of the property as of the time title vested in the Government less costs incident to care and handling as determined by the Administrator.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1099</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–284, § 6(3)</ref>, <date date="2006-09-27">Sept. 27, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1212</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 553.</num>
<heading> Property for correctional facility, law enforcement, and emergency management response purposes</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “State” includes the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the Virgin Islands, the Federated States of Micronesia, the Marshall Islands, Palau, and, the Northern Mariana Islands.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority To Transfer Property</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Administrator of General Services, in the Administrator’s discretion and under regulations that the Administrator may prescribe, may transfer or convey to a State, or political subdivision or instrumentality of a State, surplus real and related personal property that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Attorney General determines is required by the transferee or grantee for correctional facility use under a program approved by the Attorney General for the care or rehabilitation of criminal offenders;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Attorney General determines is required by the transferee or grantee for law enforcement purposes; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency determines is required by the transferee or grantee for emergency management response purposes including fire and rescue services.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">No Monetary Consideration</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A transfer or conveyance under this section shall be made without monetary consideration to the Federal Government.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Deed of Conveyance</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The deed of conveyance of any surplus real and related personal property disposed of under this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall provide that all of the property be used and maintained for the purpose for which it was conveyed in perpetuity, and that if the property ceases to be used or maintained for that purpose, all or any portion of the property shall, in its then existing condition, at the option of the Government, revert to the Government; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> may contain additional terms, reservations, restrictions, and conditions that the Administrator determines are necessary to safeguard the interests of the Government.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Enforcement and Revision of Instruments Transferring Property Under This Section</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall determine and enforce compliance with the terms, conditions, reservations, and restrictions contained in an instrument by which a transfer or conveyance under this section is made. The Administrator shall reform, correct, or amend the instrument if necessary to correct the instrument or to conform the transfer to the requirements of law. The Administrator shall grant a release from any term, condition, reservation or restriction contained in the instrument, and shall convey, quitclaim, or release to the transferee (or other eligible user) any right or interest reserved to the Government by the instrument, if the Administrator determines that the property no longer serves the purpose for which it was transferred or that a release, conveyance, or quitclaim deed will not prevent accomplishment of that purpose. The release, conveyance, or quitclaim deed may be made subject to terms and conditions that the Administrator considers necessary to protect or advance the interests of the Government.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1099</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–295, title VI, § 612(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-04">Oct. 4, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1410</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 554.</num>
<heading> Property for development or operation of a port facility</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the following definitions apply:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Base closure law</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “base closure law” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 101(a)(17) of title 10</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">State</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “State” includes the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the Virgin Islands, the Federated States of Micronesia, the Marshall Islands, Palau, and the Northern Mariana Islands.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority for Assignment to the Secretary of Transportation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Under regulations that the Administrator of General Services, after consultation with the Secretary of Defense, may prescribe, the Administrator, or the Secretary of Defense in the case of property located at a military installation closed or realigned pursuant to a base closure law, may assign to the Secretary of Transportation for disposal surplus real property, including buildings, fixtures, and equipment situated on the property, that the Secretary of Transportation recommends as needed for the development or operation of a port facility.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority for Conveyance by the Secretary of Transportation</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to disapproval by the Administrator or the Secretary of Defense within 30 days after notice of a proposed conveyance by the Secretary of Transportation, the Secretary of Transportation, for the development or operation of a port facility, may convey property assigned to the Secretary of Transportation under subsection (b) to a State or political subdivision, municipality, or instrumentality of a State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Conveyance requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A transfer of property may be made under this section only after the Secretary of Transportation has—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> determined, after consultation with the Secretary of Labor, that the property to be conveyed is located in an area of serious economic disruption;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> received and, after consultation with the Secretary of Commerce, approved an economic development plan submitted by an eligible grantee and based on assured use of the property to be conveyed as part of a necessary economic development program; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> transmitted to Congress an explanatory statement that contains information substantially similar to the information contained in statements prepared under <ref>section 545(e) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">No Monetary Consideration</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A conveyance under this section shall be made without monetary consideration to the Federal Government.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Deed of Conveyance</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The deed of conveyance of any surplus real and related personal property disposed of under this section shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provide that all of the property be used and maintained for the purpose for which it was conveyed in perpetuity, and that if the property ceases to be used or maintained for that purpose, all or any portion of the property shall, in its then existing condition, at the option of the Government, revert to the Government; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> contain additional terms, reservations, restrictions, and conditions that the Secretary of Transportation shall by regulation require to ensure use of the property for the purposes for which it was conveyed and to safeguard the interests of the Government.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Enforcement and Revision of Instruments Transferring Property Under This Section</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Transportation shall determine and enforce compliance with the terms, conditions, reservations, and restrictions contained in an instrument by which a transfer or conveyance under this section is made. The Secretary shall reform, correct, or amend the instrument if necessary to correct the instrument or to conform the transfer to the requirements of law. The Secretary shall grant a release from any term, condition, reservation or restriction contained in the instrument, and shall convey, quitclaim, or release to the grantee any right or interest reserved to the Government by the instrument, if the Secretary determines that the property no longer serves the purpose for which it was transferred or that a release, conveyance, or quitclaim deed will not prevent accomplishment of that purpose. The release, conveyance, or quitclaim deed may be made subject to terms and conditions that the Secretary considers necessary to protect or advance the interests of the Government.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1100</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title X, § 1056(a)(5)(A)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3439</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–284, § 6(4)</ref>, <date date="2006-09-27">Sept. 27, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1212</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 555.</num>
<heading> Donation of law enforcement canines to handlers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The head of a federal agency having control of a canine that has been used by a federal agency in the performance of law enforcement duties and that has been determined by the agency to be no longer needed for official purposes may donate the canine to an individual who has experience handling canines in the performance of those duties.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1102</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 556.</num>
<heading> Disposal of dredge vessels</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator of General Services, pursuant to sections 521 through 527, 529, and 549 of this title, may dispose of a United States Army Corps of Engineers vessel used for dredging, together with related equipment owned by the Federal Government and under the control of the Chief of Engineers, if the Secretary of the Army declares the vessel to be in excess of federal needs.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Recipients and Purposes</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Disposal under this section is accomplished—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> through sale or lease to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a foreign government as part of a Corps of Engineers technical assistance program;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a federal or state maritime academy for training purposes; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a non-federal public body for scientific, educational, or cultural purposes; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> through sale solely for scrap to foreign or domestic interests.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">No Dredging Activities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A vessel described in subsection (a) shall not be disposed of under any law for the purpose of engaging in dredging activities within the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Deposit of Amounts Collected</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Amounts collected from the sale or lease of a vessel or equipment under this section shall be deposited into the revolving fund authorized by section 101 (9th par.) of the Civil Functions Appropriation <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002008">1</ref> Act, 1954 (<ref>33 U.S.C. 576</ref>), to be available, as provided in appropriation laws, for the operation and maintenance of vessels under the control of the Corps of Engineers.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1102</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 557.</num>
<heading> Donation of books to Free Public Library</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to regulations under this subtitle, a book that is no longer needed by an executive department, bureau, or commission of the Federal Government, and that is not an advisable addition to the Library of Congress, shall be turned over to the Free Public Library of the District of Columbia for general use if the book is appropriate for the Free Public Library.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1102</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 558.</num>
<heading> Donation of forfeited vessels</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A vessel that is forfeited to the Federal Government may be donated, in accordance with procedures under this subtitle, to an eligible institution described in subsection (b).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Eligible Institution</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An eligible institution referred to in subsection (a) is an educational institution with a commercial fishing vessel safety program or other vessel safety, education and training program. The institution must certify to the federal officer making the donation that the program includes, at a minimum, all of the following courses in vessel safety:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Vessel stability.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Firefighting.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Shipboard first aid.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Marine safety and survival.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Seamanship rules of the road.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Terms and Conditions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The donation of a vessel under this section shall be made on terms and conditions considered appropriate by the federal officer making the donation. All of the following terms and conditions are required:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">No warranty</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The institution must accept the vessel as is, where it is, and without warranty of any kind and without any representation as to its condition or suitability for use.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Maintenance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The institution is responsible for maintaining the vessel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Instruction only</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The vessel may be used only for instructing students in a vessel safety education and training program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Documentation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the vessel is eligible to be documented, it must be documented by the institution as a vessel of the United States under chapter 121 of title 46. The requirements of paragraph (5) must be noted on the permanent record of the vessel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Disposal</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The institution must obtain prior approval from the Administrator of General Services before disposing of the vessel and any proceeds from disposal shall be payable to the Government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inspection or regulation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The vessel shall be inspected or regulated in the same manner as a nautical school vessel under chapter 33 of title 46.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Government Liability</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Government is not liable in an action arising out of the transfer or use of a vessel transferred under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1103</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 559.</num>
<heading> Advice of Attorney General with respect to antitrust law</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the term “antitrust law” includes—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Sherman Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 1</ref> et seq.);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Clayton Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 12</ref> et seq., <ref>29 U.S.C. 52</ref>, 53);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the Federal Trade Commission Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 41</ref> et seq.); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> sections 73 and 74 of the Wilson Tariff Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 8</ref>, 9).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Advice Required.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An executive agency shall not dispose of property to a private interest until the agency has received the advice of the Attorney General on whether the disposal to a private interest would tend to create or maintain a situation inconsistent with antitrust law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>This section does not apply to disposal of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> real property, if the estimated fair market value is less than $3,000,000; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> personal property (other than a patent, process, technique, or invention), if the estimated fair market value is less than $3,000,000.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Notice to Attorney General.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An executive agency that contemplates disposing of property to a private interest shall promptly transmit notice of the proposed disposal, including probable terms and conditions, to the Attorney General.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Copy</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except for the General Services Administration, an executive agency that transmits notice under paragraph (1) shall simultaneously transmit a copy of the notice to the Administrator of General Services.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Advice From Attorney General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Within a reasonable time, not later than 60 days, after receipt of notice under subsection (c), the Attorney General shall advise the Administrator and any interested executive agency whether, so far as the Attorney General can determine, the proposed disposition would tend to create or maintain a situation inconsistent with antitrust law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Request for Information</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>On request from the Attorney General, the head of an executive agency shall furnish information the agency possesses that the Attorney General determines is appropriate or necessary to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> give advice required by this section; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> determine whether any other disposition or proposed disposition of surplus property violates antitrust law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">No Effect on Antitrust Law</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This subtitle does not impair, amend, or modify antitrust law or limit or prevent application of antitrust law to a person acquiring property under this subtitle.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1103</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>PROCEEDS FROM SALE OR TRANSFER</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 571.</num>
<heading> General rules for deposit and use of proceeds</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Deposit in Treasury as Miscellaneous Receipts.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as otherwise provided in this subchapter, proceeds described in paragraph (2) shall be deposited in the Treasury as miscellaneous receipts.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Proceeds</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The proceeds referred to in paragraph (1) are proceeds under this chapter from a—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> transfer of excess property to a federal agency for agency use; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> sale, lease, or other disposition of surplus property.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Payment of Expenses of Sale Before Deposit</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to regulations under this subtitle, the expenses of the sale of old material, condemned stores, supplies, or other public property may be paid from the proceeds of sale so that only the net proceeds are deposited in the Treasury. This subsection applies whether proceeds are deposited as miscellaneous receipts or to the credit of an appropriation as authorized by law.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1104</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–287, § 20(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1477</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–318, § 7(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1616</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 572.</num>
<heading> Real property</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">In General.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Separate fund</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in subsection (b), proceeds of the disposition of surplus real and related personal property by the Administrator of General Services shall be set aside in a separate fund in the Treasury.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Payment of expenses from the fund.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>From the fund described in paragraph (1), the Administrator may obligate an amount to pay the following direct expenses incurred for the use of excess property and the disposal of surplus property under this subtitle:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Fees of appraisers, auctioneers, and realty brokers, in accordance with the scale customarily paid in similar commercial transactions.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Costs of environmental and historic preservation services, highest and best use of property studies, utilization of property studies, deed compliance inspection, and the expenses incurred in a relocation.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Advertising and surveying.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Limitations.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Percentage limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In each fiscal year, no more than 12 percent of the proceeds of all dispositions of surplus real and related personal property may be paid to meet direct expenses incurred in connection with the dispositions.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Determination of maximum amount</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Director of the Office of Management and Budget each quarter shall determine the maximum amount that may be obligated under this paragraph.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Direct payment or reimbursement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An amount obligated under this paragraph may be used to pay an expense directly or to reimburse a fund or appropriation that initially paid the expense.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transfer to miscellaneous receipts</inline>.—</heading>
<content>At least once each year, excess amounts beyond current operating needs shall be transferred from the fund described in paragraph (1) to miscellaneous receipts.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A report of receipts, disbursements, and transfers to miscellaneous receipts under this subsection shall be made annually, in connection with the budget estimate, to the Director and to Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Real Property Under Control of a Military Department.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this subsection, the following definitions apply:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Military installation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “military installation” has the meaning given that term in section 2687(e)(1) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002009">1</ref> of title 10.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Base closure law</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “base closure law” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 101(a)(17) of title 10</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Application.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This subsection applies to real property, including any improvement on the property, that is under the control of a military department and that the Secretary of the department determines is excess to the department’s needs.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exceptions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>This subsection does not apply to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> damaged or deteriorated military family housing facilities conveyed under <ref>section 2854a of title 10</ref>; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> property at a military installation designated for closure or realignment pursuant to a base closure law.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transfer between military departments</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall provide that property described in paragraph (2) is available for transfer, without reimbursement, to other military departments within the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Alternative disposition by administrator of general services</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If property is not transferred pursuant to paragraph (3), the Secretary of the military department with the property under its control shall request the Administrator to transfer or dispose of the property in accordance with this subtitle or other applicable law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Proceeds.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Deposit in special account</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For a transfer or disposition of property pursuant to paragraph (4), the Administrator shall deposit any proceeds (less expenses of the transfer or disposition as provided in subsection (a)) in a special account in the Treasury.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Availability of amount deposited</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>To the extent provided in an appropriation law, an amount deposited in a special account under subparagraph (A) is available for facility maintenance and repair or environmental restoration as follows:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> In the case of property located at a military installation that is closed, the amount is available for facility maintenance and repair or environmental restoration by the military department that had jurisdiction over the property before the closure of the military installation.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> In the case of property located at any other military installation—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> 50 percent of the amount is available for facility maintenance and repair or environmental restoration at the military installation where the property was located before it was disposed of or transferred; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> 50 percent of the amount is available for facility maintenance and repair and for environmental restoration by the military department that had jurisdiction over the property before it was disposed of or transferred.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading>
<content>As part of the annual request for authorizations of appropriations to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives, the Secretary of Defense shall include an accounting of each transfer and disposal made in accordance with this subsection during the fiscal year preceding the fiscal year in which the request is made. The accounting shall include a detailed explanation of each transfer and disposal and of the use of the proceeds received from it by the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1105</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–447, div. H, title IV, § 408</ref>, <date date="2004-12-08">Dec. 8, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3258</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–13, div. A, title VI, § 6068</ref>, <date date="2005-05-11">May 11, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 299</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title X, § 1056(a)(5)(B)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3439</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 573.</num>
<heading> Personal property</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator of General Services may retain from the proceeds of sales of personal property the Administrator conducts amounts necessary to recover, to the extent practicable, costs the Administrator (or the Administrator’s agent) incurs in conducting the sales. The Administrator shall deposit amounts retained into the Acquisition Services Fund established under <ref>section 321(a) of this title</ref>. From the amounts deposited, the Administrator may pay direct costs and reasonably related indirect costs incurred in conducting sales of personal property. At least once each year, amounts retained that are not needed to pay the direct and indirect costs shall be transferred from the Acquisition Services Fund to the general fund or another appropriate account in the Treasury.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1107</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–313, § 3(h)(4)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1736</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 574.</num>
<heading> Other rules regarding proceeds</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Credit to Reimbursable Fund or Appropriation.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Application</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>This subsection applies to property acquired with amounts—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> not appropriated from the general fund of the Treasury; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> appropriated from the general fund of the Treasury but by law reimbursable from assessment, tax, or other revenue or receipts.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The net proceeds of a disposition or transfer of property described in paragraph (1) shall be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> credited to the applicable reimbursable fund or appropriation; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> paid to the federal agency that determined the property to be excess.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Calculation of net proceeds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of this subsection, the net proceeds of a disposition or transfer of property are the proceeds less all expenses incurred for the disposition or transfer, including care and handling.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Alternative credit to miscellaneous receipts</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the agency that determined the property to be excess decides that it is uneconomical or impractical to ascertain the amount of net proceeds, the proceeds shall be credited to miscellaneous receipts.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Special Account for Refunds or Payments for Breach.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Deposits</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A federal agency that disposes of surplus property under this chapter may deposit, in a special account in the Treasury, amounts of the proceeds of the dispositions that the agency decides are necessary to permit—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> appropriate refunds to purchasers for dispositions that are rescinded or that do not become final; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> payments for breach of warranty.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Withdrawals</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A federal agency that deposits proceeds in a special account under paragraph (1) may withdraw amounts to be refunded or paid from the account without regard to the origin of the amounts withdrawn.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Credit to Cost of Contractor’s Work</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If a contract made by an executive agency, or a subcontract under that contract, authorizes the proceeds of a sale of property in the custody of a contractor or subcontractor to be credited to the price or cost of work covered by the contract or subcontract, then the proceeds of the sale shall be credited in accordance with the contract or subcontract.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Acceptance of Property Instead of Cash</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An executive agency entitled to receive cash under a contract for the lease, sale, or other disposition of surplus property may accept property instead of cash if the President determines that the property is strategic or critical material. The property is valued at the prevailing market price when the cash payment becomes due.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Management of Credit, Leases, and Permits</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For a disposition of surplus property under this chapter, if credit has been extended, or if the disposition has been by lease or permit, the Administrator of General Services, in a manner and on terms the Administrator determines are in the best interest of the Federal Government—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall administer and manage the credit, lease, or permit, and any security for the credit, lease, or permit; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> may enforce, adjust, and settle any right of the Government with respect to the credit, lease, or permit.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1107</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER V—</num>
<heading>OPERATION OF BUILDINGS AND RELATED ACTIVITIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 581.</num>
<heading> General authority of Administrator of General Services</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>[(a)</num>
<content> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 107–296, title XVII, § 1706(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2316</ref>.]</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Personnel and Equipment</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Administrator of General Services may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> employ and pay personnel at per diem rates approved by the Administrator, not exceeding rates currently paid by private industry for similar services in the place where the services are performed; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> purchase, repair, and clean uniforms for civilian employees of the General Services Administration who are required by law or regulation to wear uniform clothing.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Acquisition and Management of Property.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Real estate</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator may acquire, by purchase, condemnation, or otherwise, real estate and interests in real estate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Ground rent</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator may pay ground rent for buildings owned by the Federal Government or occupied by federal agencies, and pay the rent in advance if required by law or if the Administrator determines that advance payment is in the public interest.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rent and repairs under a lease</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator may pay rent and make repairs, alterations, and improvements under the terms of a lease entered into by, or transferred to, the Administration for the housing of a federal agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Repairs that are economically advantageous</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Administrator may repair, alter, or improve rented premises if the Administrator determines that doing so is advantageous to the Government in terms of economy, efficiency, or national security. The Administrator’s determination must—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> set forth the circumstances that make the repair, alteration, or improvement advantageous; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> show that the total cost (rental, repair, alteration, and improvement) for the expected life of the lease is less than the cost of alternative space not needing repair, alteration, or improvement.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Insurance proceeds for defense industrial reserve</inline>.—</heading>
<content>At the direction of the Secretary of Defense, the Administrator may use insurance proceeds received for damage to property that is part of the Defense Industrial Reserve to repair or restore the property.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Maintenance contracts</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator may enter into a contract, for a period not exceeding five years, for the inspection, maintenance, and repair of fixed equipment in a federally owned building.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Lease of Federal Building Sites.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator may lease a federal building site or addition, including any improvements, until the site is needed for construction purposes. The lease must be for fair rental value and on other terms and conditions the Administrator considers to be in the public interest pursuant to <ref>section 545 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Negotiation without advertising</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A lease under this subsection may be negotiated without public advertising for bids if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> the lessee is—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the former owner from whom the Government acquired the property; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the former owner’s tenant in possession; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the lease is negotiated incident to or in connection with the acquisition of the property.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Deposit of rent</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Rent received under this subsection may be deposited into the Federal Buildings Fund.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Assistance to the Inaugural Committee</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Administrator may provide direct assistance and special services for the Inaugural Committee (as defined in <ref>section 501 of title 36</ref>) during an inaugural period in connection with Presidential inaugural operations and functions. Assistance and services under this subsection may include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> employment of personal services without regard to chapters 33 and 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> providing Government-owned and leased space for personnel and parking;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> paying overtime to guard and custodial forces;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> erecting and removing stands and platforms;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> providing and operating first-aid stations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> providing furniture and equipment; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> providing other incidental services in the discretion of the Administrator.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Utilities for Defense Industrial Reserve and Surplus Property</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Administrator may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> provide utilities and services, if the utilities and services are not provided by other sources, to a person, firm, or corporation occupying or using a plant or portion of a plant that constitutes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any part of the Defense Industrial Reserve pursuant to <ref>section 4881 of title 10</ref>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> surplus real property; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> credit an amount received for providing utilities and services under this subsection to an applicable appropriation of the Administration.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Obtaining Payments</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Administrator may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> obtain payments, through advances or otherwise, for services, space, quarters, maintenance, repair, or other facilities furnished, on a reimbursable basis, to a federal agency, a mixed-ownership Government corporation (as defined in chapter 91 of title 31), or the District of Columbia; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> credit the payments to the applicable appropriation of the Administration.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Cooperative Use of Public Buildings.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Leasing space for commercial and other purposes</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator may lease space on a major pedestrian access level, courtyard, or rooftop of a public building to a person, firm, or organization engaged in commercial, cultural, educational, or recreational activity (as defined in <ref>section 3306(a) of this title</ref>). The Administrator shall establish a rental rate for leased space equivalent to the prevailing commercial rate for comparable space devoted to a similar purpose in the vicinity of the public building. The lease may be negotiated without competitive bids, but shall contain terms and conditions and be negotiated pursuant to procedures that the Administrator considers necessary to promote competition and to protect the public interest.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Occasional use of space for non-commercial purposes</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator may make available, on occasion, or lease at a rate and on terms and conditions that the Administrator considers to be in the public interest, an auditorium, meeting room, courtyard, rooftop, or lobby of a public building to a person, firm, or organization engaged in cultural, educational, or recreational activity (as defined in <ref>section 3306(a) of this title</ref>) that will not disrupt the operation of the building.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Deposit and credit of amounts received</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator may deposit into the Federal Buildings Fund an amount received under a lease or rental executed pursuant to paragraph (1) or (2). The amount shall be credited to the appropriation from the Fund applicable to the operation of the building.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Furnishing utilities and maintenance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator may furnish utilities, maintenance, repair, and other services to a person, firm, or organization leasing space pursuant to paragraph (1) or (2). The services may be provided during and outside of regular working hours of federal agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1108</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–296, title XVII, § 1706(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2316</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–284, § 6(5)</ref>, <date date="2006-09-27">Sept. 27, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1212</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1702(g)(2)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2158</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 582.</num>
<heading> Management of buildings by Administrator of General Services</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Request by Federal Agency or Instrumentality</inline>.—</heading>
<content>At the request of a federal agency, a mixed-ownership Government corporation (as defined in chapter 91 of title 31), or the District of Columbia, the Administrator of General Services may operate, maintain, and protect a building that is owned by the Federal Government (or, in the case of a wholly owned or mixed-ownership Government corporation, by the corporation) and occupied by the agency or instrumentality making the request.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Transfer of Functions by Director of the Office of Management and Budget.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>When the Director of the Office of Management and Budget determines that it is in the interest of economy or efficiency, the Director shall transfer to the Administrator all functions vested in a federal agency with respect to the operation, maintenance, and custody of an office building owned by the Government or a wholly owned Government corporation, or an office building, or part of an office building, that is occupied by a federal agency under a lease.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception for post-office buildings</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A transfer of functions shall not be made under this subsection for a post-office building, unless the Director determines that the building is not used predominantly for post-office purposes. The Administrator may delegate functions with respect to a post-office building that are transferred to the Administrator under this subsection only to another officer or employee of the General Services Administration or to the Postmaster General.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception for buildings in a foreign country</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A transfer of functions shall not be made under this subsection for a building located in a foreign country.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception for department of defense buildings</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A transfer of functions shall not be made under this subsection for a building located on the grounds of a facility of the Department of Defense (including a fort, camp, post, arsenal, navy yard, naval training station, airfield, proving ground, military supply depot, or school) unless and only to the extent that the Secretary of Defense has issued a permit for use by another agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception for groups of special purpose buildings</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A transfer of functions shall not be made under this subsection for a building that the Director finds to be a part of a group of buildings that are—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> located in the same vicinity;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> used wholly or predominantly for the special purposes of the agency with custody of the buildings; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> not generally suitable for use by another agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception for certain government buildings</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A transfer of functions shall not be made under this subsection for the Treasury Building, the Bureau of Engraving and Printing Building, the buildings occupied by the National Institute of Standards and Technology, and the buildings under the jurisdiction of the regents of the Smithsonian Institution.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1110</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 583.</num>
<heading> Construction of buildings</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>At the request of a federal agency, a mixed-ownership Government corporation (as defined in chapter 91 of title 31), or the District of Columbia, the Administrator of General Services may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> acquire land for a building or project authorized by Congress;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> make or cause to be made (under contract or otherwise) surveys and test borings and prepare plans and specifications for a building or project prior to the Attorney General’s approval of the title to the site; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> contract for, and supervise, the construction, development, and equipping of a building or project.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transfer of Amounts</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An amount available to a federal agency or instrumentality for a building or project may be transferred, in advance, to the General Services Administration for purposes the Administrator determines are necessary, including payment of salaries and expenses for preparing plans and specifications and for field supervision.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1111</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 584.</num>
<heading> Assignment and reassignment of space</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Authority.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to paragraph (2), the Administrator of General Services may assign or reassign space for an executive agency in any Federal Government-owned or leased building.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Administrator’s authority under paragraph (1) may be exercised only—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in accordance with policies and directives the President prescribes under <ref>section 121(a) of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> after consultation with the head of the executive agency affected; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> on a determination by the Administrator that the assignment or reassignment is advantageous to the Government in terms of economy, efficiency, or national security.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Priority for Public Access</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In assigning space on a major pedestrian access level (other than space leased under section 581(h)(1) or (2) of this title), the Administrator shall, where practicable, give priority to federal activities requiring regular contact with the public. If the space is not available, the Administrator shall provide space with maximum ease of access to building entrances.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1112</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 585.</num>
<heading> Lease agreements</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">In General.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator of General Services may enter into a lease agreement with a person, copartnership, corporation, or other public or private entity for the accommodation of a federal agency in a building (or improvement) which is in existence or being erected by the lessor to accommodate the federal agency. The Administrator may assign and reassign the leased space to a federal agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Terms</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A lease agreement under this subsection shall be on terms the Administrator considers to be in the interest of the Federal Government and necessary for the accommodation of the federal agency. However, the lease agreement may not bind the Government for more than 20 years and the obligation of amounts for a lease under this subsection is limited to the current fiscal year for which payments are due without regard to <ref>section 1341(a)(1)(B) of title 31</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Sublease.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Application</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>This subsection applies to rent received if the Administrator—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> determines that an unexpired portion of a lease of space to the Government is surplus property; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> disposes of the property by sublease.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of rent</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding <ref>section 571(a) of this title</ref>, the Administrator may deposit rent received into the Federal Buildings Fund. The Administrator may defray from the fund any costs necessary to provide services to the Government’s lessee and to pay the rent (not otherwise provided for) on the lease of the space to the Government.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Amounts for Rent Available for Lease of Buildings on Government Land</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Amounts made available to the General Services Administration for the payment of rent may be used to lease space, for a period of not more than 30 years, in buildings erected on land owned by the Government.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Any bargain-price option to purchase at less than fair market value contained in any lease agreement entered into on or after <date date="2021-01-01">January 1, 2021</date>, pursuant to this section may be exercised only to the extent specifically provided for in subsequent appropriation Acts or other Acts of Congress.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1112</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–257, § 1</ref>, <date date="2022-12-21">Dec. 21, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2371</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 586.</num>
<heading> Charges for space and services</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, “space and services” means space, services, quarters, maintenance, repair, and other facilities.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Charges by Administrator of General Services.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator of General Services shall impose a charge for furnishing space and services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rates</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall, from time to time, determine the rates to be charged for furnishing space and services and shall prescribe regulations providing for the rates. The rates shall approximate commercial charges for comparable space and services. However, for a building for which the Administrator is responsible for alterations only (as the term “alter” is defined in <ref>section 3301(a) of this title</ref>), the rates shall be fixed to recover only the approximate cost incurred in providing alterations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exemptions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator may exempt anyone from the charges required by this subsection when the Administrator determines that charges would be infeasible or impractical. To the extent an exemption is granted, appropriations to the General Services Administration are authorized to reimburse the Federal Buildings Fund for any loss of revenue.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Charges by Executive Agencies.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An executive agency, other than the Administration, may impose a charge for furnishing space and services at rates approved by the Administrator.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Crediting amounts received</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An amount an executive agency receives under this subsection shall be credited to the appropriation or fund initially charged for providing the space or service. However, amounts in excess of actual operating and maintenance costs shall be credited to miscellaneous receipts unless otherwise provided by law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rent Payments for Lease Space</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An agency may make rent payments to the Administration for lease space relating to expansion needs of the agency. Payment rates shall approximate commercial charges for comparable space as provided in subsection (b). Payments shall be deposited into the Federal Buildings Fund. The Administration may use amounts received under this subsection, in addition to amounts received as New Obligational Authority, in the Rental of Space activity of the Fund.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1113</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 587.</num>
<heading> Telecommuting and other alternative workplace arrangements</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “telecommuting centers” means flexiplace work telecommuting centers.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Telecommuting Centers Established by Administrator of General Services.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator of General Services may acquire space for, establish, and equip telecommuting centers for use in accordance with this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A telecommuting center may be used by employees of federal agencies, state and local governments, and the private sector. The Administrator shall give federal employees priority in using a telecommuting center. The Administrator may make a telecommuting center available for use by others to the extent it is not fully utilized by federal employees.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">User fees</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall charge a user fee for the use of a telecommuting center. The amount of the user fee shall approximate commercial charges for comparable space and services. However, the user fee may not be less than necessary to pay the cost of establishing and operating the telecommuting center, including the reasonable cost of renovation and replacement of furniture, fixtures, and equipment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Deposit and use of fees</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Administrator may—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> deposit user fees into the Federal Buildings Fund and use the fees to pay costs incurred in establishing and operating the telecommuting center; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> accept and retain income received by the General Services Administration, from federal agencies and non-federal sources, to defray costs directly associated with the functions of telecommuting centers.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Development of Alternative Workplace Arrangements by Executive Agencies and Others.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this subsection, the term “alternative workplace arrangements” includes telecommuting, hoteling, virtual offices, and other distributive work arrangements.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consideration by executive agencies</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In considering whether to acquire space, quarters, buildings, or other facilities for use by employees, the head of an executive agency shall consider whether needs can be met using alternative workplace arrangements.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Guidance from administrator</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator may provide guidance, assistance, and oversight to any person regarding the establishment and operation of alternative workplace arrangements.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Amounts Available for Flexiplace Work Telecommuting Programs.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this subsection, the term “flexiplace work telecommuting program” means a program under which employees of a department or agency set out in paragraph (2) are permitted to perform all or a portion of their duties at a telecommuting center established under this section or other federal law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Minimum funding</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For each of the following departments and agencies, in each fiscal year at least $50,000 of amounts made available for salaries and expenses is available only for carrying out a flexiplace work telecommuting program:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Department of Agriculture.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Department of Commerce.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Department of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Department of Education.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Department of Energy.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Department of Health and Human Services.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> Department of Housing and Urban Development.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> Department of the Interior.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> Department of Justice.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> Department of Labor.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> Department of State.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(L)</num>
<content> Department of Transportation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(M)</num>
<content> Department of the Treasury.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(N)</num>
<content> Department of Veterans Affairs.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(O)</num>
<content> Environmental Protection Agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(P)</num>
<content> General Services Administration.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(Q)</num>
<content> Office of Personnel Management.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(R)</num>
<content> Small Business Administration.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(S)</num>
<content> Social Security Administration.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(T)</num>
<content> United States Postal Service.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1113</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 588.</num>
<heading> Movement and supply of office furniture</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “controlled space” means a substantial and identifiable segment of space (such as a building, floor, or wing) in a location that the Administrator of General Services controls for purposes of assignment of space.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Application</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section applies if an agency (or unit of the agency), moves from one controlled space to another, whether in the same or a different location.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Moving Existing Furniture</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The furniture and furnishings used by an agency (or organizational unit of the agency) shall be moved only if the Administrator determines, after consultation with the head of the agency and with due regard for the program activities of the agency, that it would not be more economical and efficient to make suitable replacements available in the new controlled space.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Providing Replacement Furniture</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In the absence of a determination under subsection (c), suitable furniture and furnishings for the new controlled space shall be provided from stocks under the control of the moving agency or from stocks available to the Administrator, whichever the Administrator determines to be more economical and efficient. However, the same or similar items may not be provided from both sources.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Control of Replacement Furniture</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If furniture and furnishings for a new controlled space are provided from stocks available to the Administrator, the items being provided remain in the control of the Administrator.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Control of Furniture Not Moved.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If furniture and furnishings for a new controlled space are provided from stocks available to the Administrator, the furniture and furnishings that were previously used by the moving agency (or unit of the agency) pass to the control of the Administrator.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Reimbursement.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Furniture and furnishings passing to the control of the Administrator under this section pass without reimbursement.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception for trust fund</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If furniture and furnishings that were purchased from a trust fund pass to the control of the Administrator under this section, the Administrator shall reimburse the trust fund for the fair market value of the furniture and furnishings.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Revolving or working capital fund</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If furniture and furnishings are carried as assets of a revolving or working capital fund at the time they pass to the control of the Administrator under this section, the net book value of the furniture and furnishings shall be written off and the capital of the fund is diminished by the amount of the write-off.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1115</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 589.</num>
<heading> Installation, repair, and replacement of sidewalks</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An executive agency may install, repair, and replace sidewalks around buildings, installations, property, or grounds that are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> under the agency’s control;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> owned by the Federal Government; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> located in a State, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, or a territory or possession of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reimbursement</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subsection (a) may be carried out by—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> reimbursement to a State or political subdivision of a State, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, or a territory or possession of the United States; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a means other than reimbursement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subsection (a) shall be carried out in accordance with regulations the Administrator of General Services prescribes with the approval of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of Amounts</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Amounts appropriated to an executive agency for installation, repair, and maintenance, generally, are available to carry out this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Liability</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section does not increase or enlarge the tort liability of the Government for injuries to individuals or damages to property.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1116</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 590.</num>
<heading> Child care</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Guidance, Assistance, and Oversight</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Through the General Services Administration’s licensing agreements, the Administrator of General Services shall provide guidance, assistance, and oversight to federal agencies for the development of child care centers to provide economical and effective child care for federal workers.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Allotment of Space in Federal Buildings.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this subsection, the following definitions apply:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Child care provider</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “child care provider” means an individual or entity that provides or proposes to provide child care services for federal employees.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Allotment officer</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “allotment officer” means an officer or agency of the Federal Government charged with the allotment of space in federal buildings.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Allotment</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A child care provider may be allotted space in a federal building by an allotment officer if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the child care provider applies to the allotment officer in the community or district in which child care services are to be provided;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the space is available; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> the allotment officer determines that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the space will be used to provide child care services to children of whom at least 50 percent have one parent or guardian employed by the Government; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the child care provider will give priority to federal employees for available child care services in the space.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Payment for Space and Services.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of this subsection, the term “services” includes the providing of lighting, heating, cooling, electricity, office furniture, office machines and equipment, classroom furnishings and equipment, kitchen appliances, playground equipment, telephone service (including installation of lines and equipment and other expenses associated with telephone services), and security systems (including installation and other expenses associated with security systems), including replacement equipment, as needed.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">No charge</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Space allotted under subsection (b) may be provided without charge for rent or services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reimbursement for costs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For space allotted under subsection (b), if there is an agreement for the payment of costs associated with providing space or services, neither title 31, nor any other law, prohibits or restricts payment by reimbursement to the miscellaneous receipts or other appropriate account of the Treasury.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Payment of Other Costs</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>If an agency has a child care facility in its space, or is a sponsoring agency for a child care facility in other federal or leased space, the agency or the Administration may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> pay accreditation fees, including renewal fees, for the child care facility to be accredited by a nationally recognized early-childhood professional organization;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> pay travel and per diem expenses for representatives of the child care facility to attend the annual Administration child care conference; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> enter into a consortium with one or more private entities under which the private entities assist in defraying costs associated with the salaries and benefits for personnel providing services at the facility.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reimbursement for Employee Training</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding <ref>section 1345 of title 31</ref>, an agency, department, or instrumentality of the Government that provides or proposes to provide child care services for federal employees may reimburse a federal employee or any individual employed to provide child care services for travel, transportation, and subsistence expenses incurred for training classes, conferences, or other meetings in connection with providing the services. A per diem allowance made under this subsection may not exceed the rate specified in regulations prescribed under <ref>section 5707 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Criminal History Background Checks.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this subsection, the term “executive facility” means a facility owned or leased by an office or entity within the executive branch of the Government. The term includes a facility owned or leased by the General Services Administration on behalf of an office or entity within the judicial branch of the Government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>All workers in a child care center located in an executive facility shall undergo a criminal history background check as defined in section 231 of the Crime Control Act of 1990 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 13041</ref>).<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002010">1</ref></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Nonapplication to legislative branch facilities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This subsection does not apply to a facility owned by or leased on behalf of an office or entity within the legislative branch of the Government.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Appropriated Amounts for Affordable Child Care.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of this subsection, the term “Executive agency” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 105 of title 5</ref>, but does not include the Government Accountability Office.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In accordance with regulations the Office of Personnel Management prescribes, an Executive agency that provides or proposes to provide child care services for federal employees may use appropriated amounts that are otherwise available for salaries and expenses to provide child care in a federal or leased facility, or through contract, for civilian employees of the agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Affordability</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Amounts used pursuant to paragraph (2) shall be applied to improve the affordability of child care for lower income federal employees using or seeking to use the child care services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Advances</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding <ref>section 3324 of title 31</ref>, amounts may be paid in advance to licensed or regulated child care providers for services to be rendered during an agreed period.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notification</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No amounts made available by law may be used to implement this subsection without advance notice to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Application to house of representatives</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>This subsection shall apply with respect to the House of Representatives in the same manner as it applies to an Executive agency, except that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the authority granted to the Office of Personnel Management shall be exercised with respect to the House of Representatives by the Speaker of the House of Representatives in accordance with regulations promulgated by the Committee on House Administration; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> amounts may be made available to implement this subsection with respect to the House of Representatives without advance notice to the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Application to senate</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>This subsection shall apply with respect to the Senate in the same manner as it applies to an Executive agency, except that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the authority granted to the Office of Personnel Management shall be exercised with respect to the Senate, by the Majority and Minority Leaders of the Senate, in accordance with regulations promulgated by the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> amounts may be made available to implement this subsection with respect to the Senate without advance notice to the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1116</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–271, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-07-07">July 7, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 814</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–328, div. I, title I, § 117(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4924</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–47, div. E, title I, § 103(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-03-23">Mar. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 712</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 591.</num>
<heading> Purchase of electricity</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General Limitation on Use of Amounts</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A department, agency, or instrumentality of the Federal Government may not use amounts appropriated or made available by any law to purchase electricity in a manner inconsistent with state law governing the provision of electric utility service, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> state utility commission rulings; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> electric utility franchises or service territories established under state statute, state regulation, or state-approved territorial agreements.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Exceptions.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Energy savings</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section does not preclude the head of a federal agency from entering into a contract under section 801 of the National Energy Conservation Policy Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 8287</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Energy savings for military installations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>This section does not preclude the Secretary of a military department from—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> entering into a contract under section 2394 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002011">1</ref> of title 10; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> purchasing electricity from any provider if the Secretary finds that the utility having the applicable state-approved franchise (or other service authorization) is unwilling or unable to meet unusual standards of service reliability that are necessary for purposes of national defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1118</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 592.</num>
<heading> Federal Buildings Fund</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Existence</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is in the Treasury a fund known as the Federal Buildings Fund.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Deposits.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The following revenues and collections shall be deposited into the Fund:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> User charges under <ref>section 586(b) of this title</ref>, payable in advance or otherwise.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Proceeds from the lease of federal building sites or additions under <ref>section 581(d) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Receipts from carriers and others for loss of, or damage to, property belonging to the Fund.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reimbursements for special services</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This subchapter does not preclude the Administrator of General Services from providing special services, not included in the standard level user charge, on a reimbursable basis. The reimbursements may be credited to the Fund.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transfer of surplus amounts</inline>.—</heading>
<content>To prevent the accumulation of excessive surpluses in the Fund, in any fiscal year an amount specified in an appropriation law may be transferred out of the Fund and deposited as miscellaneous receipts in the Treasury.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Uses.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Deposits in the Fund are available for real property management and related activities in the amounts specified in annual appropriation laws without regard to fiscal year limitations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Salaries and expenses related to construction projects or planning programs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Deposits in the Fund that are available pursuant to annual appropriation laws may be transferred and consolidated on the books of the Treasury into a special account in accordance with, and for the purposes specified in, <ref>section 3176 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Repayment of general services administration borrowing from federal financing bank</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator, in accordance with rules and procedures that the Office of Management and Budget and the Secretary of the Treasury establish, may transfer from the Fund an amount necessary to repay the principal amount of a General Services Administration borrowing from the Federal Financing Bank, if the borrowing is a legal obligation of the Fund.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Buildings deemed federally owned</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For purposes of amounts authorized to be expended from the Fund, the following are deemed to be federally owned buildings:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A building constructed pursuant to the purchase contract authority of section 5 of the Public Buildings Amendments of 1972 (<ref>Public Law 92–313</ref>, <ref>86 Stat. 219</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A building occupied pursuant to an installment purchase contract.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> A building under the control of a department or agency, if alterations of the building are required in connection with moving the department or agency from a former building that is, or will be, under the control of the Administration.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Energy Management Programs.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Receiving cash incentives</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator may receive amounts from rebates or other cash incentives related to energy savings and shall deposit the amounts in the Fund for use as provided in paragraph (4).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Receiving goods or services</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator may accept, from a utility, goods or services that enhance the energy efficiency of federal facilities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Assignment of energy rebates</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In the administration of real property that the Administrator leases and for which the Administrator pays utility costs, the Administrator may assign all or a portion of energy rebates to the lessor to underwrite the costs incurred in undertaking energy efficiency improvements in the real property if the payback period for the improvement is at least 2 years less than the remainder of the term of the lease.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Obligating amounts for energy management improvement programs</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In addition to amounts appropriated for energy management improvement programs and without regard to subsection (c)(1), the Administrator may obligate for those programs—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> amounts received and deposited in the Fund under paragraph (1);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> goods and services received under paragraph (2); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> amounts the Administrator determines are not needed for other authorized projects and that are otherwise available to implement energy efficiency programs.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Recycling Programs.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Receiving amounts</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator may receive amounts from the sale of recycled materials and shall deposit the amounts in the Fund for use as provided in paragraph (2).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Obligating amounts for recycling programs</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In addition to amounts appropriated for such purposes and without regard to subsection (c)(1), the Administrator may obligate amounts received and deposited in the Fund under paragraph (1) for programs which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> promote further source reduction and recycling programs; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> encourage employees to participate in recycling programs by providing financing for child care.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Additional Authority Related to Energy Management and Recycling Programs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Fund may receive, in the form of rebates, cash incentives or otherwise, any revenues, collections, or other income related to energy savings or recycling efforts. Amounts received under this subsection remain in the Fund until expended and remain available for federal energy management improvement programs, recycling programs, or employee programs that are authorized by law or that the Administrator considers appropriate. The Administration may use amounts received under this subsection, in addition to amounts received as New Obligational Authority, in activities of the Fund as necessary.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1118</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 593.</num>
<heading> Protection for veterans preference employees</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the following definitions apply:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered services</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “covered services” means any guard, elevator operator, messenger, or custodial services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Sheltered workshop</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “sheltered workshop” means a sheltered workshop employing the severely handicapped under chapter 85 of title 41.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in subsection (c), amounts made available to the General Services Administration pursuant to <ref>section 592 of this title</ref> may not be obligated or expended to procure covered services by contract if an employee who was a permanent veterans preference employee of the Administration on <date date="1995-11-19">November 19, 1995</date>, would be terminated as a result.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Amounts made available to the Administration pursuant to <ref>section 592 of this title</ref> may be obligated and expended to procure covered services by contract with a sheltered workshop or, if sheltered workshops decline to contract for the provision of covered services, by competitive contract for a period of no longer than 5 years. When a competitive contract expires, or is terminated for any reason, the Administration shall again offer to procure the covered services by contract with a sheltered workshop before procuring the covered services by competitive contract.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1120</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–284, § 6(6)</ref>, <date date="2006-09-27">Sept. 27, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1212</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 5</ref>(<i>l</i>)(11), <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3852</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER VI—</num>
<heading>MOTOR VEHICLE POOLS AND TRANSPORTATION SYSTEMS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 601.</num>
<heading> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In order to provide an economical and efficient system for transportation of Federal Government personnel and property consistent with <ref>section 101 of this title</ref>, the purposes of this subchapter are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to establish procedures to ensure safe operation of motor vehicles on Government business;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to provide for proper identification of Government motor vehicles;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to establish an effective means to limit the use of Government motor vehicles to official purposes;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to reduce the number of Government-owned vehicles to the minimum necessary to transact public business; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to provide wherever practicable for centrally operated interagency pools or systems for local transportation of Government personnel and property.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1121</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 602.</num>
<heading> Authority to establish motor vehicle pools and transportation systems</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subject to <ref>section 603 of this title</ref>, and regulations issued under section 603, the Administrator of General Services shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> take over from executive agencies and consolidate, or otherwise acquire, motor vehicles and related equipment and supplies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provide for the establishment, maintenance, and operation (including servicing and storage) of motor vehicle pools or systems; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> furnish motor vehicles and related services to executive agencies for the transportation of property and passengers.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Methods of Providing Vehicles and Services</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>As determined by the Administrator, motor vehicles and related services may be furnished by providing an agency with—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Federal Government-owned motor vehicles;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the use of motor vehicles, under rental or other arrangements, through private fleet operators, taxicab companies, or local or interstate common carriers; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> both.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Recipients of Vehicles and Services</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall, so far as practicable, furnish motor vehicles and related services under this section to any federal agency, mixed-ownership Government corporation (as defined in chapter 91 of title 31), or the District of Columbia, on its request.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1121</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 603.</num>
<heading> Process for establishing motor vehicle pools and transportation systems</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Determination Requirement.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator of General Services may carry out section 602 only if the Administrator determines, after consultation with the agencies concerned and with due regard to their program activities, that doing so is advantageous to the Federal Government in terms of economy, efficiency, or service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Elements of the determination</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A determination under this section must be in writing. For each motor vehicle pool or system, the determination must set forth an analytical justification that includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a detailed comparison of estimated costs for present and proposed modes of operation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a showing that savings can be realized by the establishment, maintenance, and operation of a motor vehicle pool or system.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Regulations Related to Establishment.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The President shall prescribe regulations establishing procedures to carry out <ref>section 602 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Elements of the regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The regulations shall provide for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> adequate notice to an executive agency of any determination that affects the agency or its functions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> independent review and decision as directed by the President of any determination disputed by an agency, with the possibility that the decision may include a partial or complete exemption of the agency from the determination; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> enforcement of determinations that become effective under the regulations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Effect of the regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A determination under subsection (a) is binding on an agency only as provided in regulations issued under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1122</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 604.</num>
<heading> Treatment of assets taken over to establish motor vehicle pools and transportation systems</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Reimbursement.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>When the Administrator of General Services takes over motor vehicles or related equipment or supplies under <ref>section 602 of this title</ref>, reimbursement is required if the property is taken over from—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a Government corporation; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an agency, if the agency acquired the property through unreimbursed expenditures made from a revolving or trust fund authorized by law.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Amount</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall reimburse a Government corporation, or a fund through which an agency acquired property, by an amount equal to the fair market value of the property. If the Administrator subsequently returns property of a similar kind under <ref>section 610 of this title</ref>, the Government corporation or the fund shall reimburse the Administrator by an amount equal to the fair market value of the property returned.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Addition to Acquisition Services Fund</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the Administrator takes over motor vehicles or related equipment or supplies under <ref>section 602 of this title</ref> but reimbursement is not required under subsection (a), the value of the property taken over, as determined by the Administrator, may be added to the capital of the Acquisition Services Fund. If the Administrator subsequently returns property of a similar kind under <ref>section 610 of this title</ref>, the value of the property may be deducted from the Fund.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1122</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–313, § 3(h)(5)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1736</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 605.</num>
<heading> Payment of costs</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of Acquisition Services Fund To Cover Costs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Acquisition Services Fund provided for in <ref>section 321 of this title</ref> is available for use by or under the direction and control of the Administrator of General Services to pay the costs of carrying out <ref>section 602 of this title</ref>, including the cost of purchasing or renting motor vehicles and related equipment and supplies.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Setting Prices To Recover Costs.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall set prices for furnishing motor vehicles and related services under <ref>section 602 of this title</ref>. Prices shall be set to recover, so far as practicable, all costs of carrying out <ref>section 602 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Increment for replacement cost</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In the Administrator’s discretion, prices may include an increment for the estimated replacement cost of motor vehicles and related equipment and supplies. Notwithstanding <ref>section 321(f) of this title</ref>, the increment may be retained as a part of the capital of the Acquisition Services Fund but is available only to replace motor vehicles and related equipment and supplies.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Accounting Method</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The purchase price of motor vehicles and related equipment, and any increment for estimated replacement cost, shall be recovered only through charges for the cost of amortization. Costs shall be determined, and financial reports prepared, in accordance with the accrual accounting method.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1123</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–313, § 3(h)(6)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1736</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 606.</num>
<heading> Regulations related to operation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall prescribe regulations to govern executive agencies in authorizing civilian personnel to operate Federal Government-owned motor vehicles for official purposes within the States of the United States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, and the territories and possessions of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Elements of the Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The regulations shall prescribe standards of physical fitness for authorized operators. The regulations may require operators and prospective operators to obtain state and local licenses or permits that are required to operate similar vehicles for other than official purposes.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Agency Orders</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The head of each executive agency shall issue orders and directives necessary for compliance with the regulations. The orders and directives shall provide for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> periodically testing the physical fitness of operators and prospective operators; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> suspension and revocation of authority to operate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1123</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 607.</num>
<heading> Records</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator of General Services shall maintain an accurate record of the cost of establishing, maintaining, and operating each motor vehicle pool or system established under <ref>section 602 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1124</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 608.</num>
<heading> Scrip, tokens, tickets</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator of General Services, in the operation of motor vehicle pools or systems under this subchapter, may provide for the sale and use of scrip, tokens, tickets, and similar devices to collect payment.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1124</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 609.</num>
<heading> Identification of vehicles</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Under regulations prescribed by the Administrator of General Services, every motor vehicle acquired and used for official purposes within the United States, or the territories or possessions of the United States, by any federal agency or by the District of Columbia shall be conspicuously identified by showing, on the vehicle—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the full name of the department, establishment, corporation, or agency that uses the vehicle and the service for which the vehicle is used; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a title that readily identifies the department, establishment, corporation, or agency that uses the vehicle and that is descriptive of the service for which the vehicle is used; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the legend “For official use only”.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exceptions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The regulations prescribed pursuant to this section may provide for exemptions when conspicuous identification would interfere with the purpose for which a vehicle is acquired and used.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1124</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 610.</num>
<heading> Discontinuance of motor vehicle pool or system</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator of General Services shall discontinue a motor vehicle pool or system if there are no actual savings realized (based on accounting as provided in <ref>section 605 of this title</ref>) during a reasonable period of not longer than two successive fiscal years.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Return of Comparable Property</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If a motor vehicle pool or system is discontinued, the Administrator shall return to each agency involved motor vehicles and related equipment and supplies similar in kind and reasonably comparable in value to any motor vehicles and related equipment and supplies which were previously taken over by the Administrator.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1124</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 611.</num>
<heading> Duty to report violations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">During the regular course of the duties of the Administrator of General Services, if the Administrator becomes aware of a violation of section 1343, 1344, or 1349(b) of title 31 or of <ref>section 641 of title 18</ref> involving the conversion by a Federal Government official or employee of a Government-owned or leased motor vehicle to the official or employee’s own use or to the use of others, the Administrator shall report the violation to the head of the agency in which the official or employee is employed, for further investigation and either appropriate disciplinary action under section 1343, 1344, or 1349(b) of title 31 or, if appropriate, referral to the Attorney General for prosecution under <ref>section 641 of title 18</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1124</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–284, § 6(7)</ref>, <date date="2006-09-27">Sept. 27, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1212</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER VII—</num>
<heading>PROPERTY MANAGEMENT</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 621.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this subchapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Administrator</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “Administrator” means the Administrator of General Services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Council</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “Council” means the Federal Real Property Council established by section 623(a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Director</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “Director” means the Director of the Office of Management and Budget.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Federal agency</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “Federal agency” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an executive department or independent establishment in the executive branch of the Government; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a wholly owned Government corporation (other than the United States Postal Service).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Field office</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “field office” means any office of a Federal agency that is not the headquarters office location for the Federal agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Postal property</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “postal property” means any property owned or leased by the United States Postal Service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Public-private partnership</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “public-private partnership” means any partnership or working relationship between a Federal agency and a corporation, individual, or nonprofit organization for the purpose of financing, constructing, operating, managing, or maintaining one or more Federal real property assets.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Underutilized property</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “underutilized property” means a portion or the entirety of any real property, including any improvements, that is used—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> irregularly or intermittently by the accountable Federal agency for program purposes of the Federal agency; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for program purposes that can be satisfied only with a portion of the property.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–318, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1608</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 622.</num>
<heading> Collocation among United States Postal Service properties</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Identification of Postal Property</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each year, the Postmaster General shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> identify a list of postal properties with space available for use by Federal agencies; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> not later than September 30, submit the list to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Voluntary Identification of Postal Property</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each year, the Postmaster General may submit the list under subsection (a) to the Council.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Submission of List of Postal Properties to Federal Agencies.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 30 days after the completion of a list under subsection (a), the Council shall provide the list to each Federal agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Review by federal agencies</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not later than 90 days after the receipt of the list submitted under paragraph (1), each Federal agency shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> review the list;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> review properties under the control of the Federal agency; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> recommend collocations if appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Terms of Collocation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>On approval of the recommendations under subsection (c) by the Postmaster General and the applicable agency head, the Federal agency or appropriate landholding entity may work with the Postmaster General to establish appropriate terms of a lease for each postal property.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rule of Construction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section exceeds, modifies, or supplants any other Federal law relating to any competitive bidding process governing the leasing of postal property.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–318, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1609</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 623.</num>
<heading> Establishment of a Federal Real Property Council</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is established a Federal Real Property Council.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Purpose</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The purpose of the Council shall be—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to develop guidance and ensure implementation of an efficient and effective real property management strategy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to identify opportunities for the Federal Government to better manage property and assets of the Federal Government; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to reduce the costs of managing property of the Federal Government, including operations, maintenance, and security associated with Federal property.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Composition.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Council shall be composed exclusively of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the senior real property officers of each Federal agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Deputy Director for Management of the Office of Management and Budget;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Controller of the Office of Management and Budget;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Administrator; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> any other full-time or permanent part-time Federal officials or employees, as the Chairperson determines to be necessary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Chairperson</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Deputy Director for Management of the Office of Management and Budget shall serve as Chairperson of the Council.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Executive director.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Chairperson shall designate an Executive Director to assist in carrying out the duties of the Council.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Qualifications</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Executive Director shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> be appointed from among individuals who have substantial experience in the areas of commercial real estate and development, real property management, and Federal operations and management; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> hold no outside employment that may conflict with duties inherent to the position.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Meetings.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Council shall meet subject to the call of the Chairperson.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Minimum</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Council shall meet not fewer than 4 times each year.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duties</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Council, in consultation with the Director and the Administrator, shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this subchapter, establish a real property management plan template, to be updated annually, which shall include performance measures, specific milestones, measurable savings, strategies, and Government-wide goals based on the goals established under section 524(a)(7) to reduce surplus property or to achieve better utilization of underutilized property, and evaluation criteria to determine the effectiveness of real property management that are designed—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to enable Congress and heads of Federal agencies to track progress in the achievement of property management objectives on a Government-wide basis;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to improve the management of real property; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to allow for comparison of the performance of Federal agencies against industry and other public sector agencies;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> develop utilization rates consistent throughout each category of space, considering the diverse nature of the Federal portfolio and consistent with nongovernmental space use rates;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> develop a strategy to reduce the reliance of Federal agencies on leased space for long-term needs if ownership would be less costly;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> provide guidance on eliminating inefficiencies in the Federal leasing process;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> compile a list of field offices that are suitable for collocation with other property assets;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> research best practices regarding the use of public-private partnerships to manage properties and develop guidelines for the use of those partnerships in the management of Federal property; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<chapeau> not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this subchapter and annually during the 4-year period beginning on the date that is 1 year after the date of enactment of this subchapter and ending on the date that is 5 years after the date of enactment of this subchapter, the Council shall submit to the Director a report that contains—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a list of the remaining excess property that is real property, surplus property that is real property, and underutilized property of each Federal agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the progress of the Council toward developing guidance for Federal agencies to ensure that the assessment required under section 524(a)(11)(B) is carried out in a uniform manner;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the progress of Federal agencies toward achieving the goals established under section 524(a)(7);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> if necessary, recommendations for legislation or statutory reforms that would further the goals of the Council, including streamlining the disposal of excess or underutilized real property; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> a list of entities that are consulted under subsection (f).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consultation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In carrying out the duties described in subsection (e), the Council shall also consult with representatives of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> State, local, and tribal authorities, as appropriate, and other affected communities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> appropriate private sector entities and nongovernmental organizations that have expertise in areas of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> commercial real estate and development;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> government management and operations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> space planning;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> community development, including transportation and planning;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> historic preservation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> providing housing to the homeless population.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Council Resources</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Director and the Administrator shall provide staffing, and administrative support for the Council, as appropriate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Access to Report</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Council shall provide, on an annual basis, the real property management plan template required under subsection (e)(1) and the reports required under subsection (e)(7) to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the Comptroller General of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exclusions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, surplus property shall not include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any military installation (as defined in section 2910 of the Defense Base Closure and Realignment Act of 1990 (<ref>10 U.S.C. 2687</ref> note; <ref>Public Law 101–510</ref>));</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any property that is excepted from the definition of the term “property” under section 102;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Indian and native Eskimo property held in trust by the Federal Government as described in section 3301(a)(5)(C)(iii);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> real property operated and maintained by the Tennessee Valley Authority pursuant to the Tennessee Valley Authority Act of 1933 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 831</ref> et seq.);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> any real property the Director excludes for reasons of national security;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> any public lands (as defined in section 203 of the Public Lands Corps Act of 1993 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 1722</ref>)) administered by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> the Secretary of the Interior, acting through—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Director of the Bureau of Land Management;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the Director of the National Park Service;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the Commissioner of Reclamation; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Chief of the Forest Service; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> any property operated and maintained by the United States Postal Service.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–318, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1609</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 624.</num>
<heading> Information on certain leasing authorities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Except as provided in subsection (b), not later than December 31 of each year following the date of enactment of this subchapter, a Federal agency with independent leasing authority shall submit to the Council a list of all leases, including operating leases, in effect on the date of enactment of this subchapter that includes—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the date on which each lease was executed;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the date on which each lease will expire;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a description of the size of the space;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the location of the property;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the tenant agency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the total annual rental payment; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the amount of the net present value of the total estimated legal obligations of the Federal Government over the life of the contract.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subsection (a) shall not apply to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the United States Postal Service; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any other property the Director excludes from subsection (a) for reasons of national security.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–318, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1612</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>