<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 7—</num>
<heading>FOREIGN EXCESS PROPERTY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 701.</num>
<heading> Administrative</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Policies Prescribed by the President</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The President may prescribe policies that the President considers necessary to carry out this chapter. The policies must be consistent with this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Executive Agency Responsibility.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The head of an executive agency that has foreign excess property is responsible for the disposal of the property.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Conformance to policies</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In carrying out functions under this chapter, the head of an executive agency shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> use the policies prescribed by the President under subsection (a) for guidance; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> dispose of foreign excess property in a manner that conforms to the foreign policy of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Delegation of authority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The head of an executive agency may—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> delegate authority conferred by this chapter to an official in the agency or to the head of another executive agency; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> authorize successive redelegation of authority conferred by this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Employment of personnel</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>As necessary to carry out this chapter, the head of an executive agency may—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> appoint and fix the pay of personnel in the United States, subject to chapters 33 and 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> appoint personnel outside the States of the United States and the District of Columbia, without regard to chapter 33 of title 5.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Special Responsibilities of Secretary of State.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of foreign currencies and credits</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of State may use foreign currencies and credits acquired by the United States under <ref>section 704(b)(2) of this title</ref>—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to carry out the Mutual Educational and Cultural Exchange Act of 1961 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2451</ref> et seq.);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to carry out the Foreign Service Buildings Act, 1926 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 292</ref> et seq.); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to pay other governmental expenses payable in local currencies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Renewal of certain agreements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as otherwise directed by the President, the Secretary of State shall continue to perform functions under agreements in effect on <date date="1949-07-01">July 1, 1949</date>, related to the disposal of foreign excess property. The Secretary of State may amend, modify, and renew the agreements. Foreign currencies or credits the Secretary of State acquires under the agreements shall be administered in accordance with procedures that the Secretary of the Treasury may establish. Foreign currencies or credits reduced to United States currency must be deposited in the Treasury as miscellaneous receipts.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1125</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 702.</num>
<heading> Return of foreign excess property to United States</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Under regulations prescribed pursuant to subsection (b), foreign excess property may be returned to the United States for handling as excess or surplus property under subchapter II of chapter 5 of this title or section 549 or 551 of this title when the head of the executive agency concerned, or the Administrator of General Services after consultation with the agency head, determines that return of the property to the United States for such handling is in the interest of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall prescribe regulations to carry out this section. The regulations must require that transportation costs for returning foreign excess property to the United States are paid by the federal agency, state agency, or donee receiving the property.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1126</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 703.</num>
<heading> Donation of medical supplies for use in foreign country</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Application</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section applies to medical materials or supplies that are in a foreign country but that would, if situated within the United States, be available for donation under subchapter III of chapter 5 of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An executive agency may donate medical materials or supplies that are not disposed of under <ref>section 702 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Conditions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A donation under this section is subject to the following conditions:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The medical materials and supplies must be donated for use in a foreign country.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The donation must be made to a nonprofit medical or health organization, which may be an organization qualified to receive assistance under section 214(b) or 607 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2174(b)</ref>, 2357).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The donation must be made without cost to the donee (except for costs of care and handling).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1126</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 704.</num>
<heading> Other methods of disposal</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Foreign excess property not disposed of under section 702 or 703 of this title may be disposed of as provided in this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Methods of Disposal.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Sale, exchange, lease, or transfer</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The head of an executive agency may dispose of foreign excess property by sale, exchange, lease, or transfer, for cash, credit or other property, with or without warranty, under terms and conditions the head of the executive agency considers proper.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exchange for foreign currency or credit</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>If the head of an executive agency determines that it is in the interest of the United States, foreign excess property may be exchanged for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> foreign currencies or credits; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> substantial benefits or the discharge of claims resulting from the compromise or settlement of claims in accordance with law.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Abandonment, destruction, or donation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The head of an executive agency may authorize the abandonment, destruction, or donation of foreign excess property if the property has no commercial value or if estimated costs of care and handling exceed the estimated proceeds from sale.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Advertising</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The head of an executive agency may dispose of foreign excess property without advertising if the head of the executive agency finds that disposal without advertising is the most practicable and advantageous means for the Federal Government to dispose of the property.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transfer of Title</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The head of an executive agency may execute documents to transfer title or other interests in, and take other action necessary or proper to dispose of, foreign excess property.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1126</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 705.</num>
<heading> Handling of proceeds from disposal</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section applies to proceeds from the sale, lease, or other disposition of foreign excess property under this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Foreign Currencies or Credits</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Proceeds in the form of foreign currencies or credits, must be administered in accordance with procedures that the Secretary of the Treasury may establish.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">United States Currency.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Separate fund in treasury</inline>.—</heading>
<content><ref>Section 572(a) of this title</ref> applies to proceeds of foreign excess property disposed of for United States currency under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Deposited in treasury as miscellaneous receipts</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in paragraph (1), proceeds in the form of United States currency, including foreign currencies or credits that are reduced to United States currency, must be deposited in the Treasury as miscellaneous receipts.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Special Account for Refunds or Payments for Breach.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Deposits</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A federal agency that disposes of foreign excess property under this chapter may deposit, in a special account in the Treasury, amounts of the proceeds of the dispositions that the agency decides are necessary to permit—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> appropriate refunds to purchasers for dispositions that are rescinded or that do not become final; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> payments for breach of warranty.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Withdrawals</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A federal agency that deposits proceeds in a special account under paragraph (1) may withdraw amounts to be refunded or paid from the account without regard to the origin of the amounts withdrawn.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1127</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>