<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 65—</num>
<heading>THURGOOD MARSHALL FEDERAL JUDICIARY BUILDING</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6501.</num>
<heading> Definition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this chapter, the term “Chief Justice” means the Chief Justice of the United States or the designee of the Chief Justice, except that when there is a vacancy in the office of the Chief Justice, the most senior associate justice of the Supreme Court shall be deemed to be the Chief Justice for purposes of this chapter until the vacancy is filled.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1188</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6502.</num>
<heading> Thurgood Marshall Federal Judiciary Building</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment and Designation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is a Federal Judiciary Building in Washington, D.C., known and designated as the “Thurgood Marshall Federal Judiciary Building”.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Title.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Squares 721 and 722</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Title to squares 721 and 722 remains in the Federal Government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Building</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Title to the Building and other improvements constructed or otherwise made immediately reverts to the Government at the expiration of not more than 30 years from the effective date of the lease agreement referred to in <ref>section 6504 of this title</ref> without payment of any compensation by the Government.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Limitations.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Size of building</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Building (excluding parking facilities) may not exceed 520,000 gross square feet in size above the level of Columbia Plaza in the District of Columbia.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Height of building</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The height of the Building and other improvements shall be compatible with the height of surrounding Government and historic buildings and conform to the provisions of the Act of <date date="1910-06-01">June 1, 1910</date> (ch. 263, <ref>36 Stat. 452</ref>) (known as the Building Height Act of 1910).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Design</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Building and other improvements shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> be designed in harmony with historical and Government buildings in the vicinity;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> reflect the symbolic importance and historic character of the United States Capitol and other buildings on the United States Capitol Grounds; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> represent the dignity and stability of the Government.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Approval of Chief Justice</inline>.—</heading>
<content>All final decisions regarding architectural design of the Building are subject to the approval of the Chief Justice.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Chilled Water and Steam From Capitol Power Plant</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the Building is connected with the Capitol Power Plant, the Architect of the Capitol shall furnish chilled water and steam from the Plant to the Building on a reimbursable basis.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Construction Standards</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Building and other improvements constructed under this chapter shall meet all standards applicable to construction of a federal building.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Accounting System</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Architect shall maintain an accounting system for operation and maintenance of the Building and other improvements which will allow accurate projections of the dates and cost of major repairs, improvements, reconstructions, and replacements of the Building and improvements and other capital expenditures on the Building and improvements.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Nonapplicability of Certain Laws.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Building codes, permits, or inspection</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Building is not subject to any law of the District of Columbia relating to building codes, permits, or inspection, including any such law enacted by Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Taxes</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Building and other improvements constructed under this chapter are not subject to any law of the District of Columbia relating to real estate and personal property taxes, special assessments, or other taxes, including any such law enacted by Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1188</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6503.</num>
<heading> Commission for the Judiciary Office Building</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment and Membership</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>There is a Commission for the Judiciary Office Building, composed of the following 13 members or their designees:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Two individuals appointed by the Chief Justice from among justices of the Supreme Court and other judges of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The members of the House Office Building Commission.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The majority leader and minority leader of the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Chairman and the ranking minority member of the Senate Committee on Rules and Administration.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The Chairman and the ranking minority member of the Senate Committee on Environment and Public Works.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The Chairman and ranking minority member of the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Quorum</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Seven members of the Commission is a quorum.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duties</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commission is responsible for the supervision of the design, construction, operation, maintenance, structural, mechanical, and domestic care, and security of the Thurgood Marshall Federal Judiciary Building. The Commission shall prescribe regulations to govern the actions of the Architect of the Capitol under this chapter and to govern the use and occupancy of all space in the Building.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1189</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6504.</num>
<heading> Lease of building</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Lease Agreement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Under an agreement with the person selected to construct the Thurgood Marshall Federal Judiciary Building, the Architect of the Capitol shall lease the Building to carry out the objectives of this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Minimum Requirements of Lease Agreement</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The agreement includes at a minimum the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limit on length of lease</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Architect will lease the Building and other improvements for not more than 30 years from the effective date of the agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rental rate</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The rental rate per square foot of occupiable space for all space in the Building and other improvements will be in the best interest of the Federal Government and will carry out the objectives of this chapter. The aggregate rental rate for all space in the Building and other improvements shall produce an amount at least equal to the amount necessary to amortize the cost of development of squares 721 and 722 in the District of Columbia over the life of the lease.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority to make space available and sublease space</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Architect may make space available and sublease space in the Building and other improvements in accordance with <ref>section 6506 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Other terms and conditions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The agreement contains terms and conditions the Architect prescribes to carry out the objectives of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Obligation of Amounts</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Obligation of amounts for lease payments under this section may only be made—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> on an annual basis; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> from the account described in <ref>section 6507 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1189</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6505.</num>
<heading> Structural and mechanical care and security</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Structural and Mechanical Care</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Architect of the Capitol, under the direction of the Commission for the Judiciary Office Building—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> is responsible for the structural and mechanical care and maintenance of the Thurgood Marshall Federal Judiciary Building and improvements, including the care and maintenance of the grounds of the Building, in the same manner and to the same extent as for the structural and mechanical care and maintenance of the Supreme Court Building under <ref>section 6111 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall perform all other duties and work required for the operation and domestic care of the Building and improvements.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Security.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Capitol police</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The United States Capitol Police—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> are responsible for all exterior security of the Building and other improvements constructed under this chapter; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> may police the Building and other improvements, including the interior and exterior, and may make arrests within the interior and exterior of the Building and other improvements for any violation of federal or state law or the laws of the District of Columbia, or any regulation prescribed under any of those laws.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Marshal of the supreme court</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This chapter does not interfere with the obligation of the Marshal of the Supreme Court to protect justices, officers, employees, or other personnel of the Supreme Court who may occupy the Building and other improvements.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reimbursement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Architect shall transfer from the account described in <ref>section 6507 of this title</ref> amounts necessary to reimburse the United States Capitol Police for expenses incurred in providing exterior security under this subsection. The Capitol Police may accept amounts the Architect transfers under this paragraph. Those amounts shall be credited to the appropriation account charged by the Capitol Police in carrying out security duties.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1190</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6506.</num>
<heading> Allocation of space</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Priority.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Judicial branch</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to this section, the Architect of the Capitol shall make available to the judicial branch of the Federal Government all space in the Thurgood Marshall Federal Judiciary Building and other improvements constructed under this chapter. The space shall be made available on a reimbursable basis and substantially in accordance with the report referred to in section 3(b)(1) of the Judiciary Office Building Development Act (<ref>Public Law 100–480</ref>, <ref>102 Stat. 2330</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Other federal governmental entities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Architect may make available to federal governmental entities which are not part of the judicial branch and which are not staff of Members of Congress or congressional committees any space in the Building and other improvements that the Chief Justice decides is not needed by the judicial branch. The space shall be made available on a reimbursable basis.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Other persons</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If any space remains, the Architect may sublease it pursuant to subsection (e), under the direction of the Commission for the Judiciary Office Building, to any person.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Space for Judicial Branch and Other Federal Governmental Entities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Space made available under subsection (a)(1) or (2) is subject to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> terms and conditions necessary to carry out the objectives of this chapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> reimbursement at the rate established under <ref>section 6504(b)(2) of this title</ref> plus an amount necessary to pay each year for the cost of administering the Building and other improvements (including the cost of operation, maintenance, rehabilitation, security, and structural, mechanical, and domestic care) that is attributable to the space, with the amount to be determined by the Architect and—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the case of the judicial branch, the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of any federal governmental entity not a part of the judicial branch, the entity.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Space for Judicial Branch.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Assignment of space within judicial branch</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Director may assign space made available to the judicial branch under subsection (a)(1) among offices of the judicial branch as the Director considers appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Vacating occupied space</inline>.—</heading>
<content>When the Chief Justice notifies the Architect that the judicial branch requires additional space in the Building and other improvements, the Architect shall accommodate those requirements within 90 days after the date of the notification, except that if the space was made available to the Administrator of General Services, it shall be vacated expeditiously by not later than a date the Chief Justice and the Administrator agree on.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Unoccupied space</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Chief Justice has the right of first refusal to use unoccupied space in the Building to meet the needs of the judicial branch.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Lease by Architect.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority to lease</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to approval by the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate, the House Office Building Commission, and the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate, the Architect may lease and occupy not more than 75,000 square feet of space in the Building.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Payments</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Payments under the lease shall be made on vouchers the Architect approves. Necessary amounts may be appropriated—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to the Architect to carry out this subsection, including amounts for acquiring and installing furniture and furnishings; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to the Sergeant at Arms of the Senate to plan for, acquire, and install telecommunications equipment and services for the Architect with respect to space leased under this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Subleased Space.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rental rate</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Space subleased by the Architect under subsection (a)(3) is subject to reimbursement at a rate which is comparable to prevailing rental rates for similar facilities in the area but not less than the rate established under <ref>section 6504(b)(2) of this title</ref> plus an amount the Architect and the person subleasing the space agree is necessary to pay each year for the cost of administering the Building (including the cost of operation, maintenance, rehabilitation, security, and structural, mechanical, and domestic care) that is attributable to the space.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A sublease under subsection (a)(3) must be compatible with the dignity and functions of the judicial branch offices housed in the Building and must not unduly interfere with the activities and operations of the judicial branch agencies housed in the Building. Sections 5104(c) and 5108 of this title do not apply to any space in the Building and other improvements subleased to a non-Government tenant under subsection (a)(3).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Collection of rent</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Architect shall collect rent for space subleased under subsection (a)(3).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Deposit of Rent and Reimbursements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Amounts received under subsection (a)(3) (including lease payments and reimbursements) shall be deposited in the account described in <ref>section 6507 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1190</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6507.</num>
<heading> Account in Treasury</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment and Contents of Separate Account</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is a separate account in the Treasury. The account includes all amounts deposited in the account under <ref>section 6506(f) of this title</ref> and amounts appropriated to the account. However, the appropriated amounts may not be more than $2,000,000.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of Amounts</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Amounts in the account are available to the Architect of the Capitol—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> for paying expenses for structural, mechanical, and domestic care, maintenance, operation, and utilities of the Thurgood Marshall Federal Judiciary Building and other improvements constructed under this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> for reimbursing the United States Capitol Police for expenses incurred in providing exterior security for the Building and other improvements;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> for making lease payments under <ref>section 6504 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> for necessary personnel (including consultants).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1192</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>