<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 143—</num>
<heading>APPALACHIAN REGIONAL COMMISSION</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>ORGANIZATION AND ADMINISTRATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 14301.</num>
<heading> Establishment, membership, and employees</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is an Appalachian Regional Commission.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Membership.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Federal and state members</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commission is composed of the Federal Cochairman, appointed by the President by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, and the Governor of each participating State in the Appalachian region.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Alternate members</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each state member may have a single alternate, appointed by the Governor from among the members of the Governor’s cabinet or the Governor’s personal staff. The President,,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002033">1</ref> shall appoint an alternate for the Federal Cochairman. An alternate shall vote in the event of the absence, death, disability, removal, or resignation of the member for whom the individual is an alternate. A state alternate shall not be counted toward the establishment of a quorum of the Commission when a quorum of the state members is required.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Cochairmen</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Federal Cochairman is one of the two Cochairmen of the Commission. The state members shall elect a Cochairman of the Commission from among themselves for a term of not less than one year.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Compensation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Federal Cochairman shall be compensated by the Federal Government at level III of the Executive Schedule as set out in <ref>section 5314 of title 5</ref>. The Federal Cochairman’s alternate shall be compensated by the Government at level V of the Executive Schedule as set out in <ref>section 5316 of title 5</ref>. Each state member and alternate shall be compensated by the State which they represent at the rate established by law of that State.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Delegation.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Powers and responsibilities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Commission powers and responsibilities specified in section 14302(c) and (d) of this title, and the vote of any Commission member, may not be delegated to an individual who is not a Commission member or who is not entitled to vote in Commission meetings.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Alternate federal cochairman</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The alternate to the Federal Cochairman shall perform the functions and duties the Federal Cochairman delegates when not actively serving as the alternate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Executive Director</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commission has an executive director. The executive director is responsible for carrying out the administrative functions of the Commission, for directing the Commission staff, and for other duties the Commission may assign.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Status of Personnel</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Members, alternates, officers, and employees of the Commission are not federal employees for any purpose, except the Federal Cochairman, the alternate to the Federal Cochairman, the staff of the Federal Cochairman, and federal employees detailed to the Commission under <ref>section 14306(a)(3) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1256</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–166, § 2(n)</ref>, <date date="2012-08-10">Aug. 10, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1287</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 14302.</num>
<heading> Decisions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirements for Approval</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in <ref>section 14306(d) of this title</ref>, decisions by the Appalachian Regional Commission require the affirmative vote of the Federal Cochairman and of a majority of the state members, exclusive of members representing States delinquent under section 14306(d).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consultation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In matters coming before the Commission, the Federal Cochairman, to the extent practicable, shall consult with the federal departments and agencies having an interest in the subject matter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Decisions Requiring Quorum of State Members</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A decision involving Commission policy, approval of state, regional or subregional development plans or strategy statements, modification or revision of the Appalachian Regional Commission Code, allocation of amounts among the States, or designation of a distressed county or an economically strong county shall not be made without a quorum of state members.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Project and Grant Proposals</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The approval of project and grant proposals is a responsibility of the Commission and shall be carried out in accordance with <ref>section 14322 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1257</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 14303.</num>
<heading> Functions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In carrying out the purposes of this subtitle, the Appalachian Regional Commission shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> develop, on a continuing basis, comprehensive and coordinated plans and programs and establish priorities under those plans and programs, giving due consideration to other federal, state, and local planning in the Appalachian region;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> conduct and sponsor investigations, research, and studies, including an inventory and analysis of the resources of the region, and, in cooperation with federal, state, and local agencies, sponsor demonstration projects designed to foster regional productivity and growth;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> review and study, in cooperation with the agency involved, federal, state, and local public and private programs and, where appropriate, recommend modifications or additions which will increase their effectiveness in the region;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> formulate and recommend, where appropriate, interstate compacts and other forms of interstate cooperation and work with state and local agencies in developing appropriate model legislation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> encourage the formation of, and support, local development districts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> encourage private investment in industrial, commercial, and recreational projects;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> serve as a focal point and coordinating unit for Appalachian programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> provide a forum for consideration of problems of the region and proposed solutions and establish and utilize, as appropriate, citizens and special advisory councils and public conferences;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> encourage the use of eco-industrial development technologies and approaches;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> seek to coordinate the economic development activities of, and the use of economic development resources by, federal agencies in the region; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> support broadband access in the Appalachian region.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Identify Needs and Goals of Subregional Areas</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In carrying out its functions under this section, the Commission shall identify the characteristics of, and may distinguish between the needs and goals of, appropriate subregional areas, including central, northern, and southern Appalachia.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1258</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–58, div. A, title I, § 11506(b)</ref>, <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 584</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 14304.</num>
<heading> Recommendations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Appalachian Regional Commission may make recommendations to the President and to the Governors and appropriate local officials with respect to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the expenditure of amounts by federal, state, and local departments and agencies in the Appalachian region in the fields of natural resources, agriculture, education, training, and health and welfare and in other fields related to the purposes of this subtitle; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> additional federal, state, and local legislation or administrative actions as the Commission considers necessary to further the purposes of this subtitle.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1258</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 14305.</num>
<heading> Liaison between Federal Government and Commission</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">President</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The President shall provide effective and continuing liaison between the Federal Government and the Appalachian Regional Commission and a coordinated review within the Government of the plans and recommendations submitted by the Commission pursuant to sections 14303 and 14304 of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Interagency Coordinating Council on Appalachia</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In carrying out subsection (a), the President shall establish the Interagency Coordinating Council on Appalachia, to be composed of the Federal Cochairman and representatives of federal agencies that carry out economic development programs in the Appalachian region. The Federal Cochairman is the Chairperson of the Council.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1259</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 14306.</num>
<heading> Administrative powers and expenses</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Powers</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>To carry out its duties under this subtitle, the Appalachian Regional Commission may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> adopt, amend, and repeal bylaws and regulations governing the conduct of its business and the performance of its functions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> appoint and fix the compensation of an executive director and other personnel as necessary to enable the Commission to carry out its functions, except that the compensation shall not exceed the maximum rate of basic pay for the Senior Executive Service under <ref>section 5382 of title 5</ref>, including any applicable locality-based comparability payment that may be authorized under <ref>section 5304(h)(2)(C) of title 5</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> request the head of any federal department or agency to detail to temporary duty with the Commission personnel within the administrative jurisdiction of the head of the department or agency that the Commission may need for carrying out its functions, each detail to be without loss of seniority, pay, or other employee status;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> arrange for the services of personnel from any state or local government, subdivision or agency of a state or local government, or intergovernmental agency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> make arrangements, including contracts, with any participating state government for inclusion in a suitable retirement and employee benefit system of Commission personnel who may not be eligible for, or continue in, another governmental retirement or employee benefit system; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> otherwise provide for coverage of its personnel;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> accept, use, and dispose of gifts or donations of services or any property;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<chapeau> enter into and perform contracts, leases (including the lease of office space for any term), cooperative agreements, or other transactions, necessary in carrying out its functions, on terms as it may consider appropriate, with any—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> department, agency, or instrumentality of the Federal Government;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> State or political subdivision, agency, or instrumentality of a State; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> person;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> maintain a temporary office in the District of Columbia and establish a permanent office at a central and appropriate location it may select and field offices at other places it may consider appropriate; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> take other actions and incur other expenses as may be necessary or appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Authorizations.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Detail employees</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The head of a federal department or agency may detail personnel under subsection (a)(3).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Enter into and perform transactions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A department, agency, or instrumentality of the Government, to the extent not otherwise prohibited by law, may enter into and perform a contract, lease, cooperative agreement, or other transaction under subsection (a)(7).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Retirement and Other Employee Benefit Programs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Director of the Office of Personnel Management may contract with the Commission for continued coverage of Commission employees, if the employees are federal employees when they begin Commission employment, in the retirement program and other employee benefit programs of the Government.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Expenses</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Administrative expenses of the Commission shall be paid equally by the Government and the States in the Appalachian region, except that the expenses of the Federal Cochairman, the alternate to the Federal Cochairman, and the staff of the Federal Cochairman shall be paid only by the Government. The Commission shall determine the amount to be paid by each State. The Federal Cochairman shall not participate or vote in that determination. Assistance authorized by this subtitle shall not be furnished to any State or to any political subdivision or any resident of any State, and a state member of the Commission shall not participate or vote in any decision by the Commission, while the State is delinquent in payment of its share of administrative expenses.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1259</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 14307.</num>
<heading> Meetings</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Appalachian Regional Commission shall conduct at least one meeting each year with the Federal Cochairman and at least a majority of the state members present.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Additional Meetings by Electronic Means</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commission may conduct additional meetings by electronic means as the Commission considers advisable, including meetings to decide matters requiring an affirmative vote.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1260</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 14308.</num>
<heading> Information</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Actions of Commission</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>To obtain information needed to carry out its duties, the Appalachian Regional Commission shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> hold hearings, sit and act at times and places, take testimony, receive evidence, and print or otherwise reproduce and distribute so much of its proceedings and reports on the proceedings as the Commission may deem advisable;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> arrange for the head of any federal, state, or local department or agency to furnish to the Commission information as may be available to or procurable by the department or agency; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> keep accurate and complete records of its doings and transactions which shall be made available for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> public inspection; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> audit and examination by the Comptroller General or an authorized representative of the Comptroller General.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Authorizations.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Administer oaths</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A Cochairman of the Commission, or any member of the Commission designated by the Commission, may administer oaths when the Commission decides that testimony shall be taken or evidence received under oath.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Furnish information</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The head of any federal, state, or local department or agency, to the extent not otherwise prohibited by law, may carry out subsection (a)(2).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Public Participation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Public participation in the development, revision, and implementation of all plans and programs under this subtitle by the Commission, any State, or any local development district shall be provided for, encouraged, and assisted. The Commission shall develop and publish regulations specifying minimum guidelines for public participation, including public hearings.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1260</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–284, § 6(31)</ref>, <date date="2006-09-27">Sept. 27, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1213</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 14309.</num>
<heading> Personal financial interests</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Conflict of Interest.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">No role allowed</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Except as permitted by paragraph (2), an individual who is a state member or alternate, or an officer or employee of the Appalachian Regional Commission, shall not participate personally and substantially as a member, alternate, officer, or employee in any way in any particular matter in which, to the individual’s knowledge, any of the following has a financial interest:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the individual.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the individual’s spouse, minor child, or partner.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> an organization (except a State or political subdivision of a State) in which the individual is serving as an officer, director, trustee, partner, or employee.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> any person or organization with whom the individual—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is serving as an officer, director, trustee, partner, or employee; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> is negotiating or has any arrangement concerning prospective employment.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Paragraph (1) does not apply if the individual first advises the Commission of the nature and circumstances of the particular matter and makes full disclosure of the financial interest and receives in advance a written decision of the Commission that the interest is not so substantial as to be considered likely to affect the integrity of the services which the Commission may expect from the individual.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Criminal penalty</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An individual violating this subsection shall be fined under title 18, imprisoned for not more than two years, or both.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Additional Sources of Salary Disallowed.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">State member or alternate</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A state member or alternate may not receive any salary, or any contribution to, or supplementation of, salary, for services on the Commission from a source other than the State of the member or alternate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Individuals detailed to commission</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An individual detailed to serve the Commission under <ref>section 14306(a)(4) of this title</ref> may not receive any salary, or any contribution to, or supplementation of, salary, for services on the Commission from a source other than the state, local, or intergovernmental department or agency from which the individual was detailed or from the Commission.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Criminal penalty</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An individual violating this subsection shall be fined under title 18, imprisoned for not more than one year, or both.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Federal Cochairman, Alternate to Federal Cochairman, and Federal Officers and Employees</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Federal Cochairman, the alternate to the Federal Cochairman, and any federal officer or employee detailed to duty with the Commission under <ref>section 14306(a)(3) of this title</ref> are not subject to this section but remain subject to sections 202–209 of title 18.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rescission</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commission may declare void and rescind any contract, loan, or grant of or by the Commission in relation to which it finds that there has been a violation of subsection (a)(1) or (b) of this section or any of the provisions of sections 202–209 of title 18.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1261</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 14310.</num>
<heading> Annual report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than six months after the close of each fiscal year, the Appalachian Regional Commission shall prepare and submit to the Governor of each State in the Appalachian region and to the President, for transmittal to Congress, a report on the activities carried out under this subtitle during the fiscal year.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1262</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>FINANCIAL ASSISTANCE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 14321.</num>
<heading> Grants and other assistance</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Authorization To Make Grants.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Appalachian Regional Commission may make grants—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> for administrative expenses, including the development of areawide plans or action programs and technical assistance activities, of local development districts, but—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> the amount of the grant shall not exceed—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> 50 percent of administrative expenses;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> at the discretion of the Commission, if the grant is to a local development district that has a charter or authority that includes the economic development of a county or a part of a county for which a distressed county designation is in effect under section 14526, 75 percent of administrative expenses; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> at the discretion of the Commission, if the grant is to a local development district that has a charter or authority that includes the economic development of a county or a part of a county for which an at-risk county designation is in effect under section 14526, 70 percent of administrative expenses;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> grants for administrative expenses shall not be made for a state agency certified as a local development district for a period of more than three years beginning on the date the initial grant is made for the development district; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the local development district contributions for administrative expenses may be in cash or in kind, fairly evaluated, including space, equipment, and services;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for assistance to States for a period of not more than two years to strengthen the state development planning process for the Appalachian region and the coordination of state planning under this subtitle, the Public Works and Economic Development Act of 1965 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 3121</ref> et seq.), and other federal and state programs; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> for investigation, research, studies, evaluations, and assessments of needs, potentials, or attainments of the people of the region, technical assistance, training programs, demonstrations, and the construction of necessary facilities incident to those activities, which will further the purposes of this subtitle.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Limitation on available amounts.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), of the cost of any activity eligible for financial assistance under this section, not more than—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> 50 percent may be provided from amounts appropriated to carry out this subtitle;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in the case of a project to be carried out in a county for which a distressed county designation is in effect under section 14526, 80 percent may be provided from amounts appropriated to carry out this subtitle; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> in the case of a project to be carried out in a county for which an at-risk county designation is in effect under section 14526, 70 percent may be provided from amounts appropriated to carry out this subtitle.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Discretionary grants.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Grants to which percentage limitation doesn’t apply</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Discretionary grants made by the Commission to implement significant regional initiatives, to take advantage of special development opportunities, or to respond to emergency economic distress in the region may be made without regard to the percentage limitations specified in subparagraph (A).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on aggregate amount</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For each fiscal year, the aggregate amount of discretionary grants referred to in clause (i) shall not be more than 10 percent of the amount appropriated under <ref>section 14703 of this title</ref> for the fiscal year, except that a discretionary grant to respond to economic distress directly related to the impacts of the Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID–19) shall not be included in such aggregate amount.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Sources of grants</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Grant amounts may be provided entirely from appropriations to carry out this section, in combination with amounts available under other federal or federal grant programs, or from any other source.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Federal share</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding any law limiting the federal share in any other federal or federal grant program, amounts appropriated to carry out this section may be used to increase that federal share, as the Commission decides is appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Assistance for Demonstrations of Enterprise Development.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commission may provide assistance under this section for demonstrations of enterprise development, including site acquisition or development where necessary for the feasibility of the project, in connection with the development of the region’s energy resources and the development and stimulation of indigenous arts and crafts of the region.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Cooperation by federal agencies</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In carrying out the purposes of this subtitle and in implementing this section, the Secretary of Energy, the Environmental Protection Agency, and other federal agencies shall cooperate with the Commission and shall provide assistance that the Federal Cochairman may request.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Available amounts</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In any fiscal year, not more than—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> $3,000,000 shall be obligated for energy resource related demonstrations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> $2,500,000 shall be obligated for indigenous arts and crafts demonstrations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Records.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Commission</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commission, as required by the President, shall maintain accurate and complete records of transactions and activities financed with federal amounts and report to the President on the transactions and activities. The records of the Commission with respect to grants are available for audit by the President and the Comptroller General.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Recipients of federal assistance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Recipients of federal assistance under this section, as required by the Commission, shall maintain accurate and complete records of transactions and activities financed with federal amounts and report to the Commission on the transactions and activities. The records are be <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002034">1</ref> available for audit by the President, the Comptroller General, and the Commission.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1262</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–371, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-10-08">Oct. 8, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4037</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–136, div. B, title IV, § 14004</ref>, <date date="2020-03-27">Mar. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 526</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 14322.</num>
<heading> Approval of development plans, strategy statements, and projects</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Review and Approval Required</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Appalachian Regional Commission annually shall review and approve, in accordance with <ref>section 14302 of this title</ref>, state and regional development plans and strategy statements, and any multistate subregional plans which may be developed.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Application Process</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An application for a grant or for other assistance for a specific project under this subtitle shall be made through the state member of the Commission representing the applicant. The state member shall evaluate the application for approval. To be approved, the state member must certify, and the Federal Cochairman must determine, that the application—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> implements the Commission-approved state development plan;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> is included in the Commission-approved strategy statement;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> adequately ensures that the project will be properly administered, operated, and maintained; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> otherwise meets the requirements for assistance under this subtitle.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Affirmative Vote Requirement Deemed Met</inline>.—</heading>
<content>After the appropriate state development plan and strategy statement are approved, certification by a state member, when joined by an affirmative vote of the Federal Cochairman, is deemed to satisfy the requirements for affirmative votes for decisions under <ref>section 14302(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1264</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 14323.</num>
<heading> Congressional notification</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In the case of a project described in subsection (b), the Appalachian Regional Commission shall provide to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate notice of the award of a grant or other financial assistance not less than 3 full business days before awarding the grant or other financial assistance.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Projects Described</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A project referred to in subsection (a) is a project that the Appalachian Regional Commission has selected to receive a grant or other financial assistance under this subtitle in an amount not less than $50,000.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–58, div. A, title I, § 11506(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 584</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>