<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 173—</num>
<heading>GOVERNMENT LOSSES IN SHIPMENT</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 17301.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter, the following definitions apply:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Replacement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “replacement” means payment, reimbursement, replacement, or duplication or the expenses incident to payment, reimbursement, replacement, or duplication.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Shipment</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “shipment”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> means the transportation, or the effecting of transportation, of valuables, without limitation as to the means or facilities used or by which the transportation is effected or the person to whom it is made; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> includes shipments made to any executive department, independent establishment, agency, wholly owned or mixed-ownership Government corporation, officer, or employee of the Federal Government, or any person acting on behalf of, or at the direction of, the executive department, independent establishment, agency, wholly or partly owned Government corporation, officer, or employee.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Valuables.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “valuables” means any articles or things or representatives of value—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> in which the Government, its executive departments, independent establishments, and agencies, including wholly owned Government corporations, and officers and employees of the Government or its executive departments, independent establishments, and agencies while acting in their official capacity, have any interest, or in connection with which they have any obligation or responsibility; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> which the Secretary of the Treasury declares to be valuables within the meaning of this chapter.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirement for declaring articles or things valuable</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall not declare articles or things that are lost, destroyed, or damaged in the course of shipment to be valuables unless the Secretary determines that replacement of the articles or things in accordance with the procedure established in this chapter would be in the public interest.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Wholly owned government corporation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “wholly owned Government corporation”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> means any corporation, regardless of the law under which it is incorporated, the capital of which is entirely owned by the Government; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> includes the authorized officers, employees, and agents of the corporation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1280</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 17302.</num>
<heading> Compliance</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prescribing Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>With the approval of the President, the Secretary of the Treasury and the United States Postal Service jointly shall prescribe regulations governing the shipment of valuables by an executive department, independent establishment, agency, wholly owned Government corporation, officer, or employee of the Federal Government, with a view to minimizing the risk of loss and destruction of, and damage to, valuables in shipment.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Compliance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each executive department, independent establishment, agency, wholly owned Government corporation, officer, and employee of the Government, and each person acting for, or at the direction of, the executive department, independent establishment, agency, wholly owned Government corporation, officer, or employee, must comply with the regulations when making any shipment of valuables.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1280</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 17303.</num>
<heading> Fund for the payment of Government losses in shipment</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is a revolving fund in the Treasury known as “the fund for the payment of Government losses in shipment”.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The fund shall be used for the replacement of valuables, or the value of valuables, lost, destroyed, or damaged while being shipped in accordance with regulations prescribed under <ref>section 17302 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Unavailability</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The fund is not available with respect to any loss, destruction, or damage affecting valuables—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> that relates to property of the United States Postal Service that is chargeable to its officers or employees; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> of which shipment shall have been made at the risk of persons other than the Federal Government and the executive departments, independent establishments, agencies, wholly owned Government corporations, officers and employees of the Government.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Crediting of Recoveries and Repayments</inline>.—</heading>
<content>All recoveries and repayments on account of loss, destruction, or damage to valuables for which replacement is made out of the fund shall be credited to it and are available for the purposes of the fund.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appropriations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Necessary amounts are appropriated for the fund.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1281</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 17304.</num>
<heading> Claim for replacement</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Presentation of Claim</inline>.—</heading>
<content>When valuables that have been shipped in accordance with regulations prescribed under <ref>section 17302 of this title</ref> are lost, destroyed, or damaged, a claim in writing for replacement shall be made on the Secretary of the Treasury.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Decision of the Secretary of the Treasury.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Replacement made from fund</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the Secretary is satisfied that the loss, destruction, or damage has occurred and that shipment was made substantially in accordance with the regulations, the Secretary shall have replacement be made out of the fund described in <ref>section 17303 of this title</ref> through an officer the Secretary designates.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Replacement made by credit</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>When the Secretary decides that any part of the replacement can be made, without actual or ultimate injury to the Federal Government, by a credit in the accounts of the executive department, independent establishment, agency, officer, employee, or other accountable person making the claim, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> certify the decision to the Comptroller General who, on receiving the certification, shall make the credit in the settlement of accounts in the Government Accountability Office; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> use the fund only to the extent that the replacement cannot be made by the credit.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Decision of Secretary Not Reviewable</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The decision of the Secretary that a loss, destruction, or damage has occurred or that a shipment was made substantially in accordance with regulations is final and conclusive and is not subject to review by any other officer of the Government.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1281</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–271, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-07-07">July 7, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 814</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 17305.</num>
<heading> Replacing lost, destroyed, or damaged stamps, securities, obligations, or money</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Stamps, securities, or other obligations of the Federal Government, or money lost, destroyed, or damaged while in the custody or possession of, or charged to, the United States Postal Service while it is acting as agent for, or on behalf of, the Secretary of the Treasury for the sale of the stamps, securities, or obligations and for the collection of the money, shall be replaced out of the fund described in <ref>section 17303 of this title</ref> under regulations the Secretary may prescribe, regardless of how the loss, destruction, or damage occurs.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1282</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 17306.</num>
<heading> Agreements of indemnity</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “Federal Government” includes wholly owned Government corporations, and officers and employees of the Government or its executive departments, independent establishments, and agencies while acting in their official capacity.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority To Make Agreement</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of the Treasury may make and deliver, on behalf of the Federal Government, a binding agreement of indemnity the Secretary considers necessary and proper to enable the Government to obtain the replacement of any instrument or document—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> received by the Government or an agent of the Government in the agent’s official capacity; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> which, after having been received, is lost, destroyed, or so mutilated as to impair its value.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">When Federal Government Not Obligated</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Government is not obligated under an agreement of indemnity if the obligee named in the agreement makes a payment or delivery not required by law on the original of the instrument or document covered by the agreement.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of Fund for the Payment of Government Losses in Shipment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The fund described in <ref>section 17303 of this title</ref> is available to pay any obligation arising out of an agreement the Secretary makes under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1282</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 17307.</num>
<heading> Purchase of insurance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An executive department, independent establishment, agency, wholly owned Government corporation, officer, or employee may expend money, or incur an obligation, for insurance, or for the payment of premiums on insurance, against loss, destruction, or damage in the shipment of valuables only as specifically authorized by the Secretary of the Treasury. The Secretary may give the authorization if the Secretary finds that the risk of loss, destruction, or damage in the shipment cannot be guarded against adequately by the facilities of the Federal Government or that adequate replacement cannot be provided under this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1282</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 17308.</num>
<heading> Presumption of lawful conduct</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of the propriety of an act or omission related to a shipment to which the regulations prescribed under <ref>section 17302 of this title</ref> apply, every officer and employee of the Federal Government and every individual acting on behalf of a wholly owned Government corporation who makes a shipment of valuables in good faith under, and substantially in accordance with, the regulations is deemed to be acting in the faithful execution of the officer’s, employee’s, or individual’s duties of office and in full performance of any conditions of the officer’s, employee’s, or individual’s bond and oath of office.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1283</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 17309.</num>
<heading> Rules and regulations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>With the approval of the President, the Secretary of the Treasury may prescribe regulations necessary to carry out the duties and powers vested in the Secretary under this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Providing Information</inline>.—</heading>
<content>To carry out subsection (a), the Secretary may require a person making a shipment of valuables or a claim for replacement to make a declaration or to provide other information the Secretary considers necessary.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1283</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>