<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 7—</num>
<heading>TRADE EXPANSION PROGRAM</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1801.</num>
<heading> Statement of purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes of this chapter are, through trade agreements affording mutual trade benefits—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to stimulate the economic growth of the United States and maintain and enlarge foreign markets for the products of United States agriculture, industry, mining, and commerce;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to strengthen economic relations with foreign countries through the development of open and nondiscriminatory trading in the free world; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to prevent Communist economic penetration.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–794, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1962-10-11">Oct. 11, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 872</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 1802 to 1805.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 93–618, title VI, § 602(d)</ref>, <date date="1975-01-03">Jan. 3, 1975</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 2072</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1806.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 93–618, title VI, § 602(d)</ref>, <date date="1975-01-03">Jan. 3, 1975</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 2072</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “duty or other import restriction” includes (A) the rate and form of an import duty, and (B) a limitation, prohibition, charge, and exaction other than duty, imposed on importation or imposed for the regulation of imports.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to (5) Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 93–618, title VI, § 602(d)</ref>, <date date="1975-01-03">Jan. 3, 1975</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 2072</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The term “modification”, as applied to any duty or other import restriction, includes the elimination of any duty.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–794, title IV, § 405</ref>, <date date="1962-10-11">Oct. 11, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 902</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–618, title VI, § 602(d)</ref>, <date date="1975-01-03">Jan. 3, 1975</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 2072</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>TRADE AGREEMENTS</heading>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part I—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">General Authority</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1821.</num>
<heading> Basic authority for trade agreements</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determination by President; trade agreements; modification or continuance of existing duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Whenever the president determines that any existing duties or other import restrictions of any foreign country or the United States are unduly burdening and restricting the foreign trade of the United States and that any of the purposes stated in <ref>section 1801 of this title</ref> will be promoted thereby, the President may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> after <date date="1962-06-30">June 30, 1962</date>, and before <date date="1967-07-01">July 1, 1967</date>, enter into trade agreements with foreign countries or instrumentalities thereof; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> proclaim such modification or continuance of any existing duty or other import restriction, such continuance of existing duty-free or excise treatment, or such additional import restrictions, as he determines to be required or appropriate to carry out any such trade agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Restrictions on decrease or increase in rate of duty</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided in this subchapter, no proclamation pursuant to subsection (a) shall be made—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> decreasing any rate of duty to a rate below 50 percent of the rate existing on <date date="1962-07-01">July 1, 1962</date>; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> increasing any rate of duty to (or imposing) a rate more than 50 percent above the rate existing on <date date="1934-07-01">July 1, 1934</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–794, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1962-10-11">Oct. 11, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 872</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1822.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 93–618, title VI, § 602(d)</ref>, <date date="1975-01-03">Jan. 3, 1975</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 2072</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1823.</num>
<heading> Waiver of limitation on decrease in duty and negotiation and staging requirements for dicyandiamide and limestone</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of the Trade Expansion Act of 1962 [<ref>19 U.S.C. 1801</ref> et seq.], section 201(b)(1) [<ref>19 U.S.C. 1821(b)(1)</ref>] (relating to limit on decrease in duty), sections 221, 223, and 224 [<ref>19 U.S.C. 1841</ref>, 1843, 1844] (relating to certain requirements concerning negotiations), and section 253 [<ref>19 U.S.C. 1883</ref>] (relating to staging requirements) of such Act shall not apply with respect to dicyandiamide provided for in item 425.40 of the Tariff Schedules of the United States, and shall not apply with respect to limestone, when imported to be used in the manufacture of cement, provided for in item 513.34 of such Schedules.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–14</ref>, <date date="1967-05-05">May 5, 1967</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 14</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part II—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">European Economic Community</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 1831 to 1833.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 93–618, title VI, § 602(d)</ref>, <date date="1975-01-03">Jan. 3, 1975</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 2072</ref></heading>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part III—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Requirements Concerning Negotiations</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 1841 to 1846.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 93–618, title VI, § 602(d)</ref>, <date date="1975-01-03">Jan. 3, 1975</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 2072</ref></heading>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part IV—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">National Security</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1861.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 93–618, title VI, § 602(d)</ref>, <date date="1975-01-03">Jan. 3, 1975</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 2072</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1862.</num>
<heading> Safeguarding national security</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition on decrease or elimination of duties or other import restrictions if such reduction or elimination would threaten to impair national security</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No action shall be taken pursuant to <ref>section 1821(a) of this title</ref> or pursuant to <ref>section 1351 of this title</ref> to decrease or eliminate the duty or other import restrictions on any article if the President determines that such reduction or elimination would threaten to impair the national security.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Investigations by Secretary of Commerce to determine effects on national security of imports of articles; consultation with Secretary of Defense and other officials; hearings; assessment of defense requirements; report to President; publication in Federal Register; promulgation of regulations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Upon request of the head of any department or agency, upon application of an interested party, or upon his own motion, the Secretary of Commerce (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Secretary”) shall immediately initiate an appropriate investigation to determine the effects on the national security of imports of the article which is the subject of such request, application, or motion.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall immediately provide notice to the Secretary of Defense of any investigation initiated under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> In the course of any investigation conducted under this subsection, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> consult with the Secretary of Defense regarding the methodological and policy questions raised in any investigation initiated under paragraph (1),</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> seek information and advice from, and consult with, appropriate officers of the United States, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> if it is appropriate and after reasonable notice, hold public hearings or otherwise afford interested parties an opportunity to present information and advice relevant to such investigation.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Upon the request of the Secretary, the Secretary of Defense shall provide the Secretary an assessment of the defense requirements of any article that is the subject of an investigation conducted under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> By no later than the date that is 270 days after the date on which an investigation is initiated under paragraph (1) with respect to any article, the Secretary shall submit to the President a report on the findings of such investigation with respect to the effect of the importation of such article in such quantities or under such circumstances upon the national security and, based on such findings, the recommendations of the Secretary for action or inaction under this section. If the Secretary finds that such article is being imported into the United States in such quantities or under such circumstances as to threaten to impair the national security, the Secretary shall so advise the President in such report.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Any portion of the report submitted by the Secretary under subparagraph (A) which does not contain classified information or proprietary information shall be published in the Federal Register.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall prescribe such procedural regulations as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adjustment of imports; determination by President; report to Congress; additional actions; publication in Federal Register</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> Within 90 days after receiving a report submitted under subsection (b)(3)(A) in which the Secretary finds that an article is being imported into the United States in such quantities or under such circumstances as to threaten to impair the national security, the President shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> determine whether the President concurs with the finding of the Secretary, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> if the President concurs, determine the nature and duration of the action that, in the judgment of the President, must be taken to adjust the imports of the article and its derivatives so that such imports will not threaten to impair the national security.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> If the President determines under subparagraph (A) to take action to adjust imports of an article and its derivatives, the President shall implement that action by no later than the date that is 15 days after the day on which the President determines to take action under subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> By no later than the date that is 30 days after the date on which the President makes any determinations under paragraph (1), the President shall submit to the Congress a written statement of the reasons why the President has decided to take action, or refused to take action, under paragraph (1). Such statement shall be included in the report published under subsection (e).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> If—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the action taken by the President under paragraph (1) is the negotiation of an agreement which limits or restricts the importation into, or the exportation to, the United States of the article that threatens to impair national security, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> either—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> no such agreement is entered into before the date that is 180 days after the date on which the President makes the determination under paragraph (1)(A) to take such action, or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> such an agreement that has been entered into is not being carried out or is ineffective in eliminating the threat to the national security posed by imports of such article,</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">the President shall take such other actions as the President deems necessary to adjust the imports of such article so that such imports will not threaten to impair the national security. The President shall publish in the Federal Register notice of any additional actions being taken under this section by reason of this subparagraph.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> If—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> clauses (i) and (ii) of subparagraph (A) apply, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the President determines not to take any additional actions under this subsection,</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">the President shall publish in the Federal Register such determination and the reasons on which such determination is based.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002063">1</ref> Domestic production for national defense; impact of foreign competition on economic welfare of domestic industries</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purposes of this section, the Secretary and the President shall, in the light of the requirements of national security and without excluding other relevant factors, give consideration to domestic production needed for projected national defense requirements, the capacity of domestic industries to meet such requirements, existing and anticipated availabilities of the human resources, products, raw materials, and other supplies and services essential to the national defense, the requirements of growth of such industries and such supplies and services including the investment, exploration, and development necessary to assure such growth, and the importation of goods in terms of their quantities, availabilities, character, and use as those affect such industries and the capacity of the United States to meet national security requirements. In the administration of this section, the Secretary and the President shall further recognize the close relation of the economic welfare of the Nation to our national security, and shall take into consideration the impact of foreign competition on the economic welfare of individual domestic industries; and any substantial unemployment, decrease in revenues of government, loss of skills or investment, or other serious effects resulting from the displacement of any domestic products by excessive imports shall be considered, without excluding other factors, in determining whether such weakening of our internal economy may impair the national security.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> <sup>1</sup> Report by Secretary of Commerce</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Upon the disposition of each request, application, or motion under subsection (b), the Secretary shall submit to the Congress, and publish in the Federal Register, a report on such disposition.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Omitted.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Congressional disapproval of Presidential adjustment of imports of petroleum or petroleum products; disapproval resolution</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> An action taken by the President under subsection (c) to adjust imports of petroleum or petroleum products shall cease to have force and effect upon the enactment of a disapproval resolution, provided for in paragraph (2), relating to that action.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> This paragraph is enacted by the Congress—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> as an exercise of the rulemaking power of the House of Representatives and the Senate, respectively, and as such is deemed a part of the rules of each House, respectively, but applicable only with respect to the procedures to be followed in that House in the case of disapproval resolutions and such procedures supersede other rules only to the extent that they are inconsistent therewith; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> with the full recognition of the constitutional right of either House to change the rules (so far as relating to the procedure of that House) at any time, in the same manner, and to the same extent as any other rule of that House.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> For purposes of this subsection, the term “disapproval resolution” means only a joint resolution of either House of Congress the matter after the resolving clause of which is as follows: “That the Congress disapproves the action taken under section 232 of the Trade Expansion Act of 1962 with respect to petroleum imports under ______ dated ______.”, the first blank space being filled with the number of the proclamation, Executive order, or other Executive act issued under the authority of subsection (c) of this section for purposes of adjusting imports of petroleum or petroleum products and the second blank being filled with the appropriate date.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> All disapproval resolutions introduced in the House of Representatives shall be referred to the Committee on Ways and Means and all disapproval resolutions introduced in the Senate shall be referred to the Committee on Finance.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> No amendment to a disapproval resolution shall be in order in either the House of Representatives or the Senate, and no motion to suspend the application of this clause shall be in order in either House nor shall it be in order in either House for the Presiding Officer to entertain a request to suspend the application of this clause by unanimous consent.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–794, title II, § 232</ref>, <date date="1962-10-11">Oct. 11, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 877</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–618, title I, § 127(d)</ref>, <date date="1975-01-03">Jan. 3, 1975</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1993</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–223, title IV, § 402</ref>, <date date="1980-04-02">Apr. 2, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 301</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title I, § 1501(a)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1257</ref>, 1259.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1863.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title I, § 1501(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1259</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1864.</num>
<heading> Import sanctions for export violations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any person who violates any national security export control imposed under section 4604 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002064">1</ref> of title 50 or any regulation, order, or license issued under that section, may be subject to such controls on the importing of goods or technology into the United States as the President may prescribe.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–794, title II, § 233</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 99–64, title I, § 121</ref>, <date date="1985-07-12">July 12, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 155</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title II, § 2447(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1370</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part V—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Administrative Provisions</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1871.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 93–618, title VI, § 602(d)</ref>, <date date="1975-01-03">Jan. 3, 1975</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 2072</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1872.</num>
<heading> Interagency trade organization</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment; functions; membership and composition; participation of representatives of other agencies; meetings</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The President shall establish an interagency organization.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The functions of the organization are—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to assist, and make recommendations to, the President in carrying out the functions vested in him by the trade laws and to advise the United States Trade Representative (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “Trade Representative”) in carrying out the functions set forth in <ref>section 2171 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to assist the President, and advise the Trade Representative, with respect to the development and implementation of the international trade policy objectives of the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to advise the President and the Trade Representative with respect to the relationship between the international trade policy objectives of the United States and other major policy areas which may significantly affect the overall international trade policy and trade competitiveness of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The interagency organization shall be composed of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Trade Representative, who shall be chairperson.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Commerce.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The Secretary of State.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Treasury.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Agriculture.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Labor.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">The Trade Representative may invite representatives from other agencies, as appropriate, to attend particular meetings if subject matters of specific functional interest to such agencies are under consideration. It shall meet at such times and with respect to such matters as the President or the Chairman shall direct.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In assisting the President, the organization shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> make recommendations to the President on basic policy issues arising in the administration of the trade agreements program,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> make recommendations to the President as to what action, if any, he should take on reports submitted to him by the United States International Trade Commission under section 2251(d) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002065">1</ref> of this title,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> advise the President of the results of hearings held pursuant to section 2412(b)(2) <sup>1</sup> of this title, and recommend appropriate action with respect thereto, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> perform such other functions with respect to the trade agreements program as the President may from time to time designate.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">In carrying out its functions under this subsection, the organization shall take into account the advice of the congressional advisers and private sector advisory committees, as well as that of any committee or other body established to advise the department, agency, or office which a member of the organization heads.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of resources of agencies; procedures and committees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The organization shall, to the maximum extent practicable, draw upon the resources of the agencies represented in the organization, as well as such other agencies as it may determine, including the United States International Trade Commission. In addition, the President may establish by regulation such procedures and committees as he may determine to be necessary to enable the organization to provide for the conduct of hearings pursuant to <ref>section 2412(b)(2) of this title</ref>, and for the carrying out of other functions assigned to the organization pursuant to this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–794, title II, § 242</ref>, <date date="1962-10-11">Oct. 11, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 878</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–618, title I, § 171(b)</ref>, title VI, § 602(b), <date date="1975-01-03">Jan. 3, 1975</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 2009</ref>, 2072; <ref>Pub. L. 96–39, title IX, § 902(c)</ref>, <date date="1979-07-26">July 26, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 300</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title I, § 1621(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1263</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1873.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 93–618, title VI, § 602(d)</ref>, <date date="1975-01-03">Jan. 3, 1975</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 2072</ref></heading>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part VI—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">General Provisions</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1881.</num>
<heading> Normal trade relations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided in this subchapter, in <ref>section 1351 of this title</ref>, or in section 401(a) of the Tariff Classification Act of 1962, any duty or other import restriction or duty-free treatment proclaimed in carrying out any trade agreement under this subchapter or <ref>section 1351 of this title</ref> shall apply to products of all foreign countries, whether imported directly or indirectly.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–794, title II, § 251</ref>, <date date="1962-10-11">Oct. 11, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 879</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–206, title V, § 5003(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1998-07-22">July 22, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 789</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 1882 to 1884.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 93–618, title VI, § 602(d)</ref>, <date date="1975-01-03">Jan. 3, 1975</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 2072</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1885.</num>
<heading> Termination of proclamations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 93–618, title VI, § 602(d)</ref>, <date date="1975-01-03">Jan. 3, 1975</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 2072</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The President may at any time terminate, in whole or in part, any proclamation made under this subchapter.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–794, title II, § 255</ref>, <date date="1962-10-11">Oct. 11, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 880</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–618, title VI, § 602(d)</ref>, <date date="1975-01-03">Jan. 3, 1975</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 2072</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1886.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 93–618, title VI, § 602(d)</ref>, <date date="1975-01-03">Jan. 3, 1975</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 2072</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1887.</num>
<heading> Limitation on imports under <ref>section 624 of title 7</ref></heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing contained in this chapter shall be construed to affect in any way the provisions of <ref>section 624 of title 7</ref>, or to apply to any import restriction heretofore or hereafter imposed under such section.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–794, title II, § 257(h)</ref>, <date date="1962-10-11">Oct. 11, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 883</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1888.</num>
<heading> References in other laws</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All provisions of law (other than this chapter and the Trade Agreements Extension Act of 1951) in effect after <date date="1962-06-30">June 30, 1962</date>, referring to section 350 of the Tariff Act of 1930, to that section as amended, to the Act entitled “An Act to amend the Tariff Act of 1930”, approved <date date="1934-06-12">June 12, 1934</date>, to that Act as amended, or to agreements entered into, or proclamations issued, under any of such provisions, shall be construed, unless clearly precluded by the context, to refer also to this chapter, or to agreements entered into or proclamations issued, pursuant to this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–794, title II, § 258</ref>, <date date="1962-10-11">Oct. 11, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 883</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>TARIFF ADJUSTMENT AND OTHER ADJUSTMENT ASSISTANCE</heading>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part I—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Eligibility for Assistance</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 1901, 1902.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 93–618, title VI, § 602(d)</ref>, (e), <date date="1975-01-03">Jan. 3, 1975</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 2072</ref></heading>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part II—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Adjustment Assistance to Firms</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 1911 to 1915.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 93–618, title VI, § 602(e)</ref>, <date date="1975-01-03">Jan. 3, 1975</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 2072</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1916.</num>
<heading> Administration of financial assistance; recording of mortgages</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Guarantees, agreements for deferred participation, and loans</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In making and administering guarantees, agreements for deferred participation, and loans under section 1914 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002066">1</ref> of this title, the Secretary of Commerce may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> require security for any such guarantee, agreement, or loan, and enforce, waive, or subordinate such security;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> assign or sell at public or private sale, or otherwise dispose of, upon such terms and conditions and for such consideration as he shall determine to be reasonable, any evidence of debt, contract, claim, personal property, or security assigned to or held by him in connection with such guarantees, agreements, or loans, and collect, compromise, and obtain deficiency judgments with respect to all obligations assigned to or held by him in connection with such guarantees, agreements, or loans until such time as such obligations may be referred to the Attorney General for suit or collection;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> renovate, improve, modernize, complete, insure, rent, sell, or otherwise deal with, upon such terms and conditions and for such consideration as he shall determine to be reasonable, any real or personal property conveyed to or otherwise acquired by him in connection with such guarantees, agreements, or loans;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> acquire, hold, transfer, release, or convey any real or personal property or any interest therein whenever deemed necessary or appropriate, and execute all legal documents for such purposes; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> exercise all such other powers and take all such other acts as may be necessary or incidental to the carrying out of functions pursuant to <ref>section 1914 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Mortgages</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any mortgage acquired as security under subsection (a) shall be recorded under applicable State law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–794, title III, § 316</ref>, <date date="1962-10-11">Oct. 11, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 888</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1917.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 93–618, title VI, § 602(e)</ref>, <date date="1975-01-03">Jan. 3, 1975</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 2072</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1918.</num>
<heading> Protective provisions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Maintenance of records by recipients of assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each recipient of adjustment assistance under section 1913, 1914, or 1917 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002067">1</ref> of this title, shall keep records which fully disclose the amount and disposition by such recipient of the proceeds, if any, of such adjustment assistance, and which will facilitate an effective audit. The recipient shall also keep such other records as the Secretary of Commerce may prescribe.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Access to books, documents, papers, and records for purpose of audit and examination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Commerce and the Comptroller General of the United States shall have access for the purpose of audit and examination to any books, documents, papers, and rec­ords of the recipient pertaining to adjustment assistance under sections 1913, 1914, and 1917 <sup>1</sup> of this title.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certification of names and fees of attorneys, agents, and other persons engaged for purpose of expediting applications for assistance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">No adjustment assistance shall be extended under section 1913, 1914, or 1917 <sup>1</sup> of this title to any firm unless the owners, partners, or officers certify to the Secretary of Commerce—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the names of any attorneys, agents, and other persons engaged by or on behalf of the firm for the purpose of expediting applications for such adjustment assistance, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the fees paid or to be paid to any such person.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agreement with respect to employment of persons who occupied a position, or engaged in activities which the Secretary of Commerce determines involved discretion</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No financial assistance shall be provided to any firm under section 1914 <sup>1</sup> of this title unless the owners, partners, or officers shall execute an agreement binding them and the firm for a period of 2 years after such financial assistance is provided, to refrain from employing, tendering any office or employment to, or retaining for professional services any person who, on the date such assistance or any part thereof was provided, or within one year prior thereto, shall have served as an officer, attorney, agent, or employee occupying a position or engaging in activities which the Secretary of Commerce shall have determined involve discretion with respect to the provision of such financial assistance.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–794, title III, § 318</ref>, <date date="1962-10-11">Oct. 11, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 891</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1919.</num>
<heading> Penalties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever makes a false statement of a material fact knowing it to be false, or knowingly fails to disclose a material fact, or whoever willfully overvalues any security, for the purpose of influencing in any way the action of the Secretary of Commerce under this part, or for the purpose of obtaining money, property, or anything of value under this part, shall be fined not more than $5,000 or imprisoned for not more than two years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–794, title III, § 319</ref>, <date date="1962-10-11">Oct. 11, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 892</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1920.</num>
<heading> Suits by and against Secretary of Commerce</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In providing technical and financial assistance under sections 1913 and 1914 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002068">1</ref> of this title, the Secretary of Commerce may sue and be sued in any court of record of a State having general jurisdiction or in any United States district court, and jurisdiction is conferred upon such district court to determine such controversies without regard to the amount in controversy; but no attachment, injunction, garnishment, or other similar process, mesne or final, shall be issued against him or his property. Nothing in this section shall be construed to except the activities pursuant to sections 1913 and 1914 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002068">1</ref> of this title from the application of sections 517, 519, and 2679 of title 28.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–794, title III, § 320</ref>, <date date="1962-10-11">Oct. 11, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 892</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part III—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Adjustment Assistance to Workers</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1931.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 93–618, title VI, § 602(e)</ref>, <date date="1975-01-03">Jan. 3, 1975</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 2072</ref></heading>
</section>
<subpart>
<num class="small-caps">subpart a—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">trade readjustment allowances</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 1941 to 1944.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 93–618, title VI, § 602(e)</ref>, <date date="1975-01-03">Jan. 3, 1975</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 2072</ref></heading>
</section>
</subpart>
<subpart>
<num class="small-caps">subpart b—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">training</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 1951, 1952.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 93–618, title VI, § 602(e)</ref>, <date date="1975-01-03">Jan. 3, 1975</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 2072</ref></heading>
</section>
</subpart>
<subpart>
<num class="small-caps">subpart c—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">relocation allowances</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 1961 to 1963.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 93–618, title VI, § 602(e)</ref>, <date date="1975-01-03">Jan. 3, 1975</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 2072</ref></heading>
</section>
</subpart>
<subpart>
<num class="small-caps">subpart d—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">general provisions</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 1971 to 1978.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 93–618, title VI, § 602(e)</ref>, <date date="1975-01-03">Jan. 3, 1975</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 2072</ref></heading>
</section>
</subpart>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part IV—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Tariff Adjustment</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1981.</num>
<heading> General authority</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Proclamation of increase in, or imposition of, any duty or other import restriction; report to the Congress; adoption of resolution of approval; request for additional information</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> After receiving an affirmative finding of the United States International Trade Commission under <ref>section 1901(b) of this title</ref> with respect to an industry, the President may proclaim such increase in, or imposition of, any duty or other import restriction on the article causing or threatening to cause serious injury to such industry as he determines to be necessary to prevent or remedy serious injury to such industry.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> If the President does not, within 60 days after the date on which he receives such affirmative finding, proclaim the increase in, or imposition of, any duty or other import restriction on such article found and reported by the United States International Trade Commission pursuant to section 1901(e) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002069">1</ref> of this title—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> he shall immediately submit a report to the House of Representatives and to the Senate stating why he has not proclaimed such increase or imposition, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> such increase or imposition shall take effect (as provided in paragraph (3)) upon the adoption by both Houses of the Congress (within the 60-day period following the date on which the report referred to in subparagraph (A) is submitted to the House of Representatives and the Senate), by the yeas and nays by the affirmative vote of a majority of the authorized membership of each House, of a concurrent resolution stating in effect that the Senate and House of Representatives approve the increase in, or imposition of, any duty or other import restriction on the article found and reported by the United States International Trade Commission.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">For purposes of subparagraph (B), in the computation of the 60-day period there shall be excluded the days on which either House is not in session because of adjournment of more than 3 days to a day certain or an adjournment of the Congress sine die. The report referred to in subparagraph (A) shall be delivered to both Houses of the Congress on the same day and shall be delivered to the Clerk of the House of Representatives if the House of Representatives is not in session and to the Secretary of the Senate if the Senate is not in session.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> In any case in which the contingency set forth in paragraph (2)(B) occurs, the President shall (within 15 days after the adoption of such resolution) proclaim the increase in, or imposition of, any duty or other import restriction on the article which was found and reported by the United States International Trade Commission pursuant to <ref>section 1901(e) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The President may, within 60 days after the date on which he receives an affirmative finding of the United States International Trade Commission under section 1901(b) <sup>1</sup> of this title with respect to an industry, request additional information from the United States International Trade Commission. The United States International Trade Commission shall, as soon as practicable but in no event more than 120 days after the date on which it receives the President’s request, furnish additional information with respect to such industry in a supplemental report. For purposes of paragraph (2), the date on which the President receives such supplemental report shall be treated as the date on which the President received the affirmative finding of the United States International Trade Commission with respect to such industry.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Maximum rate of increase</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">No proclamation pursuant to subsection (a) shall be made—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> increasing any rate of duty to a rate more than 50 percent above the rate existing on <date date="1934-07-01">July 1, 1934</date>, or, if the article is dutiable but no rate existed on <date date="1934-07-01">July 1, 1934</date>, the rate existing at the time of the proclamation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in the case of an article not subject to duty, imposing a duty in excess of 50 percent ad valorem.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">For purposes of paragraph (1), the term “existing on <date date="1934-07-01">July 1, 1934</date>” has the meaning assigned to such term by paragraph (5) of section 1886 <sup>1</sup> of this title.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reduction, termination, or extension of increase in, or imposition of, any duty or other import restriction</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Any increase in, or imposition of, any duty or other import restriction proclaimed pursuant to this section or section 7 of the Trade Agreements Extension Act of 1951—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> may be reduced or terminated by the President when he determines, after taking into account the advice received from the United States International Trade Commission under subsection (d)(2) and after seeking advice of the Secretary of Commerce and the Secretary of Labor, that such reduction or termination is in the national interest, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> unless extended under <ref>section 2253 of this title</ref>, shall terminate not later than the close of the date which is 4 years (or, in the case of any such increase or imposition proclaimed pursuant to such section 7, 5 years) after the effective date of the initial proclamation or <date date="1962-10-11">October 11, 1962</date>, whichever date is the later.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 93–618, title VI, § 602(d)</ref>, <date date="1975-01-03">Jan. 3, 1975</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 2072</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review of developments with respect to industries concerned; annual report to President; advice of probable economic effect; considerations; investigations; hearings</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> So long as any increase in, or imposition of, any duty or other import restriction pursuant to this section or pursuant to section 7 of the Trade Agreements Extension Act of 1951 remains in effect, the United States International Trade Commission shall keep under review developments with respect to the industry concerned, and shall make annual reports to the President concerning such developments.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Upon request of the President or upon its own motion, the United States International Trade Commission shall advise the President of its judgment as to the probable economic effect on the industry concerned of the reduction or termination of the increase in, or imposition of, any duty or other import restriction pursuant to this section or section 7 of the Trade Agreements Extension Act of 1951.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 93–618, title VI, § 602(d)</ref>, <date date="1975-01-03">Jan. 3, 1975</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 2072</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> In advising the President under this subsection as to the probable economic effect on the industry concerned, the United States International Trade Commission shall take into account all economic factors which it considers relevant, including idling of productive facilities, inability to operate at a level of reasonable profit, and unemployment or underemployment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Advice by the United States International Trade Commission under this subsection shall be given on the basis of an investigation during the course of which the United States International Trade Commission shall hold a hearing at which interested persons shall be given a reasonable opportunity to be present, to produce evidence, and to be heard.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conformity of trade agreements with this section</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President, as soon as practicable, shall take such action as he determines to be necessary to bring trade agreements entered into under <ref>section 1351 of this title</ref> into conformity with the provisions of this section. No trade agreement shall be entered into under <ref>section 1821(a) of this title</ref> unless such agreement permits action in conformity with the provisions of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–794, title III, § 351</ref>, <date date="1962-10-11">Oct. 11, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 899</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–618, title I, § 171(b)</ref>, title VI, § 602(c), (d), <date date="1975-01-03">Jan. 3, 1975</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 2009</ref>, 2072.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1982.</num>
<heading> Marketing agreements</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Negotiations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">After receiving an affirmative finding of the United States International Trade Commission under section 1901(b) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002070">1</ref> of this title with respect to an industry, the President may, in lieu of exercising the authority contained in <ref>section 1981(a)(1) of this title</ref> but subject to the provisions of sections 1981(a)(2), (3), and (4) of this title, negotiate international agreements with foreign countries limiting the export from such countries and the import into the United States of the article causing or threatening to cause serious injury to such industry, whenever he determines that such action would be more appropriate to prevent or remedy serious injury to such industry than action under <ref>section 1981(a)(1) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations governing entry or withdrawal from warehouse</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In order to carry out an agreement concluded under subsection (a), the President is authorized to issue regulations governing the entry or withdrawal from warehouse of the article covered by such agreement. In addition, in order to carry out a multilateral agreement concluded under subsection (a) among countries accounting for a significant part of world trade in the article covered by such agreement, the President is also authorized to issue regulations governing the entry or withdrawal from warehouse of the like article which is the product of countries not parties to such agreement.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–794, title III, § 352</ref>, <date date="1962-10-11">Oct. 11, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 901</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–618, title I, § 171(b)</ref>, <date date="1975-01-03">Jan. 3, 1975</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 2009</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part V—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Advisory Board</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1991.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 93–618, title VI, § 602(d)</ref>, <date date="1975-01-03">Jan. 3, 1975</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 2072</ref></heading>
</section>
</part>
</subchapter>
</chapter>