<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 8—</num>
<heading>AUTOMOTIVE PRODUCTS</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>STATEMENT OF PURPOSES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2001.</num>
<heading> Congressional declaration of purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes of this chapter are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to provide for the implementation of the Agreement Concerning Automotive Products Between the Government of the United States of America and the Government of Canada signed on <date date="1965-01-16">January 16, 1965</date> (hereinafter referred to as the “Agreement”), in order to strengthen the economic relations and expand trade in automotive products between the United States and Canada; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to authorize the implementation of such other international agreements providing for the mutual reduction or elimination of duties applicable to automotive products as the Government of the United States may hereafter enter into.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–283, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1965-10-21">Oct. 21, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 1016</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>BASIC AUTHORITIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2011.</num>
<heading> Implementation of the Agreement</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Modification of Harmonized Tariff Schedule</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President is authorized to proclaim the modifications of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States provided for in title IV of this Act.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duty-free treatment of Canadian motor-vehicle equipment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">At any time after the issuance of the proclamation authorized by subsection (a), the President is authorized to proclaim further modifications of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States to provide for the duty-free treatment of any Canadian article which is original motor-vehicle equipment (as defined by such Schedules as modified pursuant to subsection (a)) if he determines that the importation of such article is actually or potentially of commercial significance and that such duty-free treatment is required to carry out the Agreement.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–283, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1965-10-21">Oct. 21, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 1016</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title I, § 1214(i)</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1157</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2012.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2013.</num>
<heading> Effective date of proclamations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Retroactive effect; authority of President</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to subsection (b), the President is authorized, notwithstanding <ref>section 1514 of this title</ref> or any other provision of law, to give retroactive effect to any proclamation issued pursuant to <ref>section 2011 of this title</ref> as of the earliest date after <date date="1965-01-17">January 17, 1965</date>, which he determines to be practicable.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Filing of request with customs officer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the case of liquidated customs entries, the retroactive effect pursuant to subsection (a) of any proclamation shall apply only upon request therefor filed with the customs officer concerned on or before the 90th day after the date of such proclamation and subject to such other conditions as the President may specify.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–283, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="1965-10-21">Oct. 21, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 1018</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2014.</num>
<heading> Termination of proclamations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President is authorized at any time to terminate, in whole or in part, any proclamation issued pursuant to section 2011 or 2012 of this title.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–283, title II, § 204</ref>, <date date="1965-10-21">Oct. 21, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 1018</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2015.</num>
<heading> Special reports to Congress</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report on required comprehensive review</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No later than <date date="1968-08-31">August 31, 1968</date>, the President shall submit to the Senate and the House of Representatives a special report on the comprehensive review called for by Article IV(c) of the Agreement. In such report he shall advise the Congress of the progress made toward the achievement of the objectives of Article I of the Agreement.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report on increase on Canadian value added</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever the President finds that any manufacturer has entered into any undertaking, by reason of governmental action, to increase the Canadian value added of automobiles, buses, specified commercial vehicles, or original equipment parts produced by such manufacturer in Canada after <date date="1968-08-31">August 31, 1968</date>, he shall report such finding to the Senate and the House of Representatives. The President shall also report whether such undertaking is additional to undertakings agreed to in letters of undertaking submitted by such manufacturer before <date date="1965-10-21">October 21, 1965</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recommendations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The reports provided for in subsections (a) and (b) of this section shall include recommendations for such further steps, including legislative action, if any, as may be necessary for the achievement of the purposes of the Agreement and this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–283, title II, § 205</ref>, <date date="1965-10-21">Oct. 21, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 1018</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>TARIFF ADJUSTMENT AND OTHER ADJUSTMENT ASSISTANCE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2021.</num>
<heading> General authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A petition may be filed for tariff adjustment or for a determination of eligibility to apply for adjustment assistance under title III of the Trade Expansion Act of 1962 [<ref>19 U.S.C. 1901</ref> et seq.] as though the reduction or elimination of a duty proclaimed by the President pursuant to section 2011 or 2012 of this title were a concession granted under a trade agreement referred to in section 301 of the Trade Expansion Act of 1962 [<ref>19 U.S.C. 1901</ref>].</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–283, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="1965-10-21">Oct. 21, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 1018</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 2022, 2023.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2024.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are hereby authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary from time to time to carry out the provisions of this subchapter, which sums are authorized to be appropriated to remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–283, title III, § 304</ref>, <date date="1965-10-21">Oct. 21, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 1021</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2031.</num>
<heading> Authorities; delegation of functions; rules and regulations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The head of any agency performing functions authorized by this chapter may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> authorize the head of any other agency to perform any of such functions; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> prescribe such rules and regulations as may be necessary to perform such functions.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–283, title V, § 501</ref>, <date date="1965-10-21">Oct. 21, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 1025</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2032.</num>
<heading> Annual report to Congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President shall submit to the Congress an annual report on the implementation of this chapter. Such report shall include information regarding new negotiations, reductions or eliminations of duties, reciprocal concessions obtained, and other information relating to activities under this chapter. Such report shall also include information providing an evaluation of the Agreement and this chapter in relation to the total national interest, and specifically shall include, to the extent practicable, information with respect to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the production of motor vehicles and motor vehicle parts in the United States and Canada.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the retail prices of motor vehicles and motor vehicle parts in the United States and Canada.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> employment in the motor vehicle industry and motor vehicle parts industry in the United States and Canada, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> United States and Canadian trade in motor vehicles and motor vehicle parts, particularly trade between the United States and Canada.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–283, title V, § 502</ref>, <date date="1965-10-21">Oct. 21, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 1025</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2033.</num>
<heading> Applicability of antidumping provisions and antitrust laws</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing contained in this chapter shall be construed to affect or modify the provisions of subtitle B of title VII of the Tariff Act of 1930 [<ref>19 U.S.C. 1673</ref> et seq.] or of any of the antitrust laws as designated in <ref>section 12 of title 15</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–283, title V, § 503</ref>, <date date="1965-10-21">Oct. 21, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 1026</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–39, title I, § 106(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1979-07-26">July 26, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 193</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>