<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 13—</num>
<heading>TRADE AGREEMENTS ACT OF 1979</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2501.</num>
<heading> Short title</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This Act may be cited as the “Trade Agreements Act of 1979”.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–39, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1979-07-26">July 26, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 144</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2502.</num>
<heading> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes of this Act are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to approve and implement the trade agreements negotiated under the Trade Act of 1974 [<ref>19 U.S.C. 2101</ref> et seq.];</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to foster the growth and maintenance of an open world trading system;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to expand opportunities for the commerce of the United States in international trade; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to improve the rules of international trade and to provide for the enforcement of such rules, and for other purposes.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–39, § 1(c)</ref>, <date date="1979-07-26">July 26, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 146</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2503.</num>
<heading> Approval of trade agreements</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Approval of agreements and statements of administrative action</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In accordance with the provisions of sections 2112 and 2191 of this title, the Congress approves the trade agreements described in subsection (c) submitted to the Congress on <date date="1979-06-19">June 19, 1979</date>, and the statements of administrative action proposed to implement such trade agreements submitted to the Congress on that date.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Acceptance of agreements by the President</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The President may accept for the United States the final legal instruments or texts embodying each of the trade agreements approved by the Congress under subsection (a). The President shall submit a copy of each final instrument or text to the Congress on the date such text or instrument is available, together with a notification of any changes in the instruments or texts, including their annexes, if any, as accepted and the texts of such agreements as submitted to the Congress under subsection (a). Such final legal instruments or texts shall be deemed to be the agreements submitted to and approved by the Congress under subsection (a) if such changes are—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> only rectifications of a formal character or minor technical or clerical changes which do not affect the substance or meaning of the texts as submitted to the Congress on <date date="1979-06-19">June 19, 1979</date>, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> changes in annexes to such agreements, and the President determines that the balance of United States rights and obligations under such agreements is maintained.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application of agreement between the United States and other countries</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">No agreement accepted by the President under paragraph (1) shall apply between the United States and any other country unless the President determines that such country—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> has accepted the obligations of the agreement with respect to the United States, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> should not otherwise be denied the benefits of the agreement with respect to the United States because such country has not accorded adequate benefits, including substantially equal competitive opportunities for the commerce of the United States to the extent required under section 2136(c) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002133">1</ref> of this title, to the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on acceptance concerning major industrial countries</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The President may not accept an agreement described in paragraph (1), (2), (3), (4), (5), (6), (7), (9), (10), or (11) of subsection (c), unless he determines that each major industrial country (as defined in section 2136(d) <sup>1</sup> of this title) is also accepting the agreement. Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, the President may accept such an agreement, if he determines that only one major industrial country is not accepting that agreement and the acceptance of that agreement by that country is not essential to the effective operation of the agreement, and if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> that country is not a major factor in trade in the products covered by that agreement,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the President has authority to deny the benefits of the agreement to that country and has taken steps to deny the benefits of the agreement to that country, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a significant portion of United States trade would benefit from the agreement, notwithstanding such nonacceptance, and the President determines and reports to the Congress that it is in the national interest of the United States to accept the agreement.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">For purposes of this paragraph, the acceptance of an agreement by the European Communities on behalf of its member countries shall also be treated as acceptance of that agreement by each member country, and acceptance of an agreement by all the member countries of the European Communities shall also be treated as acceptance of that agreement by the European Communities.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Trade agreements to which this Act applies</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The trade agreements to which subsection (a) applies are the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Agreement on Implementation of Article VII of the General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade (relating to customs valuation).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Agreement on Government Procurement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Agreement on Import Licensing Procedures.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Agreement on Technical Barriers to Trade (relating to product standards).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The Agreement on Interpretation and Application of Articles VI, XVI, and XXIII of the General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade (relating to subsidies and countervailing measures).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The Agreement on Implementation of Article VI of the General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade (relating to antidumping measures).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The International Dairy Arrangement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Certain bilateral agreements on cheese, other dairy products, and meat.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> The Arrangement Regarding Bovine Meat.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> The Agreement on Trade in Civil Aircraft.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> Texts Concerning a Framework for the Conduct of World Trade.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> Certain Bilateral Agreements to Eliminate the Wine-Gallon Method of Tax and Duty Assessment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<chapeau> Certain other agreements to be reflected in Schedule XX of the United States to the General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade, including Agreements—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to Modify United States Watch Marking Requirements, and to Modify United States Tariff Nomenclature and Rates of Duty for Watches,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to Provide Duty-Free Treatment for Agricultural and Horticultural Machinery, Equipment, Implements, and Parts Thereof, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to Modify United States Tariff Nomenclature and Rates of Duty for Ceramic Tableware.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> The Agreement with the Hungarian People’s Republic.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–39, § 2</ref>, <date date="1979-07-26">July 26, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2504.</num>
<heading> Relationship of trade agreements to United States law</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> United States statutes to prevail in conflict</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No provision of any trade agreement approved by the Congress under <ref>section 2503(a) of this title</ref>, nor the application of any such provision to any person or circumstance, which is in conflict with any statute of the United States shall be given effect under the laws of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementing regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Regulations necessary or appropriate to carry out actions proposed in any statement of proposed administrative action submitted to the Congress under <ref>section 2112 of this title</ref> to implement each agreement approved under <ref>section 2503(a) of this title</ref> shall be issued within 1 year after the date of the entry into force of such agreement with respect to the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Changes in statutes to implement a requirement, amendment, or recommendation</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Presidential determination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Whenever the President determines that it is necessary or appropriate to amend, repeal, or enact a statute of the United States in order to implement any requirement of, amendment to, or recommendation under such an agreement, he shall submit to the Congress a draft of a bill to accomplish the amendment, repeal, or enactment and a statement of any administrative action proposed to implement the requirement, amendment, or recommendation. Not less than 30 days before submitting such a bill, the President shall consult with the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Finance of the Senate, and each committee of the House or Senate which has jurisdiction over legislation involving subject matters which would be affected by such amendment, repeal, or enactment. The consultation shall treat all matters relating to the implementation of such requirement, amendment, or recommendation, as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conditions for taking effect under United States law</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">No such amendment shall enter into force with respect to the United States, and no such requirement, amendment, or recommendation shall be implemented under United States law, unless—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the President, after consultation with the Congress under paragraph (1), notifies the House of Representatives and the Senate of his determination and publishes notice of that determination in the Federal Register,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> the President transmits a document to the House of Representatives and to the Senate containing a copy of the text of such requirement, amendment, or recommendation, together with—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a draft of a bill to amend or repeal provisions of existing statutes or to create statutory authority and an explanation as to how the bill and any proposed administrative action affect existing law, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a statement of how the requirement, amendment, or recommendation serves the interests of United States commerce and why the legislative and administrative action is necessary or appropriate to carry out the requirement, amendment, or recommendation, and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the bill submitted by the President is enacted into law.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recommendations as to application</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The President may make the same type of recommendations, in the same manner and subject to the same conditions, to the Congress with respect to the application of any such requirement, amendment, or recommendation as he may make, under <ref>section 2112(f) of this title</ref>, with respect to a trade agreement.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Congressional procedures applicable</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The bill submitted by the President shall be introduced in accordance with the provisions of subsection (c)(1) of <ref>section 2191 of this title</ref>, and the provisions of subsections (d), (e), (f), and (g) of such section shall apply to the consideration of the bill. For the purpose of applying <ref>section 2191 of this title</ref> to such bill—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the term “trade agreement” shall be treated as a reference to the requirement, amendment, or recommendation, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the term “implementing bill” or “implementing revenue bill”, whichever is appropriate, shall be treated as a reference to the bill submitted by the President.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Unspecified private remedies not created</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Neither the entry into force with respect to the United States of any agreement approved under <ref>section 2503(a) of this title</ref>, nor the enactment of this Act, shall be construed as creating any private right of action or remedy for which provision is not explicitly made under this Act or under the laws of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–39, § 3(a)</ref>–(c), (f), <date date="1979-07-26">July 26, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 148–150</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>GOVERNMENT PROCUREMENT</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2511.</num>
<heading> General authority to modify discriminatory purchasing requirements</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Presidential waiver of discriminatory purchasing requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subject to subsection (f) of this section, the President may waive, in whole or in part, with respect to eligible products of any foreign country or instrumentality designated under subsection (b), and suppliers of such products, the application of any law, regulation, procedure, or practice regarding Government procurement that would, if applied to such products and suppliers, result in treatment less favorable than that accorded—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to United States products and suppliers of such products; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to eligible products of another foreign country or instrumentality which is a party to the Agreement and suppliers of such products.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Designation of eligible countries and instrumentalities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President may designate a foreign country or instrumentality for purposes of subsection (a) only if he determines that such country or instrumentality—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> is a country or instrumentality which (A) has become a party to the Agreement or the USMCA (as defined in <ref>section 4502 of this title</ref>), and (B) will provide appropriate reciprocal competitive government procurement opportunities to United States products and suppliers of such products;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> is a country or instrumentality, other than a major industrial country, which (A) will otherwise assume the obligations of the Agreement, and (B) will provide such opportunities to such products and suppliers;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> is a country or instrumentality, other than a major industrial country, which will provide such opportunities to such products and suppliers; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> is a least developed country.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Modification or withdrawal of waivers and designations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President may modify or withdraw any waiver granted pursuant to subsection (a) or designation made pursuant to subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Procurement procedures by certain Federal agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the President may direct any agency of the United States listed in Annex 13–A of the USMCA (as defined in <ref>section 4502 of this title</ref>) to procure eligible products in compliance with the procedural provisions of chapter 13 of the USMCA.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Small business and minority preferences</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The authority of the President under subsection (a) of this section to waive any law, regulation, procedure, or practice regarding Government procurement does not authorize the waiver of any small business or minority preference.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–39, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="1979-07-26">July 26, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 236</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title VII, § 7005(e)</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1553</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–182, title III, § 381(a)</ref>, <date date="1993-12-08">Dec. 8, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 2128</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–113, title V, § 505(a)</ref>, <date date="2020-01-29">Jan. 29, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 77</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2512.</num>
<heading> Authority to encourage reciprocal competitive procurement practices</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority to bar procurement from non-designated countries</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Subject to paragraph (2), the President, in order to encourage additional countries to become parties to the Agreement and to provide appropriate reciprocal competitive government procurement opportunities to United States products and suppliers of such products—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> shall, with respect to procurement covered by the Agreement, prohibit the procurement, after the date on which any waiver under <ref>section 2511(a) of this title</ref> first takes effect, of products—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> which are products of a foreign country or instrumentality which is not designated pursuant to <ref>section 2511(b) of this title</ref>, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> which would otherwise be eligible products; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> may, with respect to procurement covered by the Agreement, take such other actions within the President’s authority as the President deems necessary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Paragraph (1) shall not apply in the case of procurements for which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> there are no offers of products or services of the United States or of eligible products; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the offers of products or services of the United States or of eligible products are insufficient to fulfill the requirements of the United States Government.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deferrals and waivers</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Notwithstanding subsection (a), but in furtherance of the objective of encouraging countries to become parties to the Agreement and provide appropriate reciprocal competitive government procurement opportunities to United States products and suppliers of such products, the President may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> waive the prohibition required by subsection (a)(1) on procurement of products of a foreign country or instrumentality which has not yet become a party to the Agreement but—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> has agreed to apply transparent and competitive procedures to its government procurement equivalent to those in the Agreement, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> maintains and enforces effective prohibitions on bribery and other corrupt practices in connection with its government procurement;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> authorize agency heads to waive, subject to interagency review and general policy guidance by the organization established under <ref>section 1872(a) of this title</ref>, such prohibition on a case-by-case basis when in the national interest; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> authorize the Secretary of Defense to waive, subject to interagency review and policy guidance by the organization established under <ref>section 1872(a) of this title</ref>, such prohibition for products of any country or instrumentality which enters into a reciprocal procurement agreement with the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Before exercising the waiver authority under paragraph (1), the President shall consult with the appropriate private sector advisory committees established under <ref>section 2155 of this title</ref> and with the appropriate committees of the Congress.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report on impact of restrictions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Impact on the economy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">On or before <date date="1981-07-01">July 1, 1981</date>, the President shall report to the Committee on Ways and Means and the Committee on Government Operations of the House of Representatives and to the Committee on Finance and the Committee on Governmental Affairs of the Senate on the effects on the United States economy (including effects on employment, production, competition, costs and prices, technological development, export trade, balance of payments, inflation, and the Federal budget) of the refusal of developed countries to allow the Agreement to cover the entities of the governments of such countries which are the principal purchasers of goods and equipment in appropriate product sectors.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recommendations for attaining reciprocity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The report required by paragraph (1) shall include an evaluation of alternative means to obtain equity and reciprocity in such product sectors, including (A) prohibiting the procurement of products of such countries by United States entities not covered by the Agreement, and (B) modifying the application of chapter 83 of title 41. The report shall include an analysis of the effect of such alternative means on the United States economy (including effects on employment, production, competition, costs and prices, technological development, export trade, balance of payments, inflation, and the Federal budget), and on successful negotiations on the expansion of the coverage of the Agreement pursuant to section 2514(a) and (b) of this title, other trade negotiating objectives, the relationship of the Federal Government to State and local governments, and such other factors as the President deems appropriate.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In the preparation of the report required by paragraph (1) and the evaluation and analysis required by paragraph (2), the President shall consult with representatives of the public, industry, and labor, and make available pertinent, nonconfidential information obtained in the course of such preparation to the advisory committees established pursuant to <ref>section 2155 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Proposed action</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Presidential report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">On or before <date date="1981-10-01">October 1, 1981</date>, the President shall prepare and transmit to the congressional committees referred to in subsection (c)(1) a report which describes the actions he deems appropriate to establish reciprocity with major industrialized countries in the area of Government procurement.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Procedure</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Presidential determination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">If the President determines that any changes in existing law or new statutory authority are required to authorize or to implement any action proposed in the report submitted under paragraph (1), he shall, on or after <date date="1982-01-01">January 1, 1982</date>, submit to the Congress a bill to accomplish such changes or provide such new statutory authority. Prior to submitting such a bill, the President shall consult with the appropriate committees of the Congress having jurisdiction over legislation involving subject matters which would be affected by such action, and shall submit to such committees a proposed draft of such bill.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Congressional consideration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The appropriate committee of each House of the Congress shall give a bill submitted pursuant to subparagraph (A) prompt consideration and shall make its best efforts to take final committee action on such bill in an expeditious manner.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–39, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="1979-07-26">July 26, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 236</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–182, title III, § 381(b)</ref>, <date date="1993-12-08">Dec. 8, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 2129</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–465, title III, § 343(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4954</ref>, 4955.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2513.</num>
<heading> Waiver of discriminatory purchasing requirements with respect to purchases of civil aircraft</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President may waive the application of the provisions of chapter 83 of title 41 in the case of any procurement of civil aircraft and related articles of a country or instrumentality which is a party to the Agreement on Trade in Civil Aircraft referred to in <ref>section 2503(c) of this title</ref> and approved under <ref>section 2503(a) of this title</ref>. The President may modify or withdraw any waiver granted pursuant to this section.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–39, title III, § 303</ref>, <date date="1979-07-26">July 26, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 238</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–465, title III, § 342(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4953</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2514.</num>
<heading> Expansion of the coverage of the Agreement</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Overall negotiating objective</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall seek in the renegotiations provided for in article XXIV(7) of the Agreement more open and equitable market access abroad, and the harmonization, reduction, or elimination of devices which distort trade or commerce related to Government procurement, with the overall goal of maximizing the economic benefit to the United States through maintaining and enlarging foreign markets for products of United States agriculture, industry, mining, and commerce, the development of fair and equitable market opportunities, and open and nondiscriminatory world trade. In carrying out the provisions of this subsection, the President shall consider the assessment made in the report required under section 2516(a) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002134">1</ref> of this title.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sector negotiating objectives</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall seek, consistent with the overall objective set forth in subsection (a) and to the maximum extent feasible, with respect to appropriate product sectors, competitive opportunities for the export of United States products to the developed countries of the world equivalent to the competitive opportunities afforded by the United States, taking into account all barriers to, and other distortions of, international trade affecting that sector.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Independent verification objective</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall seek to establish in the renegotiation provided for in article XXIV(7) of the Agreement a system for independent verification of information provided by parties to the Agreement to the Committee on Government Procurement pursuant to article XIX(5) of the Agreement.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports on negotiations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report in the event of inadequate progress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If, during the renegotiations of the Agreement, the President at any time determines that the renegotiations are not progressing satisfactorily and are not likely to result, within twelve months of the commencement thereof, in an expansion of the Agreement to cover purchases by the entities of the governments of developed countries which are the principal purchasers of goods and equipment in appropriate product sectors, he shall so report to the congressional committees referred to in <ref>section 2512(c)(1) of this title</ref>. Taking into account the objectives set forth in subsections (a) and (b) of this section and the factors required to be analyzed under <ref>section 2512(c) of this title</ref>, the President shall further report to such committees appropriate actions to seek reciprocity in such product sectors with such countries in the area of government procurement.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Legislative recommendations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Taking into account the factors required to be analyzed under <ref>section 2512(c) of this title</ref>, the President may recommend to the Congress legislation (with respect to entities of the Government which are not covered by the Agreement) which may prohibit such entities from purchasing products of such countries.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Each annual report of the President under section 163(a) of the Trade Act of 1974 [<ref>19 U.S.C. 2213(a)</ref>] made after <date date="1979-07-26">July 26, 1979</date> shall report the actions, if any, the President deemed appropriate to establish reciprocity in appropriate product sectors with major industrial countries in the area of government procurement.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Extension of nondiscrimination and national treatment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Before exercising the waiver authority in <ref>section 2511 of this title</ref> for procurement not covered by the Agreement on the date it enters into force with respect to the United States, the President shall follow the consultation provisions of section 135 [<ref>19 U.S.C. 2155</ref>] and chapter 6 of title I of the Trade Act of 1974 [<ref>19 U.S.C. 2211</ref> et seq.] for private sector and congressional consultations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–39, title III, § 304</ref>, <date date="1979-07-26">July 26, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 238</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–465, title III, § 342(b)</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4953</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–295, § 20(c)(11)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3528</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2515.</num>
<heading> Monitoring and enforcement</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Monitoring and enforcement structure recommendations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the preparation of the recommendations for the reorganization of trade functions, the President shall ensure that careful consideration is given to monitoring and enforcing the requirements of the Agreement and this subchapter, with particular regard to the tendering procedures required by the Agreement or otherwise agreed to by a country or instrumentality likely to be designated pursuant to <ref>section 2511(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rules of origin</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Advisory rulings and final determinations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For the purposes of this subchapter, the Secretary of the Treasury shall provide for the prompt issuance of advisory rulings and final determinations on whether, under <ref>section 2518(4)(B) of this title</ref>, an article is or would be a product of a foreign country or instrumentality designated pursuant to <ref>section 2511(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Penalties for fraudulent conduct</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In addition to any other provisions of law which may be applicable, <ref>section 1001 of title 18</ref> shall apply to fraudulent conduct with respect to the origin of products for purposes of qualifying for a waiver under <ref>section 2511 of this title</ref> or avoiding a prohibition under <ref>section 2512 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report to Congress on rules of origin</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Domestic administrative practices</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">As soon as practicable after the close of the two-year period beginning on the date on which any waiver under <ref>section 2511(a) of this title</ref> first takes effect, the President shall prepare and transmit to Congress a report containing an evaluation of administrative practices under any provision of law which requires determinations to be made of the country of origin of goods, products, commodities, or other articles of commerce. Such evaluation shall be accompanied by the President’s recommendations for legislative and executive measures required to improve and simplify and to make more uniform and consistent such practices. Such evaluation and recommendations shall take into account the special problems affecting insular possessions of the United States with respect to such practices.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Foreign administrative practices</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The report required under paragraph (1) shall contain an evaluation of the administrative practices under the laws of each major industrial country which require determinations to be made of the country of origin of goods, products, commodities, or other articles of commerce, including an assessment of such practices on the exports of the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–39, title III, § 305</ref>, <date date="1979-07-26">July 26, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 239</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title VII, § 7003</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1548</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–465, title III</ref>, §§ 341, 342(c), 343(c), <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4951</ref>, 4953, 4955; <ref>Pub. L. 104–295, § 20(c)(10)</ref>, (13), <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3528</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2516.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 103–355, title VII, § 7206(c)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3382</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–465, title III, § 342(d)</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4953</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2517.</num>
<heading> Availability of information to Members of Congress designated as official advisers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The United States Trade Representative shall make available to the Members of Congress designated as official advisers pursuant to <ref>section 2211 of this title</ref> information compiled by the Committee on Government Procurement under article XIX(5) of the Agreement.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–39, title III, § 307</ref>, <date date="1979-07-26">July 26, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 240</ref>; 1979 Reorg. Plan No. 3, § 1(b)(1), eff. <date date="1980-01-02">Jan. 2, 1980</date>, 44 F.R. 69273, <ref>93 Stat. 1381</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–465, title III, § 342(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4953</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2518.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this subchapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agreement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Agreement” means the Agreement on Government Procurement referred to in <ref>section 3511(d)(17) of this title</ref>, as submitted to the Congress, but including rectifications, modifications, and amendments which are accepted by the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Civil aircraft</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “civil aircraft and related articles” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> all aircraft other than aircraft to be purchased for use by the Department of Defense or the United States Coast Guard;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the engines (and parts and components for incorporation therein) of such aircraft;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any other parts, components, and subassemblies for incorporation in such aircraft; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> any ground flight simulators, and parts and components thereof, for use with respect to such aircraft,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">whether to be purchased for use as original or replacement equipment in the manufacture, repair, maintenance, rebuilding, modification, or conversion of such aircraft, and without regard to whether such aircraft or articles receive duty-free treatment pursuant to section 601(a)(2).</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Developed countries</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “developed countries” means countries so designated by the President.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible product</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “eligible product” means, with respect to any foreign country or instrumentality that is—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a party to the Agreement, a product or service of that country or instrumentality which is covered under the Agreement for procurement by the United States;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Mexico, as a party to the USMCA (as defined in <ref>section 4502 of this title</ref>), a product or service of that country or instrumentality which is covered under the USMCA for procurement by the United States;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a party to a free trade agreement that entered into force with respect to the United States after <date date="2003-12-31">December 31, 2003</date>, and before <date date="2005-01-02">January 2, 2005</date>, a product or service of that country or instrumentality which is covered under the free trade agreement for procurement by the United States;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> a party to the Dominican Republic-Central America-United States Free Trade Agreement, a product or service of that country or instrumentality which is covered under that Agreement for procurement by the United States;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> a party to a free trade agreement that entered into force with respect to the United States after <date date="2005-12-31">December 31, 2005</date>, and before <date date="2006-07-02">July 2, 2006</date>, a product or service of that country or instrumentality which is covered under the free trade agreement for procurement by the United States;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> a party to the United States-Oman Free Trade Agreement, a product or service of that country or instrumentality which is covered under that Agreement for procurement by the United States;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> a party to the United States-Peru Trade Promotion Agreement, a product or service of that country or instrumentality which is covered under that agreement for procurement by the United States;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> a party to the United States–Korea Free Trade Agreement, a product or service of that country or instrumentality which is covered under that agreement for procurement by the United States;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ix)</num>
<content> a party to the United States–Colombia Trade Promotion Agreement, a product or service of that country or instrumentality which is covered under that agreement for procurement by the United States; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(x)</num>
<content> a party to the United States–Panama Trade Promotion Agreement, a product or service of that country or instrumentality which is covered under that agreement for procurement by the United States.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rule of origin</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">An article is a product of a country or instrumentality only if (i) it is wholly the growth, product, or manufacture of that country or instrumentality, or (ii) in the case of an article which consists in whole or in part of materials from another country or instrumentality, it has been substantially transformed into a new and different article of commerce with a name, character, or use distinct from that of the article or articles from which it was so transformed.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Lowered threshold for certain products as a consequence of United States-Israel free trade area provisions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “eligible product” includes a product or service of Israel for which the United States is obligated to waive Buy National restrictions under—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Agreement on the Establishment of a Free Trade Area between the Government of the United States of America and the Government of Israel, regardless of the thresholds provided for in the Agreement (as defined in paragraph (1)), or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any subsequent agreement between the United States and Israel which lowers on a reciprocal basis the applicable threshold for entities covered by the Agreement.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Lowered threshold for certain products as a consequence of United States-Canada Free-Trade Agreement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Except as otherwise agreed by the United States and Canada under paragraph 3 of article 1304 of the United States-Canada Free-Trade Agreement, the term “eligible product” includes a product or service of Canada having a contract value of $25,000 or more that would be covered for procurement by the United States under the Agreement (as defined in paragraph (1)), but for the thresholds provided for in the Agreement.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Instrumentality</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “instrumentality” shall not be construed to include an agency or division of the government of a country, but may be construed to include such arrangements as the European Economic Community.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Least developed country</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “least developed country” means any country on the United Nations General Assembly list of least developed countries.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Major industrial country</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “major industrial country” means any such country as defined in <ref>section 2136 of this title</ref> and any instrumentality of such a country.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–39, title III, § 308</ref>, <date date="1979-07-26">July 26, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 241</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–47, § 7</ref>, <date date="1985-06-11">June 11, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 84</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–449, title III, § 306</ref>, <date date="1988-09-28">Sept. 28, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1876</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–182, title III, § 381(c)</ref>, <date date="1993-12-08">Dec. 8, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 2129</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–465, title III, § 342(f)</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4953</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–295, § 20(c)(12)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3528</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–286, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="2004-08-03">Aug. 3, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 950</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–53, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="2005-08-02">Aug. 2, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 495</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–169, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="2006-01-11">Jan. 11, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3599</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–283, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="2006-09-26">Sept. 26, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1209</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–138, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="2007-12-14">Dec. 14, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 1486</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–41, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="2011-10-21">Oct. 21, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 459</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–42, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="2011-10-21">Oct. 21, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 494</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–43, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="2011-10-21">Oct. 21, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 529</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–113, title V, § 505(b)</ref>, <date date="2020-01-29">Jan. 29, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 77</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>TECHNICAL BARRIERS TO TRADE (STANDARDS)</heading>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part A—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Obligations of the United States</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2531.</num>
<heading> Certain standards-related activities</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> No bar to engaging in standards activity</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Nothing in this subchapter may be construed—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to prohibit a Federal agency from engaging in activity related to standards-related measures, including any such measure relating to safety, the protection of human, animal, or plant life or health, the environment, or consumers; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to limit the authority of a Federal agency to determine the level it considers appropriate of safety or of protection of human, animal, or plant life or health, the environment, or consumers.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Unnecessary obstacles</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this subchapter may be construed as prohibiting any private person, Federal agency, or State agency from engaging in standards-related activities that do not create unnecessary obstacles to the foreign commerce of the United States. No standards-related activity of any private person, Federal agency, or State agency shall be deemed to constitute an unnecessary obstacle to the foreign commerce of the United States if the demonstrable purpose of the standards-related activity is to achieve a legitimate domestic objective including, but not limited to, the protection of legitimate health or safety, essential security, environmental, or consumer interests and if such activity does not operate to exclude imported products which fully meet the objectives of such activity.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–39, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="1979-07-26">July 26, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 242</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–465, title III, § 351(b)</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4955</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2532.</num>
<heading> Federal standards-related activities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">No Federal agency may engage in any standards-related activity that creates unnecessary obstacles to the foreign commerce of the United States, including, but not limited to, standards-related activities that violate any of the following requirements:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nondiscriminatory treatment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Each Federal agency shall ensure, in applying standards-related activities with respect to any imported product, that such product is treated no less favorably than are like domestic or imported products, including, but not limited to, when applying tests or test methods, no less favorable treatment with respect to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the acceptance of the product for testing in comparable situations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the administration of the tests in comparable situations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the fees charged for tests;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the release of test results to the exporter, importer, or agents;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the siting of testing facilities and the selection of samples for testing; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the treatment of confidential information pertaining to the product.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of international standards</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Except as provided in subparagraph (B)(ii), each Federal agency, in developing standards, shall take into consideration international standards and shall, if appropriate, base the standards on international standards.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application of requirement</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">For purposes of this paragraph, the following apply:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> International standards not appropriate</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">The reasons for which the basing of a standard on an international standard may not be appropriate include, but are not limited to, the following:</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> National security requirements.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> The prevention of deceptive practices.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> The protection of human health or safety, animal or plant life or health, or the environment.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> Fundamental climatic or other geographical factors.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(V)</num>
<content> Fundamental technological problems.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regional standards</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">In developing standards, a Federal agency may, but is not required to, take into consideration any international standard promulgated by an international standards organization the membership of which is described in section 2571(6)(A)(ii) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002135">1</ref> of this title.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Performance criteria</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Each Federal agency shall, if appropriate, develop standards based on performance criteria, such as those relating to the intended use of a product and the level of performance that the product must achieve under defined conditions, rather than on design criteria, such as those relating to the physical form of the product or the types of material of which the product is made.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Access for foreign suppliers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Each Federal agency shall, with respect to any conformity assessment procedure used by it, permit access for obtaining an assessment of conformity and the mark of the system, if any, to foreign suppliers of a product on the same basis as access is permitted to suppliers of like products, whether of domestic or other foreign origin.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–39, title IV, § 402</ref>, <date date="1979-07-26">July 26, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 242</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–465, title III, § 351(c)</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4956</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–295, § 20(c)(14)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3529</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2533.</num>
<heading> State and private standards-related activities</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is the sense of the Congress that no State agency and no private person should engage in any standards-related activity that creates unnecessary obstacles to the foreign commerce of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Presidential action</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall take such reasonable measures as may be available to promote the observance by State agencies and private persons, in carrying out standards-related activities, of requirements equivalent to those imposed on Federal agencies under <ref>section 2532 of this title</ref>, and of procedures that provide for notification, participation, and publication with respect to such activities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–39, title IV, § 403</ref>, <date date="1979-07-26">July 26, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 243</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part B—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Functions of Federal Agencies</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2541.</num>
<heading> Functions of Trade Representative</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Trade Representative shall coordinate the consideration of international trade policy issues that arise as a result of, and shall develop international trade policy as it relates to, the implementation of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Negotiating functions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Trade Representative has responsibility for coordinating United States discussions and negotiations with foreign countries for the purpose of establishing mutual arrangements with respect to standards-related activities. In carrying out this responsibility, the Trade Representative shall inform and consult with any Federal agency having expertise in the matters under discussion and negotiation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cross reference</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2 fontsize7">For provisions of law regarding general authority of the Trade Representative with respect to trade agreements, see <ref>section 2171 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–39, title IV, § 411</ref>, <date date="1979-07-26">July 26, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 243</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–182, title III, § 351(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1993-12-08">Dec. 8, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 2122</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–295, § 21(b)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3529</ref>, 3530.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2542.</num>
<heading> Establishment and operation of technical offices</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> For nonagricultural products</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary of Commerce shall establish and maintain within the Department of Commerce a technical office that shall carry out the functions prescribed under subsection (b) with respect to nonagricultural products.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> For agricultural products</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary of Agriculture shall establish and maintain within the Department of Agriculture a technical office that shall carry out the functions prescribed under subsection (b) with respect to agricultural products.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Functions of offices</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall prescribe for each technical office established under subsection (a) such functions as the President deems necessary or appropriate to implement this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–39, title IV, § 412</ref>, <date date="1979-07-26">July 26, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 244</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2543.</num>
<heading> Representation of United States interests before international standards organizations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Oversight and consultation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary concerned shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> inform, and consult and coordinate with, the Trade Representative with respect to international standards-related activities identified under paragraph (2);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> keep adequately informed regarding international standards-related activities and identify those that may substantially affect the commerce of the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> carry out such functions as are required under subsections (b) and (c).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Representation of United States interests by private persons</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Organization member</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “organization member” means the private person who holds membership in a private international standards organization.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Private international standards organization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “private international standards organization” means any international standards organization before which the interests of the United States are represented by a private person who is officially recognized by that organization for such purpose.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as otherwise provided for in this subsection, the representation of United States interests before any private international standards organization shall be carried out by the organization member.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inadequate representation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the Secretary concerned, after inquiry instituted on his own motion or at the request of any private person, Federal agency, or State agency having an interest therein, has reason to believe that the participation by the organization member in the proceedings of a private international standards organization will not result in the adequate representation of United States interests that are, or may be, affected by the activities of such organization (particularly with regard to the potential impact of any such activity on the international trade of the United States), the Secretary concerned shall immediately notify the organization member concerned. During any such inquiry, the Secretary concerned may solicit and consider the advice of the appropriate representatives referred to in <ref>section 2547 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Action by organization member</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If within the 90-day period after the date on which notification is received under paragraph (3) (or such shorter period as the Secretary concerned determines to be necessary in extraordinary circumstances), the organization member demonstrates to the Secretary concerned its willingness and ability to represent adequately United States interests before the private international standards organization, the Secretary concerned shall take no further action under this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Action by Secretary concerned</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">If—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> within the appropriate period referred to in paragraph (4), the organization member does not respond to the Secretary concerned with respect to the notification, or does respond but does not demonstrate to the Secretary concerned the requisite willingness and ability to represent adequately United States interests; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> there is no organization member of the private international standards organization;</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">the Secretary concerned shall make appropriate arrangements to provide for the adequate representation of United States interests. In cases where subparagraph (A) applies, such provision shall be made by the Secretary concerned through the appropriate organization member if the private international standards organization involved requires representation by that member.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Representation of United States interests by Federal agencies</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">With respect to any international standards organization before which the interests of the United States are represented by one or more Federal agencies that are officially recognized by that organization for such purpose, the Secretary concerned shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> encourage cooperation among interested Federal agencies with a view toward facilitating the development of a uniform position with respect to the technical activities with which the organization is concerned;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> encourage such Federal agencies to seek information from, and to cooperate with, the affected domestic interests when undertaking such representation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> not preempt the responsibilities of any Federal agency that has jurisdiction with respect to the activities undertaken by such organization, unless requested to do so by such agency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–39, title IV, § 413</ref>, <date date="1979-07-26">July 26, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 244</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–182, title III, § 351(b)(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="1993-12-08">Dec. 8, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 2122</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–295, § 21(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3529</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2544.</num>
<heading> Standards information center</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Commerce shall maintain within the Department of Commerce a standards information center.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Functions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The standards information center shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> serve as the central national collection facility for information relating to (A) standards, technical regulations, conformity assessment procedures, and standards-related activities, whether such standards, technical regulations, conformity assessment procedures, or activities are public or private, domestic or foreign, or international, regional, national, or local and (B) the membership and participation of Federal, State, or local government bodies or private bodies in the United States in international and regional standardizing bodies and conformity assessment systems, as well as in bilateral and multilateral arrangements concerning standards-related activities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> make available to the public at such reasonable fee as the Secretary shall prescribe, copies of information required to be collected under paragraph (1) other than information to which paragraph (3) applies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> use its best efforts to make available to the public, at such reasonable fees as the Secretary shall prescribe, copies of information required to be collected under paragraph (1) that is of private origin, on a cooperative basis with the private individual or entity, foreign or domestic, who holds the copyright on the information;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> in case of such information that is of foreign origin, provide, at such reasonable fee as the Secretary shall prescribe, such translation services as may be necessary;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> serve as the inquiry point for requests for information regarding standards-related activities, whether adopted or proposed, within the United States, except that in carrying out this paragraph, the Secretary of Commerce shall refer all inquiries regarding agricultural products to the technical office established under <ref>section 2542(a)(2) of this title</ref> within the Department of Agriculture; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> provide such other services as may be appropriate, including but not limited to, such services to the technical offices established under <ref>section 2542 of this title</ref> as may be requested by those offices in carrying out their functions.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sanitary and phytosanitary measures</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public information</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The standards information center shall, in addition to the functions specified under subsection (b), make available to the public relevant documents, at such reasonable fees as the Secretary of Commerce may prescribe, and information regarding—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any sanitary or phytosanitary measure of general application, including any inspection procedure or approval procedure proposed, adopted, or maintained by a Federal agency or agency of a State or local government;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the procedures of a Federal agency or an agency of a State or local government for risk assessment and factors the agency considers in conducting the assessment;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the determination of the levels of protection that a Federal agency or an agency of a State or local government considers appropriate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the membership and participation of the Federal Government and State and local governments in international and regional sanitary and phytosanitary organizations and systems, and in bilateral and multilateral arrangements regarding sanitary and phytosanitary measures, and the provisions of those systems and arrangements.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The definitions in <ref>section 2575b of this title</ref> apply for purposes of this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–39, title IV, § 414</ref>, <date date="1979-07-26">July 26, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 245</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–465, title III, § 351(d)</ref>, title IV, § 431(a), <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4956</ref>, 4966; <ref>Pub. L. 104–295, § 20(c)(15)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3529</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2545.</num>
<heading> Contracts and grants</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of carrying out this subchapter, and otherwise encouraging compliance with the Agreement, the Trade Representative and the Secretary concerned may each, with respect to functions for which responsible under this subchapter, make grants to, or enter into contracts with, any other Federal agency, any State agency, or any private person, to assist such agency or person to implement appropriate programs and activities, including, but not limited to, programs and activities—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to increase awareness of proposed and adopted standards-related activities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to facilitate international trade through the appropriate international and domestic standards-related activities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to provide, if appropriate, and pursuant to <ref>section 2543 of this title</ref>, adequate United States representation in international standards-related activities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to encourage United States exports through increased awareness of foreign standards-related activities that may affect United States exports.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">No contract entered into under this section shall be effective except to such extent, and in such amount, as is provided in advance in appropriation Acts.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Terms and conditions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any contract entered into, or any grant made, under subsection (a) shall be subject to such terms and conditions as the Trade Representative or Secretary concerned shall by regulation prescribe as being necessary or appropriate to protect the interests of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Financial assistance extended under this section shall not exceed 75 percent of the total costs (as established by the Trade Representative or Secretary concerned, as the case may be) of the program or activity for which assistance is made available. The non-Federal share of such costs shall be made in cash or kind, consistent with the maintenance of the program or activity concerned.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Audit</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each recipient of a grant or contract under this section shall make available to the Trade Representative or the Secretary concerned, as the case may be, and to the Comptroller General of the United States, for purposes of audit and examination, any book, document, paper, and record that is pertinent to the funds received under such grant or contract.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–39, title IV, § 415</ref>, <date date="1979-07-26">July 26, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 246</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–182, title III, § 351(b)(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="1993-12-08">Dec. 8, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 2122</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–295, § 21(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3529</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2546.</num>
<heading> Technical assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Trade Representative and the Secretary concerned may each, with respect to functions for which responsible under this subchapter, make available, on a reimbursable basis or otherwise, to any other Federal agency, State agency, or private person such assistance, including, but not limited to, employees, services, and facilities, as may be appropriate to assist such agency or person in carrying out standards-related activities in a manner consistent with this subchapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–39, title IV, § 416</ref>, <date date="1979-07-26">July 26, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 247</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–182, title III, § 351(b)(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="1993-12-08">Dec. 8, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 2122</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–295, § 21(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3529</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2547.</num>
<heading> Consultations with representatives of domestic interests</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In carrying out the functions for which responsible under this subchapter, the Trade Representative and the Secretary concerned shall solicit technical and policy advice from the committees, established under <ref>section 2155 of this title</ref>, that represent the interests concerned, and may solicit advice from appropriate State agencies and private persons.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–39, title IV, § 417</ref>, <date date="1979-07-26">July 26, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 247</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–182, title III, § 351(b)(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="1993-12-08">Dec. 8, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 2122</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–295, § 21(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3529</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part C—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Administrative and Judicial Proceedings Regarding Standards-Related Activities</heading>
<subpart>
<num class="small-caps">subpart 1—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">representations alleging united states violations of obligations</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2551.</num>
<heading> Right of action</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as provided under this subpart, the provisions of this part do not create any right of action under the laws of the United States with respect to allegations that any standards-related activity engaged in within the United States violates the obligations of the United States under the Agreement.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–39, title IV, § 421</ref>, <date date="1979-07-26">July 26, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 247</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2552.</num>
<heading> Representations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Any—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Party to the Agreement; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> foreign country that is not a Party to the Agreement but is found by the Trade Representative to extend rights and privileges to the United States that are substantially the same as those that would be so extended if that foreign country were a Party to the Agreement;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">may make a representation to the Trade Representative alleging that a standards-related activity engaged in within the United States violates the obligations of the United States under the Agreement. Any such representation must be made in accordance with procedures that the Trade Representative shall by regulation prescribe and must provide a reasonable indication that the standards-related activity concerned is having a significant trade effect. No person other than a Party to the Agreement or a foreign country described in paragraph (2) may make such a representation.</continuation>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–39, title IV, § 422</ref>, <date date="1979-07-26">July 26, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 247</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–182, title III, § 351(b)(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="1993-12-08">Dec. 8, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 2122</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–295, § 21(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3529</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2553.</num>
<heading> Action after receipt of representations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Upon receipt of any representation made under <ref>section 2552 of this title</ref>, the Trade Representative shall review the issues concerned in consultation with—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the agency or person alleged to be engaging in violations under the Agreement;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the member agencies of the interagency trade organization established under <ref>section 1872(a) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> other appropriate Federal agencies; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> appropriate representatives referred to in <ref>section 2547 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Resolution</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Trade Representative shall undertake to resolve, on a mutually satisfactory basis, the issues set forth in the representation through consultation with the parties concerned.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–39, title IV, § 423</ref>, <date date="1979-07-26">July 26, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 247</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–182, title III, § 351(b)(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="1993-12-08">Dec. 8, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 2122</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–295, § 21(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3529</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2554.</num>
<heading> Procedure after finding by international forum</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If an appropriate international forum finds that a standards-related activity being engaged in within the United States conflicts with the obligations of the United States under the Agreement, the interagency trade organization established under <ref>section 1872(a) of this title</ref> shall review the finding and the matters related thereto with a view to recommending appropriate action.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cross reference</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2 fontsize7">For provisions of law regarding remedies available to domestic persons alleging that standards activities engaged in by Parties to the Agreement (other than the United States) violate the obligations of the Agreement, see <ref>section 2411 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–39, title IV, § 424</ref>, <date date="1979-07-26">July 26, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 248</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subpart>
<subpart>
<num class="small-caps">subpart 2—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">other proceedings regarding certain standards-related activities</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2561.</num>
<heading> Findings of reciprocity required in administrative proceedings</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except as provided under subpart 1, no Federal agency may consider a complaint or petition against any standards-related activity regarding an imported product, if that activity is engaged in within the United States and is covered by the Agreement, unless the Trade Representative finds, and informs the agency concerned in writing, that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the country of origin of the imported product is a Party to the Agreement or a foreign country described in <ref>section 2552(2) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the dispute settlement procedures provided under the Agreement are not appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exemptions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">This section does not apply with respect to causes of action arising under—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the antitrust laws as defined in <ref>section 12(a) of title 15</ref>; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> statutes administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">This section does not apply with respect to petitions and proceedings that are provided for under the practices of any Federal agency for the purpose of ensuring, in accordance with <ref>section 553 of title 5</ref>, that interested persons are given an opportunity to participate in agency rulemaking or to seek the issuance, amendment, or repeal of a rule.</continuation>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–39, title IV, § 441</ref>, <date date="1979-07-26">July 26, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 248</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–182, title III, § 351(b)(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="1993-12-08">Dec. 8, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 2122</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–295, § 21(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3529</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2562.</num>
<heading> Consideration of standards-related activities by an international forum</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No standards-related activity being engaged in within the United States may be stayed in any judicial or administrative proceeding on the basis that such activity is currently being considered, pursuant to the Agreement, by an international forum.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–39, title IV, § 442</ref>, <date date="1979-07-26">July 26, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 248</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subpart>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part D—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Definitions and Miscellaneous Provisions</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2571.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this subchapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agreement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Agreement” means the Agreement on Technical Barriers to Trade referred to in <ref>section 3511(d)(5) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conformity assessment procedure</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “conformity assessment procedure” means any procedure used, directly or indirectly, to determine that relevant requirements in technical regulations or standards are fulfilled.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal agency</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “Federal agency” means any of the following within the meaning of chapter 2 of part I of title 5:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Any executive department.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Any military department.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Any Government corporation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Any Government-controlled corporation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Any independent establishment.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> International conformity assessment procedure</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “international conformity assessment procedure” means a conformity assessment procedure that is adopted by an international standards organization.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> International standard</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “international standard” means any standard that is promulgated by an international standards organization.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> International standards organization</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “international standards organization” means any organization—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the membership of which is open to representatives, whether public or private, of the United States and at least all Members; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> that is engaged in international standards-related activities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> International standards-related activity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “international standards-related activity” means the negotiation, development, or promulgation of, or any amendment or change to, an international standard, or an international conformity assessment procedure, or both.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Member</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Member” means a WTO member as defined in <ref>section 3501(10) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Private person</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “private person” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any individual who is a citizen or national of the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any corporation, partnership, association, or other legal entity organized or existing under the law of any State, whether for profit or not for profit.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(10)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Product</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “product” means any natural or manufactured item.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(11)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary concerned</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Secretary concerned” means the Secretary of Commerce with respect to functions under this subchapter relating to non­agricultural products, and the Secretary of Agriculture with respect to functions under this subchapter relating to agricultural products.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(12)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Trade Representative</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Trade Representative” means the United States Trade Representative.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(13)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Standard</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “standard” means a document approved by a recognized body, that provides, for common and repeated use, rules, guidelines, or characteristics for products or related processes and production methods, with which compliance is not mandatory. Such term may also include or deal exclusively with terminology, symbols, packaging, marking, or labeling requirements as they apply to a product, process, or production method.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(14)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Standards-related activity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “standards-related activity” means the development, adoption, or application of any standard, technical regulation, or conformity assessment procedure.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(15)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “State” means any of the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, American Samoa, Guam and any other Commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(16)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State agency</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “State agency” means any department, agency, or other instrumentality of the government of any State or of any political subdivision of any State.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(17)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Technical regulation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “technical regulation” means a document which lays down product characteristics or their related processes and production methods, including the applicable administrative provisions, with which compliance is mandatory. Such term may also include or deal exclusively with terminology, symbols, packaging, marking, or labeling requirements as they apply to a product, process, or production method.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(18)</num>
<heading class="bold"> United States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “United States”, when used in a geographical context, means all States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–39, title IV, § 451</ref>, <date date="1979-07-26">July 26, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 249</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–182, title III, § 351(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1993-12-08">Dec. 8, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 2122</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–465, title III, § 351(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4956</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–295, § 20(c)(16)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3529</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2572.</num>
<heading> Exemptions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">This subchapter does not apply to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any standards activity engaged in by any Federal agency or State agency for the use (including, but not limited to, use with respect to research and development, production, or consumption) of that agency or the use of another such agency; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any standards activity engaged in by any private person solely for use in the production or consumption of products by that person.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–39, title IV, § 452</ref>, <date date="1979-07-26">July 26, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 250</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2573.</num>
<heading> Reports to Congress on operation of agreement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As soon as practicable after the close of the 3-year period beginning on the date on which this subchapter takes effect, and as soon as practicable after the close of each succeeding 3-year period through 2001, the Trade Representative shall prepare and submit to Congress a report containing an evaluation of the operation of the Agreement, both domestically and internationally, during the period.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–39, title IV, § 453</ref>, <date date="1979-07-26">July 26, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 250</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–182, title III, § 351(b)(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="1993-12-08">Dec. 8, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 2122</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–465, title III, § 351(f)</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4957</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–295, § 21(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3529</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part E—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Standards and Measures Under the North American Free Trade Agreement</heading>
<subpart>
<num class="small-caps">subpart 1—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">sanitary and phytosanitary measures</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2575.</num>
<heading> General</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Nothing in this subpart may be construed—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to prohibit a Federal agency or State agency from engaging in activity related to sanitary or phytosanitary measures to protect human, animal, or plant life or health; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to limit the authority of a Federal agency or State agency to determine the level of protection of human, animal, or plant life or health the agency considers appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–39, title IV, § 461</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 103–182, title III, § 351(a)</ref>, <date date="1993-12-08">Dec. 8, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 2118</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2575a.</num>
<heading> Inquiry point</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The standards information center maintained under <ref>section 2544 of this title</ref> shall, in addition to the functions specified therein, make available to the public relevant documents, at such reasonable fees as the Secretary of Commerce may prescribe, and information regarding—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any sanitary or phytosanitary measure of general application, including any control or inspection procedure or approval procedure proposed, adopted, or maintained by a Federal or State agency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the procedures of a Federal or State agency for risk assessment, and factors the agency considers in conducting the assessment and in establishing the levels of protection that the agency considers appropriate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the membership and participation of the Federal Government and State governments in international and regional sanitary and phytosanitary organizations and systems, and in bilateral and multilateral arrangements regarding sanitary and phytosanitary measures, and the provisions of those systems and arrangements; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the location of notices of the type required under article 719 of the NAFTA, or where the information contained in such notices can be obtained.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–39, title IV, § 462</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 103–182, title III, § 351(a)</ref>, <date date="1993-12-08">Dec. 8, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 2118</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2575b.</num>
<heading> Subpart definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Notwithstanding <ref>section 2571 of this title</ref>, for purposes of this subpart—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Animal</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “animal” includes fish, bees, and wild fauna.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Approval procedure</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “approval procedure” means any registration, notification, or other mandatory administrative procedure for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> approving the use of an additive for a stated purpose or under stated conditions, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> establishing a tolerance for a stated purpose or under stated conditions for a contaminant,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">in a food, beverage, or feedstuff prior to permitting the use of the additive or the marketing of a food, beverage, or feedstuff containing the additive or contaminant.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contaminant</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “contaminant” includes pesticide and veterinary drug residues and extraneous matter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Control or inspection procedure</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “control or inspection procedure” means any procedure used, directly or indirectly, to determine that a sanitary or phytosanitary measure is fulfilled, including sampling, testing, inspection, evaluation, verification, monitoring, auditing, assurance of conformity, accreditation, registration, certification, or other procedure involving the physical examination of a good, of the packaging of a good, or of the equipment or facilities directly related to production, marketing, or use of a good, but does not mean an approval procedure.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Plant</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “plant” includes wild flora.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Risk assessment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “risk assessment” means an evaluation of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the potential for the introduction, establishment or spread of a pest or disease and associated biological and economic consequences; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the potential for adverse effects on human or animal life or health arising from the presence of an additive, contaminant, toxin or disease-causing organism in a food, beverage, or feedstuff.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sanitary or phytosanitary measure</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “sanitary or phytosanitary measure” means a measure to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> protect animal or plant life or health in the United States from risks arising from the introduction, establishment, or spread of a pest or disease;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> protect human or animal life or health in the United States from risks arising from the presence of an additive, contaminant, toxin, or disease-causing organism in a food, beverage, or feedstuff;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> protect human life or health in the United States from risks arising from a disease-causing organism or pest carried by an animal or plant, or a product thereof; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> prevent or limit other damage in the United States arising from the introduction, establishment, or spread of a pest.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Form</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The form of a sanitary or phytosanitary measure includes—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> end product criteria;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a product-related processing or production method;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a testing, inspection, certification, or approval procedure;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> a relevant statistical method;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> a sampling procedure;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> a method of risk assessment;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> a packaging and labeling requirement directly related to food safety; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> a quarantine treatment, such as a relevant requirement associated with the transportation of animals or plants or with material necessary for their survival during transportation.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–39, title IV, § 463</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 103–182, title III, § 351(a)</ref>, <date date="1993-12-08">Dec. 8, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 2119</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subpart>
<subpart>
<num class="small-caps">subpart 2—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">standards-related measures</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2576.</num>
<heading> General</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> No bar to engaging in standards activity</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Nothing in this subpart shall be construed—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to prohibit a Federal agency from engaging in activity related to standards-related measures, including any such measure relating to safety, the protection of human, animal, or plant life or health, the environment or consumers; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to limit the authority of a Federal agency to determine the level it considers appropriate of safety or of protection of human, animal, or plant life or health, the environment or consumers.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exclusion</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">This subpart does not apply to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> technical specifications prepared by a Federal agency for production or consumption requirements of the agency; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> sanitary or phytosanitary measures under subpart 1.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–39, title IV, § 471</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 103–182, title III, § 351(a)</ref>, <date date="1993-12-08">Dec. 8, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 2120</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2576a.</num>
<heading> Inquiry point</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The standards information center maintained under <ref>section 2544 of this title</ref> shall, in addition to the functions specified therein, make available to the public relevant documents, at such reasonable fees as the Secretary of Commerce may prescribe, and information regarding—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the membership and participation of the Federal Government, State governments, and relevant nongovernmental bodies in the United States in international and regional standardizing bodies and conformity assessment systems, and in bilateral and multilateral arrangements regarding standards-related measures, and the provisions of those systems and arrangements;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the location of notices of the type required under article 909 of the NAFTA, or where the information contained in such notice can be obtained; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the Federal agency procedures for assessment of risk, and factors the agency considers in conducting the assessment and establishing the levels of protection that the agency considers appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–39, title IV, § 472</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 103–182, title III, § 351(a)</ref>, <date date="1993-12-08">Dec. 8, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 2120</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2576b.</num>
<heading> Subpart definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Notwithstanding <ref>section 2571 of this title</ref>, for purposes of this subpart—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Approval procedure</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “approval procedure” means any registration, notification, or other mandatory administrative procedure for granting permission for a good or service to be produced, marketed, or used for a stated purpose or under stated conditions.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conformity assessment procedure</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “conformity assessment procedure” means any procedure used, directly or indirectly, to determine that a technical regulation or standard is fulfilled, including sampling, testing, inspection, evaluation, verification, monitoring, auditing, assurance of conformity, accreditation, registration, or approval used for such a purpose, but does not mean an approval procedure.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Objective</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “objective” includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> safety,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> protection of human, animal, or plant life or health, the environment or consumers, including matters relating to quality and identifiability of goods or services, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> sustainable development,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">but does not include the protection of domestic production.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Service</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “service” means a land transportation service or a telecommunications service.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Standard</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “standard” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> characteristics for a good or a service,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> characteristics, rules, or guidelines for—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> processes or production methods relating to such good, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> operating methods relating to such service, and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> provisions specifying terminology, symbols, packaging, marking, or labelling for—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a good or its related process or production methods, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a service or its related operating methods,</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">for common and repeated use, including explanatory and other related provisions set out in a document approved by a standardizing body, with which compliance is not mandatory.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Standards-related measure</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “standards-related measure” means a standard, technical regulation, or conformity assessment procedure.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Technical regulation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “technical regulation” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> characteristics or their related processes and production methods for a good,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> characteristics for a service or its related operating methods, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> provisions specifying terminology, symbols, packaging, marking, or labelling for—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a good or its related process or production method, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a service or its related operating method,</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">set out in a document, including applicable administrative, explanatory, and other related provisions, with which compliance is mandatory.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Telecommunications service</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “telecommunications service” means a service provided by means of the transmission and reception of signals by any electromagnetic means, but does not mean the cable, broadcast, or other electromagnetic distribution of radio or television programming to the public generally.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–39, title IV, § 473</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 103–182, title III, § 351(a)</ref>, <date date="1993-12-08">Dec. 8, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 2120</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subpart>
<subpart>
<num class="small-caps">subpart 3—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">part definitions</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2577.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Notwithstanding <ref>section 2571 of this title</ref>, for purposes of this part—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> NAFTA</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “NAFTA” means the North American Free Trade Agreement.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “State” means any of the several States, the District of Columbia, and the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–39, title IV, § 481</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 103–182, title III, § 351(a)</ref>, <date date="1993-12-08">Dec. 8, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 2122</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subpart>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part F—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">International Standard-Setting Activities</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2578.</num>
<heading> Notice of United States participation in international standard-setting activities</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall designate an agency to be responsible for informing the public of the sanitary and phytosanitary standard-setting activities of each international standard-setting organization.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than June 1 of each year, the agency designated under subsection (a) with respect to each international standard-setting organization shall publish notice in the Federal Register of the information specified in subsection (c) with respect to that organization. The notice shall cover the period ending on June 1 of the year in which the notice is published, and beginning on the date of the preceding notice under this subsection, except that the first such notice shall cover the 1-year period ending on the date of the notice.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Required information</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The information to be provided in the notice under subsection (b) is—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the sanitary or phytosanitary standards under consideration or planned for consideration by that organization;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> for each sanitary or phytosanitary standard specified in paragraph (1)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a description of the consideration or planned consideration of the standard;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> whether the United States is participating or plans to participate in the consideration of the standard;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the agenda for the United States participation, if any; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the agency responsible for representing the United States with respect to the standard.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public comment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The agency specified in subsection (c)(2)(D) shall provide an opportunity for public comment with respect to the standards for which the agency is responsible and shall take the comments into account in participating in the consideration of the standards and in proposing matters to be considered by the organization.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–39, title IV, § 491</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 103–465, title IV, § 432</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4970</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2578a.</num>
<heading> Equivalence determinations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An agency may not determine that a sanitary or phytosanitary measure of a foreign country is equivalent to a sanitary or phytosanitary measure established under the authority of Federal law unless the agency determines that the sanitary or phytosanitary measure of the foreign country provides at least the same level of sanitary or phytosanitary protection as the comparable sanitary or phytosanitary measure established under the authority of Federal law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> FDA determination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the Commissioner proposes to issue a determination of the equivalency of a sanitary or phytosanitary measure of a foreign country to a measure that is required to be promulgated as a rule under the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<ref>21 U.S.C. 301</ref> et seq.) or other statute administered by the Food and Drug Administration, the Commissioner shall issue a proposed regulation to incorporate such determination and shall include in the notice of proposed rulemaking the basis for the determination that the sanitary or phytosanitary measure of a foreign country provides at least the same level of sanitary or phytosanitary protection as the comparable Federal sanitary or phytosanitary measure. The Commissioner shall provide opportunity for interested persons to comment on the proposed regulation. The Commissioner shall not issue a final regulation based on the proposal without taking into account the comments received.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the Commissioner proposes to issue a determination of the equivalency of a sanitary or phytosanitary measure of a foreign country to a sanitary or phytosanitary measure of the Food and Drug Administration that is not required to be promulgated as a rule under the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act [<ref>21 U.S.C. 301</ref> et seq.] or other statute administered by the Food and Drug Administration, the Commissioner shall publish a notice in the Federal Register that identifies the basis for the determination that the measure provides at least the same level of sanitary or phytosanitary protection as the comparable Federal sanitary or phytosanitary measure. The Commissioner shall provide opportunity for interested persons to comment on the notice. The Commissioner shall not issue a final determination on the issue of equivalency without taking into account the comments received.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–39, title IV, § 492</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 103–465, title IV, § 432</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4971</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–295, § 20(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3529</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2578b.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this part:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agency</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “agency” means a Federal department or agency (or combination of Federal departments or agencies).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Commissioner</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Commissioner” means the Commissioner of Food and Drugs.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> International standard-setting organization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “international standard-setting organization” means an organization consisting of representatives of 2 or more countries, the purpose of which is to negotiate, develop, promulgate, or amend an international standard.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sanitary or phytosanitary standard</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “sanitary or phytosanitary standard” means a standard intended to form a basis for a sanitary or phytosanitary measure.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> International standard</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “international standard” means a standard, guideline, or recommendation—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> regarding food safety, adopted by the Codex Alimentarius Commission, including a standard, guideline, or recommendation regarding decomposition elaborated by the Codex Committee on Fish and Fishery Products, food additives, contaminants, hygienic practice, and methods of analysis and sampling;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> regarding animal health and zoonoses, developed under the auspices of the International Office of Epizootics;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> regarding plant health, developed under the auspices of the Secretariat of the International Plant Protection Convention in cooperation with the North American Plant Protection Organization; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> established by or developed under any other international organization agreed to by the USMCA countries (as defined in <ref>section 4502 of this title</ref>) or by the WTO members (as defined in <ref>section 3501(10) of this title</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other definitions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The definitions set forth in <ref>section 2575b of this title</ref> apply for purposes of this part except that in applying paragraph (7) of <ref>section 2575b of this title</ref> with respect to a sanitary or phytosanitary measure of a foreign country, any reference in such paragraph to the United States shall be deemed to be a reference to that foreign country.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–39, title IV, § 493</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 103–465, title IV, § 432</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4972</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–260, div. O, title VI, § 602(f)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 2154</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2581.</num>
<heading> Auction of import licenses</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the President may sell import licenses at public auction under such terms and conditions as he deems appropriate. Regulations prescribed under this subsection shall, to the extent practicable and consistent with efficient and fair administration, insure against inequitable sharing of imports by a relatively small number of the larger importers.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> “Import license” defined</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the term “import license” means any documentation used to administer a quantitative restriction imposed or modified after <date date="1979-07-26">July 26, 1979</date> under—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> section 125, 203, 301, or 406 of the Trade Act of 1974 (<ref>19 U.S.C. 2135</ref>, 2253, 2411, or 2436),</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<ref>50 U.S.C. 1701–170</ref>6),</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> authority under the notes of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States, but not including any quantitative restriction imposed under section 22 of the Agricultural Adjustment Act of 1934 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 624</ref>),</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the Trading With the Enemy Act (50 U.S.C. App. 1–44),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002136">1</ref></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> section 204 of the Agricultural Act of 1956 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1854</ref>) other than for meat or meat products, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> any Act enacted explicitly for the purpose of implementing an international agreement to which the United States is a party, including such agreements relating to commodities, but not including any agreement relating to cheese or dairy products.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–39, title XI, § 1102</ref>, <date date="1979-07-26">July 26, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 307</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title I, § 1214(k)</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1158</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2582.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 98–67, title II, § 214(d)</ref>, <date date="1983-08-05">Aug. 5, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 393</ref></heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>