<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 16—</num>
<heading>WINE TRADE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2801.</num>
<heading> Congressional findings and purposes</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Congress finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> there is a substantial imbalance in international wine trade resulting, in part, from the relative accessibility enjoyed by foreign wines to the United States market while the United States wine industry faces restrictive tariff and nontariff barriers in virtually every existing or potential foreign market;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the restricted access to foreign markets and the continued low prices for United States wine and grape products adversely affect the economic position of our Nation’s winemakers and grape growers, as well as all other domestic sectors that depend upon wine production;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the competitive position of United States wine in international trade has been weakened by foreign trade practices, high domestic interest rates, and unfavorable foreign exchange rates;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> wine consumption per capita is very low in many major non-wine producing markets and the demand potential for United States wine is significant; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the United States winemaking industry has the capacity and the ability to export substantial volumes of wine and an increase in United States wine exports will create new jobs, improve this Nation’s balance of trade, and otherwise strengthen the national economy.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> The purposes of this chapter are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to provide wine consumers with the greatest possible choice of wines from wine-producing countries;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to encourage the initiation of an export promotion program to develop, maintain, and expand foreign markets for United States wine; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to achieve greater access to foreign markets for United States wine and grape products through the reduction or elimination of tariff barriers and nontariff barriers to (or other distortions of) trade in wine.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–573, title IX, § 902</ref>, <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 3047</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2802.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “Committees” means the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “grape product” means grapes and any product (other than wine) made from grapes, including, but not limited to, raisins and grape juice, whether or not concentrated.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “major wine trading country” means any foreign country, or group of foreign countries, designated as such under <ref>section 2803 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The phrase “nontariff barrier to (or other distortion of)”, in the context of trade in United States wine, includes any measure implemented by the government of a major wine trading country that either gives a competitive advantage to the wine industry of that country or restricts the importation of United States wine into that country.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The term “Trade Representative” means the United States Trade Representative.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The term “United States wine” means wine produced within the customs territory of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<chapeau> The term “wine” means any fermented alcoholic beverage that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is made from grapes or other fruit;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> contains not less than 0.5 percent alcohol by volume and not more than 24 percent alcohol by volume, including all dilutions and mixtures thereof by whatever process produced; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> is for nonindustrial use.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–573, title IX, § 903</ref>, <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 3048</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2803.</num>
<heading> Designation of major wine trading countries</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Trade Representative shall designate as a major wine trading country each foreign country, or group of foreign countries represented as an economic union, that, in the judgment of the Trade Representative—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> is a potential significant market for United States wine; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> maintains tariff barriers or nontariff barriers to (or other distortions of) trade in United States wine.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> In deciding, for purposes of subsection (a)(2), whether a foreign country or group of countries maintains nontariff barriers to (or other distortions of) trade in United States wine, the Trade Representative shall take into account—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the review and report required under section 854(a) of the Trade Agreements Act of 1979 (<ref>19 U.S.C. 2135</ref> note);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> such relevant actions that may have been taken by that country or group since that review was conducted; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> such information as may be submitted under <ref>section 2805 of this title</ref> by representatives of the wine and grape products industries in the United States, as well as other sources.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–573, title IX, § 904</ref>, <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 3048</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2804.</num>
<heading> Actions to reduce or eliminate tariff and nontariff barriers affecting United States wine</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultations with major wine trading countries</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall direct the Trade Representative to enter into consultations with each major wine trading country to seek a reduction or elimination of that country’s tariff barriers and nontariff barriers to (or other distortions of) trade in United States wine.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports to Congress on actions taken to expand export opportunities</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002147">1</ref> President shall notify each of the Committees regarding the extent and effect of the efforts undertaken since the submission of the report required under section 854(a) of the Trade Agreements Act of 1979 [<ref>19 U.S.C. 2135</ref> note], and during the 12-month period beginning on <date date="1984-10-30">October 30, 1984</date>, to expand opportunities in each major wine trading country for exports of United States wine. Such notification, which shall be in the form of a separate written report (that must be submitted within 30 days after the close of that 12-month period) for each major wine trading country, shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a description of each act, policy, and practice (and of its legal basis and operation) in that country that constitutes a tariff barrier or nontariff barrier to (or other distortion of) trade in United States wine (and that description shall be based upon an updating of the report that was submitted to the Congress under section 854(a) of the Trade Agreements Act of 1979);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an assessment of the extent to which each such act, policy, or practice is subject to international agreements to which the United States is a party;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> information with respect to any action taken, or proposed to be taken, under existing authority to eliminate or reduce each such act, policy, or practice, including, but not limited to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any action under the Trade Act of 1974 [<ref>19 U.S.C. 2101</ref> et seq.], and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any negotiation or consultation with any foreign government;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> if action referred to in subparagraph (C) was not taken, an explanation of the reasons therefore; <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002148">2</ref> and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> recommendations to the Congress of any additional legislative authority or other action which the President believes is necessary and appropriate to obtain the elimination or reduction of foreign tariff barriers or nontariff barriers to (or other distortions of) trade in United States wine.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The reports required under paragraph (1) shall be developed and coordinated by the Trade Representative through the interagency trade organization established by <ref>section 1872(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Enforcement of rights</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">If the President, after taking into account information and advice received under subsections (a) and (b), <ref>section 2805 of this title</ref> or from other sources, determines that action is appropriate to respond to any act, policy, or practice of a major wine trading country constitutes a tariff barrier or nontariff barrier to (or other distortion of) trade in United States wine and—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> is inconsistent with the provisions of, or otherwise denies benefits to the United States under, any trade agreement; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> is unjustifiable, unreasonable, or discriminatory and burdens or restricts United States commerce;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">the President, shall take all appropriate and feasible action under the Trade Act of 1974 [<ref>19 U.S.C. 2101</ref> et seq.] to enforce the rights of the United States under any such trade agreement or to obtain the elimination of such act, policy, or practice.</continuation>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–573, title IX, § 905</ref>, <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 3049</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2805.</num>
<heading> Required consultations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Trade Representative shall consult with the Committees and with representatives of the wine and grape products industries in the United States—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> before identifying tariff barriers and nontariff barriers to (or other distortions of) trade in United States wine and designating major wine trading countries under <ref>section 2803 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in developing the reports required under <ref>section 2804(b) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> for purposes of determining whether action by the President is appropriate under any provision of the Trade Act of 1974 [<ref>19 U.S.C. 2101</ref> et seq.] with respect to any act, policy, or practice referred to in <ref>section 2804(b)(1) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–573, title IX, § 906</ref>, <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 3050</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2806.</num>
<heading> United States wine export promotion</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In order to develop, maintain, and expand foreign markets for United States wine, the President is encouraged to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> utilize, for the fiscal year ending <date date="1985-09-30">September 30, 1985</date>, the authority provided under section 135 of the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1982 [<ref>7 U.S.C. 612c</ref> note] to make available sufficient funds to initiate, in cooperation with nongovernmental trade associations representative of United States wineries, an export promotion program for United States; <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002149">1</ref> and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> request, for each subsequent fiscal year, an appropriation for such a wine export promotion program that will not be at the expense of any appropriations requested for export promotion programs involving other agriculture commodities.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–573, title IX, § 907</ref>, <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 3050</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>