<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 6—</num>
<heading>TRADE FAIR PROGRAM</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1751.</num>
<heading> Designation of fairs</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice to Secretary of the Treasury</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">When the Secretary of Commerce is satisfied that the public interest in promoting trade will be served by allowance of the privileges provided for in this chapter to any fair to be held in the United States, he shall so advise the Secretary of the Treasury, designating (1) the name of the fair, (2) the place where the fair will be held, (3) the date when the fair will open and the date when it will close, and (4) the name of the operator of the fair.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “fair” means any fair, exhibition, or exposition designated by the Secretary of Commerce pursuant to this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “closing date” in the case of any fair means the date designated pursuant to subsection (a)(3) as the date when the fair will close, or (if earlier) the date on which such fair actually closes.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Commerce may prescribe such regulations as he deems necessary or appropriate to carry out the provisions of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 86–14, § 2</ref>, <date date="1959-04-22">Apr. 22, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 18</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1752.</num>
<heading> Entry of articles for fairs</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Any article imported or brought into the United States—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> which is in continuous customs custody, covered by a customs exhibition bond, or in a foreign trade zone, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> on which no duty or internal-revenue tax has been paid,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">may, without payment of any duty or internal-revenue tax, be entered under bond under this section for the purpose of exhibition at a fair, or for use in constructing, installing, or maintaining foreign exhibits at a fair.</continuation>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 86–14, § 3</ref>, <date date="1959-04-22">Apr. 22, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 18</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1753.</num>
<heading> Disposition of articles entered for fairs</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disposition upon payment of duties and taxes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">At any time before, or within 3 months after, the closing date of any fair, any article entered for such fair under <ref>section 1752 of this title</ref> may be sold or otherwise disposed of within, or may be removed from, the area of such fair. This subsection shall apply only if, before such disposition or removal—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the article, after the entry for such fair under <ref>section 1752 of this title</ref>, has been entered under any provision of the customs laws, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any applicable duties and internal-revenue taxes are paid on such article in its condition and quantity, and at the rate in effect, at the time of such entry as if such article were imported or brought into the United States at the time of such entry.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disposition without payment of duties or taxes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">At any time before, or within 3 months after, the closing date of any fair, any article entered for such fair under <ref>section 1752 of this title</ref> may, without the payment of any duties or internal-revenue taxes, be—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> exported,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> transferred from such fair to other customs custody status or to a foreign-trade zone,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> destroyed, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> abandoned to the Government.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Mandatory abandonment to Government</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If any article entered under <ref>section 1752 of this title</ref> is still in customs custody, under such entry, at the expiration of 3 months after the closing date of the fair for which it was entered, such article shall thereupon be regarded as an article abandoned to the Government and shall be subject to sale or destruction of the article and disposition of the proceeds of sale in the manner provided for in sections 1491, 1492, and 1493 of this title. For purposes of this subsection, any duties or internal-revenue taxes on the article shall be computed on the basis of its condition and quantity at the time it becomes subject to sale.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Period for performance of certain acts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever any article entered under <ref>section 1752 of this title</ref> is transferred pursuant to subsection (b)(2) or entered under subsection (a), the period prescribed for the performance of any act required by the provision governing the status to which the article is transferred, or under which the article is entered, shall run from the date of such transfer or entry.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 86–14, § 4</ref>, <date date="1959-04-22">Apr. 22, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 18</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1754.</num>
<heading> Marking, packaging, and labeling requirements</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Marking requirements of the customs laws</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Articles entered under <ref>section 1752 of this title</ref> shall not be subject to any marking requirements of the customs laws, except that when any such article is entered for consumption under <ref>section 1753 of this title</ref> it shall not be released from customs custody until the marking requirements of the customs laws have been complied with.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Packaging, marking, or labeling requirements of the internal-revenue laws or the Federal Alcohol Administration Act</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Articles entered under <ref>section 1752 of this title</ref> shall not be subject to the packaging, marking, or labeling requirements of the internal-revenue laws or of the Federal Alcohol Administration Act [<ref>27 U.S.C. 201</ref> et seq.], except that any such article failing to comply with such requirements—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall be conspicuously marked prior to exhibition “Not labeled or packaged as required by law—not for sale”, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> when entered for consumption under <ref>section 1753 of this title</ref>, shall not be released from customs custody until such packaging, marking, and labeling requirements have been complied with.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">The application of the permit requirements of the Federal Alcohol Administration Act and the occupational taxes prescribed by chapter 51 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 shall be determined without regard to this chapter.</continuation>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 86–14, § 5</ref>, <date date="1959-04-22">Apr. 22, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 19</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 2095</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1755.</num>
<heading> Responsibilities of fair operator</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sole consignee and importer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each fair operator designated by the Secretary of Commerce pursuant to <ref>section 1751 of this title</ref> shall be deemed the sole consignee and importer of all articles entered under <ref>section 1752 of this title</ref> for the fair for which such operator has been designated.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reimbursement of customs charges and expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The actual and necessary customs charges for labor, services, and other expenses in connection with the entry, examination, appraisement, custody, abandonment, destruction, or release of articles entered under <ref>section 1752 of this title</ref>, together with the necessary charges for salaries of customs officers and employees in connection with the accounting for, custody of, and supervision over, such articles, shall be reimbursed to the United States by the operator of the fair for which they are entered. Receipts from such reimbursements shall be deposited as refunds to the appropriation from which paid, in the manner provided for in <ref>section 1524 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 86–14, § 6</ref>, <date date="1959-04-22">Apr. 22, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 19</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1756.</num>
<heading> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Treasury may prescribe such regulations as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the provisions of this chapter (other than section 1751 thereof).</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 86–14, § 7</ref>, <date date="1959-04-22">Apr. 22, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 19</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>