<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 10—</num>
<heading>CUSTOMS SERVICE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2071.</num>
<heading> Establishment of Service; Commissioner; appointment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There shall be in the Department of the Treasury a service to be known as the United States Customs Service, and a Commissioner of Customs.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002071">1</ref> The Commissioner of Customs,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002071">1</ref> who shall be appointed by the President by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> be at the head of the United States Customs Service;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> carry out the duties and powers prescribed by the Secretary of the Treasury; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> report to the Secretary of the Treasury through such other officials as may be designated by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 3, 1927, ch. 348, § 1</ref>, <ref>44 Stat. 1381</ref>; <ref>May 27, 1930, ch. 342, § 8</ref>, <ref>46 Stat. 430</ref>; Ex. Ord. No. 6639, § 1a, <date date="1934-03-10">Mar. 10, 1934</date>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–207, § 3(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1989-12-07">Dec. 7, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1833</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–125, title VIII, § 802(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="2016-02-24">Feb. 24, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 210</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2072.</num>
<heading> Officers and employees</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment by Secretary of the Treasury</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Treasury is authorized to appoint, in the service established by <ref>section 2071 of this title</ref>, one assistant commissioner, three deputy commissioners, one chief clerk, and such attorneys and other officers and employees as he may deem necessary. One of the deputy commissioners of the United States Customs Service shall have charge of investigations. Appointments under this subsection shall be subject to the provisions of the civil service laws, and the salaries shall be fixed in accordance with chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Absence or disability of Commissioner</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Treasury is authorized to designate an officer of the United States Customs Service to act as Commissioner of Customs,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002072">1</ref> during the absence or disability of the Commissioner of Customs,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002072">1</ref> or in the event that there is no Commissioner of Customs.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002072">1</ref></p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties of personnel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The personnel of the United States Customs Service shall perform such duties as the Secretary of the Treasury may prescribe.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> International Trade Committee</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Commissioner shall establish an International Trade Committee, to be chaired by the Commissioner, and to include the Deputy Commissioner, the Assistant Commissioner in the Office of Field Operations, the Assistant Commissioner in the Office of Finance, the Assistant Commissioner in the Office of International Affairs, the Assistant Commissioner in the Office of International Trade, the Director of the Office of Trade Relations, and any other official determined by the Commissioner to be important to the work of the Committee.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Responsibilities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The International Trade Committee shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> be responsible for advising the Commissioner with respect to the commercial customs and trade facilitation functions of the United States Customs and Border Protection;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> assist the Commissioner in coordinating with the Secretary regarding commercial customs and trade facilitation functions; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> oversee the operation of all programs and systems that are involved in the assessment and collection of duties, bonds, and other charges or penalties associated with the entry of cargo into the United States, or the export of cargo from the United States, including the administration of duty drawback and the collection of antidumping and countervailing duties.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 30 days after the end of each fiscal year, the International Trade Committee shall submit a report to the Committee on Finance of the Senate and the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives. The report shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> detail the activities of the International Trade Committee during the preceding fiscal year; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> identify the priorities of the International Trade Committee for the fiscal year in which the report is filed.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Commissioner</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Commissioner” means the Commissioner responsible for the United States Customs and Border Protection in the Department of Homeland Security.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Commercial Operations Advisory Committee</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Commercial Operations Advisory Committee” means the Advisory Committee established pursuant to section 9503(c) of the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1987 (<ref>19 U.S.C. 2071</ref> note) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002073">2</ref> or any successor committee.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 3, 1927, ch. 348, § 2</ref>, <ref>44 Stat. 1381</ref>; <ref>May 27, 1930, ch. 342, § 8</ref>, <ref>46 Stat. 430</ref>; <ref>June 17, 1930, ch. 497</ref>, title IV, § 650, <ref>46 Stat. 762</ref>; Ex. Ord. No. 6639, § 1a, <date date="1934-03-10">Mar. 10, 1934</date>; <ref>Oct. 28, 1949, ch. 782</ref>, title XI, § 1106(a), <ref>63 Stat. 972</ref>; <ref>Sept. 3, 1954, ch. 1263, § 9</ref>, <ref>68 Stat. 1228</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–347, title IV, § 402</ref>, <date date="2006-10-13">Oct. 13, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1924</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–125, title VIII, § 802(d)(2)</ref>, (h)(3), <date date="2016-02-24">Feb. 24, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 210</ref>, 215.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2073.</num>
<heading> Transfer of personnel, etc., to Service</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Repealed. <ref>Sept. 3, 1954, ch. 1263, § 10</ref>, <ref>68 Stat. 1229</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The records, property (including office equipment), and personnel of the Division of Customs are transferred to the United States Customs Service.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 3, 1927, ch. 348, § 3</ref>, <ref>44 Stat. 1382</ref>; <ref>Sept. 3, 1954, ch. 1263, § 10</ref>, <ref>68 Stat. 1229</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2074.</num>
<heading> Establishment of revolving fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established a revolving fund of $300,000 which shall be available, without fiscal year limitation exclusively for transfer to the appropriation for collecting the revenue from customs to cover obligations of the United States Customs Service arising from authorized reimbursable services, pending reimbursement from parties in interest: <i>Provided,</i> That amounts so transferred shall be returned to the revolving fund not later than six months after the close of the fiscal year in which transferred.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 30, 1949, ch. 286</ref>, title I, <ref>63 Stat. 360</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2075.</num>
<heading> Appropriations authorization</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> For the fiscal year beginning <date date="1979-10-01">October 1, 1979</date>, and each fiscal year thereafter, there are authorized to be appropriated to the Department of the Treasury for the United States Customs Service only such sums as may hereafter be authorized by law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The authorization of the appropriations for the United States Customs Service for each fiscal year after fiscal year 1987 shall specify—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the amount authorized for the fiscal year for the salaries and expenses of the Service in conducting commercial operations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the amount authorized for the fiscal year for the salaries and expenses of the Service for other than commercial operations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> By not later than the date on which the President submits to Congress the budget of the United States Government for a fiscal year, the Commissioner of Customs <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002074">1</ref> shall submit to the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate the projected amount of funds for the succeeding fiscal year that will be necessary for the operations of the Customs Service as provided for in subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> For noncommercial operations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">There are authorized to be appropriated for the salaries and expenses of the Customs Service that are incurred in noncommercial operations not to exceed the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> $1,365,456,000 for fiscal year 2003.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> $1,399,592,400 for fiscal year 2004.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> For commercial operations</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> There are authorized to be appropriated for the salaries and expenses of the Customs Service that are incurred in commercial operations not less than the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> $1,642,602,000 for fiscal year 2003.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> $1,683,667,050 for fiscal year 2004.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The monies authorized to be appropriated under subparagraph (A) for any fiscal year, except for such sums as may be necessary for the salaries and expenses of the Customs Service that are incurred in connection with the processing of merchandise that is exempt from the fees imposed under section 58c(a)(9) and (10) of this title, shall be appropriated from the Customs User Fee Account.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> For air interdiction</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">There are authorized to be appropriated for the operation (including salaries and expenses) and maintenance of the air interdiction program of the Customs Service not to exceed the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> $170,829,000 for fiscal year 2003.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> $175,099,725 for fiscal year 2004.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Mandatory 10-day deferment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No part of any sum that is appropriated under the authority of subsection (b) may be used to implement any procedure relating to the time of collection of estimated duties that shortens the maximum 10-day deferment procedure in effect on <date date="1981-01-01">January 1, 1981</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Overtime pay limitations; waiver</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No part of any sum that is appropriated under subsection (b) for fiscal years after <date date="1984-09-30">September 30, 1984</date>, may be used for administrative expenses to pay any employee of the United States Customs Service overtime pay in an amount exceeding $25,000; except that the Commissioner of Customs <sup>1</sup> or his designee may waive this limitation in individual cases in order to prevent excessive costs or to meet emergency requirements of the Service.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Pay comparability authorization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the fiscal year beginning <date date="1982-10-01">October 1, 1982</date>, and for each fiscal year thereafter, there are authorized to be appropriated to the Department of the Treasury for salaries of the United States Customs Service such additional sums as may be provided by law to reflect pay rate changes made in accordance with the Federal Pay Comparability Act of 1970.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of savings resulting from administrative consolidations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If savings in salaries and expenses result from the consolidation of administrative functions within the Customs Service, the Commissioner of Customs <sup>1</sup> shall apply those savings, to the extent they are not needed to meet emergency requirements of the Service, to strengthening the commercial operations of the Service by increasing the number of inspector, import specialist, patrol officer, and other line operational positions.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Allocation of resources; notice to Congressional committees</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Commissioner of Customs <sup>1</sup> shall ensure that existing levels of commercial services, including inspection and control, classification, and value, shall continue to be provided by Customs personnel assigned to the headquarters office of any Customs district designated by statute before <date date="1986-04-07">April 7, 1986</date>. The number of such personnel assigned to any such district headquarters shall not be reduced through attrition or otherwise, and such personnel shall be afforded the opportunity to maintain their proficiency through training and workshops to the same extent provided to Customs personnel in any other district. Automation and other modernization equipment shall be made available, as needed on a timely basis, to such headquarters to the same extent as such equipment is made available to any other district headquarters.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Commissioner of Customs <sup>1</sup> shall notify the Committee on Finance of the Senate and the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives at least 180 days prior to taking any action which would—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> result in any significant reduction in force of employees other than by means of attrition;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> result in any significant reduction in hours of operation or services rendered at any office of the United States Customs Service or any port of entry;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> eliminate or relocate any office of the United States Customs Service;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> eliminate any port of entry; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> significantly reduce the number of employees assigned to any office of the United States Customs Service or any port of entry.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The total number of employees of the United States Customs Service shall be equivalent to at least 17,174 full-time employees.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Resource Allocation Model</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Resource Allocation Model</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than <date date="2007-06-30">June 30, 2007</date>, and every 2 years thereafter, the Commissioner shall prepare and submit to the Committee on Finance of the Senate and the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives a Resource Allocation Model to determine the optimal staffing levels required to carry out the commercial operations of United States Customs and Border Protection, including commercial inspection and release of cargo and the revenue functions described in <ref>section 212(b)(2) of title 6</ref>. The Model shall comply with the requirements of section 212(b)(1) of such title and shall take into account previous staffing models, historic and projected trade volumes, and trends. The Resource Allocation Model shall apply both risk-based and random sampling approaches for determining adequate staffing needs for priority trade functions, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> performing revenue functions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> enforcing antidumping and countervailing duty laws;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> protecting intellectual property rights;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> enforcing provisions of law relating to trade in textiles and apparel;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> conducting agricultural inspections;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> enforcing fines, penalties, and forfeitures; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> facilitating trade.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Personnel</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Not later than <date date="2007-09-30">September 30, 2007</date>, the Commissioner shall ensure that the requirements of <ref>section 212(b) of title 6</ref> are fully satisfied and shall report to the Committee on Finance of the Senate and the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives regarding the implementation of this subparagraph.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Customs and Border Protection Officers</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The initial Resource Allocation Model required pursuant to paragraph (1) shall provide for the hiring of a minimum of 200 additional Customs and Border Protection Officers per year for each of the fiscal years 2008 through 2012. The Commissioner shall hire such additional Officers subject to the appropriation of funds to pay for the salaries and expenses of such Officers. In assigning the 1,000 additional Officers authorized by this subparagraph, the Commissioner shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> consider the volume of trade and the incidence of nonvoluntarily disclosed customs and trade law violations in addition to security priorities among United States ports of entry; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> before <date date="2010-10-01">October 1, 2010</date>, assign at least 10 additional Officers among each service port and the ports of entry serviced by such service port, except as provided in subparagraph (C).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assignment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In assigning such Officers pursuant to subparagraph (B), the Commissioner shall consult with the port directors of each service port and the other ports of entry serviced by such service port. The Commissioner shall not assign an Officer to a port of entry pursuant to subparagraph (B)(ii) if the port director of the service port that services such port of entry certifies to the Commissioner that an additional Officer is not needed at such port of entry.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Not later than 60 days after the beginning of each of the fiscal years 2008 through 2012, the Commissioner shall submit a report to the Committee on Finance of the Senate, the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate, the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives, that describes how the additional Officers authorized under subparagraph (B) will be allocated among the ports of entry in the United States in accordance with subparagraph (C).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In addition to any monies hereafter appropriated to United States Customs and Border Protection in the Department of Homeland Security, there are authorized to be appropriated for the purpose of meeting the requirements of paragraph (2)(B), to remain available until expended—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> $36,000,000 for fiscal year 2008;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> $75,000,000 for fiscal year 2009;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> $118,000,000 for fiscal year 2010;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> $165,000,000 for fiscal year 2011; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> $217,000,000 for fiscal year 2012.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 30 days after the end of each fiscal year, the Commissioner shall report to the Committee on Finance of the Senate and the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives on the resources directed to commercial and trade facilitation functions within the Office of Field Operations for the preceding fiscal year. Such information shall be reported for each category of personnel within the Office of Field Operations.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations to implement trade agreements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 30 days after <date date="2006-10-13">October 13, 2006</date>, the Commissioner shall designate and maintain not less than 5 attorneys within the Office of International Trade established pursuant to <ref>section 2072 of this title</ref>, with responsibility for the prompt development and promulgation of regulations necessary to implement any trade agreement entered into by the United States, in addition to any other responsibilities assigned by the Commissioner.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In this subsection, the term “Commissioner” means the Commissioner responsible for United States Customs and Border Protection in the Department of Homeland Security.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–410, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="1978-10-03">Oct. 3, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 905</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–456, § 2</ref>, <date date="1983-01-12">Jan. 12, 1983</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2503</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–573, title VII, § 702</ref>, <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 3043</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–272, title XIII, § 13022(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-04-07">Apr. 7, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 305</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–509, title VIII, § 8102</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1967</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–570, title III, § 3141(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3207–92</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–203, title IX, § 9503(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1330–380</ref>, 1330–381; <ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title VII, § 7361(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4474</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–207, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="1989-12-07">Dec. 7, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1833</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–382, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1990-08-20">Aug. 20, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 634</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–210, div. A, title III, § 311(a)</ref>, (b)(1), (c), (d), <date date="2002-08-06">Aug. 6, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 973</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–347, title IV, § 403</ref>, <date date="2006-10-13">Oct. 13, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1926</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–125, title VIII, § 802(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="2016-02-24">Feb. 24, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 210</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2076.</num>
<heading> Advances in foreign countries</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Section 3648 of the Revised Statutes (<ref>31 U.S.C. 529b</ref>) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002075">1</ref> shall not apply to payments made for the Bureau of Customs <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002076">2</ref> in foreign countries.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 28, 1938, ch. 55</ref>, <ref>52 Stat. 126</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2077.</num>
<heading> Advances for enforcement of customs provisions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commissioner of Customs,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002077">1</ref> with the approval of the Secretary of the Treasury, is authorized to direct the advance of funds by the Fiscal Service, Treasury Department, in connection with the enforcement of the customs laws.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 28, 1928, ch. 266, § 2</ref>, as added <ref>Aug. 7, 1939, ch. 566, § 1</ref>, <ref>53 Stat. 1263</ref>; amended 1940 Reorg. Plan No. III, § 1(a)(1), eff. <date date="1940-06-30">June 30, 1940</date>, 5 F.R. 2107, <ref>54 Stat. 1231</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–125, title VIII, § 802(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="2016-02-24">Feb. 24, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 210</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2078.</num>
<heading> Certification of reason for advance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A certificate by the Commissioner of Customs <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002078">1</ref> stating the amount of an expenditure made from funds advanced and certifying that the confidential nature of the transaction involved renders it inadvisable to specify the details thereof or impracticable to furnish the payee’s receipt shall be a sufficient voucher for the sum expressed to have been expended.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 28, 1928, ch. 266, § 3</ref>, as added <ref>Aug. 7, 1939, ch. 566, § 1</ref>, <ref>53 Stat. 1263</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 91–513, title III, § 1102(n)(2)</ref>, <date date="1970-10-27">Oct. 27, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1293</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–125, title VIII, § 802(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="2016-02-24">Feb. 24, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 210</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2079.</num>
<heading> Payments in foreign countries; claims for reimbursement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The provisions of this Act shall not affect payments made for the United States Customs Service in foreign countries, nor the right of any customs officer or employee to claim reimbursement for personal funds expended in connection with the enforcement of the customs laws.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 28, 1928, ch. 266, § 4</ref>, as added <ref>Aug. 7, 1939, ch. 566, § 1</ref>, <ref>53 Stat. 1263</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 91–513, title III, § 1102(n)(3)</ref>, <date date="1970-10-27">Oct. 27, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1293</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2080.</num>
<heading> Advances from available appropriations; rules and regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Advances pursuant to this Act, in connection with the enforcement of the customs laws may be made, notwithstanding the provisions of section 3324(a) and (b) of title 31, from the appropriations available for the enforcement of such laws. The Secretary of the Treasury is authorized to prescribe such rules and regulations concerning advances made pursuant to this Act as are necessary or appropriate for the protection of the interests of the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 28, 1928, ch. 266, § 5</ref>, as added <ref>Aug. 7, 1939, ch. 566, § 1</ref>, <ref>53 Stat. 1263</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 91–513, title III, § 1102(n)(4)</ref>, <date date="1970-10-27">Oct. 27, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1293</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2081.</num>
<heading> Undercover investigative operations of Customs Service</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certification required for exemption of undercover operations from certain laws</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">With respect to any undercover investigative operation of the United States Customs Service (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “Service”) which is necessary for the detection and prosecution of offenses against the United States which are within the jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Treasury—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> sums authorized to be appropriated for the Service may be used—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> to purchase property, buildings, and other facilities, and to lease space, within the United States, the District of Columbia, and the territories and possessions of the United States without regard to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> sections 1341 and 3324 of title 31,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> sections 6301(a) and (b)(1) to (3) and 6306 of title 41,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> chapter 45 of title 41,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content><ref>section 8141 of title 40</ref>, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content><ref>section 3901 of title 41</ref>, and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to establish or to acquire proprietary corporations or business entities as part of the undercover operation, and to operate such corporations or business entities on a commercial basis, without regard to sections 9102 and 9103 of title 31;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> sums authorized to be appropriated for the Service and the proceeds from the undercover operation, may be deposited in banks or other financial institutions without regard to the provisions of <ref>section 648 of title 18</ref> and <ref>section 3302 of title 31</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the proceeds from the undercover operation may be used to offset necessary and reasonable expenses incurred in such operation without regard to the provisions of <ref>section 3302 of title 31</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">only upon the written certification of the Commissioner of Customs <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002079">1</ref> (or, if designated by the Commissioner the Deputy or an Assistant Commissioner of Customs) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002079">1</ref> that any action authorized by paragraph (1), (2), or (3) of this subsection is necessary for the conduct of such undercover operation.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Liquidation of corporations and business entities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If a corporation or business entity established or acquired as part of an undercover operation under paragraph (1)(B) of subsection (a) with a net value over $50,000 is to be liquidated, sold, or otherwise disposed of, the Service, as much in advance as the Commissioner or his designee determines is practicable, shall report the circumstances to the Secretary of the Treasury. The proceeds of the liquidation, sale, or other disposition, after obligations are met, shall be deposited in the Treasury of the United States as miscellaneous receipts.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deposit of proceeds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As soon as the proceeds from an undercover investigative operation with respect to which an action is authorized and carried out under paragraphs (2) and (3) of subsection (a) of this section are no longer necessary for the conduct of such operation, such proceeds or the balance of such proceeds remaining at the time shall be deposited into the Treasury of the United States as miscellaneous receipts.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Audits</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Service shall conduct a detailed financial audit of each undercover investigative operation which is closed in each fiscal year, and</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> submit the results of the audit in writing to the Secretary of the Treasury; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> not later than 180 days after such undercover operation is closed, submit a report to the Congress concerning such audit.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Service shall also submit a report annually to the Congress specifying as to its undercover investigative operations—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the number, by programs, of undercover investigative operations pending as of the end of the 1-year period for which such report is submitted;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the number, by programs, of undercover investigative operations commenced in the 1-year period preceding the period for which such report is submitted; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the number, by programs, of undercover investigative operations closed in the 1-year period preceding the period for which such report is submitted and, with respect to each such closed undercover operation, the results obtained and any civil claims made with respect thereto.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of subsection (d) of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The term “closed” refers to the earliest point in time at which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> all criminal proceedings (other than appeals) are concluded, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> covert activities are concluded, whichever occurs later.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “employees” means employees, as defined in <ref>section 2105 of title 5</ref>, of the Service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The terms “undercover investigative operation” and “undercover operation” mean any undercover investigative operation of the Service—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> in which—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the gross receipts (excluding interest earned) exceed $50,000, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> expenditures (other than expenditures for salaries of employees) exceed $150,000; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> which is exempt from section 3302 or 9102 of title 31;</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">except that subparagraphs (A) and (B) shall not apply with respect to the report required under paragraph (2) of subsection (d) of this section.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–570, title III, § 3131</ref>, <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3207–90</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title X, § 1074(d)(3)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2661</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–316, title I, § 110(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3832</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–125, title VIII, § 802(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="2016-02-24">Feb. 24, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 210</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2082.</num>
<heading> Customs Service administration</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Commissioner of Customs <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002080">1</ref> shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> develop and implement accounting systems that accurately determine and report the allocations made of Customs Service personnel and other resources among the various operational functions of the Service, such as passenger processing, merchandise processing and drug enforcement; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> develop and implement periodic labor distribution surveys of major workforce activities (such as inspectors, import specialists, fines, penalties, and forfeiture officers, special agents, data transcribers, and Customs aides) to determine the costs of different types of passenger and merchandise processing transactions, such as informal and formal entries, and automated and manual entries.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Survey reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commissioner of Customs <sup>1</sup> shall no later than <date date="1991-01-31">January 31, 1991</date>, submit to the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate a report on the results of the first survey implemented under subsection (a)(2).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–382, title I, § 113</ref>, <date date="1990-08-20">Aug. 20, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 639</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–508, title X, § 10001(d)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1388–386</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–125, title VIII, § 802(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="2016-02-24">Feb. 24, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 210</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2083.</num>
<heading> Annual national trade and customs law violation estimates and enforcement strategy</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Violation estimates</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 30 days before the beginning of each fiscal year after fiscal year 1991, the Commissioner of Customs <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002081">1</ref> shall submit to the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Committees”) a report that contains estimates of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the number and extent of violations of the trade, customs, and illegal drug control laws listed under subsection (b) that will likely occur during the fiscal year; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the relative incidence of the violations estimated under paragraph (1) among the various ports of entry and customs regions within the customs territory.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicable statutory provisions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Commissioner of Customs,<sup>1</sup> after consultation with the Committees—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall, within 60 days after <date date="1990-08-20">August 20, 1990</date>, prepare a list of those provisions of the trade, customs, and illegal drug control laws of the United States for which the United States Customs Service has enforcement responsibility and to which the reports required under subsection (a) will apply; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> may from time-to-time amend the listing developed under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Enforcement strategy</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Within 90 days after submitting a report under subsection (a) for any fiscal year, the Commissioner of Customs <sup>1</sup> shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> develop a nationally uniform enforcement strategy for dealing during that year with the violations estimated in the report; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> submit to the Committees a report setting forth the details of the strategy.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compliance program</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Commissioner of Customs <sup>1</sup> shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> devise and implement a methodology for estimating the level of compliance with the laws administered by the Customs Service; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> include as an additional part of the report required to be submitted under subsection (a) for each of fiscal years 1994, 1995, and 1996, an evaluation of the extent to which such compliance was obtained during the 12-month period preceding the 60th day before each such fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Confidentiality</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The contents of any report submitted to the Committees under subsection (a) or (c)(2) are confidential and disclosure of all or part of the contents is restricted to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> officers and employees of the United States designated by the Commissioner of Customs; <sup>1</sup></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the chairman of each of the Committees; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> those members of each of the Committees and staff persons of each of the Committees who are authorized by the chairman thereof to have access to the contents.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–382, title I, § 123</ref>, <date date="1990-08-20">Aug. 20, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 642</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–182, title VI, § 691(c)</ref>, <date date="1993-12-08">Dec. 8, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 2224</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–125, title VIII, § 802(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="2016-02-24">Feb. 24, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 210</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2084.</num>
<heading> Office of Trade</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established in U.S. Customs and Border Protection an Office of Trade.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Executive Assistant Commissioner</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There shall be at the head of the Office of Trade an Executive Assistant Commissioner, who shall report to the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Office of Trade shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> direct the development and implementation, pursuant to the customs and trade laws of the United States, of policies and regulations administered by U.S. Customs and Border Protection;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> advise the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection with respect to the impact on trade facilitation and trade enforcement of any policy or regulation otherwise proposed or administered by U.S. Customs and Border Protection;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> coordinate with the Executive Assistant Commissioner for the Office of Field Operations with respect to the trade facilitation and trade enforcement activities of U.S. Customs and Border Protection;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> direct the development and implementation of matters relating to the priority trade issues identified by the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection in the joint strategic plan for trade facilitation and trade enforcement required under <ref>section 4314 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> otherwise advise the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection with respect to the development and implementation of the joint strategic plan;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> direct the trade enforcement activities of U.S. Customs and Border Protection;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> oversee the trade modernization activities of U.S. Customs and Border Protection, including the development and implementation of the Automated Commercial Environment computer system authorized under <ref>section 58c(f)(4) of this title</ref> and support for the establishment of the International Trade Data System under the oversight of the Department of the Treasury pursuant to <ref>section 1411(d) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> direct the administration of customs revenue functions as otherwise provided by law or delegated by the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<chapeau> prepare an annual report to be submitted to the Committee on Finance of the Senate and the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives not later than <date date="2016-06-01">June 1, 2016</date>, and March 1 of each calendar year thereafter that includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a summary of the changes to customs policies and regulations adopted by U.S. Customs and Border Protection during the preceding calendar year; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a description of the public vetting and interagency consultation that occurred with respect to each such change.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer of assets, functions, personnel, or liabilities; elimination of offices</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Office of International Trade</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Not later than 30 days after <date date="2016-02-24">February 24, 2016</date>, the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection shall transfer the assets, functions, personnel, and liabilities of the Office of International Trade to the Office of Trade established under subsection (b).<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002082">1</ref></p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Elimination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Not later than 30 days after <date date="2016-02-24">February 24, 2016</date>, the Office of International Trade shall be abolished.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">No funds appropriated to U.S. Customs and Border Protection or the Department of Homeland Security may be used to transfer the assets, functions, personnel, or liabilities of the Office of International Trade to an office other than the Office of Trade established under subsection (a), unless the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection notifies the Committee on Homeland Security and the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and the Committee on Finance of the Senate of the specific assets, functions, personnel, or liabilities to be transferred, and the reason for the transfer, not less than 90 days prior to the transfer of such assets, functions, personnel, or liabilities.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Office of International Trade defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In this paragraph, the term “Office of International Trade” means the Office of International Trade established by <ref>section 2072 of this title</ref> and as in effect on the day before <date date="2016-02-24">February 24, 2016</date>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other transfers</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection is authorized to transfer any other assets, functions, or personnel within U.S. Customs and Border Protection to the Office of Trade established under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Congressional notification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Not less than 90 days prior to the transfer of assets, functions, personnel, or liabilities under subparagraph (A), the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection shall notify the Committee on Homeland Security and the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and the Committee on Finance of the Senate of the specific assets, functions, personnel, or liabilities to be transferred, and the reason for such transfer.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this section, the terms “customs and trade laws of the United States”, “trade enforcement”, and “trade facilitation” have the meanings given such terms in <ref>section 4301 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 3, 1927, ch. 348, § 4</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 114–125, title VIII, § 802(h)(1)</ref>, <date date="2016-02-24">Feb. 24, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 213</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>