<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 15—</num>
<heading>CARIBBEAN BASIN ECONOMIC RECOVERY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2701.</num>
<heading> Authority to grant duty-free treatment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President may proclaim duty-free treatment (or other preferential treatment) for all eligible articles from any beneficiary country in accordance with the provisions of this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–67, title II, § 211</ref>, <date date="1983-08-05">Aug. 5, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 384</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–200, title II, § 211(e)(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="2000-05-18">May 18, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 287</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2702.</num>
<heading> Beneficiary country</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions; termination of designation</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of this chapter—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The term “beneficiary country” means any country listed in subsection (b) with respect to which there is in effect a proclamation by the President designating such country as a beneficiary country for purposes of this chapter. Before the President designates any country as a beneficiary country for purposes of this chapter, he shall notify the House of Representatives and the Senate of his intention to make such designation, together with the considerations entering into such decision.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The term “entered” means entered, or withdrawn from warehouse for consumption, in the customs territory of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The term “HTS” means Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The term “USMCA” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 4502 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The terms “WTO” and “WTO member” have the meanings given those terms in <ref>section 3501 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> The term “former beneficiary country” means a country that ceases to be designated as a beneficiary country under this chapter because the country has become a party to a free trade agreement with the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If the President has designated any country as a beneficiary country for purposes of this chapter, he shall not terminate such designation (either by issuing a proclamation for that purpose or by issuing a proclamation which has the effect of terminating such designation) unless, at least sixty days before such termination, he has notified the House of Representatives and the Senate and has notified such country of his intention to terminate such designation, together with the considerations entering into such decision.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Countries eligible for designation as beneficiary countries; conditions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In designating countries as “beneficiary countries” under this chapter the President shall consider only the following countries and territories or successor political entities:</chapeau>
<chapeau class="indent0 firstIndent0">In addition, the President shall not designate any country a beneficiary country under this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> if such country is a Communist country;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> if such country—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> has nationalized, expropriated or otherwise seized ownership or control of property owned by a United States citizen or by a corporation, partnership, or association which is 50 per centum or more beneficially owned by United States citizens,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> has taken steps to repudiate or nullify—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any existing contract or agreement with, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any patent, trademark, or other intellectual property of,</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">a United States citizen or a corporation, partnership, or association which is 50 per centum or more beneficially owned by United States citizens, the effect of which is to nationalize, expropriate, or otherwise seize ownership or control of property so owned, or</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> has imposed or enforced taxes or other exactions, restrictive maintenance or operational conditions, or other measures with respect to property so owned, the effect of which is to nationalize, expropriate, or otherwise seize ownership or control of such property, unless the President determines that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> prompt, adequate, and effective compensation has been or is being made to such citizen, corporation, partnership, or association,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> good-faith negotiations to provide prompt, adequate, and effective compensation under the applicable provisions of international law are in progress, or such country is otherwise taking steps to discharge its obligations under international law with respect to such citizen, corporation, partnership, or association, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a dispute involving such citizen, corporation, partnership, or association, over compensation for such a seizure has been submitted to arbitration under the provisions of the Convention for the Settlement of Investment Disputes, or in another mutually agreed upon forum, and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">promptly furnishes a copy of such determination to the Senate and House of Representatives;</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> if such country fails to act in good faith in recognizing as binding or in enforcing arbitral awards in favor of United States citizens or a corporation, partnership or association which is 50 per centum or more beneficially owned by United States citizens, which have been made by arbitrators appointed for each case or by permanent arbitral bodies to which the parties involved have submitted their dispute;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> if such country affords preferential treatment to the products of a developed country, other than the United States, which has, or is likely to have, a significant adverse effect on United States commerce, unless the President has received assurances satisfactory to him that such preferential treatment will be eliminated or that action will be taken to assure that there will be no such significant adverse effect, and he reports those assurances to the Congress;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> if a government-owned entity in such country engages in the broadcast of copyrighted material, including films or television material, belonging to United States copyright owners without their express consent;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> unless such country is a signatory to a treaty, convention, protocol, or other agreement regarding the extradition of United States citizens; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> if such country has not or is not taking steps to afford internationally recognized worker rights (as defined in <ref>section 2467(4) of this title</ref>) to workers in the country (including any designated zone in that country).</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Paragraphs (1), (2), (3), (5), and (7) shall not prevent the designation of any country as a beneficiary country under this Act if the President determines that such designation will be in the national economic or security interest of the United States and reports such determination to the Congress with his reasons therefor.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Factors determining designation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In determining whether to designate any country a beneficiary country under this chapter, the President shall take into account—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an expression by such country of its desire to be so designated;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the economic conditions in such country, the living standards of its inhabitants, and any other economic factors which he deems appropriate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the extent to which such country has assured the United States it will provide equitable and reasonable access to the markets and basic commodity resources of such country;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the degree to which such country follows the accepted rules of international trade provided for under the WTO Agreement and the multilateral trade agreements (as such terms are defined in paragraphs (9) and (4), respectively, of <ref>section 3501 of this title</ref>);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the degree to which such country uses export subsidies or imposes export performance requirements or local content requirements which distort international trade;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the degree to which the trade policies of such country as they relate to other beneficiary countries are contributing to the revitalization of the region;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the degree to which such country is undertaking self-help measures to promote its own economic development;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> whether or not such country has taken or is taking steps to afford to workers in that country (including any designated zone in that country) internationally recognized worker rights.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002141">1</ref></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> the extent to which such country provides under its law adequate and effective means for foreign nationals to secure, exercise, and enforce exclusive rights in intellectual property, including patent, trademark, and copyright rights;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> the extent to which such country prohibits its nationals from engaging in the broadcast of copyrighted material, including films or television material, belonging to United States copyright owners without their express consent; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> the extent to which such country is prepared to cooperate with the United States in the administration of the provisions of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Withdrawal or suspension of duty-free treatment to specific articles</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> The President may, after the requirements of subsection (a)(2) and paragraph (2) have been met—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> withdraw or suspend the designation of any country as a beneficiary country, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> withdraw, suspend, or limit the application of duty-free treatment under this chapter to any article of any country,</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">if, after such designation, the President determines that as a result of changed circumstances such country would be barred from designation as a beneficiary country under subsection (b).</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> The President may, after the requirements of subsection (a)(2) and paragraph (2) have been met—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> withdraw or suspend the designation of any country as a CBTPA beneficiary country; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> withdraw, suspend, or limit the application of preferential treatment under section 2703(b)(2) and (3) of this title to any article of any country,</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">if, after such designation, the President determines that, as a result of changed circumstances, the performance of such country is not satisfactory under the criteria set forth in <ref>section 2703(b)(5)(B) of this title</ref>.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The President shall publish in the Federal Register notice of the action the President proposes to take under paragraph (1) at least 30 days prior to taking such action.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> The United States Trade Representative shall, within the 30-day period beginning on the date on which the President publishes under subparagraph (A) notice of proposed action—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> accept written comments from the public regarding such proposed action,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> hold a public hearing on such proposed action, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> publish in the Federal Register—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> notice of the time and place of such hearing prior to the hearing, and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the time and place at which such written comments will be accepted.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> If preferential treatment under section 2703(b)(2) and (3) of this title is withdrawn, suspended, or limited with respect to a CBTPA beneficiary country, such country shall not be deemed to be a “party” for the purposes of applying <ref>section 2703(b)(5)(C) of this title</ref> to imports of articles for which preferential treatment has been withdrawn, suspended, or limited with respect to such country.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reporting requirements</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than <date date="2001-12-31">December 31, 2001</date>, and every 2 years thereafter during the period this chapter is in effect, the United States Trade Representative shall submit to Congress a report regarding the operation of this chapter, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> with respect to subsections (b) and (c), the results of a general review of beneficiary countries based on the considerations described in such subsections; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the performance of each beneficiary country or CBTPA beneficiary country, as the case may be, under the criteria set forth in <ref>section 2703(b)(5)(B) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public comment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Before submitting the report described in paragraph (1), the United States Trade Representative shall publish a notice in the Federal Register requesting public comments on whether beneficiary countries are meeting the criteria listed in <ref>section 2703(b)(5)(B) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–67, title II, § 212</ref>, <date date="1983-08-05">Aug. 5, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 384</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–570, title IX, § 9002(b)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3207–166</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title I</ref>, §§ 1214(q)(1), 1909(c), <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1159</ref>, 1318; <ref>Pub. L. 101–382, title II</ref>, §§ 213, 214, <date date="1990-08-20">Aug. 20, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 656</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–465, title VI, § 621(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4992</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–188, title I, § 1954(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1927</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–200, title II, § 211(b)</ref>, (c)(1), (e)(2), <date date="2000-05-18">May 18, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 286</ref>, 287; <ref>Pub. L. 109–53, title IV, § 402(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2005-08-02">Aug. 2, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 495</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–43, title IV, § 402(a)</ref>, <date date="2011-10-21">Oct. 21, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 530</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–260, div. O, title VI, § 602(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 2152</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2703.</num>
<heading> Eligible articles</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Growth, product, or manufacture of beneficiary countries</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Unless otherwise excluded from eligibility by this chapter, and subject to section 423 of the Tax Reform Act of 1986, and except as provided in subsection (b)(2) and (3), the duty-free treatment provided under this chapter shall apply to any article which is the growth, product, or manufacture of a beneficiary country if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> that article is imported directly from a beneficiary country into the customs territory of the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the sum of (i) the cost or value of the materials produced in a beneficiary country or two or more beneficiary countries, plus (ii) the direct costs of processing operations performed in a beneficiary country or countries is not less than 35 per centum of the appraised value of such article at the time it is entered.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">For purposes of determining the percentage referred to in subparagraph (B), the term “beneficiary country” includes the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, and any former beneficiary country. If the cost or value of materials produced in the customs territory of the United States (other than the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico) is included with respect to an article to which this paragraph applies, an amount not to exceed 15 per centum of the appraised value of the article at the time it is entered that is attributed to such United States cost or value may be applied toward determining the percentage referred to in subparagraph (B).</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of the Treasury shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to carry out this subsection including, but not limited to, regulations providing that, in order to be eligible for duty-free treatment under this chapter, an article must be wholly the growth, product, or manufacture of a beneficiary country, or must be a new or different article of commerce which has been grown, produced, or manufactured in the beneficiary country; but no article or material of a beneficiary country shall be eligible for such treatment by virtue of having merely undergone—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> simple combining or packaging operations, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> mere dilution with water or mere dilution with another substance that does not materially alter the characteristics of the article.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> As used in this subsection, the phrase “direct costs of processing operations” includes, but is not limited to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> all actual labor costs involved in the growth, production, manufacture, or assembly of the specific merchandise, including fringe benefits, on-the-job training and the cost of engineering, supervisory, quality control, and similar personnel; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> dies, molds, tooling, and depreciation on machinery and equipment which are allocable to the specific merchandise.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Such phrase does not include costs which are not directly attributable to the merchandise concerned or are not costs of manufacturing the product, such as (i) profit, and (ii) general expenses of doing business which are either not allocable to the specific merchandise or are not related to the growth, production, manufacture, or assembly of the merchandise, such as administrative salaries, casualty and liability insurance, advertising, and salesmen’s salaries, commissions or expenses.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding <ref>section 1311 of this title</ref>, the products of a beneficiary country which are imported directly from any beneficiary country into Puerto Rico may be entered under bond for processing or use in manufacturing in Puerto Rico. No duty shall be imposed on the withdrawal from warehouse of the product of such processing or manufacturing if, at the time of such withdrawal, such product meets the requirements of paragraph (1)(B).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> The duty-free treatment provided under this chapter shall apply to an article (other than an article listed in subsection (b)) which is the growth, product, or manufacture of the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the article is imported directly from the beneficiary country into the customs territory of the United States,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the article was by any means advanced in value or improved in condition in a beneficiary country, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> if any materials are added to the article in a beneficiary country, such materials are a product of a beneficiary country or the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> Notwithstanding paragraph (1), the duty-free treatment provided under this chapter shall apply to liqueurs and spirituous beverages produced in the territory of Canada from rum if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> such rum is the growth, product, or manufacture of a beneficiary country or of the Virgin Islands of the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> such rum is imported directly from a beneficiary country or the Virgin Islands of the United States into the territory of Canada, and such liqueurs and spirituous beverages are imported directly from the territory of Canada into the customs territory of the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> when imported into the customs territory of the United States, such liqueurs and spirituous beverages are classified in subheading 2208.90 or 2208.40 of the HTS; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> such rum accounts for at least 90 percent by volume of the alcoholic content of such liqueurs and spirituous beverages.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Import-sensitive articles</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Subject to paragraphs (2) through (5), the duty-free treatment provided under this chapter does not apply to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> textile and apparel articles which were not eligible articles for purposes of this chapter on <date date="1994-01-01">January 1, 1994</date>, as this chapter was in effect on that date;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> footwear provided for in any of subheadings 6401.10.00, 6401.91.00, 6401.92.90, 6401.99.30, 6401.99.60, 6401.99.90, 6402.30.50, 6402.30.70, 6402.30.80, 6402.91.50, 6402.91.80, 6402.91.90, 6402.99.20, 6402.99.80, 6402.99.90, 6403.59.60, 6403.91.30, 6403.99.60, 6403.99.90, 6404.11.90, and 6404.19.20 of the HTS that was not designated at the time of the effective date of this chapter [<date date="1983-08-05">Aug. 5, 1983</date>] as eligible articles for the purpose of the generalized system of preferences under title V of the Trade Act of 1974 [<ref>19 U.S.C. 2461</ref> et seq.];</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> tuna, prepared or preserved in any manner, in airtight containers;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> petroleum, or any product derived from petroleum, provided for in headings 2709 and 2710 of the HTS;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> watches and watch parts (including cases, bracelets, and straps), of whatever type including, but not limited to, mechanical, quartz digital or quartz analog, if such watches or watch parts contain any material which is the product of any country with respect to which HTS column 2 rates of duty apply; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> articles to which reduced rates of duty apply under subsection (h).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transition period treatment of certain textile and apparel articles</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Articles covered</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">During the transition period, the preferential treatment described in subparagraph (B) shall apply to the following articles:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Apparel articles assembled in one or more CBTPA beneficiary countries</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">Apparel articles sewn or otherwise assembled in one or more CBTPA beneficiary countries from fabrics wholly formed and cut, or from components knit-to-shape, in the United States from yarns wholly formed in the United States, or both (including fabrics not formed from yarns, if such fabrics are classifiable under heading 5602 or 5603 of the HTS and are wholly formed and cut in the United States) that are—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> entered under subheading 9802.00.80 of the HTS; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> entered under chapter 61 or 62 of the HTS, if, after such assembly, the articles would have qualified for entry under subheading 9802.00.80 of the HTS but for the fact that the articles were embroidered or subjected to stone-washing, enzyme-washing, acid washing, perma-pressing, oven-baking, bleaching, garment-dyeing, screen printing, or other similar processes.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent3 firstIndent-1"> Apparel articles entered on or after <date date="2002-09-01">September 1, 2002</date>, shall qualify under the preceding sentence only if all dyeing, printing, and finishing of the fabrics from which the articles are assembled, if the fabrics are knit fabrics, is carried out in the United States. Apparel articles entered on or after <date date="2002-09-01">September 1, 2002</date>, shall qualify under the first sentence of this clause only if all dyeing, printing, and finishing of the fabrics from which the articles are assembled, if the fabrics are woven fabrics, is carried out in the United States.</continuation>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other apparel articles assembled in one or more CBTPA beneficiary countries</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Apparel articles sewn or otherwise assembled in one or more CBTPA beneficiary countries with thread formed in the United States from fabrics wholly formed in the United States and cut in one or more CBTPA beneficiary countries from yarns wholly formed in the United States, or from components knit-to-shape in the United States from yarns wholly formed in the United States, or both (including fabrics not formed from yarns, if such fabrics are classifiable under heading 5602 or 5603 of the HTS and are wholly formed in the United States). Apparel articles entered on or after <date date="2002-09-01">September 1, 2002</date>, shall qualify under the preceding sentence only if all dyeing, printing, and finishing of the fabrics from which the articles are assembled, if the fabrics are knit fabrics, is carried out in the United States. Apparel articles entered on or after <date date="2002-09-01">September 1, 2002</date>, shall qualify under the first sentence of this clause only if all dyeing, printing, and finishing of the fabrics from which the articles are assembled, if the fabrics are woven fabrics, is carried out in the United States.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certain knit apparel articles</heading>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> Apparel articles knit to shape (other than socks provided for in heading 6115 of the HTS) in a CBTPA beneficiary country from yarns wholly formed in the United States, and knit apparel articles (other than t-shirts described in subclause (III)) cut and wholly assembled in one or more CBTPA beneficiary countries from fabric formed in one or more CBTPA beneficiary countries or the United States from yarns wholly formed in the United States (including fabrics not formed from yarns, if such fabrics are classifiable under heading 5602 or 5603 of the HTS and are formed in one or more CBTPA beneficiary countries), in an amount not exceeding the amount set forth in subclause (II).</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<chapeau> The amount referred to in subclause (I) is as follows:</chapeau>
<item class="indent4">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> 500,000,000 square meter equivalents during the 1-year period beginning on <date date="2002-10-01">October 1, 2002</date>.</content>
</item>
<item class="indent4">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> 850,000,000 square meter equivalents during the 1-year period beginning on <date date="2003-10-01">October 1, 2003</date>.</content>
</item>
<item class="indent4">
<num>(cc)</num>
<content> 970,000,000 square meter equivalents in each succeeding 1-year period through <date date="2030-09-30">September 30, 2030</date>.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> T-shirts, other than underwear, classifiable under subheadings 6109.10.00 and 6109.90.10 of the HTS, made in one or more CBTPA beneficiary countries from fabric formed in one or more CBTPA beneficiary countries from yarns wholly formed in the United States, in an amount not exceeding the amount set forth in subclause (IV).</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(IV)</num>
<chapeau> The amount referred to in subclause (III) is as follows:</chapeau>
<item class="indent4">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> 4,872,000 dozen during the 1-year period beginning on <date date="2001-10-01">October 1, 2001</date>.</content>
</item>
<item class="indent4">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> 9,000,000 dozen during the 1-year period beginning on <date date="2002-10-01">October 1, 2002</date>.</content>
</item>
<item class="indent4">
<num>(cc)</num>
<content> 10,000,000 dozen during the 1-year period beginning on <date date="2003-10-01">October 1, 2003</date>.</content>
</item>
<item class="indent4">
<num>(dd)</num>
<content> 12,000,000 dozen in each succeeding 1-year period through <date date="2030-09-30">September 30, 2030</date>.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(V)</num>
<content> It is the sense of the Congress that the Congress should determine, based on the record of expansion of exports from the United States as a result of the preferential treatment of articles under this clause, the percentage by which the amount provided in subclauses (II) and (IV) should be compounded for the 1-year periods occurring after the 1-year period ending on <date date="2004-09-30">September 30, 2004</date>.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iv)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certain other apparel articles</heading>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(I)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General rule</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent4">Subject to subclause (II), any apparel article classifiable under subheading 6212.10 of the HTS, except for articles entered under clause (i), (ii), (iii), (v), or (vi), if the article is both cut and sewn or otherwise assembled in the United States, or one or more CBTPA beneficiary countries, or both.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(II)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent4">During the 1-year period beginning on <date date="2001-10-01">October 1, 2001</date>, and during each of the 28 succeeding 1-year periods, apparel articles described in subclause (I) of a producer or an entity controlling production shall be eligible for preferential treatment under subparagraph (B) only if the aggregate cost of fabrics (exclusive of all findings and trimmings) formed in the United States that are used in the production of all such articles of that producer or entity that are entered and eligible under this clause during the preceding 1-year period is at least 75 percent of the aggregate declared customs value of the fabric (exclusive of all findings and trimmings) contained in all such articles of that producer or entity that are entered and eligible under this clause during the preceding 1-year period.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(III)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Development of procedure to ensure compliance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent4">The United States Customs Service shall develop and implement methods and procedures to ensure ongoing compliance with the requirement set forth in subclause (II). If the Customs Service finds that a producer or an entity controlling production has not satisfied such requirement in a 1-year period, then apparel articles described in subclause (I) of that producer or entity shall be ineligible for preferential treatment under subparagraph (B) during any succeeding 1-year period until the aggregate cost of fabrics (exclusive of all findings and trimmings) formed in the United States that are used in the production of such articles of that producer or entity entered during the preceding 1-year period is at least 85 percent of the aggregate declared customs value of the fabric (exclusive of all findings and trimmings) contained in all such articles of that producer or entity that are entered and eligible under this clause during the preceding 1-year period.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(v)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Apparel articles assembled from fabrics or yarn not widely available in commercial quantities</heading>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> Apparel articles that are both cut (or knit-to-shape) and sewn or otherwise assembled in one or more CBTPA beneficiary countries, to the extent that apparel articles of such fabrics or yarn would be eligible for preferential treatment, without regard to the source of the fabrics or yarn, under Annex 4–B of the USMCA.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<chapeau> At the request of any interested party, the President is authorized to proclaim additional fabrics and yarn as eligible for preferential treatment under subclause (I) if—</chapeau>
<item class="indent4">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> the President determines that such fabrics or yarn cannot be supplied by the domestic industry in commercial quantities in a timely manner;</content>
</item>
<item class="indent4">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> the President has obtained advice regarding the proposed action from the appropriate advisory committee established under section 135 of the Trade Act of 1974 (<ref>19 U.S.C. 2155</ref>) and the United States International Trade Commission;</content>
</item>
<item class="indent4">
<num>(cc)</num>
<content> within 60 days after the request, the President has submitted a report to the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate that sets forth the action proposed to be proclaimed and the reasons for such actions, and the advice obtained under division (bb);</content>
</item>
<item class="indent4">
<num>(dd)</num>
<content> a period of 60 calendar days, beginning with the first day on which the President has met the requirements of division (cc), has expired; and</content>
</item>
<item class="indent4">
<num>(ee)</num>
<content> the President has consulted with such committees regarding the proposed action during the period referred to in division (cc).</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> If the President determines that any fabric or yarn was determined to be eligible for preferential treatment under subclause (I) on the basis of fraud, the President is authorized to remove that designation from that fabric or yarn with respect to articles entered after such removal.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(vi)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Handloomed, handmade, and folklore articles</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">A handloomed, handmade, or folklore article of a CBTPA beneficiary country identified under subparagraph (C) that is certified as such by the competent authority of such beneficiary country.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(vii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rules</heading>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(I)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception for findings and trimmings</heading>
<item class="indent4">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> An article otherwise eligible for preferential treatment under this paragraph shall not be ineligible for such treatment because the article contains findings or trimmings of foreign origin, if such findings and trimmings do not exceed 25 percent of the cost of the components of the assembled product. Examples of findings and trimmings are sewing thread, hooks and eyes, snaps, buttons, “bow buds”, decorative lace, trim, elastic strips, zippers, including zipper tapes and labels, and other similar products. Elastic strips are considered findings or trimmings only if they are each less than 1 inch in width and are used in the production of brassieres.</content>
</item>
<item class="indent4">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> In the case of an article described in clause (ii) of this subparagraph, sewing thread shall not be treated as findings or trimmings under this subclause.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(II)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certain interlining</heading>
<item class="indent4">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> An article otherwise eligible for preferential treatment under this paragraph shall not be ineligible for such treatment because the article contains certain interlinings of foreign origin, if the value of such interlinings (and any findings and trimmings) does not exceed 25 percent of the cost of the components of the assembled article.</content>
</item>
<item class="indent4">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> Interlinings eligible for the treatment described in division (aa) include only a chest type plate, “hymo” piece, or “sleeve header”, of woven or weft-inserted warp knit construction and of coarse animal hair or man-made filaments.</content>
</item>
<item class="indent4">
<num>(cc)</num>
<content> The treatment described in this subclause shall terminate if the President makes a determination that United States manufacturers are producing such interlinings in the United States in commercial quantities.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(III)</num>
<heading class="bold"> De minimis rule</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent4">An article that would otherwise be ineligible for preferential treatment under this paragraph because the article contains fibers or yarns not wholly formed in the United States or in one or more CBTPA beneficiary countries shall not be ineligible for such treatment if the total weight of all such fibers or yarns is not more than 7 percent of the total weight of the good. Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, an apparel article containing elastomeric yarns shall be eligible for preferential treatment under this paragraph only if such yarns are wholly formed in the United States.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(IV)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special origin rule</heading>
<chapeau class="indent4">An article otherwise eligible for preferential treatment under clause (i), (ii), or (ix) of this subparagraph shall not be ineligible for such treatment because the article contains nylon filament yarn (other than elastomeric yarn) that is classifiable under subheading 5402.10.30, 5402.10.60, 5402.31.30, 5402.31.60, 5402.32.30, 5402.32.60, 5402.41.10, 5402.41.90, 5402.51.00, or 5402.61.00 of the HTS duty-free from—</chapeau>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> a country that is a party to an agreement with the United States establishing a free trade area, which entered into force before <date date="1995-01-01">January 1, 1995</date>; or</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> a USMCA country (as defined in <ref>section 4502 of this title</ref>).</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(V)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Thread</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent4">An article otherwise eligible for preferential treatment under this paragraph shall not be ineligible for such treatment because the thread used to assemble the article is dyed, printed, or finished in one or more CBTPA beneficiary countries.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(viii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Textile luggage</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">Textile luggage—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> assembled in a CBTPA beneficiary country from fabric wholly formed and cut in the United States, from yarns wholly formed in the United States, that is entered under subheading 9802.00.80 of the HTS; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> assembled from fabric cut in a CBTPA beneficiary country from fabric wholly formed in the United States from yarns wholly formed in the United States.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ix)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Apparel articles assembled in one or more CBTPA beneficiary countries from United States and CBTPA beneficiary country components</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Apparel articles sewn or otherwise assembled in one or more CBTPA beneficiary countries with thread formed in the United States from components cut in the United States and in one or more CBTPA beneficiary countries from fabric wholly formed in the United States from yarns wholly formed in the United States, or from components knit-to-shape in the United States and one or more CBTPA beneficiary countries from yarns wholly formed in the United States, or both (including fabrics not formed from yarns, if such fabrics are classifiable under heading 5602 or 5603 of the HTS). Apparel articles shall qualify under this clause only if they meet the requirements of clause (i) or (ii) (as the case may be) with respect to dyeing, printing, and finishing of knit and woven fabrics from which the articles are assembled.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Preferential treatment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Except as provided in subparagraph (E), during the transition period, the articles to which this subparagraph applies shall enter the United States free of duty and free of any quantitative restrictions, limitations, or consultation levels.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Handloomed, handmade, and folklore articles</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">For purposes of subparagraph (A)(vi), the President shall consult with representatives of the CBTPA beneficiary countries concerned for the purpose of identifying particular textile and apparel goods that are mutually agreed upon as being handloomed, handmade, or folklore goods of a kind described in article 6.2 of the USMCA.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Penalties for transshipments</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Penalties for exporters</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">If the President determines, based on sufficient evidence, that an exporter has engaged in transshipment with respect to textile or apparel articles from a CBTPA beneficiary country, then the President shall deny all benefits under this chapter to such exporter, and any successor of such exporter, for a period of 2 years.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Penalties for countries</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Whenever the President finds, based on sufficient evidence, that transshipment has occurred, the President shall request that the CBTPA beneficiary country or countries through whose territory the transshipment has occurred take all necessary and appropriate actions to prevent such transshipment. If the President determines that a country is not taking such actions, the President shall reduce the quantities of textile and apparel articles that may be imported into the United States from such country by the quantity of the transshipped articles multiplied by 3, to the extent consistent with the obligations of the United States under the WTO.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transshipment described</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Transshipment within the meaning of this subparagraph has occurred when preferential treatment under subparagraph (B) has been claimed for a textile or apparel article on the basis of material false information concerning the country of origin, manufacture, processing, or assembly of the article or any of its components. For purposes of this clause, false information is material if disclosure of the true information would mean or would have meant that the article is or was ineligible for preferential treatment under subparagraph (B).</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(E)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Bilateral emergency actions</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The President may take bilateral emergency tariff actions of a kind described in section 4 of the Annex with respect to any apparel article imported from a CBTPA beneficiary country if the application of tariff treatment under subparagraph (B) to such article results in conditions that would be cause for the taking of such actions under such section 4 with respect to a like article described in the same 8-digit subheading of the HTS that is imported from Mexico.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rules relating to bilateral emergency action</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">For purposes of applying bilateral emergency action under this subparagraph—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the requirements of paragraph (5) of section 4 of the Annex (relating to providing compensation) shall not apply;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the term “transition period” in section 4 of the Annex shall have the meaning given that term in paragraph (5)(D) of this subsection; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> the requirements to consult specified in section 4 of the Annex shall be treated as satisfied if the President requests consultations with the CBTPA beneficiary country in question and the country does not agree to consult within the time period specified under section 4.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transition period treatment of certain other articles originating in beneficiary countries</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Equivalent tariff treatment</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Subject to clauses (ii) and (iii), the tariff treatment accorded at any time during the transition period to any article referred to in any of subparagraphs (B) through (F) of paragraph (1) that is a CBTPA originating good shall be identical to the tariff treatment that is accorded at such time under Annex 2–B of the USMCA to an article described in the same 8-digit subheading of the HTS that is a good of Mexico and is imported into the United States.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Clause (i) does not apply to any article accorded duty-free treatment under U.S. Note 2(b) to subchapter II of chapter 98 of the HTS.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certain footwear</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">Notwithstanding paragraph (1)(B) and clause (i) of this subparagraph, footwear provided for in any of subheadings 6403.59.60, 6403.91.30, 6403.99.60, and 6403.99.90 of the HTS shall be eligible for the duty-free treatment provided for under this chapter if—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the article of footwear is the growth, product, or manufacture of a CBTPA beneficiary country; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the article otherwise meets the requirements of subsection (a), except that in applying such subsection, “CBTPA beneficiary country” shall be substituted for “beneficiary country” each place it appears.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Relationship to subsection (h) duty reductions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">If at any time during the transition period the rate of duty that would (but for action taken under subparagraph (A)(i) in regard to such period) apply with respect to any article under subsection (h) is a rate of duty that is lower than the rate of duty resulting from such action, then such lower rate of duty shall be applied for the purposes of implementing such action.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Customs procedures</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Any importer that claims preferential treatment under paragraph (2) or (3) shall comply with customs procedures similar in all material respects to the requirements of article 5.4.1 of the USMCA as implemented pursuant to United States law, in accordance with regulations promulgated by the Secretary of the Treasury.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determination</heading>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(I)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent4">In order to qualify for the preferential treatment under paragraph (2) or (3) and for a Certificate of Origin to be valid with respect to any article for which such treatment is claimed, there shall be in effect a determination by the President that each country described in subclause (II)—</chapeau>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> has implemented and follows; or</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> is making substantial progress toward implementing and following,</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<continuation class="indent4 firstIndent-2">  procedures and requirements similar in all material respects to the relevant procedures and requirements under chapter 5 of the USMCA.</continuation>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(II)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Country described</heading>
<chapeau class="indent4">A country is described in this subclause if it is a CBTPA beneficiary country—</chapeau>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> from which the article is exported; or</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> in which materials used in the production of the article originate or in which the article or such materials undergo production that contributes to a claim that the article is eligible for preferential treatment under paragraph (2) or (3).</content>
</item>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certificate of origin</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Certificate of Origin that otherwise would be required pursuant to the provisions of subparagraph (A) shall not be required in the case of an article imported under paragraph (2) or (3) if such Certificate of Origin would not be required under article 5.5 of the USMCA (as implemented pursuant to United States law), if the article were imported from Mexico.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report by USTR on cooperation of other countries concerning circumvention</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The United States Commissioner of Customs shall conduct a study analyzing the extent to which each CBTPA beneficiary country—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> has cooperated fully with the United States, consistent with its domestic laws and procedures, in instances of circumvention or alleged circumvention of existing quotas on imports of textile and apparel goods, to establish necessary relevant facts in the places of import, export, and, where applicable, transshipment, including investigation of circumvention practices, exchanges of documents, correspondence, reports, and other relevant information, to the extent such information is available;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> has taken appropriate measures, consistent with its domestic laws and procedures, against exporters and importers involved in instances of false declaration concerning fiber content, quantities, description, classification, or origin of textile and apparel goods; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> has penalized the individuals and entities involved in any such circumvention, consistent with its domestic laws and procedures, and has worked closely to seek the cooperation of any third country to prevent such circumvention from taking place in that third country.</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">The Trade Representative shall submit to Congress, not later than <date date="2001-10-01">October 1, 2001</date>, a report on the study conducted under this subparagraph.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions and special rules</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annex</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “the Annex” means Annex 300–B of the North American Free Trade Agreement entered into between the United States, Mexico, and Canada on <date date="1992-12-17">December 17, 1992</date>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> CBTPA beneficiary country</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “CBTPA beneficiary country” means any “beneficiary country”, as defined in <ref>section 2702(a)(1)(A) of this title</ref>, which the President designates as a CBTPA beneficiary country, taking into account the criteria contained in subsections (b) and (c) of <ref>section 2702 of this title</ref> and other appropriate criteria, including the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> Whether the beneficiary country has demonstrated a commitment to—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> undertake its obligations under the WTO, including those agreements listed in <ref>section 3511(d) of this title</ref>, on or ahead of schedule; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> participate in negotiations toward the completion of the FTAA or another free trade agreement.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The extent to which the country provides protection of intellectual property rights consistent with or greater than the protection afforded under the Agreement on Trade-Related Aspects of Intellectual Property Rights described in <ref>section 3511(d)(15) of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> The extent to which the country provides internationally recognized worker rights, including—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the right of association;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the right to organize and bargain collectively;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> a prohibition on the use of any form of forced or compulsory labor;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> a minimum age for the employment of children; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(V)</num>
<content> acceptable conditions of work with respect to minimum wages, hours of work, and occupational safety and health;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> Whether the country has implemented its commitments to eliminate the worst forms of child labor, as defined in section 507(6) of the Trade Act of 1974 [<ref>19 U.S.C. 2467(6)</ref>].</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> The extent to which the country has met the counter-narcotics certification criteria set forth in <ref>section 2291j of title 22</ref> for eligibility for United States assistance.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> The extent to which the country has taken steps to become a party to and implements the Inter-American Convention Against Corruption.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<chapeau> The extent to which the country—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> applies transparent, nondiscriminatory, and competitive procedures in government procurement equivalent to those contained in the Agreement on Government Procurement described in <ref>section 3511(d)(17) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> contributes to efforts in international fora to develop and implement international rules in transparency in government procurement.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> CBTPA originating good</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The term “CBTPA originating good” means a good that meets the rules of origin for a good set forth in chapter 4 of the USMCA as implemented pursuant to United States law.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application of chapter 4</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">In applying chapter 4 of the USMCA with respect to a CBTPA beneficiary country for purposes of this subsection—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> no country other than the United States and a CBTPA beneficiary country may be treated as being a party to the USMCA;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> any reference to trade between the United States and Mexico shall be deemed to refer to trade between the United States and a CBTPA beneficiary country;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> any reference to a party shall be deemed to refer to a CBTPA beneficiary country or the United States; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> any reference to parties shall be deemed to refer to any combination of CBTPA beneficiary countries or to the United States and one or more CBTPA beneficiary countries (or any combination thereof).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transition period</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “transition period” means, with respect to a CBTPA beneficiary country, the period that begins on <date date="2000-10-01">October 1, 2000</date>, and ends on the earlier of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content><date date="2030-09-30">September 30, 2030</date>; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the date on which the FTAA or another free trade agreement that makes substantial progress in achieving the negotiating objectives set forth in <ref>section 108(b)(5) of Public Law 103–182</ref> (<ref>19 U.S.C. 3317(b)(5)</ref>) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002142">1</ref> enters into force with respect to the United States and the CBTPA beneficiary country.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(E)</num>
<heading class="bold"> CBTPA</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “CBTPA” means the United States-Caribbean Basin Trade Partnership Act.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(F)</num>
<heading class="bold"> FTAA</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “FTAA” means the Free Trade Area of the Americas.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(G)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Former CBTPA beneficiary country</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “former CBTPA beneficiary country” means a country that ceases to be designated as a CBTPA beneficiary country under this chapter because the country has become a party to a free trade agreement with the United States.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(H)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Articles that undergo production in a CBTPA beneficiary country and a former CBTPA beneficiary country</heading>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of determining the eligibility of an article for preferential treatment under paragraph (2) or (3), references in either such paragraph, and in subparagraph (C) of this paragraph to—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> a “CBTPA beneficiary country” shall be considered to include any former CBTPA beneficiary country, and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> “CBTPA beneficiary countries” shall be considered to include former CBTPA beneficiary countries,</content>
</subclause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">if the article, or a good used in the production of the article, undergoes production in a CBTPA beneficiary country.</continuation>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> An article that is eligible for preferential treatment under clause (i) shall not be ineligible for such treatment because the article is imported directly from a former CBTPA beneficiary country.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> Notwithstanding clauses (i) and (ii), an article that is a good of a former CBTPA beneficiary country for purposes of <ref>section 1304 of this title</ref> or <ref>section 3592 of this title</ref>, as the case may be, shall not be eligible for preferential treatment under paragraph (2) or (3), unless—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> it is an article that is a good of the Dominican Republic under either such section 1304 or 3592 of this title; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the article, or a good used in the production of the article, undergoes production in Haiti.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sugar and beef products; stable food production plan; suspension of duty-free treatment; monitoring</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> As used in this subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> The term “sugar and beef products” means—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> sugars, sirups, and molasses provided for in subheadings 1701.11.00, 1701.12.00, 1701.91.20, 1701.99.00, 1702.90.30, 1806.10.40, and 2106.90.10 of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> articles of beef or veal, however provided for in chapters 2 and 16 of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> The term “Plan” means a stable food production plan that consists of measures and proposals designed to ensure that the present level of food production in, and the nutritional level of the population of, a beneficiary country will not be adversely affected by changes in land use and land ownership that will result if increased production of sugar and beef products is undertaken in response to the duty-free treatment extended under this chapter to such products. A Plan must specify such facts regarding, and such proposed actions by, a beneficiary country as the President deems necessary for purposes of carrying out this subsection, including but not limited to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the current levels of food production and nutritional health of the population;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> current level of production and export of sugar and beef products;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> expected increases in production and export of sugar and beef products as a result of the duty-free access to the United States market provided under this chapter;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> measures to be taken to ensure that the expanded production of those products because of such duty-free access will not occur at the expense of stable food production; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> proposals for a system to monitor the impact of such duty-free access on stable food production and land use and land ownership patterns.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Duty-free treatment extended under this chapter to sugar and beef products that are the product of a beneficiary country shall be suspended by the President under this subsection if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the beneficiary country, within the ninety-day period beginning on the date of its designation as such a country under <ref>section 2702 of this title</ref>, does not submit a Plan to the President for evaluation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> on the basis of his evaluation, the President determines that the Plan of a beneficiary country does not meet the criteria set forth in paragraph (1)(B); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> as a result of the monitoring of the operation of the Plan under paragraph (5), the President determines that a beneficiary country is not making a good faith effort to implement its Plan, or that the measures and proposals in the Plan, although being implemented, are not achieving their purposes.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Before the President suspends duty-free treatment by reason of paragraph (2)(A), (B), or (C) to the sugar and beef products of a beneficiary country, he must offer to enter into consultation with the beneficiary country for purposes of formulating appropriate remedial action which may be taken by that country to avoid such suspension. If the beneficiary country thereafter enters into consultation within a reasonable time and undertakes to formulate remedial action in good faith, the President shall withhold the suspension of duty-free treatment on the condition that the remedial action agreed upon be appropriately implemented by that country.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> The President shall monitor on a biennial basis the operation of the Plans implemented by beneficiary countries, and shall submit a written report to Congress by March 15 following the close of each biennium, that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> specifies the extent to which each Plan, and remedial actions, if any, agreed upon under paragraph (4), have been implemented; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> evaluates the results of such implementation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The President shall terminate any suspension of duty-free treatment imposed under this subsection if he determines that the beneficiary country has taken appropriate action to remedy the factors on which the suspension was based.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tariff-rate quotas</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No quantity of an agricultural product subject to a tariff-rate quota that exceeds the in-quota quantity shall be eligible for duty-free treatment under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Proclamations suspending duty-free treatment</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The President may by proclamation suspend the duty-free treatment provided by this chapter with respect to any eligible article and may proclaim a duty rate for such article if such action is provided under chapter 1 of title II of the Trade Act of 1974 [<ref>19 U.S.C. 2251</ref> et seq.] or <ref>section 1862 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In any report by the International Trade Commission to the President under section 202(f) of the Trade Act of 1974 [<ref>19 U.S.C. 2252(f)</ref>] regarding any article for which duty-free treatment has been proclaimed by the President pursuant to this chapter, the Commission shall state whether and to what extent its findings and recommendations apply to such article when imported from beneficiary countries.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> For purposes of subsections <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002143">2</ref> section 203 of the Trade Act of 1974 [<ref>19 U.S.C. 2253(a)</ref>, (c)], the suspension of the duty-free treatment provided by this chapter shall be treated as an increase in duty.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> No proclamation which provides solely for a suspension referred to in paragraph (3) of this subsection with respect to any article shall be taken under section 203 of the Trade Act of 1974 [<ref>19 U.S.C. 2253</ref>] unless the United States International Trade Commission, in addition to making an affirmative determination with respect to such article under section 202(b) of the Trade Act of 1974 [<ref>19 U.S.C. 2252(b)</ref>], determines in the course of its investigation under such section that the serious injury (or threat thereof) substantially caused by imports to the domestic industry producing a like or directly competitive article results from the duty-free treatment provided by this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Any action taken under section 203 of the Trade Act of 1974 [<ref>19 U.S.C. 2253</ref>] that is in effect when duty-free treatment pursuant to section 2701 <sup>1</sup> of this title is proclaimed shall remain in effect until modified or terminated.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> If any article is subject to any such action at the time duty-free treatment is proclaimed pursuant to section 2701 <sup>1</sup> of this title, the President may reduce or terminate the application of such action to the importation of such article from beneficiary countries prior to the otherwise scheduled date on which such reduction or termination would occur pursuant to the criteria and procedures of section 203 of the Trade Act of 1974 [<ref>19 U.S.C. 2253</ref>].</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Petitions to International Trade Commission</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> If a petition is filed with the International Trade Commission pursuant to the provisions of section 201 of the Trade Act of 1974 [<ref>19 U.S.C. 2251</ref>] regarding a perishable product and alleging injury from imports from beneficiary countries, then the petition may also be filed with the Secretary of Agriculture with a request that emergency relief be granted pursuant to paragraph (3) of this subsection with respect to such article.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Within fourteen days after the filing of a petition under paragraph (1) of this subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> if the Secretary of Agriculture has reason to believe that a perishable product from a beneficiary country is being imported into the United States in such increased quantities as to be a substantial cause of serious injury, or the threat thereof, to the domestic industry producing a perishable product like or directly competitive with the imported product and that emergency action is warranted, he shall advise the President and recommend that the President take emergency action; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Agriculture shall publish a notice of his determination not to recommend the imposition of emergency action and so advise the petitioner.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Within seven days after the President receives a recommendation from the Secretary of Agriculture to take emergency action pursuant to paragraph (2) of this subsection, he shall issue a proclamation withdrawing the duty-free treatment provided by this chapter or publish a notice of his determination not to take emergency action.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> The emergency action provided by paragraph (3) of this subsection shall cease to apply—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> upon the taking of action under section 203 of the Trade Act of 1974 [<ref>19 U.S.C. 2253</ref>],</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> on the day a determination by the President not to take action <sup>2</sup> under section 203 of such Act [<ref>19 U.S.C. 2253</ref>] not to take action <sup>2</sup> becomes final,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> in the event of a report of the United States International Trade Commission containing a negative finding, on the day the Commission’s report is submitted to the President, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> whenever the President determines that because of changed circumstances such relief is no longer warranted.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of this subsection, the term “perishable product” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> live plants and fresh cut flowers provided for in chapter 6 of the HTS;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> fresh or chilled vegetables provided for in headings 0701 through 0709 (except subheading 0709.52.00) and heading 0714 of the HTS;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> fresh fruit provided for in subheadings 0804.20 through 0810.90 (except citrons of subheading 0805.90.00, tamarinds and kiwi fruit of subheading 0810.90.20, and cashew apples, mameyes colorados, sapodillas, soursops and sweetsops of subheading 0810.90.40) of the HTS; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> concentrated citrus fruit juice provided for in subheadings 2009.11.00, 2009.19.40, 2009.20.40, 2009.30.20, and 2009.30.60 of the HTS.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fees not affected by proclamation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No proclamation issued pursuant to this chapter shall affect fees imposed pursuant to <ref>section 624 of title 7</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duty reduction for certain leather-related products</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Subject to paragraph (2), the President shall proclaim reductions in the rates of duty on handbags, luggage, flat goods, work gloves, and leather wearing apparel that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> are the product of any beneficiary country; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> were not designated on <date date="1983-08-05">August 5, 1983</date>, as eligible articles for purposes of the generalized system of preferences under title V of the Trade Act of 1974 [<ref>19 U.S.C. 2461</ref> et seq.].</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The reduction required under paragraph (1) in the rate of duty on any article shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> result in a rate that is equal to 80 percent of the rate of duty that applies to the article on <date date="1991-12-31">December 31, 1991</date>, except that, subject to the limitations in paragraph (3), the reduction may not exceed 2.5 percent ad valorem; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> be implemented in 5 equal annual stages with the first one-fifth of the aggregate reduction in the rate of duty being applied to entries, or withdrawals from warehouse for consumption, of the article on or after <date date="1992-01-01">January 1, 1992</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The reduction required under this subsection with respect to the rate of duty on any article is in addition to any reduction in the rate of duty on that article that may be proclaimed by the President as being required or appropriate to carry out any trade agreement entered into under the Uruguay Round of trade negotiations; except that if the reduction so proclaimed—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is less than 1.5 percent ad valorem, the aggregate of such proclaimed reduction and the reduction under this subsection may not exceed 3.5 percent ad valorem, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is 1.5 percent ad valorem or greater, the aggregate of such proclaimed reduction and the reduction under this subsection may not exceed the proclaimed reduction plus 1 percent ad valorem.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–67, title II, § 213</ref>, <date date="1983-08-05">Aug. 5, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 387</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–573, title II, § 235</ref>, <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2992</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–514, title IV, § 423(f)(2)</ref>, title XVIII, § 1890, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 2232</ref>, 2926; <ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title I</ref>, §§ 1214(q)(2), 1401(b)(2), <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1159</ref>, 1239; <ref>Pub. L. 100–647, title IX, § 9001(a)(14)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3808</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–382, title II</ref>, §§ 212, 215(a), <date date="1990-08-20">Aug. 20, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 655</ref>, 657; <ref>Pub. L. 103–465, title IV, § 404(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4961</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–200, title II</ref>, §§ 211(a), (e)(1)(B), 212, <date date="2000-05-18">May 18, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 276</ref>, 287, 288; <ref>Pub. L. 107–206, title III, § 3001[(a)]</ref>, <date date="2002-08-02">Aug. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 909</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–210, div. C, title XXXI, § 3107(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-08-06">Aug. 6, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1035</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–429, title I, § 1558</ref>, title II, § 2004(b), <date date="2004-12-03">Dec. 3, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2579</ref>, 2592; <ref>Pub. L. 109–53, title IV, § 402(c)</ref>, (d), <date date="2005-08-02">Aug. 2, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 496</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–432, div. D, title V, § 5005(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3189</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title XV, § 15408</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1546</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title XV, § 15408, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2308; <ref>Pub. L. 111–171, § 3(1)</ref>, <date date="2010-05-24">May 24, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 1195</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–164, § 2</ref>, <date date="2020-10-10">Oct. 10, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 758</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–260, div. O, title VI, § 602(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 2152</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2703a.</num>
<heading> Special rules for Haiti</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initial applicable 1-year period</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “initial applicable 1-year period” means the 1-year period beginning on <date date="2006-12-20">December 20, 2006</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appropriate congressional committees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “appropriate congressional committees” means the Committee on Finance of the Senate and the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Core labor standards</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “core labor standards” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> freedom of association;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the effective recognition of the right to bargain collectively;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the elimination of all forms of compulsory or forced labor;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the effective abolition of child labor and a prohibition on the worst forms of child labor; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the elimination of discrimination in respect of employment and occupation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Enter; entry</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The terms “enter” and “entry” refer to the entry, or withdrawal from warehouse for consumption, in the customs territory of the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Imported directly from Haiti or the Dominican Republic</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Articles are “imported directly from Haiti or the Dominican Republic” if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the articles are shipped directly from Haiti or the Dominican Republic into the United States without passing through the territory of any intermediate country; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> the articles are shipped from Haiti or the Dominican Republic into the United States through the territory of an intermediate country, and—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the articles in the shipment do not enter into the commerce of any intermediate country, and the invoices, bills of lading, and other shipping documents specify the United States as the final destination; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> the invoices and other documents do not specify the United States as the final destination, but the articles in the shipment—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> remain under the control of the customs authority in the intermediate country;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> do not enter into the commerce of the intermediate country except for the purpose of a sale other than at retail; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> have not been subjected to operations in the intermediate country other than loading, unloading, or other activities necessary to preserve the articles in good condition.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Knit-to-shape</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A good is “knit-to-shape” if 50 percent or more of the exterior surface area of the good is formed by major parts that have been knitted or crocheted directly to the shape used in the good, with no consideration being given to patch pockets, appliqués, or the like. Minor cutting, trimming, or sewing of those major parts shall not affect the determination of whether a good is “knit-to-shape.” <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002144">1</ref></p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> TAICNAR Program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “TAICNAR Program” means the Technical Assistance Improvement and Compliance Needs Assessment and Remediation Program established pursuant to subsection (e).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Wholly assembled</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A good is “wholly assembled” in Haiti if all components, of which there must be at least two, pre-existed in essentially the same condition as found in the finished good and were combined to form the finished good in Haiti. Minor attachments and minor embellishments (for example, appliqués, beads, spangles, embroidery, and buttons) not appreciably affecting the identity of the good, and minor subassemblies (for example, collars, cuffs, plackets, and pockets), shall not affect the determination of whether a good is “wholly assembled” in Haiti.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Apparel and other textile articles</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Value-added rule for apparel articles</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Apparel articles described in subparagraph (B) of a producer or entity controlling production that are imported directly from Haiti or the Dominican Republic shall enter the United States free of duty during the initial applicable 1-year period and any 1-year period thereafter, subject to the limitations set forth in subparagraphs (B) and (C), and subject to subparagraph (D).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Apparel articles described</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">In the initial applicable 1-year period and any 1-year period thereafter, apparel articles described in this paragraph are apparel articles that are wholly assembled, or are knit-to-shape, in Haiti from any combination of fabrics, fabric components, components knit-to-shape, and yarns, only if, for each entry in that 1-year period, the sum of—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the cost or value of the materials produced in Haiti or one or more countries described in clause (iii), or any combination thereof, plus</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the direct costs of processing operations (as defined in <ref>section 2703(a)(3) of this title</ref>) performed in Haiti or one or more countries described in clause (iii), or any combination thereof,</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent3 firstIndent-1"> is not less than the applicable percentage (as defined in clause (v)(I)) of the declared customs value of such apparel articles.</continuation>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deductions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">In calculating cost or value under clause (i)(I), there shall be deducted the cost or value of—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> any foreign materials that are used in the production of the apparel articles in Haiti; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> any foreign materials that are used in the production of the materials described in clause (i)(I).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Countries described</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">The countries referred to in clause (i) are the following:</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> The United States.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> Any country that is a party to a free trade agreement with the United States that is in effect on <date date="2006-12-20">December 20, 2006</date>, or that enters into force thereafter.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> Any country designated as a beneficiary country under <ref>section 2703(b)(5)(B) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> Any country designated as a beneficiary country under <ref>section 2466a(a)(1) of this title</ref>, if a finding has been made by the President or the President’s designee, and published in the Federal Register, that the country has satisfied the requirements of <ref>section 3722 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(V)</num>
<content> Any country designated as a beneficiary country under <ref>section 3203(b)(6)(B) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iv)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual aggregation</heading>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(I)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initial applicable 1-year period</heading>
<chapeau class="indent4">In the initial applicable 1-year period, the requirements under clause (i) relating to applicable percentage may also be met for articles of a producer or an entity controlling production that enter during the initial applicable 1-year period by aggregating—</chapeau>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> the cost or value of materials under subclause (I) of clause (i), and</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> the direct costs of processing operations under subclause (II) of clause (i),</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<continuation class="indent4 firstIndent-2">  of all apparel articles of that producer or entity controlling production that are wholly assembled, or are knit-to-shape, in Haiti and are entered during the initial applicable 1-year period.</continuation>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(II)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other 1-year periods</heading>
<chapeau class="indent4">In any 1-year period after the initial applicable 1-year period, the requirements under clause (i) relating to applicable percentage may also be met for articles of a producer or an entity controlling production that enter during the 1-year period by aggregating—</chapeau>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> the cost or value of materials under subclause (I) of clause (i), and</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> the direct costs of processing operations under subclause (II) of clause (i),</content>
</item>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent4 firstIndent-2">  of all apparel articles of that producer or entity controlling production that are wholly assembled, or are knit-to-shape, in Haiti and are entered during the preceding 1-year period.</continuation>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(III)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deductions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent4">In calculating cost or value under subclause (I)(aa) or (II)(aa), there shall be deducted the cost or value of—</chapeau>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> any foreign materials that are used in the production of the apparel articles in Haiti; and</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> any foreign materials that are used in the production of the materials described in subclause (I)(aa) or (II)(aa) (as the case may be).</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(IV)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inclusion in calculation of other articles receiving preferential treatment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent4">Entries of apparel articles that receive preferential treatment under any provision of law other than this subparagraph or are subject to the “General” column 1 rate of duty under the HTS are not included in the annual aggregation under subclause (I) or (II) unless the producer or entity controlling production elects, at the time the annual aggregation calculation is made, to include such entries in such aggregation.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(v)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">In this paragraph:</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(I)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicable percentage</heading>
<chapeau class="indent4">The term “applicable percentage” means—</chapeau>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> 50 percent or more during the initial applicable 1-year period and the succeeding 8 1-year periods;</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> 55 percent or more during the 1-year period beginning on <date date="2015-12-20">December 20, 2015</date>, and the 1-year period beginning on <date date="2016-12-20">December 20, 2016</date>; and</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(cc)</num>
<content> 60 percent or more during the 1-year period beginning on <date date="2017-12-20">December 20, 2017</date>, and each of the 7 succeeding 1-year periods.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(II)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Foreign material</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent4">The term “foreign material” means a material produced in a country other than Haiti or any country described in clause (iii).</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(vi)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Development of procedure to ensure compliance</heading>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(I)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent4">U.S. Customs and Border Protection of the Department of Homeland Security shall develop and implement methods and procedures to ensure ongoing compliance with the requirements set forth in clauses (i) and (iv).</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(II)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Noncompliance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent4">If U.S. Customs and Border Protection finds that a producer or an entity controlling production has not satisfied such requirements in the initial applicable 1-year period or any 1-year period thereafter, either for individual entries entered pursuant to clause (i) or for entries entered in aggregate pursuant to clause (iv), then apparel articles described in clause (i) of that producer or entity shall be ineligible for preferential treatment under paragraph (1) during any succeeding 1-year period until—</chapeau>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> the cost or value of materials under subclause (I) of clause (i), plus</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> the direct costs of processing operations under subclause (II) of clause (i),</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<continuation class="indent4 firstIndent-2">  of that producer or entity controlling production, is not less than the applicable percentage under clause (v)(I), plus 10 percent, of the aggregate declared customs value of all apparel articles of that producer or entity controlling production that are wholly assembled, or are knit-to-shape, in Haiti and are entered during the preceding 1-year period.</continuation>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(III)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Retroactive application of duty-free treatment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent4">If—</chapeau>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> a producer or an entity controlling production is ineligible for preferential treatment under subparagraph (A) in the initial applicable 1-year period or any 1-year period thereafter because that producer or entity controlling production did not satisfy the requirements of clause (i) or (iv), and</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> that producer or entity controlling production satisfies the requirements of subclause (II) of this clause in that 1-year period,</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<continuation class="indent4 firstIndent-2">  then, notwithstanding <ref>section 1514 of this title</ref> or any other provision of law, upon proper request filed with U.S. Customs and Border Protection before the 90th day after U.S. Customs and Border Protection determines that item (bb) applies, the entry of any articles—</continuation>
<subitem class="indent5">
<num>(AA)</num>
<content> that was made during that 1-year period, and</content>
</subitem>
<subitem class="indent5">
<num>(BB)</num>
<content> with respect to which there would have been preferential treatment under subparagraph (A) if the producer or entity controlling production had satisfied the requirements in clause (i) or (iv) (as the case may be),</content>
</subitem>
<continuation class="indent4 firstIndent-2">  shall be liquidated or reliquidated as though such preferential treatment under subparagraph (A) applied to such entry.</continuation>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(vii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fabrics not available in commercial quantities</heading>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(I)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent4">For purposes of determining the applicable percentage under clause (i) or (iv), there may be included in that percentage—</chapeau>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> the cost of fabrics or yarns to the extent that apparel articles of such fabrics or yarns would be eligible for preferential treatment, without regard to the source of the fabrics or yarns, under Annex 4–B of the USMCA; and</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(bb)</num>
<chapeau> the cost of fabrics or yarns that are designated as not being available in commercial quantities for purposes of—</chapeau>
<subitem class="indent6">
<num>(AA)</num>
<content><ref>section 2703(b)(2)(A)(v) of this title</ref>,</content>
</subitem>
<subitem class="indent6">
<num>(BB)</num>
<content><ref>section 3721(b)(5) of this title</ref>,</content>
</subitem>
<subitem class="indent6">
<num>(CC)</num>
<content> section 3203(b)(3)(B)(i)(III) or (ii) of this title, or</content>
</subitem>
<subitem class="indent6">
<num>(DD)</num>
<content> any other provision, relating to determining whether a textile or apparel article is an originating good eligible for preferential treatment, of a law that implements a free trade agreement that enters into force with respect to the United States,</content>
</subitem>
</item>
</subclause>
<continuation class="indent4 firstIndent-2">  without regard to the source of the fabrics or yarns.</continuation>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(II)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Removal of designation of fabrics or yarns not available in commercial quantities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent4">If the President determines that—</chapeau>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> any fabric or yarn described in subclause (I)(aa) was determined to be eligible for preferential treatment, or</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> any fabric or yarn described in subclause (I)(bb) was designated as not being available in commercial quantities,</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<continuation class="indent4 firstIndent-2">  on the basis of fraud, the President is authorized to remove the eligibility or designation (as the case may be) of that fabric or yarn with respect to articles entered after such removal.</continuation>
</clause>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Quantitative limitations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The preferential treatment described in subparagraph (A) shall be extended, during each of the 1-year periods set forth in the following table, to not more than the corresponding percentage of the aggregate square meter equivalents of all apparel articles imported into the United States in the most recent 12-month period for which data are available:<table width="50%" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><colgroup><col/><col/></colgroup><thead><tr class="header"><th><p><b>During:</b></p></th><th><p><b>the corresponding percentage is:</b></p></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><p>the initial applicable 1-year period</p></td><td><p>1 percent.</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>each of the 16 succeeding 1-year periods</span></p></td><td><p>1.25 percent.</p></td></tr></tbody></table>
</p>
<p class="indent2 firstIndent0">No preferential treatment shall be provided under subparagraph (A) after <date date="2025-12-19">December 19, 2025</date>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other preferential treatment not affected by quantitative limitations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Any apparel article that qualifies for preferential treatment under paragraph (2), (3), (4), or (5) or any other provision of this chapter shall not be subject to, or included in the calculation of, the quantitative limitations under subparagraph (C).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rule for woven articles and certain knit articles</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rule for articles of chapter 62 of the HTS</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General rule</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Any apparel article classifiable under chapter 62 of the HTS that is wholly assembled, or knit-to-shape, in Haiti from any combination of fabrics, fabric components, components knit-to-shape, or yarns and is imported directly from Haiti or the Dominican Republic shall enter the United States free of duty, subject to clauses (ii) and (iii), without regard to the source of the fabric, fabric components, components knit-to-shape, or yarns from which the article is made.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Except as provided in paragraph (2A), the preferential treatment described in clause (i) shall be extended, in the 1-year period beginning <date date="2008-10-01">October 1, 2008</date>, and in each of the 16 succeeding 1-year periods, to not more than 70,000,000 square meter equivalents of apparel articles described in such clause.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other preferential treatment not affected by quantitative limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Any apparel article that qualifies for preferential treatment under paragraph (1), (3), (4), or (5) or subparagraph (B) of this paragraph or any other provision of this chapter shall not be subject to, or included in the calculation of, the quantitative limitation under clause (ii).</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rule for certain articles of chapter 61 of the HTS</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General rule</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Any apparel article classifiable under chapter 61 of the HTS that is wholly assembled, or knit-to-shape, in Haiti from any combination of fabrics, fabric components, components knit-to-shape, or yarns and is imported directly from Haiti or the Dominican Republic shall enter the United States free of duty, subject to clauses (ii), (iii), and (iv), without regard to the source of the fabric, fabric components, components knit-to-shape, or yarns from which the article is made.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exclusions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">The preferential treatment described in clause (i) shall not apply to the following:</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<chapeau> The following apparel articles of cotton, for men or boys, that are classifiable under subheading 6109.10.00 of the HTS:</chapeau>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> All white T-shirts, with short hemmed sleeves and hemmed bottom, with crew or round neckline or with V-neck and with a mitered seam at the center of the V, and without pockets, trim, or embroidery.</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> All white singlets, without pockets, trim, or embroidery.</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(cc)</num>
<content> Other T-shirts, but not including thermal undershirts.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> T-shirts for men or boys that are classifiable under subheading 6109.90.10.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<chapeau> The following apparel articles of cotton, for men or boys, that are classifiable under subheading 6110.20.20 of the HTS:</chapeau>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> Sweatshirts.</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> Pullovers, other than sweaters, vests, or garments imported as part of playsuits.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> Sweatshirts for men or boys, of man-made fibers and containing less than 65 percent by weight of man-made fibers, that are classifiable under subheading 6110.30.30 of the HTS.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Except as provided in paragraph (2A), the preferential treatment described in clause (i) shall be extended, in the 1-year period beginning <date date="2008-10-01">October 1, 2008</date>, and in each of the 16 succeeding 1-year periods, to not more than 70,000,000 square meter equivalents of apparel articles described in such clause.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iv)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other preferential treatment not affected by quantitative limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Any apparel article that qualifies for preferential treatment under paragraph (1), (3), (4), or (5) or subparagraph (A) of this paragraph or any other provision of this chapter shall not be subject to, or included in the calculation of, the quantitative limitation under clause (iii).</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rule for certain woven articles and certain knit articles entered during fiscal year 2010 and succeeding 1-year periods</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Except as provided in subparagraphs (B) and (C) and subject to subparagraph (D), if 52,000,000 square meter equivalents of apparel articles described in paragraph (2)(A)(i) or (2)(B)(i) enter the United States during the 1-year period beginning <date date="2009-10-01">October 1, 2009</date>, or any of the succeeding 1-year periods, the President shall extend the preferential treatment described in paragraph (2)(A)(i) or (2)(B)(i) (as the case may be) to not more than 200,000,000 square meter equivalents of apparel articles described in paragraph (2)(A)(i) or (2)(B)(i) (as the case may be) during that 1-year period, and shall publish notice of the extension in the Federal Register.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception for certain woven articles</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">In the case of apparel articles described in clause (ii), subparagraph (A) shall be applied by substituting “70,000,000” for “200,000,000”.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Apparel articles described</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">Apparel articles described in this clause are apparel articles described in paragraph (2)(A)(i) that are the following:</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(I)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Category 347</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent4">Apparel articles in category 347 that fall within the following statistical reporting numbers of the HTS (as in effect on the day before <date date="2010-05-24">May 24, 2010</date>):<table width="50%" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><colgroup><col/><col/><col/></colgroup><thead><tr class="header"><td/></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>6203.19.1020</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>6203.42.4011</span></p></td><td><p>6203.42.4061</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>6203.19.9020</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>6203.42.4016</span></p></td><td><p>6203.49.8020</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>6203.22.3020</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>6203.42.4026</span></p></td><td><p>6210.40.9033</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>6203.22.3030</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>6203.42.4036</span></p></td><td><p>6211.20.1520</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>6203.42.4003</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>6203.42.4046</span></p></td><td><p>6211.20.3810</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>6203.42.4006</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>6203.42.4051</span></p></td><td><p>6211.32.0040</p></td></tr></tbody></table>
</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(II)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Category 348</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent4">Apparel articles in category 348 that fall within the following statistical reporting numbers of the HTS (as in effect on the day before <date date="2010-05-24">May 24, 2010</date>):<table width="50%" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><colgroup><col/><col/><col/></colgroup><thead><tr class="header"><td/></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>6204.12.0030</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>6204.62.4011</span></p></td><td><p>6204.69.9010</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>6204.19.8030</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>6204.62.4021</span></p></td><td><p>6210.50.9060</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>6204.22.3040</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>6204.62.4031</span></p></td><td><p>6211.20.1550</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>6204.22.3050</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>6204.62.4041</span></p></td><td><p>6211.20.6810</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>6204.29.4034</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>6204.62.4051</span></p></td><td><p>6211.42.0030</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>6204.62.3000</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>6204.62.4056</span></p></td><td><p>6217.90.9050</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>6204.62.4003</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>6204.62.4066</span></p></td><td><p> </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>6204.62.4006</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>6204.69.6010</span></p></td><td><p> </p></td></tr></tbody></table>
</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(III)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Category 647</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent4">Apparel articles in category 647 that fall within the following statistical reporting numbers of the HTS (as in effect on the day before <date date="2010-05-24">May 24, 2010</date>):<table width="50%" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><colgroup><col/><col/><col/></colgroup><thead><tr class="header"><td/></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>6203.23.0060</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>6203.43.4020</span></p></td><td><p>6203.49.8030</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>6203.23.0070</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>6203.43.4030</span></p></td><td><p>6210.40.5031</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>6203.29.2030</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>6203.43.4040</span></p></td><td><p>6210.40.5039</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>6203.29.2035</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>6203.49.1500</span></p></td><td><p>6211.20.1525</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>6203.43.2500</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>6203.49.2015</span></p></td><td><p>6211.20.3820</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>6203.43.3510</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>6203.49.2030</span></p></td><td><p>6211.33.0030</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>6203.43.3590</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>6203.49.2045</span></p></td><td><p> </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>6203.43.4010</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>6203.49.2060</span></p></td><td><p> </p></td></tr></tbody></table>
</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(IV)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Category 648</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent4">Apparel articles in category 648 that fall within the following statistical reporting numbers of the HTS (as in effect on the day before <date date="2010-05-24">May 24, 2010</date>):<table width="50%" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><colgroup><col/><col/><col/></colgroup><thead><tr class="header"><td/></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>6204.23.0040</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>6204.63.3510</span></p></td><td><p>6204.69.6030</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>6204.23.0045</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>6204.63.3530</span></p></td><td><p>6204.69.9030</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>6204.29.2020</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>6204.63.3532</span></p></td><td><p>6210.50.5031</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>6204.29.2025</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>6204.63.3540</span></p></td><td><p>6210.50.5039</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>6204.29.4038</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>6204.69.2510</span></p></td><td><p>6211.20.1555</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>6204.63.2000</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>6204.69.2530</span></p></td><td><p>6211.20.6820</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>6204.63.3010</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>6204.69.2540</span></p></td><td><p>6211.43.0040</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>6204.63.3090</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>6204.69.2560</span></p></td><td><p>6217.90.9060</p></td></tr></tbody></table>
</p>
</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception for certain knit articles</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">In the case of apparel articles described in clause (ii), subparagraph (A) shall be applied by substituting “85,000,000” for “200,000,000”.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Apparel articles described</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Apparel articles described in this clause are apparel articles described in paragraph (2)(B)(i) that fall within the following statistical reporting numbers of the HTS (as in effect on the day before <date date="2010-05-24">May 24, 2010</date>), other than shirts with plackets and pointed collars:<table width="50%" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><colgroup><col/><col/><col/></colgroup><thead><tr class="header"><td/></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>6105.10.0010</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>6109.10.0040</span></p></td><td><p>6110.30.3053</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>6109.10.0018</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>6109.10.0045</span></p></td><td><p>6110.30.3059</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>6109.10.0027</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>6110.20.2079</span></p></td><td><p> </p></td></tr></tbody></table>
</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Verification with respect to transshipment for certain apparel articles</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Not later than April 1, July 1, October 1, and January 1 of each year, the Commissioner responsible for United States Customs and Border Protection shall verify that apparel articles imported into the United States under this paragraph are not being unlawfully transshipped (within the meaning of subsection (f)) into the United States.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report to President</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">If the Commissioner determines pursuant to clause (i) that apparel articles imported into the United States under this paragraph are being unlawfully transshipped into the United States, the Commissioner shall report that determination to the President.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority to reduce quantitative limitation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">If, in any 1-year period with respect to which the President extends preferential treatment as described in this paragraph, the Commissioner reports to the President pursuant to clause (ii) regarding unlawful transshipments, the President—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> may modify the quantitative limitation under this paragraph as the President considers appropriate to account for such transshipments; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> if the President modifies the limitation under subclause (I), shall publish notice of the modification in the Federal Register.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(E)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Category defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In this paragraph, the term “category” means the number assigned under the U.S. Textile and Apparel Category System of the Office of Textiles and Apparel of the Department of Commerce, as listed in the HTS under the applicable heading or subheading (as in effect on the day before <date date="2010-05-24">May 24, 2010</date>).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Apparel and other articles subject to certain assembly rules</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Brassieres</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Any apparel article classifiable under subheading 6212.10 of the HTS that is wholly assembled, or knit-to-shape, in Haiti from any combination of fabrics, fabric components, components knit-to-shape, or yarns and is imported directly from Haiti or the Dominican Republic shall enter the United States free of duty, without regard to the source of the fabric, fabric components, components knit-to-shape, or yarns from which the article is made.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other apparel articles</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Any of the following apparel articles that is wholly assembled, or knit-to-shape, in Haiti from any combination of fabrics, fabric components, components knit-to-shape, or yarns and is imported directly from Haiti or the Dominican Republic shall enter the United States free of duty, without regard to the source of the fabric, fabric components, components knit-to-shape, or yarns from which the article is made:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Any apparel article that is of a type listed in chapter rule 3, 4, or 5 for chapter 61 of the HTS (as such chapter rules are contained in section A of the Annex to Proclamation 8213 of the President of <date date="2007-12-20">December 20, 2007</date>) as being excluded from the scope of such chapter rule, when such chapter rule is applied to determine whether an apparel article is an originating good for purposes of general note 29(n) to the HTS, except that, for purposes of this clause, reference in such chapter rules to “6104.12.00” shall be deemed to be a reference to “6104.19.60”.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> Subject to subclause (II), any apparel article that is of a type listed in chapter rule 3(a), 4(a), or 5(a) for chapter 62 of the HTS, as such chapter rules are contained in paragraph 9 of section A of the Annex to Proclamation 8213 of the President of <date date="2007-12-20">December 20, 2007</date>.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> Subclause (I) shall not include any apparel article to which subparagraph (A) of this paragraph applies.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Luggage and similar items</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Any article classifiable under subheading 4202.12, 4202.22, 4202.32 or 4202.92 of the HTS that is wholly assembled in Haiti and is imported directly from Haiti or the Dominican Republic shall enter the United States free of duty, without regard to the source of the fabric, components, or materials from which the article is made.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Headgear</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Any article classifiable under heading 6501, 6502, or 6504 of the HTS, or under subheading 6505.90 of the HTS, that is wholly assembled, knit-to-shape, or formed in Haiti from any combination of fabrics, fabric components, components knit-to-shape, or yarns and is imported directly from Haiti or the Dominican Republic shall enter the United States free of duty, without regard to the source of the fabric, fabric components, components knit-to-shape, or yarns from which the article is made.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(E)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certain sleepwear</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Any of the following apparel articles that is wholly assembled, or knit-to-shape, in Haiti from any combination of fabrics, fabric components, components knit-to-shape, or yarns and is imported directly from Haiti or the Dominican Republic shall enter the United States free of duty, without regard to the source of the fabric, fabric components, components knit-to-shape, or yarns from which the article is made:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Pajama bottoms and other sleepwear for women and girls, of cotton, that are classifiable under subheading 6208.91.30, or of man-made fibers, that are classifiable under subheading 6208.92.00.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Pajama bottoms and other sleepwear for girls, of other textile materials, that are classifiable under subheading 6208.99.20.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(F)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certain other apparel articles</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Any of the apparel articles described in clause (ii) that is wholly assembled, or knit-to-shape, in Haiti from any combination of fabrics, fabric components, components knit-to-shape, or yarns and is imported directly from Haiti or the Dominican Republic shall enter the United States free of duty, without regard to the source of the fabric, fabric components, components knit-to-shape, or yarns from which the article is made.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Articles described</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Apparel articles described in this clause are apparel articles in the following category numbers that fall within the following statistical reporting numbers of the HTS (as in effect on the day before <date date="2010-05-24">May 24, 2010</date>):<table width="50%" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><colgroup><col/><col/></colgroup><thead><tr class="header"><td/></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><p><b>Category Number</b></p></td><td><p><b>HTS Statistical Reporting Number</b></p></td></tr><tr><td><p>334</p></td><td><p>6101.90.9010</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6112.11.0010</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6103.22.0010</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6113.00.9015</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>335</p></td><td><p>6104.22.0010</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6104.29.2010</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6112.11.0020</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>336</p></td><td><p>6104.49.9010</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>338</p></td><td><p>6103.22.0050</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6105.90.8010</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6112.11.0030</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>339</p></td><td><p>6104.22.0060</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6104.29.2049</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6106.90.2510</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6106.90.3010</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6110.20.1031</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6110.20.1033</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6112.11.0040</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>342</p></td><td><p>6104.22.0030</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6104.29.2022</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6104.52.0010</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6104.52.0020</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6104.59.8010</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>350</p></td><td><p>6107.91.0040</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6107.91.0090</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>351</p></td><td><p>6107.21.0010</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6107.21.0020</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6107.91.0030</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6108.31.0010</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6108.31.0020</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>433</p></td><td><p>6103.23.0007</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6103.29.0520</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6103.31.0000</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6103.33.1000</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6103.39.8020</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>434</p></td><td><p>6101.30.1500</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6101.90.0500</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6101.90.9020</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6103.23.0005</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6103.29.0510</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>435</p></td><td><p>6102.30.1000</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6102.90.9010</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6104.23.0010</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6104.29.0510</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6104.29.2012</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6104.33.1000</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6104.39.2020</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>438</p></td><td><p>6103.23.0025</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6103.29.0550</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6104.23.0020</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6104.29.0560</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6104.29.2051</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6105.90.1000</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6105.90.8020</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6106.20.1020</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6106.90.1010</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6106.90.1020</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6106.90.2520</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6106.90.3020</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6110.11.0070</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6110.12.2070</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6110.12.2080</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6110.19.0070</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6110.19.0080</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6110.30.1550</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6110.30.1560</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>633</p></td><td><p>6103.23.0037</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6103.29.1015</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6103.33.2000</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6103.39.1000</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6103.39.8030</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>634</p></td><td><p>6101.30.1000</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6101.90.9030</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6103.23.0036</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6103.29.1010</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6112.12.0010</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6112.19.1010</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6112.20.1010</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6112.20.1030</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6113.00.9025</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>635</p></td><td><p>6102.30.0500</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6102.90.9015</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6104.23.0026</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6104.29.1010</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6104.29.2014</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6104.39.2030</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6112.12.0020</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6112.19.1020</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6112.20.1020</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6112.20.1040</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6113.00.9030</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>636</p></td><td><p>6104.49.9030</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6104.44.2020</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>638</p></td><td><p>6103.23.0075</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6103.29.1050</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6105.90.8030</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6110.30.1050</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6110.30.2051</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6110.30.2053</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6112.12.0030</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6112.19.1030</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>639</p></td><td><p>6104.23.0036</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6104.29.1050</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6104.29.2055</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6106.90.2530</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6106.90.3030</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6110.30.1060</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6110.30.2061</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6110.30.2063</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6112.12.0040</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6112.19.1040</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>651</p></td><td><p>6107.22.0010</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6107.22.0015</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6107.22.0025</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6107.99.1030</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6108.32.0015</p></td></tr></tbody></table>
</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Category defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">In this subparagraph, the term “category” has the meaning given that term in paragraph (2A)(E) of this subsection.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(G)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Made-up textile articles</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Any of the made-up textile articles described in clauses (ii) and (iii) that is wholly assembled, or knit-to-shape, in Haiti from any combination of fabrics, fabric components, components knit-to-shape, or yarns and is imported directly from Haiti or the Dominican Republic shall enter the United States free of duty, without regard to the source of the fabric, fabric components, components knit-to-shape, or yarns from which the article is made.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Articles described</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Made-up textile articles described in this clause are articles in the following category numbers that fall within the following statistical reporting numbers of the HTS (as in effect on the day before <date date="2010-05-24">May 24, 2010</date>):<table width="50%" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><colgroup><col/><col/></colgroup><thead><tr class="header"><td/></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><p><b>Category Number</b></p></td><td><p><b>HTS Statistical Reporting Number</b></p></td></tr><tr><td><p>363</p></td><td><p>6302.60.0020</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6302.91.0015</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6302.91.0035</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6307.90.8940</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>369</p></td><td><p>6304.91.0020</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6304.92.0000</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6302.60.0010</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6302.60.0030</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6302.91.0005</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6302.91.0050</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6307.90.8910</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6307.90.8945</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>5701.90.2020</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>5702.39.2010</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>5702.50.5600</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>5702.99.0500</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>5702.99.1500</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>5705.00.2020</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>5807.10.0510</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>5807.90.0510</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6307.90.3010</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6301.30.0010</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6305.20.0000</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6307.10.1020</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6307.10.1090</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6406.10.7700</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>9404.90.1000</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>9404.90.9505</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6301.30.0020</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6302.91.0045</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>465</p></td><td><p>5701.10.9000</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>5702.50.2000</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>5702.50.4000</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>5702.91.3000</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>5702.91.4000</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>5703.10.2000</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>5703.10.8000</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>5704.10.0010</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>5705.00.2005</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>5705.00.2015</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>5702.31.1000</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>5702.31.2000</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>469</p></td><td><p>6304.19.3040</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6304.91.0050</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6304.99.1500</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6304.99.6010</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>5601.29.0020</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6302.39.0010</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6406.10.9020</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>665</p></td><td><p>5701.90.1030</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>5701.90.2030</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>5702.32.1000</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>5702.32.2000</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>5702.42.2090</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>5702.50.5200</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>5702.92.1000</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>5702.92.9000</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>5703.20.1000</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>5703.30.2000</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>5703.30.8030</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>5703.30.8080</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>5704.10.0090</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>5705.00.2030</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>5703.20.2010</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>5703.20.2090</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>666</p></td><td><p>6304.11.2000</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6304.91.0040</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6304.93.0000</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6304.99.6020</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6301.40.0010</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6301.40.0020</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6301.90.0010</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>669</p></td><td><p>5601.10.2000</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>5601.22.0090</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>5807.10.0520</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>5807.90.0520</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6307.90.3020</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6305.32.0010</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6305.32.0020</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6305.32.0050</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6305.32.0060</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6305.39.0000</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6406.10.9040</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6308.00.0020</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>899</p></td><td><p>6304.11.3000</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6304.19.3060</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6304.91.0070</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6304.99.3500</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6304.99.6040</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>5601.29.0090</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6301.90.0030</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6305.90.0000</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6406.10.9060</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>900</p></td><td><p>5601.29.0010</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>5701.90.2010</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p>6301.90.0020</p></td></tr></tbody></table>
</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other articles described</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Made-up textile articles described in this clause are articles that fall within statistical reporting number 6406.10.9090 of the HTS (as in effect on the day before <date date="2010-05-24">May 24, 2010</date>).</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iv)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Category defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">In this subparagraph, the term “category” has the meaning given that term in paragraph (2A)(E) of this subsection.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Earned import allowance rule</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Apparel articles wholly assembled, or knit-to-shape, in Haiti from any combination of fabrics, fabric components, components knit-to-shape, or yarns and imported directly from Haiti or the Dominican Republic shall enter the United States free of duty, without regard to the source of the fabric, fabric components, components knit-to-shape, or yarns from which the articles are made, if such apparel articles are accompanied by an earned import allowance certificate that reflects the amount of credits equal to the total square meter equivalents of such apparel articles, in accordance with the program established under subparagraph (B). For purposes of determining the quantity of square meter equivalents under this subparagraph, the conversion factors listed in “Correlation: U.S. Textile and Apparel Industry Category System with the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States of America, 2008”, or its successor publications, of the United States Department of Commerce, shall apply.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Earned import allowance program</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The Secretary of Commerce shall establish a program to provide earned import allowance certificates to any producer or entity controlling production for purposes of subparagraph (A), based on the elements described in clause (ii).</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Elements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">The elements referred to in clause (i) are the following:</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> One credit shall be issued to a producer or an entity controlling production for every two square meter equivalents of qualifying woven fabric or qualifying knit fabric that the producer or entity controlling production can demonstrate that it purchased for the manufacture in Haiti of articles like or similar to any article eligible for preferential treatment under subparagraph (A). The Secretary of Commerce shall, if requested by a producer or entity controlling production, create and maintain an account for such producer or entity controlling production, into which such credits shall be deposited.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> Such producer or entity controlling production may redeem credits issued under subclause (I) for earned import allowance certificates reflecting such number of earned credits as the producer or entity may request and has available.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Commerce may require any textile mill or other entity located in the United States that exports to Haiti qualifying woven fabric or qualifying knit fabric to submit, upon such export or upon request, documentation, such as a Shipper’s Export Declaration, to the Secretary of Commerce—</chapeau>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> verifying that the qualifying woven fabric or qualifying knit fabric was exported to a producer in Haiti or to an entity controlling production; and</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> identifying such producer or entity controlling production, and the quantity and description of qualifying woven fabric or qualifying knit fabric exported to such producer or entity controlling production.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Commerce may require that a producer or entity controlling production submit documentation to verify purchases of qualifying woven fabric or qualifying knit fabric.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(V)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Commerce may make available to each person or entity identified in documentation submitted under subclause (III) or (IV) information contained in such documentation that relates to the purchase of qualifying woven fabric or qualifying knit fabric involving such person or entity.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(VI)</num>
<content> The program under this subparagraph shall be established so as to allow, to the extent feasible, the submission, storage, retrieval, and disclosure of information in electronic format, including information with respect to the earned import allowance certificates required under subparagraph (A)(i).<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002145">2</ref></content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(VII)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Commerce may reconcile discrepancies in information provided under subclause (III) or (IV) and verify the accuracy of such information.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(VIII)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Commerce shall establish procedures to carry out the program under this subparagraph and may establish additional requirements to carry out this subparagraph. Such additional requirements may include—</chapeau>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> submissions by textile mills or other entities in the United States documenting exports of yarns wholly formed in the United States to countries described in paragraph (1)(B)(iii) for the manufacture of qualifying knit fabric; and</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> procedures imposed on producers or entities controlling production to allow the Secretary of Commerce to obtain and verify information relating to the production of qualifying knit fabric.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Qualifying woven fabric defined</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">For purposes of this subparagraph, the term “qualifying woven fabric” means fabric wholly formed in the United States from yarns wholly formed in the United States, except that—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> fabric otherwise eligible as qualifying woven fabric shall not be ineligible as qualifying woven fabric because the fabric contains nylon filament yarn to which <ref>section 2703(b)(2)(A)(vii)(IV) of this title</ref> applies;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> fabric that would otherwise be ineligible as qualifying woven fabric because the fabric contains yarns not wholly formed in the United States shall not be ineligible as qualifying woven fabric if the total weight of all such yarns is not more than 10 percent of the total weight of the fabric; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> fabric otherwise eligible as qualifying woven fabric shall not be ineligible as qualifying fabric because the fabric contains yarns covered by clause (i) or (ii) of paragraph (5)(A).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iv)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Qualifying knit fabric defined</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">For purposes of this subparagraph, the term “qualifying knit fabric” means fabric or knit-to-shape components wholly formed or knit-to-shape in any country or any combination of countries described in paragraph (1)(B)(iii), from yarns wholly formed in the United States, except that—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> fabric or knit-to-shape components otherwise eligible as qualifying knit fabric shall not be ineligible as qualifying knit fabric because the fabric or knit-to-shape components contain nylon filament yarn to which <ref>section 2703(b)(2)(A)(vii)(IV) of this title</ref> applies;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> fabric or knit-to-shape components that would otherwise be ineligible as qualifying knit fabric because the fabric or knit-to-shape components contain yarns not wholly formed in the United States shall not be ineligible as qualifying knit fabric if the total weight of all such yarns is not more than 10 percent of the total weight of the fabric or knit-to-shape components; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> fabric or knit-to-shape components otherwise eligible as qualifying knit fabric shall not be ineligible as qualifying knit fabric because the fabric or knit-to-shape components contain yarns covered by clause (i) or (ii) of paragraph (5)(A).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Enforcement provisions</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fraudulent claims of preference</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Any person who makes a false claim for preference under the program established under subparagraph (B) shall be subject to any applicable civil or criminal penalty that may be imposed under the customs laws of the United States or under title 18.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Penalties for other fraudulent information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The Secretary of Commerce may establish and impose penalties for the submission to the Secretary of Commerce of fraudulent information under the program established under subparagraph (B), other than a claim described in clause (i).</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Short supply provision</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Any apparel article that is wholly assembled, or knit-to-shape, in Haiti from any combination of fabrics, fabric components, components knit-to-shape, or yarns and is imported directly from Haiti or the Dominican Republic shall enter the United States free of duty, without regard to the source of the fabrics, fabric components, components knit-to-shape, or yarns from which the article is made, if the fabrics, fabric components, components knit-to-shape, or yarns comprising the component that determines the tariff classification of the article are of any of the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Fabrics or yarns, to the extent that apparel articles of such fabrics or yarns would be eligible for preferential treatment, without regard to the source of the fabrics or yarns, under Annex 4–B of the USMCA.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> Fabrics or yarns, to the extent that such fabrics or yarns are designated as not being available in commercial quantities for purposes of—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content><ref>section 2703(b)(2)(A)(v) of this title</ref>;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content><ref>section 3721(b)(5) of this title</ref>;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> clause (i)(III) or (ii) of <ref>section 3203(b)(3)(B) of this title</ref>; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> any other provision, relating to determining whether a textile or apparel article is an originating good eligible for preferential treatment, of a law that implements a free trade agreement entered into by the United States that is in effect at the time the claim for preferential treatment is made.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Removal of designation of fabrics or yarns not available in commercial quantities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">If the President determines that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any fabric or yarn described in clause (i) of subparagraph (A) was determined to be eligible for preferential treatment, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any fabric or yarn described in clause (ii) of subparagraph (A) was designated as not being available in commercial quantities,</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">on the basis of fraud, the President is authorized to remove the eligibility or designation (as the case may be) of that fabric or yarn with respect to articles entered after such removal.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other preferential treatment not affected</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The duty-free treatment provided under this subsection is in addition to any other preferential treatment under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rule for certain wire harness automotive components</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Any wire harness automotive component that is the product or manufacture of Haiti and is imported directly from Haiti into the customs territory of the United States shall enter the United States free of duty, during the 10-year period beginning on <date date="2006-12-20">December 20, 2006</date>, if Haiti has met the requirements of subsection (d) and if the sum of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the cost or value of the materials produced in Haiti or one or more countries described in subsection (b)(2)(C), or any combination thereof, plus</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the direct costs of processing operations (as defined in <ref>section 2703(a)(3) of this title</ref>) performed in Haiti or the United States, or both,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">is not less than 50 percent of the declared customs value of such wire harness automotive component.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Wire harness automotive component</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, the term “wire harness automotive component” means any article provided for in subheading 8544.30.00 of the HTS, as in effect on <date date="2006-12-20">December 20, 2006</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility requirements</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Haiti shall be eligible for preferential treatment under this section if the President determines and certifies to Congress that Haiti—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> has established, or is making continual progress toward establishing—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a market-based economy that protects private property rights, incorporates an open rules-based trading system, and minimizes government interference in the economy through measures such as price controls, subsidies, and government ownership of economic assets;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the rule of law, political pluralism, and the right to due process, a fair trial, and equal protection under the law;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> the elimination of barriers to United States trade and investment, including by—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the provision of national treatment and measures to create an environment conducive to domestic and foreign investment;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the protection of intellectual property; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> the resolution of bilateral trade and investment disputes;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> economic policies to reduce poverty, increase the availability of health care and educational opportunities, expand physical infrastructure, promote the development of private enterprise, and encourage the formation of capital markets through microcredit or other programs;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> a system to combat corruption and bribery, such as signing and implementing the Convention on Combating Bribery of Foreign Public Officials in International Business Transactions; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> protection of internationally recognized worker rights, including the right of association, the right to organize and bargain collectively, a prohibition on the use of any form of forced or compulsory labor, a minimum age for the employment of children, and acceptable conditions of work with respect to minimum wages, hours of work, and occupational safety and health;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> does not engage in activities that undermine United States national security or foreign policy interests; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> does not engage in gross violations of internationally recognized human rights or provide support for acts of international terrorism and cooperates in international efforts to eliminate human rights violations and terrorist activities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Time limit for determination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The President shall determine whether Haiti meets the requirements of paragraph (1) not later than 90 days after <date date="2006-12-20">December 20, 2006</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Continuing compliance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the President determines that Haiti is not making continual progress in meeting the requirements described in paragraph (1)(A), the President shall terminate the preferential treatment under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Petition process</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any interested party may file a request to have the status of Haiti reviewed with respect to the eligibility requirements listed in paragraph (1), and the President shall provide for this purpose the same procedures as those that are provided for reviewing the status of eligible beneficiary developing countries with respect to the designation criteria listed in subsections (b) and (c) of <ref>section 2462 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Technical assistance improvement and compliance needs assessment and remediation program</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Continued eligibility for preferences</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Presidential certification of compliance by Haiti with requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Upon the expiration of the 16-month period beginning on the date of the enactment of the Haitian Hemispheric Opportunity through Partnership Encouragement Act of 2008, Haiti shall continue to be eligible for the preferential treatment provided under subsection (b) only if the President determines and certifies to the Congress that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Haiti has implemented the requirements set forth in paragraphs (2) and (3); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Haiti has agreed to require producers of articles for which duty-free treatment may be requested under subsection (b) to participate in the TAICNAR Program described in paragraph (3) and has developed a system to ensure participation in such program by such producers, including by developing and maintaining the registry described in paragraph (2)(B)(i).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Extension</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The President may extend the period for compliance by Haiti under subparagraph (A) if the President—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> determines that Haiti has made a good faith effort toward such compliance and has agreed to take additional steps to come into full compliance that are satisfactory to the President; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> provides to the appropriate congressional committees, not later than 6 months after the last day of the 16-month period specified in subparagraph (A), and every 6 months thereafter, a report identifying the steps that Haiti has agreed to take to come into full compliance and the progress made over the preceding 6-month period in implementing such steps.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Continuing compliance</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination of preferential treatment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">If, after making a certification under subparagraph (A), the President determines that Haiti is no longer meeting the requirements set forth in subparagraph (A), the President shall terminate the preferential treatment provided under subsection (b), unless the President determines, after consulting with the appropriate congressional committees, that meeting such requirements is not practicable because of extraordinary circumstances existing in Haiti when the determination is made.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Subsequent compliance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">If the President, after terminating preferential treatment under clause (i), determines that Haiti is meeting the requirements set forth in subparagraph (A), the President shall reinstate the application of preferential treatment under subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Labor Ombudsman</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The requirement under this paragraph is that Haiti has established an independent Labor Ombudsman’s Office within the national government that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> reports directly to the President of Haiti;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> is headed by a Labor Ombudsman chosen by the President of Haiti, in consultation with Haitian labor unions and industry associations; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> is vested with the authority to perform the functions described in subparagraph (B).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Functions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The functions of the Labor Ombudsman’s Office shall include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> developing and maintaining a registry of producers of articles for which duty-free treatment may be requested under subsection (b), and developing, in consultation and coordination with any other appropriate officials of the Government of Haiti, a system to ensure participation by such producers in the TAICNAR Program described in paragraph (3);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> overseeing the implementation of the TAICNAR Program described in paragraph (3);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> receiving and investigating comments from any interested party regarding the conditions described in paragraph (3)(B) in facilities of producers listed in the registry described in clause (i) and, where appropriate, referring such comments or the result of such investigations to the appropriate Haitian authorities, or to the entity operating the TAICNAR Program described in paragraph (3);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> assisting, in consultation and coordination with any other appropriate Haitian authorities, producers listed in the registry described in clause (i) in meeting the conditions set forth in paragraph (3)(B); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> coordinating, with the assistance of the entity operating the TAICNAR Program described in paragraph (3), a tripartite committee comprised of appropriate representatives of government agencies, employers, and workers, as well as other relevant interested parties, for the purposes of evaluating progress in implementing the TAICNAR Program described in paragraph (3), and consulting on improving core labor standards and working conditions in the textile and apparel sector in Haiti, and on other matters of common concern relating to such core labor standards and working conditions.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Technical assistance improvement and compliance needs assessment and remediation program</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The requirement under this paragraph is that Haiti, in cooperation with the International Labor Organization, has established a Technical Assistance Improvement and Compliance Needs Assessment and Remediation Program meeting the requirements under subparagraph (C)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> to assess compliance by producers listed in the registry described in paragraph (2)(B)(i) with the conditions set forth in subparagraph (B) and to assist such producers in meeting such conditions; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> to provide assistance to improve the capacity of the Government of Haiti—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> to inspect facilities of producers listed in the registry described in paragraph (2)(B)(i); and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> to enforce national labor laws and resolve labor disputes, including through measures described in subparagraph (E).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conditions described</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The conditions referred to in subparagraph (A) are—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> compliance with core labor standards; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> compliance with the labor laws of Haiti that relate directly to core labor standards and to ensuring acceptable conditions of work with respect to minimum wages, hours of work, and occupational health and safety.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The requirements for the TAICNAR Program are that the program—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> be operated by the International Labor Organization (or any subdivision, instrumentality, or designee thereof), which prepares the biannual reports described in subparagraph (D);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> be developed through a participatory process that includes the Labor Ombudsman described in paragraph (2) and appropriate representatives of government agencies, employers, and workers;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> assess compliance by each producer listed in the registry described in paragraph (2)(B)(i) with the conditions set forth in subparagraph (B) and identify any deficiencies by such producer with respect to meeting such conditions, including by—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> conducting unannounced site visits to manufacturing facilities of the producer;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> conducting confidential interviews separately with workers and management of the facilities of the producer;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<chapeau> providing to management and workers, and where applicable, worker organizations in the facilities of the producer, on a confidential basis—</chapeau>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> the results of the assessment carried out under this clause; and</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> specific suggestions for remediating any such deficiencies;</content>
</item>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> assist the producer in remediating any deficiencies identified under clause (iii);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> conduct prompt follow-up site visits to the facilities of the producer to assess progress on remediation of any deficiencies identified under clause (iii); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> provide training to workers and management of the producer, and where appropriate, to other persons or entities, to promote compliance with subparagraph (B).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Biannual report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The biannual reports referred to in subparagraph (C)(i) are a report, by the entity operating the TAICNAR Program, that is published (and available to the public in a readily accessible manner) on a biannual basis, beginning 6 months after Haiti implements the TAICNAR Program under this paragraph, covering the preceding 6-month period, and that includes the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The name of each producer listed in the registry described in paragraph (2)(B)(i) that has been identified as having met the conditions under subparagraph (B).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The name of each producer listed in the registry described in paragraph (2)(B)(i) that has been identified as having deficiencies with respect to the conditions under subparagraph (B), and has failed to remedy such deficiencies.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> For each producer listed under clause (ii)—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> a description of the deficiencies found to exist and the specific suggestions for remediating such deficiencies made by the entity operating the TAICNAR Program;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> a description of the efforts by the producer to remediate the deficiencies, including a description of assistance provided by any entity to assist in such remediation; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> with respect to deficiencies that have not been remediated, the amount of time that has elapsed since the deficiencies were first identified in a report under this subparagraph.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> For each producer identified as having deficiencies with respect to the conditions described under subparagraph (B) in a prior report under this subparagraph, a description of the progress made in remediating such deficiencies since the submission of the prior report, and an assessment of whether any aspect of such deficiencies persists.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(E)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Capacity building</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The assistance to the Government of Haiti referred to in subparagraph (A)(ii) shall include programs—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> to review the labor laws and regulations of Haiti and to develop and implement strategies for bringing the laws and regulations into conformity with core labor standards;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> to develop additional strategies for facilitating protection of core labor standards and providing acceptable conditions of work with respect to minimum wages, hours of work, and occupational safety and health, including through legal, regulatory, and institutional reform;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> to increase awareness of worker rights, including under core labor standards and national labor laws;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> to promote consultation and cooperation between government representatives, employers, worker representatives, and United States importers on matters relating to core labor standards and national labor laws;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> to assist the Labor Ombudsman appointed pursuant to paragraph (2) in establishing and coordinating operation of the committee described in paragraph (2)(B)(v);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> to assist worker representatives in more fully and effectively advocating on behalf of their members; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> to provide on-the-job training and technical assistance to labor inspectors, judicial officers, and other relevant personnel to build their capacity to enforce national labor laws and resolve labor disputes.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compliance with eligibility criteria</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Country compliance with worker rights eligibility criteria</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In making a determination of whether Haiti is meeting the requirement set forth in subsection (d)(1)(A)(vi) relating to internationally recognized worker rights, the President shall consider the reports produced under paragraph (3)(D).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Producer eligibility</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Identification of producers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Beginning in the second calendar year after the President makes the certification under paragraph (1)(A), the President shall identify on a biennial basis whether a producer listed in the registry described in paragraph (2)(B)(i) has failed to comply with core labor standards and with the labor laws of Haiti that directly relate to and are consistent with core labor standards.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistance to producers; withdrawal, etc., of preferential treatment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">For each producer that the President identifies under clause (i), the President shall seek to assist such producer in coming into compliance with core labor standards and with the labor laws of Haiti that directly relate to and are consistent with core labor standards. If such efforts fail, the President shall withdraw, suspend, or limit the application of preferential treatment under subsection (b) to articles of such producer.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reinstating preferential treatment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">If the President, after withdrawing, suspending, or limiting the application of preferential treatment under clause (ii) to articles of a producer, determines that such producer is complying with core labor standards and with the labor laws of Haiti that directly relate to and are consistent with core labor standards, the President shall reinstate the application of preferential treatment under subsection (b) to the articles of the producer.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iv)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consideration of reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">In making the identification under clause (i) and the determination under clause (iii), the President shall consider the reports made available under paragraph (3)(D).</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports by the President</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of the Haitian Hemispheric Opportunity through Partnership Encouragement Act of 2008, and annually thereafter, the President shall transmit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the implementation of this subsection during the preceding 1-year period.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Matters to be included</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Each report required by subparagraph (A) shall include the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> An explanation of the efforts of Haiti, the President, and the International Labor Organization to carry out this subsection.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> A summary of each report produced under paragraph (3)(D) during the preceding 1-year period and a summary of the findings contained in such report.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Identifications made under paragraph (4)(B)(i) and determinations made under paragraph (4)(B)(iii).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this subsection the sum of $10,000,000 for the period beginning on <date date="2008-10-01">October 1, 2008</date>, and ending on <date date="2013-09-30">September 30, 2013</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conditions regarding enforcement of circumvention</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The preferential treatment under subsection (b)(1) shall not apply unless the President certifies to Congress that Haiti is meeting the following conditions:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Haiti has adopted an effective visa system, domestic laws, and enforcement procedures applicable to articles described in subsection (b) to prevent unlawful transshipment of the articles and the use of counterfeit documents relating to the importation of the articles into the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Haiti has enacted legislation or promulgated regulations that would permit U.S. Customs and Border Protection verification teams to have the access necessary to investigate thoroughly allegations of transshipment through such country.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Haiti agrees to report, on a timely basis, at the request of U.S. Customs and Border Protection, on the total exports from and imports into that country of articles described in subsection (b), consistent with the manner in which the records are kept by Haiti.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Haiti agrees to cooperate fully with the United States to address and take action necessary to prevent circumvention as provided in Article 5 of the Agreement on Textiles and Clothing.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Haiti agrees to require all producers and exporters of articles described in subsection (b) in that country to maintain complete records of the production and the export of such articles, including materials used in the production, for at least 5 years after the production or export (as the case may be).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Haiti agrees to report, on a timely basis, at the request of U.S. Customs and Border Protection, documentation establishing the country of origin of articles described in subsection (b) as used by that country in implementing an effective visa system.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition of transshipment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Transshipment within the meaning of this subsection has occurred when preferential treatment for a textile or apparel article under this section has been claimed on the basis of material false information concerning the country of origin, manufacture, processing, or assembly of the article or any of its components. For purposes of this paragraph, false information is material if disclosure of the true information would mean or would have meant that the article is or was ineligible for preferential treatment under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on goods shipped from the Dominican Republic</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Notwithstanding subsection (a)(5), relating to the definition of “imported directly from Haiti or the Dominican Republic”, articles described in subsection (b) that are shipped from the Dominican Republic, directly or through the territory of an intermediate country, whether or not such articles undergo processing in the Dominican Republic, shall not be considered to be “imported directly from Haiti or the Dominican Republic” until the President certifies to the Congress that Haiti and the Dominican Republic have developed procedures to prevent unlawful transshipment of the articles and the use of counterfeit documents related to the importation of the articles into the United States.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Technical and other assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Commissioner responsible for U.S. Customs and Border Protection shall provide technical and other assistance to Haiti and the Dominican Republic to develop expeditiously the procedures described in subparagraph (A).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall issue regulations to carry out this section not later than 180 days after <date date="2006-12-20">December 20, 2006</date>. The President shall consult with the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate in preparing such regulations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as provided in subsection (b)(1), the duty-free treatment provided under this section shall remain in effect until <date date="2025-09-30">September 30, 2025</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–67, title II, § 213A</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 109–432, div. D, title V, § 5002(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3181</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title XV</ref>, §§ 15402–15405, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1527–1545</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title XV, §§ 15402–15405, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2289–2307; <ref>Pub. L. 110–436, § 7</ref>, <date date="2008-10-16">Oct. 16, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4981</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–171</ref>, §§ 3(2)–8, <date date="2010-05-24">May 24, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 1195–1205</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–234, § 2(f)</ref>, <date date="2012-12-28">Dec. 28, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1625</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–27, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="2015-06-29">June 29, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 373</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–260, div. O, title VI, § 602(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 2153</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2704.</num>
<heading> International Trade Commission reports on impact of Caribbean Basin Economic Recovery Program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reporting requirement</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The United States International Trade Commission (in this section referred to as the “Commission”) shall submit to Congress and the President biennial reports regarding the economic impact of this chapter on United States industries and consumers and on the economy of the beneficiary countries.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> First report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The first report shall be submitted not later than <date date="2001-09-30">September 30, 2001</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment of Puerto Rico, etc.</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of this section, industries in the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico and the insular possessions of the United States are considered to be United States industries.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requisite areas of Commission assessment</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Each report required under subsection (a) shall include, but not be limited to, an assessment by the Commission regarding—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the actual effect, during the period covered by the report, of this Act on the United States economy generally as well as on those specific domestic industries which produce articles that are like, or directly competitive with, articles being imported into the United States from beneficiary countries; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the probable future effect which this Act will have on the United States economy generally, as well as on such domestic industries, before the provisions of this Act terminate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> In preparing the assessments required under paragraph (1), the Commission shall, to the extent practicable—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> analyze the production, trade and consumption of United States products affected by this Act, taking into consideration employment, profit levels, and use of productive facilities with respect to the domestic industries concerned, and such other economic factors in such industries as it considers relevant, including prices, wages, sales, inventories, patterns of demand, capital investment, obsolescence of equipment, and diversification of production; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> describe the nature and extent of any significant change in employment, profit levels, and use of productive facilities, and such other conditions as it deems relevant in the domestic industries concerned, which it believes are attributable to this Act.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Time of submission of reports; public participation</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Each report required under subsection (a) shall be submitted to the Congress and to the President before the close of the nine-month period beginning on the day after the last day of the period covered by the report.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Commission shall provide opportunity for the submission by the public, either orally or in writing, or both, of information relating to matters that will be addressed in the reports.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–67, title II, § 215</ref>, <date date="1983-08-05">Aug. 5, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 393</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–200, title II, § 211(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="2000-05-18">May 18, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 287</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2705.</num>
<heading> Impact study by Secretary of Labor</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Labor, in consulation <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002146">1</ref> with other appropriate Federal agencies, shall undertake a continuing review and analysis of the impact which the implementation of the provisions of this chapter have with respect to United States labor; and shall make an annual written report to Congress on the results of such review and analysis.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–67, title II, § 216</ref>, <date date="1983-08-05">Aug. 5, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 394</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2706.</num>
<heading> Effective date</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> This chapter shall take effect on <date date="1983-08-05">August 5, 1983</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 101–382, title II, § 211</ref>, <date date="1990-08-20">Aug. 20, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 655</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–67, title II, § 218</ref>, <date date="1983-08-05">Aug. 5, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 395</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–382, title II, § 211</ref>, <date date="1990-08-20">Aug. 20, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 655</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2707.</num>
<heading> Center for the Study of Western Hemispheric Trade</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commissioner of Customs, after consultation with appropriate officials in the State of Texas, is authorized and directed to make grants to an institution (or a consortium of such institutions) to assist such institution in planning, establishing, and operating a Center for the Study of Western Hemispheric Trade (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Center”). The Commissioner of Customs shall make the first grant not later than <date date="1994-12-01">December 1, 1994</date>, and the Center shall be established not later than <date date="1995-02-01">February 1, 1995</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Scope of Center</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Center shall be a year-round program operated by an institution located in the State of Texas (or a consortium of such institutions), the purpose of which is to promote and study trade between and among Western Hemisphere countries. The Center shall conduct activities designed to examine—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the impact of the NAFTA on the economies in, and trade within, the Western Hemisphere;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the negotiation of any future free trade agreements, including possible accessions to the NAFTA; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> adjusting tariffs, reducing nontariff barriers, improving relations among customs officials, and promoting economic relations among countries in the Western Hemisphere.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation; selection criteria</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Commissioner of Customs shall consult with appropriate officials of the State of Texas and private sector authorities with respect to selecting, planning, and establishing the Center. In selecting the appropriate institution, the Commissioner of Customs shall give consideration to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the institution’s ability to carry out the programs and activities described in this section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any resources the institution can provide the Center in addition to Federal funds provided under this program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Programs and activities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Center shall conduct the following activities:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Provide forums for international discussion and debate for representatives from countries in the Western Hemisphere regarding issues which affect trade and other economic relations within the hemisphere, including the impact of the NAFTA on individual economies and the desirability and feasibility of possible accessions to the NAFTA by such countries.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Conduct studies and research projects on subjects which affect Western Hemisphere trade, including tariffs, customs, regional and national economics, business development and finance, production and personnel management, manufacturing, agriculture, engineering, transportation, immigration, telecommunications, medicine, science, urban studies, border demographics, social anthropology, and population.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Publish materials, disseminate information, and conduct seminars and conferences to support and educate representatives from countries in the Western Hemisphere who seek to do business with or invest in other Western Hemisphere countries.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Provide grants, fellowships, endowed chairs, and financial assistance to outstanding scholars and authorities from Western Hemisphere countries.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Provide grants, fellowships, and other financial assistance to qualified graduate students, from Western Hemisphere countries, to study at the Center.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Implement academic exchange programs and other cooperative research and instructional agreements with the complementary Dante B. Fascell North-South Center at the University of Miami at Coral Gables.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> NAFTA</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “NAFTA” means the North American Free Trade Agreement.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Western Hemisphere countries</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The terms “Western Hemisphere countries”, “countries in the Western Hemisphere”, and “Western Hemisphere” mean Canada, the United States, Mexico, countries located in South America, beneficiary countries (as defined by <ref>section 2702 of this title</ref>), the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and the United States Virgin Islands.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fees for seminars and publications</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a grant made under this section may provide that the Center may charge a reasonable fee for attendance at seminars and conferences and for copies of publications, studies, reports, and other documents the Center publishes. The Center may waive such fees in any case in which it determines imposing a fee would impose a financial hardship and the purposes of the Center would be served by granting such a waiver.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duration of grant</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commissioner of Customs is directed to make grants to any institution or institutions selected as the Center for fiscal years 1994, 1995, 1996, and 1997.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Commissioner of Customs shall, no later than <date date="1994-07-01">July 1, 1994</date>, and annually thereafter for years for which grants are made, submit a written report to the Committee on Finance of the Senate and the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives. The first report shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a statement identifying the institution or institutions selected as the Center;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the reasons for selecting the institution or institutions as the Center; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the plan of such institution or institutions for operating the Center.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Each subsequent report shall include information with respect to the operations of the Center, the collaboration of the Center with, and dissemination of information to, Government policymakers and the business community with respect to the study of Western Hemispheric trade by the Center, and the plan and efforts of the Center to continue operations after grants under this section have expired.</continuation>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–67, title II, § 219</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 103–182, title V, § 515(a)</ref>, <date date="1993-12-08">Dec. 8, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 2158</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–295, § 21(d)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3530</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–29, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1999-05-21">May 21, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 54</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>