<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 22—</num>
<heading>URUGUAY ROUND TRADE AGREEMENTS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3501.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this Act:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> GATT 1947; GATT 1994</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> GATT 1947</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “GATT 1947” means the General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade, dated <date date="1947-10-30">October 30, 1947</date>, annexed to the Final Act Adopted at the Conclusion of the Second Session of the Preparatory Committee of the United Nations Conference on Trade and Employment, as subsequently rectified, amended, or modified by the terms of legal instruments which have entered into force before the date of entry into force of the WTO Agreement.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> GATT 1994</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “GATT 1994” means the General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade annexed to the WTO Agreement.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> HTS</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “HTS” means the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> International Trade Commission</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “International Trade Commission” means the United States International Trade Commission.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Multilateral trade agreement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “multilateral trade agreement” means an agreement described in <ref>section 3511(d) of this title</ref> (other than an agreement described in paragraph (17) or (18) of such section).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Schedule XX</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Schedule XX” means Schedule XX—United States of America annexed to the Marrakesh Protocol to the GATT 1994.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Trade Representative</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Trade Representative” means the United States Trade Representative.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Uruguay Round Agreements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Uruguay Round Agreements” means the agreements approved by the Congress under <ref>section 3511(a)(1) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> World Trade Organization and WTO</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The terms “World Trade Organization” and “WTO” mean the organization established pursuant to the WTO Agreement.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> WTO Agreement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “WTO Agreement” means the Agreement Establishing the World Trade Organization entered into on <date date="1994-04-15">April 15, 1994</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(10)</num>
<heading class="bold"> WTO member and WTO member country</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The terms “WTO member” and “WTO member country” mean a state, or separate customs territory (within the meaning of Article XII of the WTO Agreement), with respect to which the United States applies the WTO Agreement.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–465, § 2</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4813</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>APPROVAL OF, AND GENERAL PROVISIONS RELATING TO, URUGUAY ROUND AGREEMENTS</heading>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part A—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Approval of Agreements and Related Provisions</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3511.</num>
<heading> Approval and entry into force of Uruguay Round Agreements</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Approval of agreements and statement of administrative action</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Pursuant to <ref>section 2903 of this title</ref> and <ref>section 2191 of this title</ref>, the Congress approves—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the trade agreements described in subsection (d) resulting from the Uruguay Round of multilateral trade negotiations under the auspices of the General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade, entered into on <date date="1994-04-15">April 15, 1994</date>, and submitted to the Congress on <date date="1994-09-27">September 27, 1994</date>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the statement of administrative action proposed to implement the agreements that was submitted to the Congress on <date date="1994-09-27">September 27, 1994</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Entry into force</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">At such time as the President determines that a sufficient number of foreign countries are accepting the obligations of the Uruguay Round Agreements, in accordance with article XIV of the WTO Agreement, to ensure the effective operation of, and adequate benefits for the United States under, those Agreements, the President may accept the Uruguay Round Agreements and implement article VIII of the WTO Agreement.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated annually such sums as may be necessary for the payment by the United States of its share of the expenses of the WTO.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Trade agreements to which this Act applies</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subsection (a) applies to the WTO Agreement and to the following agreements annexed to that Agreement:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade 1994.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Agreement on Agriculture.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Agreement on the Application of Sanitary and Phytosanitary Measures.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Agreement on Textiles and Clothing.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The Agreement on Technical Barriers to Trade.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The Agreement on Trade-Related Investment Measures.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The Agreement on Implementation of Article VI of the General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade 1994.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> The Agreement on Implementation of Article VII of the General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade 1994.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> The Agreement on Preshipment Inspection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> The Agreement on Rules of Origin.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> The Agreement on Import Licensing Procedures.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> The Agreement on Subsidies and Countervailing Measures.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> The Agreement on Safeguards.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> The General Agreement on Trade in Services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<content> The Agreement on Trade-Related Aspects of Intellectual Property Rights.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(16)</num>
<content> The Understanding on Rules and Procedures Governing the Settlement of Disputes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(17)</num>
<content> The Agreement on Government Procurement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(18)</num>
<content> The International Bovine Meat Agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–465, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4814</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3512.</num>
<heading> Relationship of agreements to United States law and State law</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Relationship of agreements to United States law</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> United States law to prevail in conflict</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">No provision of any of the Uruguay Round Agreements, nor the application of any such provision to any person or circumstance, that is inconsistent with any law of the United States shall have effect.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Construction</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Nothing in this Act shall be construed—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> to amend or modify any law of the United States, including any law relating to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the protection of human, animal, or plant life or health,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the protection of the environment, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> worker safety, or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to limit any authority conferred under any law of the United States, including <ref>section 2411 of this title</ref>,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">unless specifically provided for in this Act.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Relationship of agreements to State law</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal-State consultation</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">On <date date="1994-12-08">December 8, 1994</date>, the President shall, through the intergovernmental policy advisory committees on trade established under <ref>section 2114c(2)(A) of this title</ref>, consult with the States for the purpose of achieving conformity of State laws and practices with the Uruguay Round Agreements.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal-State consultation process</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Trade Representative shall establish within the Office of the United States Trade Representative a Federal-State consultation process for addressing issues relating to the Uruguay Round Agreements that directly relate to, or will potentially have a direct effect on, the States. The Federal-State consultation process shall include procedures under which—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the States will be informed on a continuing basis of matters under the Uruguay Round Agreements that directly relate to, or will potentially have a direct impact on, the States;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the States will be provided an opportunity to submit, on a continuing basis, to the Trade Representative information and advice with respect to matters referred to in clause (i); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the Trade Representative will take into account the information and advice received from the States under clause (ii) when formulating United States positions regarding matters referred to in clause (i).</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">Chapter 10 of title 5 shall not apply to the Federal-State consultation process established by this paragraph.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal-State cooperation in WTO dispute settlement</heading>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> When a WTO member requests consultations with the United States under Article 4 of the Understanding on Rules and Procedures Governing the Settlement of Disputes referred to in <ref>section 3511(d)(16) of this title</ref> (hereafter in this subsection referred to as the “Dispute Settlement Understanding”) concerning whether the law of a State is inconsistent with the obligations undertaken by the United States in any of the Uruguay Round Agreements, the Trade Representative shall notify the Governor of the State or the Governor’s designee, and the chief legal officer of the jurisdiction whose law is the subject of the consultations, as soon as possible after the request is received, but in no event later than 7 days thereafter.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Not later than 30 days after receiving such a request for consultations, the Trade Representative shall consult with representatives of the State concerned regarding the matter. If the consultations involve the laws of a large number of States, the Trade Representative may consult with an appropriate group of representatives of the States concerned, as determined by those States.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> The Trade Representative shall make every effort to ensure that the State concerned is involved in the development of the position of the United States at each stage of the consultations and each subsequent stage of dispute settlement proceedings regarding the matter. In particular, the Trade Representative shall—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> notify the State concerned not later than 7 days after a WTO member requests the establishment of a dispute settlement panel or gives notice of the WTO member’s decision to appeal a report by a dispute settlement panel regarding the matter; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> provide the State concerned with the opportunity to advise and assist the Trade Representative in the preparation of factual information and argumentation for any written or oral presentations by the United States in consultations or in proceedings of a panel or the Appellate Body regarding the matter.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> If a dispute settlement panel or the Appellate Body finds that the law of a State is inconsistent with any of the Uruguay Round Agreements, the Trade Representative shall consult with the State concerned in an effort to develop a mutually agreeable response to the report of the panel or the Appellate Body and shall make every effort to ensure that the State concerned is involved in the development of the United States position regarding the response.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice to States regarding consultations on foreign subcentral government laws</heading>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Subject to clause (ii), the Trade Representative shall, at least 30 days before making a request for consultations under Article 4 of the Dispute Settlement Understanding regarding a subcentral government measure of another WTO member, notify, and solicit the views of, appropriate representatives of each State regarding the matter.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> In exigent circumstances clause (i) shall not apply, in which case the Trade Representative shall notify the appropriate representatives of each State not later than 3 days after making the request for consultations referred to in clause (i).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Legal challenge</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">No State law, or the application of such a State law, may be declared invalid as to any person or circumstance on the ground that the provision or application is inconsistent with any of the Uruguay Round Agreements, except in an action brought by the United States for the purpose of declaring such law or application invalid.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Procedures governing action</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In any action described in subparagraph (A) that is brought by the United States against a State or any subdivision thereof—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a report of a dispute settlement panel or the Appellate Body convened under the Dispute Settlement Understanding regarding the State law, or the law of any political subdivision thereof, shall not be considered as binding or otherwise accorded deference;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the United States shall have the burden of proving that the law that is the subject of the action, or the application of that law, is inconsistent with the agreement in question;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> any State whose interests may be impaired or impeded in the action shall have the unconditional right to intervene in the action as a party, and the United States shall be entitled to amend its complaint to include a claim or cross-claim concerning the law of a State that so intervenes; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> any State law that is declared invalid shall not be deemed to have been invalid in its application during any period before the court’s judgment becomes final and all timely appeals, including discretionary review, of such judgment are exhausted.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports to congressional committees</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">At least 30 days before the United States brings an action described in subparagraph (A), the Trade Representative shall provide a report to the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> describing the proposed action;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> describing efforts by the Trade Representative to resolve the matter with the State concerned by other means; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> if the State law was the subject of consultations under the Dispute Settlement Understanding, certifying that the Trade Representative has substantially complied with the requirements of paragraph (1)(C) in connection with the matter.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">Following the submission of the report, and before the action is brought, the Trade Representative shall consult with the committees referred to in the preceding sentence concerning the matter.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> “State law” defined</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> the term “State law” includes—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any law of a political subdivision of a State; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any State law regulating or taxing the business of insurance; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the terms “dispute settlement panel” and “Appellate Body” have the meanings given those terms in <ref>section 3531 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect of agreement with respect to private remedies</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">No person other than the United States—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall have any cause of action or defense under any of the Uruguay Round Agreements or by virtue of congressional approval of such an agreement, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> may challenge, in any action brought under any provision of law, any action or inaction by any department, agency, or other instrumentality of the United States, any State, or any political subdivision of a State on the ground that such action or inaction is inconsistent with such agreement.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Intent of Congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">It is the intention of the Congress through paragraph (1) to occupy the field with respect to any cause of action or defense under or in connection with any of the Uruguay Round Agreements, including by precluding any person other than the United States from bringing any action against any State or political subdivision thereof or raising any defense to the application of State law under or in connection with any of the Uruguay Round Agreements—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> on the basis of a judgment obtained by the United States in an action brought under any such agreement; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> on any other basis.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Statement of administrative action</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The statement of administrative action approved by the Congress under <ref>section 3511(a) of this title</ref> shall be regarded as an authoritative expression by the United States concerning the interpretation and application of the Uruguay Round Agreements and this Act in any judicial proceeding in which a question arises concerning such interpretation or application.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–465, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4815</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(a)(142)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4321</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3513.</num>
<heading> Implementing actions in anticipation of entry into force; regulations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementing actions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">After <date date="1994-12-08">December 8, 1994</date>—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the President may proclaim such actions, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> other appropriate officers of the United States Government may issue such regulations,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">as may be necessary to ensure that any provision of this Act, or amendment made by this Act, that takes effect on the date any of the Uruguay Round Agreements enters into force with respect to the United States is appropriately implemented on such date. Such proclamation or regulation may not have an effective date earlier than the date of entry into force with respect to the United States of the agreement to which the proclamation or regulation relates.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any interim regulation necessary or appropriate to carry out any action proposed in the statement of administrative action approved under <ref>section 3511(a) of this title</ref> to implement an agreement described in section 3511(d)(7), (12), or (13) of this title shall be issued not later than 1 year after the date on which the agreement enters into force with respect to the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–465, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4819</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part B—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Tariff Modifications</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3521.</num>
<heading> Tariff modifications</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In addition to the authority provided by <ref>section 2902 of this title</ref>, the President shall have the authority to proclaim—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> such other modification of any duty,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> such other staged rate reduction, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> such additional duties,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">as the President determines to be necessary or appropriate to carry out Schedule XX.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other tariff modifications</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subject to the consultation and layover requirements of <ref>section 3524 of this title</ref>, the President may proclaim—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the modification of any duty or staged rate reduction of any duty set forth in Schedule XX if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the United States agrees to such modification or staged rate reduction in a multilateral negotiation under the auspices of the WTO, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> such modification or staged rate reduction applies to the rate of duty on an article contained in a tariff category that was the subject of reciprocal duty elimination or harmonization negotiations during the Uruguay Round of multilateral trade negotiations, and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> such modifications as are necessary to correct technical errors in Schedule XX or to make other rectifications to the Schedule.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority to increase duties on articles from certain countries</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determination with respect to certain countries</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Notwithstanding <ref>section 1881 of this title</ref>, after the entry into force of the WTO Agreement with respect to the United States, if the President—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> determines that a foreign country (other than a foreign country that is a WTO member country) is not according adequate trade benefits to the United States, including substantially equal competitive opportunities for the commerce of the United States, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> consults with the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate,</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">the President may proclaim an increase in the rate of duty with respect to any article of such country in accordance with subparagraph (B).</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rate of duty described</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The President may proclaim a rate of duty on any article of a country identified under subparagraph (A) that is equal to the greater of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the rate of duty set forth for such article in the base rate of duty column of Schedule XX, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the rate of duty set forth for such article in the bound rate of duty column of Schedule XX.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination of increased duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The President shall terminate any increase in the rate of duty proclaimed under this subsection by a proclamation which shall be effective on the earlier of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the date set out in such proclamation of termination, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the date the WTO Agreement enters into force with respect to the foreign country with respect to which the determination under paragraph (1) was made.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Publication of determination and termination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The President shall publish in the Federal Register notice of a determination made under paragraph (1) and a termination occurring by reason of paragraph (2).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adjustments to certain column 2 rates of duty</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">At such time as the President proclaims any modification to the HTS to implement the provisions of Schedule XX, the President shall also proclaim the rate of duty set forth in Column B as the column 2 rate of duty for the subheading of the HTS that corresponds to the subheading in Schedule XX listed in Column A.<table width="50%" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><colgroup><col/><col/></colgroup><thead><tr class="header"><th><p><b>Column A</b></p></th><th><p><b>Column B</b></p></th></tr><tr class="header"><th><p>Schedule XX</p><p>  subheading:</p></th><th><p>Rate of duty for column 2 of the</p><p>  HTS:</p></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0201.10.50</span></p></td><td><p>31.1%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0201.20.80</span></p></td><td><p>31.1%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0201.30.80</span></p></td><td><p>31.1%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0202.10.50</span></p></td><td><p>31.1%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0202.20.80</span></p></td><td><p>31.1%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0202.30.80</span></p></td><td><p>31.1%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0401.30.25</span></p></td><td><p>90.8¢/liter</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0401.30.75</span></p></td><td><p>$1.936/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0402.10.50</span></p></td><td><p>$1.018/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0402.21.25</span></p></td><td><p>$1.018/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0402.21.50</span></p></td><td><p>$1.285/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0402.21.90</span></p></td><td><p>$1.831/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0402.29.50</span></p></td><td><p>$1.299/kg + 17.5%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0402.91.60</span></p></td><td><p>36.8¢/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0402.99.50</span></p></td><td><p>58.4¢/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0402.99.90</span></p></td><td><p>54.5¢/kg + 17.5%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0403.10.50</span></p></td><td><p>$1.217/kg + 20%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0403.90.16</span></p></td><td><p>90.8¢/liter</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0403.90.45</span></p></td><td><p>$1.03/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0403.90.55</span></p></td><td><p>$1.285/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0403.90.65</span></p></td><td><p>$1.831/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0403.90.78</span></p></td><td><p>$1.936/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0403.90.95</span></p></td><td><p>$1.217/kg + 20%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0404.10.11</span></p></td><td><p>20%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0404.10.15</span></p></td><td><p>$1.217/kg + 10%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0404.10.90</span></p></td><td><p>$1.03/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0404.90.30</span></p></td><td><p>25%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0404.90.50</span></p></td><td><p>$1.399/kg + 10%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0405.00.40</span></p></td><td><p>$1.813/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0405.00.90</span></p></td><td><p>$2.194/kg + 10%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0406.10.08</span></p></td><td><p>$1.775/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0406.10.18</span></p></td><td><p>$2.67/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0406.10.28</span></p></td><td><p>$1.443/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0406.10.38</span></p></td><td><p>$1.241/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0406.10.48</span></p></td><td><p>$2.121/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0406.10.58</span></p></td><td><p>$2.525/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0406.10.68</span></p></td><td><p>$1.631/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0406.10.78</span></p></td><td><p>$1.328/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0406.10.88</span></p></td><td><p>$1.775/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0406.20.28</span></p></td><td><p>$2.67/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0406.20.33</span></p></td><td><p>$1.443/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0406.20.39</span></p></td><td><p>$1.241/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0406.20.48</span></p></td><td><p>$2.121/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0406.20.53</span></p></td><td><p>$2.525/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0406.20.63</span></p></td><td><p>$2.67/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0406.20.67</span></p></td><td><p>$1.443/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0406.20.71</span></p></td><td><p>$1.241/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0406.20.75</span></p></td><td><p>$2.121/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0406.20.79</span></p></td><td><p>$2.525/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0406.20.83</span></p></td><td><p>$1.631/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0406.20.87</span></p></td><td><p>$1.328/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0406.20.91</span></p></td><td><p>$1.775/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0406.30.18</span></p></td><td><p>$2.67/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0406.30.28</span></p></td><td><p>$1.443/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0406.30.38</span></p></td><td><p>$1.241/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0406.30.48</span></p></td><td><p>$2.121/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0406.30.53</span></p></td><td><p>$1.631/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0406.30.63</span></p></td><td><p>$2.67/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0406.30.67</span></p></td><td><p>$1.443/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0406.30.71</span></p></td><td><p>$1.241/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0406.30.75</span></p></td><td><p>$2.121/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0406.30.79</span></p></td><td><p>$2.525/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0406.30.83</span></p></td><td><p>$1.631/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0406.30.87</span></p></td><td><p>$1.328/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0406.30.91</span></p></td><td><p>$1.775/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0406.40.70</span></p></td><td><p>$2.67/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0406.90.12</span></p></td><td><p>$1.443/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0406.90.18</span></p></td><td><p>$2.121/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0406.90.33</span></p></td><td><p>$2.525/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0406.90.38</span></p></td><td><p>$2.525/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0406.90.43</span></p></td><td><p>$2.525/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0406.90.48</span></p></td><td><p>$2.208/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0406.90.64</span></p></td><td><p>$1.241/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0406.90.68</span></p></td><td><p>$2.525/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0406.90.74</span></p></td><td><p>$2.67/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0406.90.78</span></p></td><td><p>$1.443/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0406.90.84</span></p></td><td><p>$1.241/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0406.90.88</span></p></td><td><p>$2.121/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0406.90.92</span></p></td><td><p>$1.631/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0406.90.94</span></p></td><td><p>$1.328/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>0406.90.97</span></p></td><td><p>$1.775/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1202.10.80</span></p></td><td><p>192.7%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1202.20.80</span></p></td><td><p>155%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1517.90.60</span></p></td><td><p>40.2¢/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1701.11.50</span></p></td><td><p>39.85¢/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1701.12.10</span></p></td><td><p>6.58170¢/kg less 0.0622005¢/kg for each degree under 100 degrees (and fractions of a degree in proportion) but not less than 5.031562¢/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1701.12.50</span></p></td><td><p>42.05¢/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1701.91.10</span></p></td><td><p>6.58170¢/kg less 0.0622005¢/kg for each degree under 100 degrees (and fractions of a degree in proportion) but not less than 5.031562¢/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1701.91.30</span></p></td><td><p>42.05¢/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1701.91.48</span></p></td><td><p>39.9¢/kg + 6%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1701.91.58</span></p></td><td><p>39.9¢/kg + 6%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1701.99.10</span></p></td><td><p>6.58170¢/kg less 0.0622005¢/kg for each degree under 100 degrees (and fractions of a degree in proportion) but not less than 5.031562¢/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1701.99.50</span></p></td><td><p>42.05¢/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1702.20.28</span></p></td><td><p>19.9¢/kg of total sugars + 6%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1702.30.28</span></p></td><td><p>19.9¢/kg of total sugars + 6%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1702.40.28</span></p></td><td><p>39.9¢/kg of total sugars + 6%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1702.60.28</span></p></td><td><p>39.9¢/kg of total sugars + 6%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1702.90.10</span></p></td><td><p>6.58170¢/kg of total sugars</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1702.90.20</span></p></td><td><p>42.05¢/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1702.90.58</span></p></td><td><p>39.9¢/kg of total sugars + 6%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1702.90.68</span></p></td><td><p>39.9¢/kg + 6%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1704.90.58</span></p></td><td><p>47.4¢/kg + 12.2%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1704.90.68</span></p></td><td><p>47.4¢/kg + 12.2%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1704.90.78</span></p></td><td><p>47.4¢/kg + 12.2%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1806.10.15</span></p></td><td><p>25.5¢/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1806.10.28</span></p></td><td><p>39.5¢/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1806.10.38</span></p></td><td><p>39.5¢/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1806.10.55</span></p></td><td><p>39.5¢/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1806.10.75</span></p></td><td><p>39.5¢/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1806.20.26</span></p></td><td><p>43.8¢/kg + 5%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1806.20.28</span></p></td><td><p>62.1¢/kg + 5%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1806.20.36</span></p></td><td><p>43.8¢/kg + 5%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1806.20.38</span></p></td><td><p>62.1¢/kg + 5%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1806.20.73</span></p></td><td><p>35.9¢/kg + 10%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1806.20.77</span></p></td><td><p>35.9¢/kg + 10%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1806.20.82</span></p></td><td><p>43.8¢/kg + 10%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1806.20.83</span></p></td><td><p>62.1¢/kg + 10%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1806.20.87</span></p></td><td><p>43.8¢/kg + 10%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1806.20.89</span></p></td><td><p>62.1¢/kg + 10%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1806.20.92</span></p></td><td><p>43.8¢/kg + 10%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1806.20.93</span></p></td><td><p>62.1¢/kg + 10%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1806.20.96</span></p></td><td><p>43.8¢/kg + 10%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1806.20.97</span></p></td><td><p>62.1¢/kg + 10%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1806.32.06</span></p></td><td><p>43.8¢/kg + 5%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1806.32.08</span></p></td><td><p>62.1¢/kg + 5%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1806.32.16</span></p></td><td><p>43.8¢/kg + 5%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1806.32.18</span></p></td><td><p>62.1¢/kg + 5%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1806.32.70</span></p></td><td><p>43.8¢/kg + 7%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1806.32.80</span></p></td><td><p>62.1¢/kg + 7%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1806.90.08</span></p></td><td><p>43.8¢/kg + 7%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1806.90.10</span></p></td><td><p>62.1¢/kg + 7%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1806.90.18</span></p></td><td><p>43.8¢/kg + 7%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1806.90.20</span></p></td><td><p>62.1¢/kg + 7%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1806.90.28</span></p></td><td><p>43.8¢/kg + 7%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1806.90.30</span></p></td><td><p>62.1¢/kg + 7%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1806.90.38</span></p></td><td><p>43.8¢/kg + 7%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1806.90.40</span></p></td><td><p>62.1¢/kg + 7%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1806.90.48</span></p></td><td><p>43.8¢/kg + 7%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1806.90.50</span></p></td><td><p>62.1¢/kg + 7%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1806.90.58</span></p></td><td><p>43.8¢/kg + 7%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1806.90.60</span></p></td><td><p>62.1¢/kg + 7%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1901.10.30</span></p></td><td><p>$1.217/kg + 17.5%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1901.10.40</span></p></td><td><p>$1.217/kg + 17.5%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1901.10.75</span></p></td><td><p>$1.217/kg + 17.5%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1901.10.85</span></p></td><td><p>$1.217/kg + 17.5%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1901.20.15</span></p></td><td><p>49.8¢/kg + 10%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1901.20.25</span></p></td><td><p>49.8¢/kg + 10%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1901.20.35</span></p></td><td><p>49.8¢/kg + 10%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1901.20.50</span></p></td><td><p>49.8¢/kg + 10%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1901.20.60</span></p></td><td><p>49.8¢/kg + 10%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1901.20.70</span></p></td><td><p>49.8¢/kg + 10%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1901.90.36</span></p></td><td><p>$1.328/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1901.90.42</span></p></td><td><p>25%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1901.90.44</span></p></td><td><p>$1.217/kg + 16%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1901.90.46</span></p></td><td><p>25%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1901.90.48</span></p></td><td><p>$1.217/kg + 16%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1901.90.54</span></p></td><td><p>27.9¢/kg + 10%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1901.90.58</span></p></td><td><p>27.9¢/kg + 10%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>2008.11.15</span></p></td><td><p>155%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>2008.11.35</span></p></td><td><p>155%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>2008.11.60</span></p></td><td><p>155%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>2101.10.38</span></p></td><td><p>35.9¢/kg + 10%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>2101.10.48</span></p></td><td><p>35.9¢/kg + 10%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>2101.10.58</span></p></td><td><p>35.9¢/kg + 10%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>2101.20.38</span></p></td><td><p>35.9¢/kg + 10%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>2101.20.48</span></p></td><td><p>35.9¢/kg + 10%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>2101.20.58</span></p></td><td><p>35.9¢/kg + 10%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>2103.90.78</span></p></td><td><p>35.9¢/kg + 7.5%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>2105.00.20</span></p></td><td><p>59¢/kg + 20%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>2105.00.40</span></p></td><td><p>59¢/kg + 20%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>2106.90.02</span></p></td><td><p>$1.014/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>2106.90.04</span></p></td><td><p>$2.348/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>2106.90.08</span></p></td><td><p>$2.348/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>2106.90.11</span></p></td><td><p>6.58170¢/kg of total sugars</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>2106.90.12</span></p></td><td><p>42.05¢/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>2106.90.34</span></p></td><td><p>82.8¢/kg + 10%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>2106.90.38</span></p></td><td><p>82.8¢/kg + 10%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>2106.90.44</span></p></td><td><p>82.8¢/kg + 10%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>2106.90.48</span></p></td><td><p>82.8¢/kg + 10%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>2106.90.57</span></p></td><td><p>33.9¢/kg + 10%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>2106.90.67</span></p></td><td><p>33.9¢/kg + 10%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>2106.90.77</span></p></td><td><p>33.9¢/kg + 10%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>2106.90.87</span></p></td><td><p>33.9¢/kg + 10%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>2202.90.28</span></p></td><td><p>27.6¢/liter + 17.5%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>2309.90.28</span></p></td><td><p>94.6¢/kg + 7.5%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>2309.90.48</span></p></td><td><p>94.6¢/kg + 7.5%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>2401.10.70</span></p></td><td><p>85¢/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>2401.10.90</span></p></td><td><p>85¢/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>2401.20.30</span></p></td><td><p>$1.21/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>2401.20.45</span></p></td><td><p>$1.15/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>2401.20.55</span></p></td><td><p>$1.15/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>2801.30.20</span></p></td><td><p>37%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>2805.30.00</span></p></td><td><p>31.3%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>2805.40.00</span></p></td><td><p>5.7%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>2811.19.10</span></p></td><td><p>4.9%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>2818.10.20</span></p></td><td><p>4.1%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>2822.00.00</span></p></td><td><p>1.7%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>2827.39.20</span></p></td><td><p>31.9%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>2833.11.50</span></p></td><td><p>3.6%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>2833.27.00</span></p></td><td><p>4.2%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>2836.40.20</span></p></td><td><p>4.8%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>2836.60.00</span></p></td><td><p>8.4%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>2837.20.10</span></p></td><td><p>5.1%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>2840.11.00</span></p></td><td><p>1.2%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>2840.19.00</span></p></td><td><p>0.4%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>2849.20.20</span></p></td><td><p>1.6%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>2903.15.00</span></p></td><td><p>88%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>2903.16.00</span></p></td><td><p>33.3%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>2903.30.05</span></p></td><td><p>46.3%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>2906.11.00</span></p></td><td><p>6.2%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>2907.12.00</span></p></td><td><p>48.3%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>2909.11.00</span></p></td><td><p>4%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>2912.11.00</span></p></td><td><p>12.1%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>2916.15.10</span></p></td><td><p>35.2%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>2916.19.30</span></p></td><td><p>24.4%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>2923.20.20</span></p></td><td><p>33.4%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>3213.90.00</span></p></td><td><p>48.6%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>3307.10.20</span></p></td><td><p>81.7%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>3307.49.00</span></p></td><td><p>73.2%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>3403.11.20</span></p></td><td><p>0.4%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>3403.19.10</span></p></td><td><p>0.4%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>3506.10.10</span></p></td><td><p>30.4%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>3603.00.30</span></p></td><td><p>8.3%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>3603.00.90</span></p></td><td><p>0.3%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>3604.10.00</span></p></td><td><p>12.5%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>3606.90.30</span></p></td><td><p>56.7%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>3706.10.30</span></p></td><td><p>7%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>3807.00.00</span></p></td><td><p>0.2%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>3823.90.33</span></p></td><td><p>26.3%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>3904.61.00</span></p></td><td><p>34.1%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>3916.90.10</span></p></td><td><p>40.6%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>3920.51.50</span></p></td><td><p>48.2%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>3920.59.80</span></p></td><td><p>51.7%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>3926.90.65</span></p></td><td><p>8.4%</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>5201.00.18</span></p></td><td><p>36.9¢/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>5201.00.28</span></p></td><td><p>36.9¢/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>5201.00.38</span></p></td><td><p>36.9¢/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>5201.00.80</span></p></td><td><p>36.9¢/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>5202.99.30</span></p></td><td><p>9.2¢/kg</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>5203.00.30</span></p></td><td><p>36.9¢/kg</p></td></tr></tbody></table>
</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority to consolidate subheadings and modify column 2 rates of duty for tariff simplification purposes</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Whenever the HTS column 1 general rates of duty for 2 or more 8-digit subheadings are at the same level and such subheadings are subordinate to a provision required by the International Convention on the Harmonized Commodity Description and Coding System, the President may proclaim, subject to the consultation and layover requirements of <ref>section 3524 of this title</ref>, that the goods described in such subheadings be provided for in a single 8-digit subheading of the HTS, and that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the HTS column 1 general rate of duty for such single subheading be the column 1 general rate of duty common to all such subheadings, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the HTS column 2 rate of duty for such single subheading be the highest column 2 rate of duty for such subheadings that is in effect on the day before the effective date of such proclamation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Same level of duty</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The provisions of this subsection apply to subheadings described in paragraph (1) that have the same column 1 general rate of duty—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> on <date date="1994-12-08">December 8, 1994</date>, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> after <date date="1994-12-08">December 8, 1994</date>, as a result of a staged reduction in such column 1 rates of duty.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–465, title I, § 111</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4819</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3522.</num>
<heading> Liquidation or reliquidation and refund of duty paid on certain entries</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Liquidation or reliquidation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding <ref>section 1514 of this title</ref> or any other provision of law, and subject to subsection (b), the Secretary of the Treasury shall liquidate or reliquidate the entries listed or otherwise described in subsection (c) and refund any duty or excess duty that was paid, as provided in subsection (c).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requests</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Liquidation or reliquidation may be made under subsection (a) with respect to an entry only if a request therefor is filed with the Customs Service, within 180 days after the date on which the WTO Agreement enters into force with respect to the United States, that contains sufficient information to enable the Customs Service—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to locate the entry; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to reconstruct the entry if it cannot be located.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Entries</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The entries referred to in subsection (a) are as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agglomerated stone tiles</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Any goods—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> for which the importer claimed or would have claimed entry under subheading 6810.19.12 of the HTS on or after <date date="1990-10-01">October 1, 1990</date>, and before the effective date of a proclamation issued by the President under <ref>section 3513(a) of this title</ref> with respect to items under such subheading in order to carry out Schedule XX, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> entered on or after <date date="1989-01-01">January 1, 1989</date>, and before <date date="1990-10-01">October 1, 1990</date>, for which entry would have been claimed under subheading 6810.19.12 of the HTS on or after <date date="1990-10-01">October 1, 1990</date>,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">shall be liquidated or reliquidated as if the wording of that subheading were “Of stone agglomerated with binders other than cement”, and the Secretary of the Treasury shall refund any excess duties paid with respect to such entries.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Clomiphene citrate</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Any entry, or withdrawal from warehouse for consumption, of goods described in heading 9902.29.95 of the HTS (relating to clomiphene citrate) which was made after <date date="1988-12-31">December 31, 1988</date>, and before <date date="1993-01-01">January 1, 1993</date>, and with respect to which there would have been no duty if the reference to subheading “2922.19.15” in such heading were a reference to subheading “2922.19.15 or any subheading of chapter 30” at the time of such entry or withdrawal, shall be liquidated or reliquidated as free of duty.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Treasury shall refund any duties paid with respect to entries described in subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–465, title I, § 113</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4826</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3523.</num>
<heading> Duty free treatment for octadecyl isocyanate and 5-Chloro-2-(2,4-dichloro-phenoxy)phenol</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall proclaim duty-free entry for octadecyl isocyanate and 5-Chloro-2-(2,4-dichloro-phenoxy)phenol, to be effective on the effective date of the proclamation issued by the President under <ref>section 3513(a) of this title</ref> to carry out Schedule XX, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall take such actions as are necessary to reflect such tariff treatment in Schedule XX.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–465, title I, § 114(b)</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4827</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3524.</num>
<heading> Consultation and layover requirements for, and effective date of, proclaimed actions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">If a provision of this Act provides that the implementation of an action by the President by proclamation is subject to the consultation and layover requirements of this section, such action may be proclaimed only if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the President has obtained advice regarding the proposed action from—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the appropriate advisory committees established under <ref>section 2155 of this title</ref>, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the International Trade Commission;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the President has submitted a report to the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate that sets forth—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the action proposed to be proclaimed and the reasons for such actions, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the advice obtained under paragraph (1);</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a period of 60 calendar days, beginning with the first day on which the President has met the requirements of paragraphs (1) and (2) with respect to such action, has expired; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the President has consulted with such committees regarding the proposed action during the period referred to in paragraph (3).</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–465, title I, § 115</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4828</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part C—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Uruguay Round Implementation and Dispute Settlement</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3531.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this part:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administering authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “administering authority” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 1677(1) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appellate Body</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Appellate Body” means the Appellate Body established under Article 17.1 of the Dispute Settlement Understanding.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appropriate congressional committees; congressional committees</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appropriate congressional committees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “appropriate congressional committees” means the committees referred to in subparagraph (B) and any other committees of the Congress that have jurisdiction involving the matter with respect to which consultations are to be held.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Congressional committees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “congressional committees” means the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Dispute settlement panel; panel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The terms “dispute settlement panel” and “panel” mean a panel established pursuant to Article 6 of the Dispute Settlement Understanding.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Dispute Settlement Body</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Dispute Settlement Body” means the Dispute Settlement Body administering the rules and procedures set forth in the Dispute Settlement Understanding.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Dispute Settlement Understanding</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Dispute Settlement Understanding” means the Understanding on Rules and Procedures Governing the Settlement of Disputes referred to in <ref>section 3511(d)(16) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General Council</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “General Council” means the General Council established under paragraph 2 of Article IV of the WTO Agreement.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Ministerial Conference</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Ministerial Conference” means the Ministerial Conference established under paragraph 1 of Article IV of the WTO Agreement.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other terms</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The terms “Antidumping Agreement”, “Agreement on Subsidies and Countervailing Measures”, and “Safeguards Agreement” mean the agreements referred to in section 3511(d)(7), (12), and (13) of this title, respectively.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–465, title I, § 121</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4828</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3532.</num>
<heading> Implementation of Uruguay Round Agreements</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Decisionmaking</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the implementation of the Uruguay Round Agreements and the functioning of the World Trade Organization, it is the objective of the United States to ensure that the Ministerial Conference and the General Council continue the practice of decisionmaking by consensus followed under the GATT 1947, as required by paragraph 1 of article IX of the WTO Agreement.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultations with congressional committees</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In furtherance of the objective set forth in subsection (a), the Trade Representative shall consult with the appropriate congressional committees before any vote is taken by the Ministerial Conference or the General Council relating to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the adoption of an interpretation of the WTO Agreement or another multilateral trade agreement,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the amendment of any such agreement,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the granting of a waiver of any obligation under any such agreement,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the adoption of any amendment to the rules or procedures of the Ministerial Conference or the General Council,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the accession of a state or separate customs territory to the WTO Agreement, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the adoption of any other decision,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">if the action described in paragraph (1), (2), (3), (4), (5), or (6) would substantially affect the rights or obligations of the United States under the WTO Agreement or another multilateral trade agreement or potentially entails a change in Federal or State law.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report on decisions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 30 days after the end of any calendar year in which the Ministerial Conference or the General Council adopts by vote any decision to take any action described in paragraph (1), (2), (4), or (6) of subsection (b), the Trade Representative shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees describing—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the nature of the decision;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the efforts made by the United States to have the matter decided by consensus pursuant to paragraph 1 of article IX of the WTO Agreement, and the results of those efforts;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> which countries voted for, and which countries voted against, the decision;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the rights or obligations of the United States affected by the decision and any Federal or State law that would be amended or repealed, if the President after consultation with the Congress determined that such amendment or repeal was an appropriate response; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the action the President intends to take in response to the decision or, if the President does not intend to take any action, the reasons therefor.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional reporting requirements</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grant of waiver</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In the case of a decision to grant a waiver described in subsection (b)(3), the report under paragraph (1) shall describe the terms and conditions of the waiver and the rights and obligations of the United States that are affected by the waiver.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Accession</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In the case of a decision on accession described in subsection (b)(5), the report under paragraph (1) shall state whether the United States intends to invoke Article XIII of the WTO Agreement.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation on report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Promptly after the submission of a report under subsection (c), the Trade Representative shall consult with the appropriate congressional committees with respect to the report.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–465, title I, § 122</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4829</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3533.</num>
<heading> Dispute settlement panels and procedures</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review by President</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall review annually the WTO panel roster and shall include the panel roster and the list of persons serving on the Appellate Body in the annual report submitted by the President under <ref>section 2213(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Qualifications of appointees to panels</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Trade Representative shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> seek to ensure that persons appointed to the WTO panel roster are well-qualified, and that the roster includes persons with expertise in the subject areas covered by the Uruguay Round Agreements; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> inform the President of persons nominated to the roster by other WTO member countries.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rules governing conflicts of interest</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Trade Representative shall seek the establishment by the General Council and the Dispute Settlement Body of rules governing conflicts of interest by persons serving on panels and members of the Appellate Body and shall describe, in the annual report submitted under <ref>section 3534 of this title</ref>, any progress made in establishing such rules.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification of disputes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Promptly after a dispute settlement panel is established to consider the consistency of Federal or State law with any of the Uruguay Round Agreements, the Trade Representative shall notify the appropriate congressional committees of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the nature of the dispute, including the matters set forth in the request for the establishment of the panel, the legal basis of the complaint, and the specific measures, in particular any State or Federal law cited in the request for establishment of the panel;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the identity of the persons serving on the panel; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> whether there was any departure from the rule of consensus with respect to the selection of persons to serve on the panel.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice of appeals of panel reports</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">If an appeal is taken of a report of a panel in a proceeding described in subsection (d), the Trade Representative shall, promptly after the notice of appeal is filed, notify the appropriate congressional committees of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the issues under appeal; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the identity of the persons serving on the Appellate Body who are reviewing the report of the panel.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Actions upon circulation of reports</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Promptly after the circulation of a report of a panel or of the Appellate Body to WTO members in a proceeding described in subsection (d), the Trade Representative shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> notify the appropriate congressional committees of the report;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in the case of a report of a panel, consult with the appropriate congressional committees concerning the nature of any appeal that may be taken of the report; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> if the report is adverse to the United States, consult with the appropriate congressional committees concerning whether to implement the report’s recommendation and, if so, the manner of such implementation and the period of time needed for such implementation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements for agency action</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Changes in agency regulations or practice</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In any case in which a dispute settlement panel or the Appellate Body finds in its report that a regulation or practice of a department or agency of the United States is inconsistent with any of the Uruguay Round Agreements, that regulation or practice may not be amended, rescinded, or otherwise modified in the implementation of such report unless and until—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the appropriate congressional committees have been consulted under subsection (f);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Trade Representative has sought advice regarding the modification from relevant private sector advisory committees established under <ref>section 2155 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the head of the relevant department or agency has provided an opportunity for public comment by publishing in the Federal Register the proposed modification and the explanation for the modification;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Trade Representative has submitted to the appropriate congressional committees a report describing the proposed modification, the reasons for the modification, and a summary of the advice obtained under subparagraph (B) with respect to the modification;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the Trade Representative and the head of the relevant department or agency have consulted with the appropriate congressional committees on the proposed contents of the final rule or other modification; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the final rule or other modification has been published in the Federal Register.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date of modification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A final rule or other modification to which paragraph (1) applies may not go into effect before the end of the 60-day period beginning on the date on which consultations under paragraph (1)(E) begin, unless the President determines that an earlier effective date is in the national interest.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Vote by congressional committees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">During the 60-day period described in paragraph (2), the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate may vote to indicate the agreement or disagreement of the committee with the proposed contents of the final rule or other modification. Any such vote shall not be binding on the department or agency which is implementing the rule or other modification.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inapplicability to ITC</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">This subsection does not apply to any regulation or practice of the International Trade Commission.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultations regarding review of WTO rules and procedures</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Before the review is conducted of the dispute settlement rules and procedures of the WTO that is provided for in the Decision on the Application of the Understanding on Rules and Procedures Governing the Settlement of Disputes, as such decision is set forth in the Ministerial Declarations and Decisions adopted on <date date="1994-04-15">April 15, 1994</date>, together with the Uruguay Round Agreements, the Trade Representative shall consult with the congressional committees regarding the policy of the United States concerning the review.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–465, title I, § 123</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4830</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3534.</num>
<heading> Annual report on WTO</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than March 1 of each year beginning in 1996, the Trade Representative shall submit to the Congress a report describing, for the preceding fiscal year of the WTO—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the major activities and work programs of the WTO, including the functions and activities of the committees established under article IV of the WTO Agreement, and the expenditures made by the WTO in connection with those activities and programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the percentage of budgetary assessments by the WTO that were accounted for by each WTO member country, including the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the total number of personnel employed or retained by the Secretariat of the WTO, and the number of professional, administrative, and support staff of the WTO;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> for each personnel category described in paragraph (3), the number of citizens of each country, and the average salary of the personnel, in that category;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> each report issued by a panel or the Appellate Body in a dispute settlement proceeding regarding Federal or State law, and any efforts by the Trade Representative to provide for implementation of the recommendations contained in a report that is adverse to the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> each proceeding before a panel or the Appellate Body that was initiated during that fiscal year regarding Federal or State law, the status of the proceeding, and the matter at issue;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the status of consultations with any State whose law was the subject of a report adverse to the United States that was issued by a panel or the Appellate Body; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> any progress achieved in increasing the transparency of proceedings of the Ministerial Conference and the General Council, and of dispute settlement proceedings conducted pursuant to the Dispute Settlement Understanding.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–465, title I, § 124</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4832</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3535.</num>
<heading> Review of participation in WTO</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report on operation of WTO</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The first annual report submitted to the Congress under <ref>section 3534 of this title</ref>—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> after the end of the 5-year period beginning on the date on which the WTO Agreement enters into force with respect to the United States, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> after the end of every 5-year period thereafter,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall include an analysis of the effects of the WTO Agreement on the interests of the United States, the costs and benefits to the United States of its participation in the WTO, and the value of the continued participation of the United States in the WTO.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Congressional disapproval of U.S. participation in WTO</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General rule</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The approval of the Congress, provided under <ref>section 3511(a) of this title</ref>, of the WTO Agreement shall cease to be effective if, and only if, a joint resolution described in subsection (c) is enacted into law pursuant to the provisions of paragraph (2).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Procedural provisions</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> The requirements of this paragraph are met if the joint resolution is enacted under subsection (c), and—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Congress adopts and transmits the joint resolution to the President before the end of the 90-day period (excluding any day described in <ref>section 2194(b) of this title</ref>), beginning on the date on which the Congress receives a report referred to in subsection (a), and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> if the President vetoes the joint resolution, each House of Congress votes to override that veto on or before the later of the last day of the 90-day period referred to in clause (i) or the last day of the 15-day period (excluding any day described in <ref>section 2194(b) of this title</ref>) beginning on the date on which the Congress receives the veto message from the President.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A joint resolution to which this section applies may be introduced at any time on or after the date on which the President transmits to the Congress a report described in subsection (a), and before the end of the 90-day period referred to in subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Joint resolutions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Joint resolutions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of this section, the term “joint resolution” means only a joint resolution of the 2 Houses of Congress, the matter after the resolving clause of which is as follows: “That the Congress withdraws its approval, provided under section 101(a) of the Uruguay Round Agreements Act, of the WTO Agreement as defined in section 2(9) of that Act.”</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Procedures</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Joint resolutions may be introduced in either House of the Congress by any member of such House.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Subject to the provisions of this subsection, the provisions of subsections (b), (d), (e), and (f) of <ref>section 2192 of this title</ref> apply to joint resolutions to the same extent as such provisions apply to resolutions under such section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> If the committee of either House to which a joint resolution has been referred has not reported it by the close of the 45th day after its introduction (excluding any day described in <ref>section 2194(b) of this title</ref>), such committee shall be automatically discharged from further consideration of the joint resolution and it shall be placed on the appropriate calendar.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> It is not in order for—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Senate to consider any joint resolution unless it has been reported by the Committee on Finance or the committee has been discharged under subparagraph (C); or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the House of Representatives to consider any joint resolution unless it has been reported by the Committee on Ways and Means or the committee has been discharged under subparagraph (C).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> A motion in the House of Representatives to proceed to the consideration of a joint resolution may only be made on the second legislative day after the calendar day on which the Member making the motion announces to the House his or her intention to do so.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consideration of second resolution not in order</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">It shall not be in order in either the House of Representatives or the Senate to consider a joint resolution (other than a joint resolution received from the other House), if that House has previously adopted a joint resolution under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rules of House of Representatives and Senate</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">This section is enacted by the Congress—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> as an exercise of the rulemaking power of the House of Representatives and the Senate, respectively, and as such is deemed a part of the rules of each House, respectively, and such procedures supersede other rules only to the extent that they are inconsistent with such other rules; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> with the full recognition of the constitutional right of either House to change the rules (so far as relating to the procedures of that House) at any time, in the same manner, and to the same extent as any other rule of that House.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–465, title I, § 125</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4833</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3536.</num>
<heading> Increased transparency</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Trade Representative shall seek the adoption by the Ministerial Conference and General Council of procedures that will ensure broader application of the principle of transparency and clarification of the costs and benefits of trade policy actions, through the observance of open and equitable procedures in trade matters by the Ministerial Conference and the General Council, and by the dispute settlement panels and the Appellate Body under the Dispute Settlement Understanding.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–465, title I, § 126</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4834</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3537.</num>
<heading> Access to WTO dispute settlement process</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever the United States is a party before a dispute settlement panel established pursuant to Article 6 of the Dispute Settlement Understanding, the Trade Representative shall, at each stage of the proceeding before the panel or the Appellate Body, consult with the appropriate congressional committees, the petitioner (if any) under <ref>section 2412(a) of this title</ref> with respect to the matter that is the subject of the proceeding, and relevant private sector advisory committees established under <ref>section 2155 of this title</ref>, and shall consider the views of representatives of appropriate interested private sector and nongovernmental organizations concerning the matter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice and public comment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In any proceeding described in subsection (a), the Trade Representative shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> promptly after requesting the establishment of a panel, or receiving a request from another WTO member country for the establishment of a panel, publish a notice in the Federal Register—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> identifying the initial parties to the dispute,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> setting forth the major issues raised by the country requesting the establishment of a panel and the legal basis of the complaint,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> identifying the specific measures, including any State or Federal law cited in the request for establishment of the panel, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> seeking written comments from the public concerning the issues raised in the dispute; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> take into account any advice received from appropriate congressional committees and relevant private sector advisory committees referred to in subsection (a), and written comments received pursuant to paragraph (1)(D), in preparing United States submissions to the panel or the Appellate Body.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Access to documents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In each proceeding described in subsection (a), the Trade Representative shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> make written submissions by the United States referred to in subsection (b) available to the public promptly after they are submitted to the panel or Appellate Body, except that the Trade Representative is authorized to withhold from disclosure any information contained in such submissions identified by the provider of the information as proprietary information or information treated as confidential by a foreign government;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> request each other party to the dispute to permit the Trade Representative to make that party’s written submissions to the panel or the Appellate Body available to the public; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> make each report of the panel or the Appellate Body available to the public promptly after it is circulated to WTO members, and inform the public of such availability.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requests for nonconfidential summaries</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In any dispute settlement proceeding conducted pursuant to the Dispute Settlement Understanding, the Trade Representative shall request each party to the dispute to provide nonconfidential summaries of its written submissions, if that party has not made its written submissions public, and shall make those summaries available to the public promptly after receiving them.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public file</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Trade Representative shall maintain a file accessible to the public on each dispute settlement proceeding to which the United States is a party that is conducted pursuant to the Dispute Settlement Understanding. The file shall include all United States submissions in the proceeding and a listing of any submissions to the Trade Representative from the public with respect to the proceeding, as well as the report of the dispute settlement panel and the report of the Appellate Body.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–465, title I, § 127</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4835</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3538.</num>
<heading> Administrative action following WTO panel reports</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Action by United States International Trade Commission</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Advisory report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If a dispute settlement panel finds in an interim report under Article 15 of the Dispute Settlement Understanding, or the Appellate Body finds in a report under Article 17 of that Understanding, that an action by the International Trade Commission in connection with a particular proceeding is not in conformity with the obligations of the United States under the Antidumping Agreement, the Safeguards Agreement, or the Agreement on Subsidies and Countervailing Measures, the Trade Representative may request the Commission to issue an advisory report on whether title VII of the Tariff Act of 1930 [<ref>19 U.S.C. 1671</ref> et seq.] or title II of the Trade Act of 1974 [<ref>19 U.S.C. 2251</ref> et seq.], as the case may be, permits the Commission to take steps in connection with the particular proceeding that would render its action not inconsistent with the findings of the panel or the Appellate Body concerning those obligations. The Trade Representative shall notify the congressional committees of such request.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Time limits for report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Commission shall transmit its report under paragraph (1) to the Trade Representative—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the case of an interim report described in paragraph (1), within 30 calendar days after the Trade Representative requests the report; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of a report of the Appellate Body, within 21 calendar days after the Trade Representative requests the report.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultations on request for Commission determination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If a majority of the Commissioners issues an affirmative report under paragraph (1), the Trade Representative shall consult with the congressional committees concerning the matter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Commission determination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding any provision of the Tariff Act of 1930 [<ref>19 U.S.C. 1202</ref> et seq.] or title II of the Trade Act of 1974 [<ref>19 U.S.C. 2251</ref> et seq.], if a majority of the Commissioners issues an affirmative report under paragraph (1), the Commission, upon the written request of the Trade Representative, shall issue a determination in connection with the particular proceeding that would render the Commission’s action described in paragraph (1) not inconsistent with the findings of the panel or Appellate Body. The Commission shall issue its determination not later than 120 days after the request from the Trade Representative is made.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultations on implementation of Commission determination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Trade Representative shall consult with the congressional committees before the Commission’s determination under paragraph (4) is implemented.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Revocation of order</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If, by virtue of the Commission’s determination under paragraph (4), an antidumping or countervailing duty order with respect to some or all of the imports that are subject to the action of the Commission described in paragraph (1) is no longer supported by an affirmative Commission determination under title VII of the Tariff Act of 1930 [<ref>19 U.S.C. 1671</ref> et seq.] or this subsection, the Trade Representative may, after consulting with the congressional committees under paragraph (5), direct the administering authority to revoke the antidumping or countervailing duty order in whole or in part.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Action by administering authority</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultations with administering authority and congressional committees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Promptly after a report by a dispute settlement panel or the Appellate Body is issued that contains findings that an action by the administering authority in a proceeding under title VII of the Tariff Act of 1930 [<ref>19 U.S.C. 1671</ref> et seq.] is not in conformity with the obligations of the United States under the Antidumping Agreement or the Agreement on Subsidies and Countervailing Measures, the Trade Representative shall consult with the administering authority and the congressional committees on the matter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determination by administering authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding any provision of the Tariff Act of 1930 [<ref>19 U.S.C. 1202</ref> et seq.], the administering authority shall, within 180 days after receipt of a written request from the Trade Representative, issue a determination in connection with the particular proceeding that would render the administering authority’s action described in paragraph (1) not inconsistent with the findings of the panel or the Appellate Body.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultations before implementation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Before the administering authority implements any determination under paragraph (2), the Trade Representative shall consult with the administering authority and the congressional committees with respect to such determination.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementation of determination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Trade Representative may, after consulting with the administering authority and the congressional committees under paragraph (3), direct the administering authority to implement, in whole or in part, the determination made under paragraph (2).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effects of determinations; notice of implementation</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effects of determinations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Determinations concerning title VII of the Tariff Act of 1930 [<ref>19 U.S.C. 1671</ref> et seq.] that are implemented under this section shall apply with respect to unliquidated entries of the subject merchandise (as defined in section 771 of that Act [<ref>19 U.S.C. 1677</ref>]) that are entered, or withdrawn from warehouse, for consumption on or after—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the case of a determination by the Commission under subsection (a)(4), the date on which the Trade Representative directs the administering authority under subsection (a)(6) to revoke an order pursuant to that determination, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of a determination by the administering authority under subsection (b)(2), the date on which the Trade Representative directs the administering authority under subsection (b)(4) to implement that determination.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice of implementation</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The administering authority shall publish in the Federal Register notice of the implementation of any determination made under this section with respect to title VII of the Tariff Act of 1930 [<ref>19 U.S.C. 1671</ref> et seq.].</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Trade Representative shall publish in the Federal Register notice of the implementation of any determination made under this section with respect to title II of the Trade Act of 1974 [<ref>19 U.S.C. 2251</ref> et seq.].</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Opportunity for comment by interested parties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Prior to issuing a determination under this section, the administering authority or the Commission, as the case may be, shall provide interested parties with an opportunity to submit written comments and, in appropriate cases, may hold a hearing, with respect to the determination.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–465, title I, § 129</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4836</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3539.</num>
<heading> Fund for WTO dispute settlements</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established in the Treasury a fund for the payment of settlements under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority of USTR to pay settlements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Amounts in the fund established under subsection (a) shall be available, as provided in appropriations Acts, only for the payment by the United States Trade Representative of the amount of the total or partial settlement of any dispute pursuant to proceedings under the auspices of the World Trade Organization, if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in the case of a total or partial settlement in an amount of not more than $10,000,000, the Trade Representative certifies to the Secretary of the Treasury that the settlement is in the best interests of the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in the case of a total or partial settlement in an amount of more than $10,000,000, the Trade Representative certifies to the Congress that the settlement is in the best interests of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appropriations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to the fund established under subsection (a)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> $50,000,000; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> amounts equivalent to amounts recovered by the United States pursuant to the settlement of disputes pursuant to proceedings under the auspices of the World Trade Organization.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Amounts appropriated to the fund are authorized to remain available until expended.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Management of fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Sections 9601 and 9602(b) of title 26 shall apply to the fund established under subsection (a) to the same extent as such provisions apply to trust funds established under subchapter A of chapter 98 of such title.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–210, div. E, title L, § 5201</ref>, <date date="2002-08-06">Aug. 6, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1047</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part D—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Related Provisions</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3551.</num>
<heading> Working party on worker rights</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall seek the establishment in the GATT 1947, and, upon entry into force of the WTO Agreement with respect to the United States, in the WTO, of a working party to examine the relationship of internationally recognized worker rights, as defined in <ref>section 2467(4) of this title</ref>, to the articles, objectives, and related instruments of the GATT 1947 and of the WTO, respectively.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Objectives of working party</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The objectives of the United States for the working party described in subsection (a) are to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> explore the linkage between international trade and internationally recognized worker rights, as defined in <ref>section 2467(4) of this title</ref>, taking into account differences in the level of development among countries;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> examine the effects on international trade of the systematic denial of such rights;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> consider ways to address such effects; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> develop methods to coordinate the work program of the working party with the International Labor Organization.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall report to the Congress, not later than 1 year after <date date="1994-12-08">December 8, 1994</date>, on the progress made in establishing the working party under this section, and on United States objectives with respect to the working party’s work program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–465, title I, § 131</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4839</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–188, title I, § 1954(a)(6)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1928</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3552.</num>
<heading> Implementation of Rules of Origin work program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the President enters into an agreement developed under the work program described in Article 9 of the Agreement on Rules of Origin referred to in <ref>section 3511(d)(10) of this title</ref>, the President may implement United States obligations under such an agreement under United States law only pursuant to authority granted to the President for that purpose by law enacted after the effective date of this section.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–465, title I, § 132</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4839</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–295, § 20(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3527</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3553.</num>
<heading> Membership in WTO of boycotting countries</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is the sense of the Congress that the Trade Representative should vigorously oppose the admission into the World Trade Organization of any country which, through its laws, regulations, official policies, or governmental practices, fosters, imposes, complies with, furthers, or supports any boycott described in <ref>section 4607(a) of title 50</ref> (as in effect on <date date="1994-08-20">August 20, 1994</date>), including requiring or encouraging entities within that country to refuse to do business with persons who do not comply with requests to take any action prohibited under that section.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–465, title I, § 133</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4839</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3554.</num>
<heading> Africa trade and development policy</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Development of policy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President should develop and implement a comprehensive trade and development policy for the countries of Africa.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall, not later than 12 months after <date date="1994-12-08">December 8, 1994</date>, and annually thereafter for a period of 4 years, submit to the Committee on Ways and Means and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Finance and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate, and other appropriate committees of the Congress, a report on the steps taken to carry out subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–465, title I, § 134</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4840</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3555.</num>
<heading> Objectives for extended negotiations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Trade in financial services</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The principal negotiating objective of the United States in the extended negotiations on financial services to be conducted under the auspices of the WTO is to seek to secure commitments, from a wide range of commercially important developed and developing countries, to reduce or eliminate barriers to the supply of financial services, including barriers that deny national treatment or market access by restricting the establishment or operation of financial services providers, as the condition for the United States—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> offering commitments to provide national treatment and market access in each of the financial services subsectors, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> making such commitments on a normal trade relations basis.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Trade in basic telecommunications services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The principal negotiating objective of the United States in the extended negotiations on basic telecommunications services to be conducted under the auspices of the WTO is to obtain the opening on nondiscriminatory terms and conditions of foreign markets for basic telecommunications services through facilities-based competition or through the resale of services on existing networks.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Trade in civil aircraft</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Negotiations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The principal negotiating objectives of the United States in the extended negotiations on trade in civil aircraft to be conducted under the auspices of the WTO are—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to obtain competitive opportunities for United States exports in foreign markets substantially equivalent to those afforded to foreign products in the United States,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to obtain the reduction or elimination of specific tariff and nontariff barriers, including through expanded membership in the Agreement on Trade in Civil Aircraft and in the US–EC bilateral agreement for large civil aircraft,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to maintain vigorous and effective disciplines on subsidies practices with respect to civil aircraft products under the Agreement on Subsidies and Countervailing Measures referred to in <ref>section 3511(d)(12) of this title</ref>,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> to maintain the scope and coverage on indirect support as specified in the US–EC bilateral agreement on large civil aircraft, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> to obtain increased transparency with respect to foreign subsidy programs in the civil aircraft sector, both through greater government disclosure with respect to the use of taxpayer moneys and higher financial disclosure standards for companies receiving government supports (including disclosure comparable to that required under United States securities laws).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of paragraph (1)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the term “civil aircraft” means those products to which the Agreement on Trade in Civil Aircraft applies,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the term “large civil aircraft” has the meaning given that term in Annex II to the US–EC bilateral agreement,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the term “indirect support” means indirect government support as defined in Annex II to the US–EC bilateral agreement,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the term “Agreement on Trade in Civil Aircraft” means the Agreement on Trade in Civil Aircraft approved by the Congress under <ref>section 2503 of this title</ref>, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the term “US–EC bilateral agreement” means the Agreement Concerning the Application of the GATT Agreement on Trade in Civil Aircraft Between the European Economic Community and the Government of the United States of America on trade in large civil aircraft, entered into on <date date="1992-07-17">July 17, 1992</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–465, title I, § 135</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4840</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–206, title V, § 5003(b)(5)</ref>, <date date="1998-07-22">July 22, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 790</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3556.</num>
<heading> Certain nonrubber footwear</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In the case of nonrubber footwear imported from Brazil—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> which is subject to Treasury Decision 74-233, dated <date date="1974-09-09">September 9, 1974</date>,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> which was entered, or withdrawn from warehouse for consumption, on or before <date date="1981-10-28">October 28, 1981</date>, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> with respect to which entries are unliquidated on <date date="1994-12-08">December 8, 1994</date>,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">countervailing duties shall be assessed at rates equal to the amount of the cash deposit of the estimated countervailing duties required on such footwear at the time of entry or withdrawal from warehouse for consumption. Interest on underpayments of amounts required to be deposited as countervailing duties shall be paid in accordance with <ref>section 1677g of this title</ref>.</continuation>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–465, title I, § 137</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4842</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>ENFORCEMENT OF UNITED STATES RIGHTS UNDER SUBSIDIES AGREEMENT</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3571.</num>
<heading> Subsidies enforcement</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistance regarding multilateral subsidy remedies</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The administering authority shall provide information to the public upon request, and, to the extent feasible, assistance and advice to interested parties concerning—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> remedies and benefits available under relevant provisions of the Subsidies Agreement, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the procedures relating to such remedies and benefits.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibited subsidies</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification of Trade Representative</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the administering authority determines pursuant to title VII of the Tariff Act of 1930 [<ref>19 U.S.C. 1671</ref> et seq.] that a class or kind of merchandise is benefiting from a subsidy which is prohibited under Article 3 of the Subsidies Agreement, the administering authority shall notify the Trade Representative and shall provide the Trade Representative with the information upon which the administering authority based its determination.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Request by interested party regarding prohibited subsidy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">An interested party may request that the administering authority determine if there is reason to believe that merchandise produced in a WTO member country is benefiting from a subsidy which is prohibited under Article 3 of the Subsidies Agreement. The request shall contain such information as the administering authority may require to support the allegations contained in the request. If the administering authority, after analyzing the request and other information reasonably available to the administering authority, determines that there is reason to believe that such merchandise is benefiting from a subsidy which is prohibited under Article 3 of the Subsidies Agreement, the administering authority shall so notify the Trade Representative, and shall include supporting information with the notification.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Subsidies actionable under Agreement</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the administering authority determines pursuant to title VII of the Tariff Act of 1930 [<ref>19 U.S.C. 1671</ref> et seq.] that a class or kind of merchandise is benefiting from a subsidy described in Article 6.1 of the Subsidies Agreement, the administering authority shall notify the Trade Representative, and shall provide the Trade Representative with the information upon which the administering authority based its determination.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Request by interested party regarding adverse effects</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">An interested party may request the administering authority to determine if there is reason to believe that a subsidy which is actionable under the Subsidies Agreement is causing adverse effects. The request shall contain such information as the administering authority may require to support the allegations contained in the request. At the request of the administering authority, the Commission shall assist the administering authority in analyzing the information pertaining to the existence of such adverse effects. If the administering authority, after analyzing the request and other information reasonably available to the administering authority, determines that there is reason to believe that a subsidy which is actionable under the Subsidies Agreement is causing adverse effects, the administering authority shall so notify the Trade Representative, and shall include supporting information with the notification.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initiation of section 2411 investigation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On the basis of the notification and information provided by the administering authority pursuant to subsection (b) or (c), such other information as the Trade Representative may have or obtain, and where applicable, after consultation with an interested party referred to in subsection (b)(2) or (c)(2), the Trade Representative shall, unless such interested party objects, determine as expeditiously as possible, in accordance with the procedures in section 302(b)(1) of the Trade Act of 1974 (<ref>19 U.S.C. 2412(b)(1)</ref>), whether to initiate an investigation pursuant to title III of that Act (<ref>19 U.S.C. 2411</ref> et seq.). At the request of the Trade Representative, the administering authority and the Commission shall assist the Trade Representative in an investigation initiated pursuant to this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonactionable subsidies</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compliance with Article 8 of the Subsidies Agreement</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Monitoring</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In order to monitor whether a subsidy meets the conditions and criteria described in Article 8.2 of the Subsidies Agreement and is nonactionable, the Trade Representative shall provide the administering authority on a timely basis with any information submitted or report made pursuant to Article 8.3 or 8.4 of the Subsidies Agreement regarding a notified subsidy program. The administering authority shall review such information and reports, and where appropriate, shall recommend to the Trade Representative that the Trade Representative seek pursuant to Article 8.3 or 8.4 of the Subsidies Agreement additional information regarding the notified subsidy program or a subsidy granted pursuant to the notified subsidy program. If the administering authority has reason to believe that a violation of Article 8 of the Subsidies Agreement exists, the administering authority shall so notify the Trade Representative, and shall include supporting information with the notification.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Request by interested party regarding violation of Article 8</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">An interested party may request the administering authority to determine if there is reason to believe that a violation of Article 8 of the Subsidies Agreement exists. The request shall contain such information as the administering authority may require to support the allegations contained in the request. If the administering authority, after analyzing the request and other information reasonably available to the administering authority, determines that additional information is needed, the administering authority shall recommend to the Trade Representative that the Trade Representative seek, pursuant to Article 8.3 or 8.4 of the Subsidies Agreement, additional information regarding the particular notified subsidy program or a subsidy granted pursuant to the notified subsidy program. If the administering authority determines that there is reason to believe that a violation of Article 8 of the Subsidies Agreement exists, the administering authority shall so notify the Trade Representative, and shall include supporting information with the notification.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Action by Trade Representative</heading>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> If the Trade Representative, on the basis of the notification and information provided by the administering authority pursuant to subparagraph (A) or (B), and such other information as the Trade Representative may have or obtain, and after consulting with the interested party referred to in subparagraph (B) and appropriate domestic industries, determines that there is reason to believe that a violation of Article 8 of the Subsidies Agreement exists, the Trade Representative shall invoke the procedures of Article 8.4 or 8.5 of the Subsidies Agreement.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> For purposes of clause (i), the Trade Representative shall determine that there is reason to believe that a violation of Article 8 exists in any case in which the Trade Representative determines that a notified subsidy program or a subsidy granted pursuant to a notified subsidy program does not satisfy the conditions and criteria required for a nonactionable subsidy program under this Act, the Subsidies Agreement, and the statement of administrative action approved under <ref>section 3511(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification of administering authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Trade Representative shall notify the administering authority whenever a violation of Article 8 of the Subsidies Agreement has been found to exist pursuant to Article 8.4 or 8.5 of that Agreement.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Serious adverse effects</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Request by interested party</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">An interested party may request the administering authority to determine if there is reason to believe that serious adverse effects resulting from a program referred to in Article 8.2 of the Subsidies Agreement exist. The request shall contain such information as the administering authority may require to support the allegations contained in the request.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Action by administering authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Within 90 days after receipt of the request described in subparagraph (A), the administering authority, after analyzing the request and other information reasonably available to the administering authority, shall determine if there is reason to believe that serious adverse effects resulting from a program referred to in Article 8.2 of the Subsidies Agreement exist. If the determination of the administering authority is affirmative, it shall so notify the Trade Representative and shall include supporting information with the notification. The Commission shall assist the administering authority in analyzing the information pertaining to the existence of such serious adverse effects if the administering authority requests the Commission’s assistance. If the subsidy program that is alleged to result in serious adverse effects has been the subject of a countervailing duty investigation or review under subtitle A or C of title VII of the Tariff Act of 1930 [<ref>19 U.S.C. 1671</ref> et seq., 1675 et seq.], the administering authority shall take into account the determinations made by the administering authority and the Commission in such investigation or review and the administering authority shall complete its analysis as expeditiously as possible.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Action by Trade Representative</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Trade Representative, on the basis of the notification and information provided by the administering authority pursuant to subparagraph (B), and such other information as the Trade Representative may have or obtain, shall determine as expeditiously as possible, but not later than 30 days after receipt of the notification provided by the administering authority, if there is reason to believe that serious adverse effects exist resulting from the subsidy program which is the subject of the administering authority’s notification. The Trade Representative shall make an affirmative determination regarding the existence of such serious adverse effects unless the Trade Representative finds that the notification of the administering authority is not supported by the facts.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">If the Trade Representative determines that there is reason to believe that serious adverse effects resulting from the subsidy program exist, the Trade Representative, unless the interested party referred to in subparagraph (A) objects, shall invoke the procedures of Article 9 of the Subsidies Agreement, and shall request consultations pursuant to Article 9.2 of the Subsidies Agreement with respect to such serious adverse effects. If such consultations have not resulted in a mutually acceptable solution within 60 days after the request is made for such consultations, the Trade Representative shall refer the matter to the Subsidies Committee pursuant to Article 9.3 of the Subsidies Agreement.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(E)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determination by Subsidies Committee</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">If the Trade Representative determines that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> the Subsidies Committee has been prevented from making an affirmative determination regarding the existence of serious adverse effects under Article 9 of the Subsidies Agreement by reason of the refusal of the WTO member country with respect to which the consultations have been invoked to join in an affirmative consensus—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> that such serious adverse effects exist, or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> regarding a recommendation to such WTO member country to modify the subsidy program in such a way as to remove the serious adverse effects, or</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the Subsidies Committee has not presented its conclusions regarding the existence of such serious adverse effects within 120 days after the date the matter was referred to it, as required by Article 9.4 of the Subsidies Agreement,</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">the Trade Representative shall, within 30 days after such determination, make a determination under section 304(a)(1) of the Trade Act of 1974 (<ref>19 U.S.C. 2414(a)(1)</ref>) regarding what action to take under section 301(a)(1)(A) of that Act [<ref>19 U.S.C. 2411(a)(1)(A)</ref>].</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(F)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Noncompliance with Committee recommendation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In the event that the Subsidies Committee makes a recommendation under Article 9.4 of the Subsidies Agreement and the WTO member country with respect to which such recommendation is made does not comply with such recommendation within 6 months after the date of the recommendation, the Trade Representative shall make a determination under section 304(a)(1) of the Trade Act of 1974 (<ref>19 U.S.C. 2414(a)(1)</ref>) regarding what action to take under section 301(a) of that Act [<ref>19 U.S.C. 2411(a)</ref>].</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification, consultation, and publication</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification of Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Trade Representative shall submit promptly to the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Finance of the Senate, and other appropriate committees of the Congress any information submitted or report made pursuant to Article 8.3 or 8.4 of the Subsidies Agreement regarding a notified subsidy program.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Publication in the Federal Register</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The administering authority shall publish regularly in the Federal Register a summary notice of any information submitted or report made pursuant to Article 8.3 or 8.4 of the Subsidies Agreement regarding notified subsidy programs.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultations with Congress and private sector</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Trade Representative and the administering authority promptly shall consult with the committees referred to in paragraph (1), and with interested representatives of the private sector, regarding all information submitted or reports made pursuant to Article 8.3 or 8.4 of the Subsidies Agreement regarding a notified subsidy program.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than February 1 of each year beginning in 1996, the Trade Representative and the administering authority shall issue a joint report to the Congress detailing—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the subsidies practices of major trading partners of the United States, including subsidies that are prohibited, are causing serious prejudice, or are nonactionable, under the Subsidies Agreement, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the monitoring and enforcement activities of the Trade Representative and the administering authority during the preceding calendar year which relate to subsidies practices.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cooperation of other agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All agencies, departments, and independent agencies of the Federal Government shall cooperate fully with one another in carrying out the provisions of this section, and, upon the request of the administering authority, shall furnish to the administering authority all records, papers, and information in their possession which relate to the requirements of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adverse effects</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “adverse effects” has the meaning given that term in Articles 5(a) and 5(c) of the Subsidies Agreement.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administering authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “administering authority” has the meaning given that term in section 771(1) of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<ref>19 U.S.C. 1677(1)</ref>).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Commission</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Commission” means the United States International Trade Commission.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interested party</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “interested party” means a party described in subparagraph (C), (D), (E), (F), or (G) of section 771(9) of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<ref>19 U.S.C. 1677(9)(C)</ref>, (D), (E), (F), or (G)).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonactionable subsidy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “nonactionable subsidy” means a subsidy described in Article 8.1(b) of the Subsidies Agreement.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notified subsidy program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “notified subsidy program” means a subsidy program which has been notified pursuant to Article 8.3 of the Subsidies Agreement.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Serious adverse effects</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “serious adverse effects” has the meaning given that term in Article 9.1 of the Subsidies Agreement.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Subsidies Agreement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Subsidies Agreement” means the Agreement on Subsidies and Countervailing Measures described in section 771(8) of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<ref>19 U.S.C. 1677(8)</ref>).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Subsidies Committee</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Subsidies Committee” means the committee established pursuant to Article 24 of the Subsidies Agreement.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(10)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Subsidy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “subsidy” has the meaning given that term in Article 1 of the Subsidies Agreement.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(11)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Trade Representative</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Trade Representative” means the United States Trade Representative.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(12)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Violation of Article 8</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “violation of Article 8” means the failure of a notified subsidy program or an individual subsidy granted pursuant to a notified subsidy program to meet the applicable conditions and criteria described in Article 8.2 of the Subsidies Agreement.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment of proprietary information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the administering authority may provide the Trade Representative with a copy of proprietary information submitted to, or obtained by, the administering authority that the Trade Representative considers relevant in carrying out its responsibilities under this subchapter. The Trade Representative shall protect from public disclosure proprietary information obtained from the administering authority under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–465, title II, § 281</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4922</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–295, § 20(b)(13)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3527</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3572.</num>
<heading> Review of Subsidies Agreement</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General objectives</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The general objectives of the United States under this subchapter are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to ensure that parts II and III of the Agreement on Subsidies and Countervailing Measures referred to in <ref>section 3511(d)(12) of this title</ref> (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Subsidies Agreement”) are effective in disciplining the use of subsidies and in remedying the adverse effects of subsidies, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to ensure that part IV of the Subsidies Agreement does not undermine the benefits derived from any other part of that Agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Specific objective</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The specific objective of the United States under this subchapter shall be to create a mechanism which will provide for an ongoing review of the operation of part IV of the Subsidies Agreement.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sunset of noncountervailable subsidies provisions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Subparagraphs (B), (C), (D), and (E) of section 1677(5B) of this title shall cease to apply as provided in subparagraph (G)(i) of such section, unless, before the date referred to in such subparagraph (G)(i)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Subsidies Committee determines to extend Articles 6.1, 8, and 9 of the Subsidies Agreement as in effect on the date on which the Subsidies Agreement enters into force or in a modified form, in accordance with Article 31 of such Agreement,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the President consults with the Congress in accordance with paragraph (2), and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> an implementing bill is submitted and enacted into law in accordance with paragraphs (3) and (4).<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002154">1</ref></content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation with Congress before Subsidies Committee agrees to extend</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Before a determination is made by the Subsidies Committee to extend Articles 6.1, 8, and 9 of the Subsidies Agreement, the President shall consult with the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate regarding such extension.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementation of extension</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification and submission</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Any extension of subparagraphs (B), (C), (D), and (E) of section 1677(5B) of this title shall take effect if (and only if)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> after the Subsidies Committee determines to extend Articles 6.1, 8, and 9 of the Subsidies Agreement, the President submits to the committees referred to in paragraph (2) a copy of the document describing the terms of such extension, together with—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> a draft of an implementing bill,</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> a statement of any administrative action proposed to implement the extension, and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> the supporting information described in subparagraph (C); and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the implementing bill is enacted into law.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementing bill</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The implementing bill referred to in subparagraph (A) shall contain only those provisions that are necessary or appropriate to implement an extension of the provisions of section 1677(5B)(B), (C), (D), and (E) of this title as in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of the implementing bill or as modified to reflect the determination of the Subsidies Committee to extend Articles 6.1, 8, and 9 of the Subsidies Agreement.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Supporting information</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The supporting information required under subparagraph (A)(i)(III) consists of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an explanation as to how the implementing bill and proposed administrative action will change or affect existing law; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> a statement regarding—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> how the extension serves the interests of United States commerce, and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> why the implementing bill and proposed administrative action is required or appropriate to carry out the extension.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report by the Trade Representative</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than the date referred to in section 1677(5B)(G)(i) of this title, the Trade Representative shall submit to the Congress a report setting forth the provisions of law which were enacted to implement Articles 6.1, 8, and 9 of the Subsidies Agreement and should be repealed or modified if such provisions are not extended.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review of operation of Subsidies Agreement</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of Commerce, in consultation with other appropriate departments and agencies of the Federal Government, shall undertake an ongoing review of the operation of the Subsidies Agreement. The review shall address—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the effectiveness of part II of the Subsidies Agreement in disciplining the use of subsidies which are prohibited under Article 3 of the Agreement,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the effectiveness of part III and, in particular, Article 6.1 of the Subsidies Agreement, in remedying the adverse effects of subsidies which are actionable under the Agreement, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> the extent to which the provisions of part IV of the Subsidies Agreement may have undermined the benefits derived from other parts of the Agreement, and, in particular—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the extent to which WTO member countries have cooperated in reviewing and improving the operation of part IV of the Subsidies Agreement,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the extent to which the provisions of Articles 8.4 and 8.5 of the Subsidies Agreement have been effective in identifying and remedying violations of the conditions and criteria described in Article 8.2 of the Agreement, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the extent to which the provisions of Article 9 of the Subsidies Agreement have been effective in remedying the serious adverse effects of subsidy programs described in Article 8.2 of the Agreement.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Not later than 4 years and 6 months after <date date="1994-12-08">December 8, 1994</date>, the Secretary of Commerce shall submit to the Congress a report on the review required under this subsection.</continuation>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–465, title II, § 282</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4927</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–295, § 20(b)(16)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3527</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>ADDITIONAL IMPLEMENTATION OF AGREEMENTS</heading>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part A—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Foreign Trade Barriers and Unfair Trade Practices</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3581.</num>
<heading> Objectives in intellectual property</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the objective of the United States—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to accelerate the implementation of the Agreement on Trade-Related Aspects of Intellectual Property Rights referred to in <ref>section 3511(d)(15) of this title</ref>,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> to seek enactment and effective implementation by foreign countries of laws to protect and enforce intellectual property rights that supplement and strengthen the standards of the Agreement on Trade-Related Aspects of Intellectual Property Rights referred to in <ref>section 3511(d)(15) of this title</ref> and the North American Free Trade Agreement and, in particular—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to conclude bilateral and multilateral agreements that create obligations to protect and enforce intellectual property rights that cover new and emerging technologies and new methods of transmission and distribution, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to prevent or eliminate discrimination with respect to matters affecting the availability, acquisition, scope, maintenance, use, and enforcement of intellectual property rights,</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to secure fair, equitable, and nondiscriminatory market access opportunities for United States persons that rely upon intellectual property protection,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to take an active role in the development of the intellectual property regime under the World Trade Organization to ensure that it is consistent with other United States objectives, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to take an active role in the World Intellectual Property Organization (WIPO) to develop a cooperative and mutually supportive relationship between the World Trade Organization and WIPO.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–465, title III, § 315</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4942</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part B—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Textiles</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3591.</num>
<heading> Textile product integration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 120 days after the date that the WTO Agreement enters into force with respect to the United States, the Secretary of Commerce shall publish in the Federal Register a notice containing the list of products to be integrated in each stage set out in Article 2(8) of the Agreement on Textiles and Clothing referred to in <ref>section 3511(d)(4) of this title</ref>. After publication of such list, the list may not be changed unless otherwise required by statute or the international obligations of the United States, to correct technical errors, or to reflect reclassifications. Within 30 days after the publication of such list, the Trade Representative shall notify the list to the Textiles Monitoring Body established under Article 8 of the Agreement on Textiles and Clothing.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–465, title III, § 331</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4947</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–295, § 20(c)(7)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3528</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3592.</num>
<heading> Rules of origin for textile and apparel products</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulatory authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Treasury shall prescribe rules implementing the principles contained in subsection (b) for determining the origin of textiles and apparel products. Such rules shall be promulgated in final form not later than <date date="1995-07-01">July 1, 1995</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Principles</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Except as otherwise provided for by statute, a textile or apparel product, for purposes of the customs laws and the administration of quantitative restrictions, originates in a country, territory, or insular possession, and is the growth, product, or manufacture of that country, territory, or insular possession, if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the product is wholly obtained or produced in that country, territory, or possession;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> the product is a yarn, thread, twine, cordage, rope, cable, or braiding and—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the constituent staple fibers are spun in that country, territory, or possession, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the continuous filament is extruded in that country, territory, or possession;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the product is a fabric, including a fabric classified under chapter 59 of the HTS, and the constituent fibers, filaments, or yarns are woven, knitted, needled, tufted, felted, entangled, or transformed by any other fabric-making process in that country, territory, or possession; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the product is any other textile or apparel product that is wholly assembled in that country, territory, or possession from its component pieces.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rules</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> Notwithstanding paragraph (1)(D) and except as provided in subparagraphs (B) and (C)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the origin of a good that is classified under one of the following HTS headings or subheadings shall be determined under subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) of paragraph (1), as appropriate: 5609, 5807, 5811, 6209.20.50.40, 6213, 6214, 6301, 6302, 6303, 6304, 6305, 6306, 6307.10, 6307.90, 6308, or 9404.90; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a textile or apparel product which is knit to shape shall be considered to originate in, and be the growth, product, or manufacture of, the country, territory, or possession in which it is knit.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding paragraph (1)(C), fabric classified under the HTS as of silk, cotton, man-made fiber, or vegetable fiber shall be considered to originate in, and be the growth, product, or manufacture of, the country, territory, or possession in which the fabric is both dyed and printed when accompanied by two or more of the following finishing operations: bleaching, shrinking, fulling, napping, decating, permanent stiffening, weighting, permanent embossing, or moireing.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding paragraph (1)(D), goods classified under HTS heading 6117.10, 6213.00, 6214.00, 6302.22, 6302.29, 6302.52, 6302.53, 6302.59, 6302.92, 6302.93, 6302.99, 6303.92, 6303.99, 6304.19, 6304.93, 6304.99, 9404.90.85, or 9404.90.95, except for goods classified under such headings as of cotton or of wool or consisting of fiber blends containing 16 percent or more by weight of cotton, shall be considered to originate in, and be the growth, product, or manufacture of, the country, territory, or possession in which the fabric is both dyed and printed when accompanied by two or more of the following finishing operations: bleaching, shrinking, fulling, napping, decating, permanent stiffening, weighting, permanent embossing, or moireing.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Multicountry rule</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">If the origin of a good cannot be determined under paragraph (1) or (2), then that good shall be considered to originate in, and be the growth, product, or manufacture of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the country, territory, or possession in which the most important assembly or manufacturing process occurs, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> if the origin of the good cannot be determined under subparagraph (A), the last country, territory, or possession in which important assembly or manufacturing occurs.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Components cut in the United States</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> The value of a component that is cut to shape (but not to length, width, or both) in the United States from foreign fabric and exported to another country, territory, or insular possession for assembly into an article that is then returned to the United States—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> shall not be included in the dutiable value of such article, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> may be applied toward determining the percentage referred to in General Note 7(b)(i)(B) of the HTS, subject to the limitation provided in that note.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> No article (except a textile or apparel product) assembled in whole of components described in subparagraph (A), or of such components and components that are products of the United States, in a beneficiary country as defined in General Note 7(a) of the HTS shall be treated as a foreign article, or as subject to duty if—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the components after exportation from the United States, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the article itself before importation into the United States</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">do not enter into the commerce of any foreign country other than such a beneficiary country.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception for United States-Israel Free Trade Agreement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">This section shall not affect, for purposes of the customs laws and administration of quantitative restrictions, the status of goods that, under rulings and administrative practices in effect immediately before <date date="1994-12-08">December 8, 1994</date>, would have originated in, or been the growth, product, or manufacture of, a country that is a party to an agreement with the United States establishing a free trade area, which entered into force before <date date="1987-01-01">January 1, 1987</date>. For such purposes, such rulings and administrative practices that were applied, immediately before <date date="1994-12-08">December 8, 1994</date>, to determine the origin of textile and apparel products covered by such agreement shall continue to apply after <date date="1994-12-08">December 8, 1994</date>, and on and after the effective date described in subsection (c), unless such rulings and practices are modified by the mutual consent of the parties to the agreement.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">This section shall apply to goods entered, or withdrawn from warehouse, for consumption on or after <date date="1996-07-01">July 1, 1996</date>, except that this section shall not apply to goods if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the contract for the sale of such goods to the United States is entered into before <date date="1994-07-20">July 20, 1994</date>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> all of the material terms of sale in such contract, including the price and quantity of the goods, are fixed and determinable before <date date="1994-07-20">July 20, 1994</date>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a copy of the contract is filed with the Commissioner of Customs within 60 days after <date date="1994-12-08">December 8, 1994</date>, together with a certification that the contract meets the requirements of paragraphs (1) and (2); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the goods are entered, or withdrawn from warehouse, for consumption on or before <date date="1998-01-01">January 1, 1998</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">The origin of goods to which this section does not apply shall be determined in accordance with the applicable rules in effect on <date date="1994-07-20">July 20, 1994</date>.</continuation>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–465, title III, § 334</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4949</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–295, § 20(c)(9)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3528</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–200, title IV, § 405(a)</ref>, <date date="2000-05-18">May 18, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 292</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>AGRICULTURE-RELATED PROVISIONS</heading>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part A—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Market Access</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3601.</num>
<heading> Administration of tariff-rate quotas</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Orderly marketing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In implementing the tariff-rate quotas set out in Schedule XX for the entry, or withdrawal from warehouse, for consumption of goods in the United States, the President shall take such action as may be necessary to ensure that imports of agricultural products do not disrupt the orderly marketing of commodities in the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inadequate supply</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Where imports of an agricultural product are subject to a tariff-rate quota, and where the President determines and proclaims that the supply of the same or directly competitive or substitutable agricultural product will be inadequate, because of a natural disaster, disease, or major national market disruption, to meet domestic demand at reasonable prices, the President may temporarily increase the quantity of imports of the agricultural product that is subject to the in-quota rate of duty established under the tariff-rate quota.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Monitoring</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture shall monitor the domestic supply of agricultural products subject to a tariff-rate quota as the Secretary considers appropriate and shall advise the President when the domestic supply of the products and substitutable products combined with the estimated imports of the products under the tariff-rate quota may be inadequate to meet domestic demand at reasonable prices.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coverage of tariff-rate quotas</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exclusions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The President may, subject to terms and conditions determined appropriate by the President, provide that the entry, or withdrawal from warehouse, for consumption in the United States of an agricultural product shall not be subject to the over-quota rate of duty established under a tariff-rate quota if the agricultural product—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is imported by, or for the account of, any agency of the United States or of any foreign embassy;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is imported as a sample for taking orders, for the personal use of the importer, or for the testing of equipment;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> is a commercial sample or is entered for exhibition, display, or sampling at a trade fair or for research; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> is a blended syrup provided for in subheadings 1702.20.28, 1702.30.28, 1702.40.28, 1702.60.28, 1702.90.58, 1806.20.92, 1806.20.93, 1806.90.38, 1806.90.40, 2101.10.38, 2101.20.38, 2106.90.38, or 2106.90.67 of Schedule XX, if entered from a foreign trade zone by a foreign trade zone user whose facilities were in operation on <date date="1990-06-01">June 1, 1990</date>, to the extent that the annual quantity entered into the customs territory from such zone does not contain a quantity of sugar of nondomestic origin greater than the quantity authorized by the Foreign Trade Zones Board for processing in that zone during calendar year 1985.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reclassification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subject to the consultation and layover requirements of <ref>section 3524 of this title</ref>, the President may proclaim a modification to the coverage of a tariff-rate quota for any agricultural product if the President determines the modification is necessary or appropriate to conform the tariff-rate quota to Schedule XX as a result of a reclassification of any item by the Secretary of the Treasury.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Allocation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The President may allocate the in-quota quantity of a tariff-rate quota for any agricultural product among supplying countries or customs areas and may modify any allocation as determined appropriate by the President.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Bilateral agreement</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The President may proclaim an increase in the tariff-rate quota for beef if the President determines that an increase is necessary to implement—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the <date date="1994-03-24">March 24, 1994</date>, agreement between the United States and Argentina; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the <date date="1994-03-09">March 9, 1994</date>, agreement between the United States and Uruguay.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Continuation of sugar headnote</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The President is authorized to proclaim additional United States note 3 to chapter 17 of the HTS, and to proclaim the modifications to the note, as determined appropriate by the President to reflect Schedule XX.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–465, title IV, § 404</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4959</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3602.</num>
<heading> Special agricultural safeguard authority</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determination of trigger levels</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Consistent with Article 5 as determined by the President, the President shall cause to be published in the Federal Register—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the list of special safeguard agricultural goods not later than the date of entry into force of the WTO Agreement with respect to the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> for each special safeguard agricultural good—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the trigger level specified in subparagraph 1(a) of Article 5, on an annual basis;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the trigger price specified in subparagraph 1(b) of Article 5; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the relevant period.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determination of safeguard</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">If the President determines with respect to a special safeguard agricultural good that it is appropriate to impose—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the price-based safeguard in accordance with subparagraph 1(b) of Article 5; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the volume-based safeguard in accordance with subparagraph 1(a) of Article 5,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">the President shall, consistent with Article 5 as determined by the President, determine the amount of the duty to be imposed, the period such duty shall be in effect, and any other terms and conditions applicable to the duty.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Imposition of safeguard</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall direct the Secretary of the Treasury to impose a duty on a special safeguard agricultural good entered, or withdrawn from warehouse, for consumption in the United States in accordance with a determination made under subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> No simultaneous safeguard</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A duty may not be in effect for a special safeguard agricultural good pursuant to this section during any period in which such good is the subject of any action proclaimed pursuant to section 2252 or 2253 of this title.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exclusion of originating goods of USMCA countries</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The President shall exempt from any duty imposed under this section any good that qualifies as an originating good under <ref>section 4531 of this title</ref> of a USMCA country with respect to which preferential tariff treatment is provided under the USMCA.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In this subsection, the terms “preferential tariff treatment”, “USMCA”, and “USMCA country” have the meanings given those terms in <ref>section 4502 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Advice of Secretary of Agriculture</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture shall advise the President on the implementation of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall cease to be effective on the date, as determined by the President, that the special safeguard provisions of Article 5 are no longer in force with respect to the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “Article 5” means Article 5 of the Agreement on Agriculture described in <ref>section 3511(d)(2) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “relevant period” means the period determined by the President to be applicable to a special safeguard agricultural good for purposes of applying this section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “special safeguard agricultural good” means an agricultural good on which an additional duty may be imposed pursuant to the special safeguard provisions of Article 5.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–465, title IV, § 405</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4961</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–295, § 11</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3520</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–113, title II, § 201(a)</ref>, <date date="2020-01-29">Jan. 29, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 19</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part B—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Exports</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3611.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title II, § 201(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 951</ref></heading>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part C—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Other Provisions</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3621.</num>
<heading> Tobacco proclamation authority</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President, after consultation with the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and with the Committee on Finance of the Senate, may proclaim the reduction or elimination of any duty with respect to cigar binder and filler tobacco, wrapper tobacco, or oriental tobacco set forth in Schedule XX.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall take effect on <date date="1994-12-08">December 8, 1994</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–465, title IV, § 423</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4965</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3622.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 105–362, title XIV, § 1401(c)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-10">Nov. 10, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3294</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3623.</num>
<heading> Study of milk marketing order system</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture shall conduct a study to determine the effects of the Uruguay Round Agreements on the Federal milk marketing order system. Not later than 6 months after the date of entry into force of the WTO Agreement with respect to the United States, the Secretary of Agriculture shall report to the Congress on the results of the study.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–465, title IV, § 425</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4965</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3624.</num>
<heading> Additional program funding</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of additional funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Consistent, as determined by the President, with the obligations undertaken by the United States set forth in the Uruguay Round Agreements, the Commodity Credit Corporation shall use, in addition to any other funds appropriated or made available for such purposes, any funds made available under subsection (b) for authorized export promotion, foreign market development, export credit financing, and promoting the development, commercialization, and marketing of products resulting from alternative uses of agricultural commodities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amount of additional funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Amounts shall be credited to the Commodity Credit Corporation in fiscal year 1995 equal to the lesser of the dollar amount of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the fiscal year 1995 Pay-As-You-Go savings; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the 5-year Pay-As-You-Go savings;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">under <ref>section 902 of title 2</ref>, resulting from the enactment of the Federal Crop Insurance Reform Act of 1994.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall take effect on <date date="1994-12-08">December 8, 1994</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–465, title IV, § 426</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4966</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
</subchapter>
</chapter>