<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 34—</num>
<heading>NATIONAL EMERGENCIES</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>TERMINATING EXISTING DECLARED EMERGENCIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1601.</num>
<heading> Termination of existing declared emergencies</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> All powers and authorities possessed by the President, any other officer or employee of the Federal Government, or any executive agency, as defined in <ref>section 105 of title 5</ref>, as a result of the existence of any declaration of national emergency in effect on <date date="1976-09-14">September 14, 1976</date>, are terminated two years from <date date="1976-09-14">September 14, 1976</date>. Such termination shall not affect—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any action taken or proceeding pending not finally concluded or determined on such date;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any action or proceeding based on any act committed prior to such date; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> any rights or duties that matured or penalties that were incurred prior to such date.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> For the purpose of this section, the words “any national emergency in effect” means a general declaration of emergency made by the President.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 94–412, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1976-09-14">Sept. 14, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1255</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>DECLARATIONS OF FUTURE NATIONAL EMERGENCIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1621.</num>
<heading> Declaration of national emergency by President; publication in Federal Register; effect on other laws; superseding legislation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> With respect to Acts of Congress authorizing the exercise, during the period of a national emergency, of any special or extraordinary power, the President is authorized to declare such national emergency. Such proclamation shall immediately be transmitted to the Congress and published in the Federal Register.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Any provisions of law conferring powers and authorities to be exercised during a national emergency shall be effective and remain in effect (1) only when the President (in accordance with subsection (a) of this section), specifically declares a national emergency, and (2) only in accordance with this chapter. No law enacted after <date date="1976-09-14">September 14, 1976</date>, shall supersede this subchapter unless it does so in specific terms, referring to this subchapter, and declaring that the new law supersedes the provisions of this subchapter.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 94–412, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1976-09-14">Sept. 14, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1255</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1622.</num>
<heading> National emergencies</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination methods</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Any national emergency declared by the President in accordance with this subchapter shall terminate if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> there is enacted into law a joint resolution terminating the emergency; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the President issues a proclamation terminating the emergency.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Any national emergency declared by the President shall be terminated on the date specified in any joint resolution referred to in clause (1) or on the date specified in a proclamation by the President terminating the emergency as provided in clause (2) of this subsection, whichever date is earlier, and any powers or authorities exercised by reason of said emergency shall cease to be exercised after such specified date, except that such termination shall not affect—</continuation>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any action taken or proceeding pending not finally concluded or determined on such date;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any action or proceeding based on any act committed prior to such date; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any rights or duties that matured or penalties that were incurred prior to such date.</content>
</subparagraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination review of national emergencies by Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than six months after a national emergency is declared, and not later than the end of each six-month period thereafter that such emergency continues, each House of Congress shall meet to consider a vote on a joint resolution to determine whether that emergency shall be terminated.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Joint resolution; referral to Congressional committees; conference committee in event of disagreement; filing of report; termination procedure deemed part of rules of House and Senate</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A joint resolution to terminate a national emergency declared by the President shall be referred to the appropriate committee of the House of Representatives or the Senate, as the case may be. One such joint resolution shall be reported out by such committee together with its recommendations within fifteen calendar days after the day on which such resolution is referred to such committee, unless such House shall otherwise determine by the yeas and nays.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any joint resolution so reported shall become the pending business of the House in question (in the case of the Senate the time for debate shall be equally divided between the proponents and the opponents) and shall be voted on within three calendar days after the day on which such resolution is reported, unless such House shall otherwise determine by yeas and nays.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Such a joint resolution passed by one House shall be referred to the appropriate committee of the other House and shall be reported out by such committee together with its recommendations within fifteen calendar days after the day on which such resolution is referred to such committee and shall thereupon become the pending business of such House and shall be voted upon within three calendar days after the day on which such resolution is reported, unless such House shall otherwise determine by yeas and nays.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> In the case of any disagreement between the two Houses of Congress with respect to a joint resolution passed by both Houses, conferees shall be promptly appointed and the committee of conference shall make and file a report with respect to such joint resolution within six calendar days after the day on which managers on the part of the Senate and the House have been appointed. Notwithstanding any rule in either House concerning the printing of conference reports or concerning any delay in the consideration of such reports, such report shall be acted on by both Houses not later than six calendar days after the conference report is filed in the House in which such report is filed first. In the event the conferees are unable to agree within forty-eight hours, they shall report back to their respective Houses in disagreement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> Paragraphs (1)–(4) of this subsection, subsection (b) of this section, and <ref>section 1651(b) of this title</ref> are enacted by Congress—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> as an exercise of the rulemaking power of the Senate and the House of Representatives, respectively, and as such they are deemed a part of the rules of each House, respectively, but applicable only with respect to the procedure to be followed in the House in the case of resolutions described by this subsection; and they supersede other rules only to the extent that they are inconsistent therewith; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> with full recognition of the constitutional right of either House to change the rules (so far as relating to the procedure of that House) at any time, in the same manner, and to the same extent as in the case of any other rule of that House.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Automatic termination of national emergency; continuation notice from President to Congress; publication in Federal Register</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any national emergency declared by the President in accordance with this subchapter, and not otherwise previously terminated, shall terminate on the anniversary of the declaration of that emergency if, within the ninety-day period prior to each anniversary date, the President does not publish in the Federal Register and transmit to the Congress a notice stating that such emergency is to continue in effect after such anniversary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 94–412, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="1976-09-14">Sept. 14, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1255</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–93, title VIII, § 801</ref>, <date date="1985-08-16">Aug. 16, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 448</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>EXERCISE OF EMERGENCY POWERS AND AUTHORITIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1631.</num>
<heading> Declaration of national emergency by Executive order; authority; publication in Federal Register; transmittal to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">When the President declares a national emergency, no powers or authorities made available by statute for use in the event of an emergency shall be exercised unless and until the President specifies the provisions of law under which he proposes that he, or other officers will act. Such specification may be made either in the declaration of a national emergency, or by one or more contemporaneous or subsequent Executive orders published in the Federal Register and transmitted to the Congress.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 94–412, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="1976-09-14">Sept. 14, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1257</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>ACCOUNTABILITY AND REPORTING REQUIREMENTS OF PRESIDENT</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1641.</num>
<heading> Accountability and reporting requirements of President</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Maintenance of file and index of Presidential orders, rules and regulations during national emergency</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">When the President declares a national emergency, or Congress declares war, the President shall be responsible for maintaining a file and index of all significant orders of the President, including Executive orders and proclamations, and each Executive agency shall maintain a file and index of all rules and regulations, issued during such emergency or war issued pursuant to such declarations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Presidential orders, rules and regulations; transmittal to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All such significant orders of the President, including Executive orders, and such rules and regulations shall be transmitted to the Congress promptly under means to assure confidentiality where appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Expenditures during national emergency; Presidential reports to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">When the President declares a national emergency or Congress declares war, the President shall transmit to Congress, within ninety days after the end of each six-month period after such declaration, a report on the total expenditures incurred by the United States Government during such six-month period which are directly attributable to the exercise of powers and authorities conferred by such declaration. Not later than ninety days after the termination of each such emergency or war, the President shall transmit a final report on all such expenditures.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 94–412, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="1976-09-14">Sept. 14, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1257</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER V—</num>
<heading>APPLICATION TO POWERS AND AUTHORITIES OF OTHER PROVISIONS OF LAW AND ACTIONS TAKEN THEREUNDER</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1651.</num>
<heading> Other laws, powers and authorities conferred thereby, and actions taken thereunder; Congressional studies</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The provisions of this chapter shall not apply to the following provisions of law, the powers and authorities conferred thereby, and actions taken thereunder:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Chapters 1 to 11 of title 40 and division C (except sections 3302, 3307(e), 3501(b), 3509, 3906, 4710, and 4711) of subtitle I of title 41.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Section 3727(a)–(e)(1) of title 31.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content><ref>Section 6305 of title 41</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content><ref>Public Law 85–804</ref> (Act of <date date="1958-08-28">Aug. 28, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 972</ref>; <ref>50 U.S.C. 1431</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content><ref>Section 3201(a) of title 10</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Each committee of the House of Representatives and the Senate having jurisdiction with respect to any provision of law referred to in subsection (a) of this section shall make a complete study and investigation concerning that provision of law and make a report, including any recommendations and proposed revisions such committee may have, to its respective House of Congress within two hundred and seventy days after <date date="1976-09-14">September 14, 1976</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 94–412, title V, § 502</ref>, <date date="1976-09-14">Sept. 14, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1258</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–223, title I, § 101(d)</ref>, <date date="1977-12-28">Dec. 28, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 1625</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 507(b)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2919</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–362, title IX, § 901(r)(2)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-10">Nov. 10, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3291</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title X, § 1062</ref>(<i>o</i>)(1), <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2652</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1702(k)(2)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2160</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>