<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 51—</num>
<heading>WAR CLAIMS</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>TITLE I OF WAR CLAIMS ACT OF 1948</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4101.</num>
<heading> Foreign Claims Settlement Commission of the United States</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Employment of personnel; use of other facilities and services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Foreign Claims Settlement Commission of the United States (hereinafter referred to as the “Commission”) may, in accordance with the provisions of the civil-service laws and chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5, appoint and fix the compensation of such officers, attorneys, and employees, and may make such expenditures, as may be necessary to carry out its functions. Officers and employees of any other department or agency of the Government may, with the consent of the head of such department or agency, be assigned to assist the Commission in carrying out its functions. The Commission may, with the consent of the head of any other department or agency of the Government, utilize the facilities and services of such department or agency in carrying out the functions of the Commission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rules and regulations; delegation of functions; time limit on filing of claims</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission may prescribe such rules and regulations as may be necessary to enable it to carry out its functions, and may delegate functions to any member, officer, or employee of the Commission. The Commission shall give public notice of the time when, and the limit of time within which, claims may be filed, which notice shall be published in the Federal Register. The limit of time within which claims may be filed with the Commission shall in no event be later than <date date="1952-03-31">March 31, 1952</date>. The Commission shall take immediate action to advise all persons entitled to file claims under the provisions of this subchapter administered by the Commission of their rights under such provisions, and to assist them in the preparation and filing of their claims.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Subpenas; issuance; contempt; witness fees; administration of oaths</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> For the purpose of any hearing, examination, or investigation under this subchapter, the Commission and those employees designated by the Commission shall have the power to issue subpenas requiring persons to appear and testify or to appear and produce documents, or both, at any designated place where such hearing, examination, or investigation is being held. The Commission or any employee so designated shall, upon application of a claimant, issue to such claimant subpenas requiring the attendance and testimony of witnesses or the production of documents, or both, required by such claimant in hearings upon his claim: <i>Provided</i>, That the claimant making such application pay the witness fees and mileage of any witness or witnesses subpenaed upon his request. The production of a person’s documents at any place other than his place of business shall not be required, however, in any case in which, prior to the return date specified in the subpena with respect thereto, such person either has furnished the issuer of the subpena with a copy of such documents (certified by such person under oath to be a true and correct copy) or has entered into a stipulation with the issuer of the subpena as to the information contained in such documents.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Commission may, in case of a failure or refusal on the part of any person to comply with any such subpena, invoke the aid of any United States district court within the jurisdiction of which the hearing, examination, or investigation is being conducted, or such person resides or transacts business. Such court may issue an order requiring such person to appear at the designated place of hearing, examination, or investigation, there to give or produce testimony or documentary evidence concerning the matter in question. Any failure to obey such order of the court shall be punishable by such court as a contempt thereof. All process in any such case may be served in the judicial district wherein such person resides or transacts business or wherever such person may be found.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Witnesses subpenaed under this subsection shall be paid the same fees and mileage that are allowed and paid witnesses in United States district courts.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Any member of the Commission, and any employee of the Commission authorized by the Commission to do so, may administer to, or take from, any person an oath, affirmation, or affidavit when such action is necessary or appropriate in the performance of the functions or activities of the Commission.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 3, 1948, ch. 826</ref>, title I, § 2, <ref>62 Stat. 1240</ref>; <ref>May 27, 1949, ch. 145, § 1(1)</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 112</ref>; <ref>Oct. 28, 1949, ch. 782</ref>, title XI, § 1106(a), <ref>63 Stat. 972</ref>; <ref>Aug. 16, 1950, ch. 718</ref>, <ref>64 Stat. 449</ref>; <ref>Apr. 5, 1951, ch. 27</ref>, <ref>65 Stat. 28</ref>; 1954 Reorg. Plan No. 1 §§ 2, 4, eff. <date date="1954-07-01">July 1, 1954</date>, 19 F.R. 3985, <ref>68 Stat. 1279</ref>; <ref>Aug. 21, 1954, ch. 784, § 3</ref>, <ref>68 Stat. 762</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–846, title I</ref>, §§ 102, 104(a), <date date="1962-10-22">Oct. 22, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 1107</ref>, 1113; <ref>Pub. L. 96–209, title I, § 108</ref>, <date date="1980-03-14">Mar. 14, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 97</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4102.</num>
<heading> Jurisdiction of Commission</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission shall have jurisdiction to receive and adjudicate according to law claims as hereinafter provided.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 3, 1948, ch. 826</ref>, title I, § 3, <ref>62 Stat. 1241</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4103.</num>
<heading> Claims of employees of contractors</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payment by Secretary of Labor of certain claims; execution of releases</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Labor is authorized to receive, adjudicate according to law, and provide for the payment of any claim filed by any person specified in section 101(a) of the Act entitled “An Act to provide benefits for the injury, disability, death, or enemy detention of employees of contractors with the United States, and for other purposes”, approved <date date="1942-12-02">December 2, 1942</date>, as amended [<ref>42 U.S.C. 1701(a)</ref>], or by the legal representative of any such person who may have died, for the amount by which (1) the total sum which would have been payable to such person by his employer (not including any payments for overtime), if such person’s contract of employment had been in effect and he had been paid under it for the entire period during which he was entitled to receive benefits under section 101(b) of such Act [<ref>42 U.S.C. 1701(b)</ref>], exceeds (2) the entire amount creditable to such person’s account for such period under the provisions of such section plus any amounts paid to such person by such employer for such period or recovered by such person in any legal action against such employer based upon such person’s right against such employer for such period under the contract of employment, including payments in settlement of the liability of the employer arising under or out of such contract. No claim shall be allowed to any person under the provisions of this section unless such person executes a full release to the employer and to the United States in respect to the liability of the employer arising under or out of the contract of employment, except liability for workmen’s compensation benefits under the Act of <date date="1941-08-16">August 16, 1941</date>, as amended [<ref>42 U.S.C. 1651</ref> et seq.] or detention or other benefits paid under the Act of <date date="1942-12-02">December 2, 1942</date>, as amended [<ref>42 U.S.C. 1701</ref> et seq.]. Any claim allowed under the provisions of this section shall be certified by the Secretary of Labor to the Secretary of the Treasury for payment out of the War Claims Fund established by <ref>section 4110 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cancellation of employees’ obligations; repayment to employees</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of State is authorized and directed to cancel any obligation to the United States of any person specified in section 101(a) of such Act of <date date="1942-12-02">December 2, 1942</date> [<ref>42 U.S.C. 1701(a)</ref>], to pay any sum which may have been advanced to or on behalf of any such person by the Department of State for the purpose of paying the costs of food and medical services furnished to such person during his period of internment by the Imperial Japanese Government or for the purpose of paying transportation or other expenses of repatriation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Labor is authorized to receive, adjudicate according to law, and provide for the payment of any claim filed by any person specified in section 101(a) of such Act of <date date="1942-12-02">December 2, 1942</date> [<ref>42 U.S.C. 1701(a)</ref>], for the repayment of any sum which may have been paid by such person to the Department of State in settlement of any obligation of the type referred to in paragraph (1) of this subsection. Any claim allowed under the provisions of this paragraph shall be certified by the Secretary of Labor to the Secretary of the Treasury for payment out of the War Claims Fund established by <ref>section 4110 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 3, 1948, ch. 826</ref>, title I, § 4, <ref>62 Stat. 1241</ref>; 1950 Reorg. Plan No. 19, § 1, eff. <date date="1950-05-24">May 24, 1950</date>, 15 F.R. 3178, <ref>64 Stat. 1271</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–846, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1962-10-22">Oct. 22, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 1107</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4104.</num>
<heading> Internees</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> “Civilian American citizen” defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As used in subsections (b) and (f) of this section, the term “civilian American citizen” means any person who, being then a citizen of the United States, was captured by the Imperial Japanese Government on or after <date date="1941-12-07">December 7, 1941</date>, at Midway, Guam, Wake Island, the Philippine Islands, or any Territory or possession of the United States attacked or invaded by such government, or while in transit to or from any such place, or who went into hiding at any such place in order to avoid capture or internment by such government; except (1) a person who at any time voluntarily gave aid to, collaborated with, or in any manner served such government, or (2) a person who at the time of his capture or entrance into hiding was a regularly appointed, enrolled, enlisted, or inducted member of any military or naval force.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payment of detention benefits</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission is authorized to receive, adjudicate according to law, and provide for the payment of any claim filed by, or on behalf of, any civilian American citizen for detention benefits for any period of time subsequent to <date date="1941-12-06">December 6, 1941</date>, during which he was held by the Imperial Japanese Government as a prisoner, internee, hostage, or in any other capacity, or remained in hiding to avoid being captured or interned by such Imperial Japanese Government.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amount of detention benefits</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The detention benefit allowed to any person under the provisions of subsection (b) shall be at the rate of $60 for each calendar month during which such person was at least eighteen years of age and at the rate of $25 per month for each calendar month during which such person was less than eighteen years of age.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Persons entitled to detention benefits</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The detention benefits allowed under subsection (b) shall be allowed to the person entitled thereto, or, in the event of his death, only to the following persons:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Widow or husband if there is no child or children of the deceased;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Widow or husband and child or children of the deceased, one-half to the widow or husband and the other half to the child or children in equal shares;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Child or children of the deceased (in equal shares) if there is no widow or husband; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Parents (in equal shares) if there is no husband, or child.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certification of claims</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any claim allowed by the Commission under this section (except under subsections (g) and (i)) shall be certified to the Secretary of the Treasury for payment out of the war claims funds established by <ref>section 4110 of this title</ref>, and shall be payable by the Secretary of the Treasury to the person entitled thereto; except that where the person entitled to payment is under any legal disability, any part of the amount payable may, in the discretion of the Commission, be paid, for the use of the claimant, to the natural or legal guardian, committee, conservator, or curator of the claimant, or, if there is no such guardian, committee, conservator, or curator, then the Commission may, in its discretion, make payment to any other person, including the spouse of such claimant, whom the Commission may determine is vested with the care of the claimant or his estate for the use and benefit of such claimant or estate; and if such person is a minor, any part of the amount payable may, in the discretion of the Commission, be paid to such minor.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application of War Hazards Compensation Act; factors for determining benefits; effective date</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, the provisions of titles I and II of the Act entitled “An Act to provide benefits for the injury, disability, death, or enemy detention of employees of contractors with the United States, and for other purposes”, approved <date date="1942-12-02">December 2, 1942</date>, as amended [<ref>42 U.S.C. 1701</ref> et seq., 1711 et seq.], are extended and shall apply with respect to the injury, disability, or death resulting from injury of a civilian American citizen occurring while he was held by or in hiding from the Imperial Japanese Government, to the same extent as if such civilian American citizen were an employee within the purview of such Act of <date date="1942-12-02">December 2, 1942</date>, as amended.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> For the purpose of determining the benefits extended and made applicable by paragraph (1)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the average weekly wage of any such civilian American citizen, whether employed, self-employed, or not employed, shall be deemed to have been $37.50;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the provisions of such Act [<ref>42 U.S.C. 1701</ref> et seq.],<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002122">1</ref> shall be applicable whether or not any such civilian American citizen was employed;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> notice of injury or death shall not be required; and limitation provisions with respect to the filing of claims for injury, disability, or death shall not begin to run until <date date="1948-07-03">July 3, 1948</date>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the monthly compensation in cases involving partial disability shall be determined by the percentage the degree of partial disability bears to total disability and shall not be determined with respect to the extent of loss of wage earning capacity.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The following provisions of such Act of <date date="1942-12-02">December 2, 1942</date>, as amended [<ref>42 U.S.C. 1701</ref> et seq.], shall not apply in the case of such civilian American citizens: The last sentence of section 101(a), section 101(b), section 101(d) [<ref>42 U.S.C. 1701(a)</ref>, (b), (d)], section 104 [<ref>42 U.S.C. 1704</ref>], and section 105 [<ref>42 U.S.C. 1705</ref>].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Rights or benefits which, under this subsection, are to be determined with reference to other provisions of law shall be determined with reference to such provisions of law as in force on <date date="1948-01-03">January 3, 1948</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The money benefit for disability or death shall be paid only to the person entitled thereto, or to his legal or natural guardian if he has one, and shall not upon death of the person so entitled survive for the benefit of his estate or any other person.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The benefit of a minor or of an incompetent person who has no natural or legal guardian may, in the discretion of the Secretary of Labor, be paid, in whole or in such part as he may determine for and on behalf of such minor or incompetent directly to the person or institution caring for, supporting, or having custody of such minor or incompetent.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> No person, except a widow or a child, shall be entitled to benefits for disability with respect to himself, and to death benefits on account of the death of another.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> If a civilian American citizen or his dependent receives or has received from the United States any payments on account of the same injury or death, or from his employer, in the form of wages, or payments in lieu of wages, or in any form of support or compensation (including workmen’s compensation) in respect to the same objects, the benefits under this section shall be diminished by the amount of such payments in the following manner: (A) Benefits on account of injury or disability shall be reduced by the amount of payments to the injured person on account of the same injury or disability; and (B) benefits on account of death shall be reduced by the amount of payments to the dependents of the deceased civilian American citizen on account of the same death.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> This subsection shall take effect as of <date date="1941-12-07">December 7, 1941</date>, and the right of individuals to benefits shall be held to have begun to accrue as though this subsection had been in effect as of such date.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> No benefits provided by this subsection for injury, disability, or death shall accrue to any person who, without regard to this subsection, is entitled to or has received benefits for the same injury, disability, or death under such Act of <date date="1942-12-02">December 2, 1942</date>, as amended [<ref>42 U.S.C. 1701</ref> et seq.].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> No benefits provided by this subsection shall accrue to any person to whom benefits have been paid, or are payable, under the Federal Employees’ Compensation Act, or any extension thereof, by reason of disability or death of an employee of the United States suffered after capture, detention, or other restraint by an enemy of the United States, when such disability or death is deemed, in the administration of the Federal Employees’ Compensation Act to have resulted from injury occurring while in the performance of duty, under subsection (b) of section 5 of the Act entitled “An Act to amend the Act entitled ‘An Act to provide compensation for employees of the United States suffering injuries while in the performance of their duties, and for other purposes’, as amended”, approved <date date="1945-07-28">July 28, 1945</date>, as amended.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Benefits for civilian internees in Korea, and dependents; time</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> As used in this subsection, the term “civilian American citizens” means any person who, being then a citizen of the United States, was captured in Korea on or after <date date="1950-06-25">June 25, 1950</date>, by any hostile force with which the Armed Forces of the United States were actually engaged in armed conflict subsequent to such date and prior to <date date="1954-08-21">August 21, 1954</date>, or who went into hiding in Korea in order to avoid capture or internment by any such hostile force; except (A) a person who at any time voluntarily, knowingly, and without duress, gave aid to or collaborated with or in any manner served any such hostile force, or (B) a regularly appointed, enrolled, enlisted, or inducted member of the Armed Forces of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Commission is authorized to receive and to determine, according to law, the amount and validity, and provide for the payment of any claim filed by, or on behalf of, any civilian American citizen for detention benefits for any period of time subsequent to <date date="1950-06-25">June 25, 1950</date>, during which he was held by any such hostile force as a prisoner, internee, hostage, or in any other capacity, or remained in hiding to avoid being captured or interned by any such hostile force.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The detention benefit allowed to any person under the provisions of paragraph (2) of this subsection shall be at the rate of $60 for each calendar month during which such person was at least eighteen years of age and at the rate of $25 per month for each calendar month during which such person was less than eighteen years of age.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> The detention benefits allowed under paragraph (2) of this subsection shall be allowed to the person entitled thereto, or, in the event of his death, only to the following persons:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> widow or husband if there is no child or children of the deceased;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> widow or dependent husband and child or children of the deceased, one-half to the widow or dependent husband and the other half to the child or children in equal shares;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> child or children of the deceased (in equal shares) if there is no widow or dependent husband.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Any claim allowed by the Commission under this subsection shall be certified to the Secretary of the Treasury for payment out of funds appropriated pursuant to this subsection, and shall be paid by the Secretary of the Treasury to the person entitled thereto, except that where any person entitled to payment under this subsection is under any legal disability, payment may be made in accordance with the provisions of subsection (e) of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> Each claim filed under this subsection must be filed not later than one year from whichever of the following dates last occurs:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content><date date="1954-08-21">August 21, 1954</date>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The date the civilian American citizen by whom the claim is filed returned to the jurisdiction of the United States; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The date upon which the Commission, at the request of a potentially eligible survivor, makes a determination that the civilian American citizen has actually died or may be presumed to be dead, in the case of any civilian American citizen who has not returned to the jurisdiction of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">The Commission shall complete its determinations with respect to each claim filed under this subsection at the earliest practicable date, but in no event later than one year after the date on which such claim was filed.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(7)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> There are authorized to be appropriated such amounts as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this subsection, including necessary administrative expenses.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Commission shall determine, from time to time, the share of its administrative expenses attributable to the performance of its functions under this subsection and make the appropriate adjustments in its accounts, and determinations and adjustments made pursuant to this subparagraph shall be final and conclusive.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Benefits for Guamanians killed or captured at Wake Island on or after <date date="1941-12-07">December 7, 1941</date></heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the case of any Guamanian killed or captured by the Imperial Japanese Government on or after <date date="1941-12-07">December 7, 1941</date>, at Wake Island, benefits shall be granted under subsections (a) through (f) of this section in the same manner and to the same extent as apply in the case of civilian American citizens so killed or captured. Claims for benefits under subsections (a) through (e) of this section must be filed within six months after <date date="1962-08-31">August 31, 1962</date>, and the time limitation applicable to any individual by subsection (f) shall not begin to run until <date date="1962-08-31">August 31, 1962</date>, with respect to any individual who is entitled to such benefits solely by reason of this subsection. The preceding sentence shall not be construed to affect the right of any individual to receive such benefits with respect to any period prior to <date date="1962-08-31">August 31, 1962</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Detention benefits for civilian internees in Southeast Asia; definitions; authority of Commission; claim for benefits; rate of compensation; persons entitled to payments; certification for payment; filing date; determination of claims; appropriations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> As used in this subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the term “Vietnam conflict” relates to the period beginning on <date date="1961-02-28">February 28, 1961</date>, and ending on such date as shall thereafter be determined by Presidential proclamation or concurrent resolution of the Congress; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the term “civilian American citizen” means any person who, being then a citizen of the United States, was captured in Southeast Asia during the Vietnam conflict by any force hostile to the United States, or who went into hiding in Southeast Asia, in order to avoid capture or internment by any such hostile force, except (i) a person who voluntarily, knowingly, and without duress, gave aid to or collaborated with or in any manner served any such hostile force, or (ii) a regularly appointed, enrolled, enlisted, or inducted member of the Armed Forces of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Commission is authorized to receive and to determine, according to law, the amount and validity, and provide for the payment of any claim filed by, or on behalf of, any civilian American citizen for detention benefits for any period of time subsequent to <date date="1961-02-27">February 27, 1961</date>, during which he was held by any such hostile force as a prisoner, internee, hostage, or in any other capacity, or remained in hiding to avoid capture or internment by any such hostile force.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The detention benefits allowed under paragraph (2) of this subsection shall be at the rate of $150 for each calendar month.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> The detention benefits allowed under paragraph (2) of this subsection shall be allowed to the civilian American citizen entitled thereto, or, in the event of his death, only to the following persons:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the widow or husband if there is no child or children of the deceased;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the widow or dependent husband and child or children of the deceased, one-half to the widow or dependent husband and the other half to the child or children in equal shares;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the child or children of the deceased in equal shares if there is no widow or dependent husband.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Any claim allowed by the Commission under this subsection shall be certified to the Secretary of the Treasury for payment out of funds appropriated pursuant to this subsection, and shall be paid to the person entitled thereto, except that if a person entitled to payment under this section is under any legal disability, payment shall be made in accordance with the provisions of subsection (e) of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> Each claim filed under this section must be filed not later than three years from whichever of the following dates last occurs:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content><date date="1970-06-24">June 24, 1970</date>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the date the civilian American citizen by whom the claim is filed returned to the jurisdiction of the United States; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the date upon which the Commission, at the request of a potentially eligible survivor, makes a determination that the civilian American citizen has actually died or may be presumed to be dead, in the case of any civilian American citizen who has not returned to the jurisdiction of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">The Commission shall complete its determinations for each claim filed under this subsection at the earliest practicable date, but not later than one year after the date on which such claim was filed.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> There are authorized to be appropriated such amounts as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this subsection, including necessary administrative expenses.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 3, 1948, ch. 826</ref>, title I, § 5, <ref>62 Stat. 1242</ref>; 1950 Reorg. Plan No. 19, § 1, eff. <date date="1950-05-24">May 24, 1950</date>, 15 F.R. 3178, <ref>64 Stat. 1271</ref>; <ref>Apr. 9, 1952, ch. 168, § 1</ref>, <ref>66 Stat. 49</ref>; <ref>Aug. 21, 1954, ch. 784, § 1</ref>, <ref>68 Stat. 759</ref>; <ref>Aug. 31, 1954, ch. 1162</ref>, title I, §§ 101 (a)–(c), 102(a), <ref>68 Stat. 1033</ref>, 1034; <ref>Pub. L. 87–617</ref>, <date date="1962-08-31">Aug. 31, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 413</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–846, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1962-10-22">Oct. 22, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 1107</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–289, § 3</ref>, <date date="1970-06-24">June 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 324</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–383</ref>, <date date="1976-08-12">Aug. 12, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1122</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4105.</num>
<heading> Prisoners of war</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> “Prisoner of war” defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As used in subsection (b) of this section, the term “prisoner of war” means any regularly appointed, enrolled, enlisted, or inducted member of the military or naval forces of the United States who was held as a prisoner of war for any period of time subsequent to <date date="1941-12-07">December 7, 1941</date>, by any government of any nation with which the United States has been at war subsequent to such date.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payment of claims; rate allowed; certification of claims</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission is authorized to receive, adjudicate according to law, and provide for the payment of any claim filed by any prisoner of war for compensation for the violation by the enemy government by which he was held as a prisoner of war, or its agents, of its obligation to furnish him the quantity or quality of food to which he was entitled as a prisoner of war under the terms of the Geneva Convention of <date date="1929-07-27">July 27, 1929</date>. The compensation allowed to any prisoner of war under the provisions of this subsection shall be at the rate of $1 for each day he was held as a prisoner of war on which the enemy government or its agents failed to furnish him such quantity or quality of food. Any claim allowed under the provisions of this subsection shall be certified to the Secretary of the Treasury for payment out of the War Claims Fund established by <ref>section 4110 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Persons entitled to payments</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Claims pursuant to subsection (b) shall be paid to the person entitled thereto, and shall in case of death of the persons who are entitled be payable only to or for the benefit of the following persons:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Widow or husband if there is no child or children of the deceased;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Widow or husband and child or children of the deceased, one-half to the widow or husband and the other half to the child or children of the deceased in equal shares;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Child or children of the deceased (in equal shares) if there is no widow or husband; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Parents (in equal shares) if there is no widow, husband, or child.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional definition of “prisoner of war”; payment of claims; rate allowed; persons entitled to payments</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> As used in this subsection the term “prisoner of war” means any regularly appointed, enrolled, enlisted, or inducted member of the military or naval forces of the United States, who was held a prisoner of war for any period of time subsequent to <date date="1941-12-07">December 7, 1941</date>, by any government of any nation with which the United States has been at war subsequent to such date.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Commission is authorized to receive, adjudicate according to law, and to provide for the payment of any claim filed by any prisoner of war for compensation—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> for the violations by the enemy government by which he was held as a prisoner of war, or its agents, of such government’s obligations under title III, section III, of the Geneva Convention of <date date="1929-07-27">July 27, 1929</date>, relating to labor of prisoners of war; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for inhumane treatment by the enemy government by which he was held, or its agents. The term “inhumane treatment” as used herein shall include, but not be limited to, violation by such enemy government, or its agents, of one or more of the provisions of articles 2, 3, 7, 10, 12, 13, 21, 22, 54, 56, or 57, of the Geneva Convention of <date date="1929-07-27">July 27, 1929</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> Compensation shall be allowed to any prisoner of war under this subsection at the rate of $1.50 per day for each day he was held as a prisoner of war on which he alleges and proves in a manner acceptable to the Commission—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the violation by such enemy government or its agents of the provisions of title III, section III, of the Geneva Convention of <date date="1929-07-27">July 27, 1929</date>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any inhumane treatment as defined herein.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Any claim allowed under the provisions of this subsection shall be certified to the Secretary of the Treasury for payment out of the War Claims Fund established by <ref>section 4110 of this title</ref>. In no event shall the compensation allowed to any prisoner of war under this subsection exceed the sum of $1.50 with respect to any one day.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> Claims pursuant to subsection (d)(2) shall be paid to the person entitled thereto, or to his legal or natural guardian if he has one, and shall, in case of death of the persons who are entitled be payable only to or for the benefit of the following persons:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> widow or husband if there is no child or children of the deceased;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> widow or husband and child or children of the deceased, one-half to the widow or husband and the other half to the child or children of the deceased in equal shares;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> child or children of the deceased (in equal shares) if there is no widow or husband; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> parents (in equal shares) if there is no widow, husband, or child.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Extension to Korean War prisoners</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> As used in this subsection the term “prisoner of war” means any regularly appointed, enrolled, enlisted, or inducted member of the Armed Forces of the United States who was held as a prisoner of war for any period of time subsequent to <date date="1950-06-25">June 25, 1950</date>, by any hostile force with which the Armed Forces of the United States were actually engaged in armed conflict subsequent to such date and prior to <date date="1954-08-21">August 21, 1954</date>, or any person (military or civilian) assigned to duty in the U.S.S. Pueblo who was captured by the military forces of North Korea on <date date="1968-01-23">January 23, 1968</date>, and thereafter held prisoner by the Government of North Korea for any period of time ending on or before <date date="1968-12-23">December 23, 1968</date>, except any person who, at any time, voluntarily, knowingly, and without duress, gave aid to or collaborated with or in any manner served any such hostile force.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Commission is authorized to receive and to determine, according to law, the amount and validity, and provide for the payment of any claim filed by any prisoner of war for compensation for the failure of the hostile force by which he was held as a prisoner of war, or its agents, to furnish him the quantity or quality of food prescribed for prisoners of war under the terms of the Geneva Convention of <date date="1929-07-27">July 27, 1929</date>. The compensation allowed to any prisoner of war under the provisions of this paragraph shall be at the rate of $1 for each day on which he was held as a prisoner of war and on which such hostile force, or its agents, failed to furnish him such quantity or quality of food.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The Commission is authorized to receive and to determine, according to law, the amount and validity and provide for the payment of any claim filed by any prisoner of war for compensation—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> for the failure of the hostile force by which he was held as a prisoner of war, or its agents, to meet the conditions and requirements prescribed under title III, section III, of the Geneva Convention of <date date="1929-07-27">July 27, 1929</date>, relating to labor of prisoners of war; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for inhumane treatment by the hostile force by which he was held, or its agents. The term “inhumane treatment” as used herein shall include, but not be limited to, failure of such hostile force, or its agents, to meet the conditions and requirements of one or more of the provisions of articles 2, 3, 7, 10, 12, 13, 21, 22, 54, 56, or 57 of the Geneva Convention of <date date="1929-07-27">July 27, 1929</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Compensation shall be allowed to any prisoner of war under this paragraph at the rate of $1.50 per day for each day on which he was held as a prisoner of war and with respect to which he alleges and proves in a manner acceptable to the Commission the failure to meet the conditions and requirements described in subparagraph (A) or the inhumane treatment described in subparagraph (B). In no event shall the compensation allowed to any prisoner of war under this paragraph exceed the sum of $1.50 with respect to any one day.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Any claim allowed by the Commission under this subsection shall be certified to the Secretary of the Treasury for payment out of funds appropriated pursuant to this subsection and shall be paid by the Secretary of the Treasury to the person entitled thereto, and shall, in case of death or determination of death of the persons who are entitled, be paid only to or for the benefit of the persons specified, and in the order established, by paragraph (4) of subsection (d) of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> Each claim filed under this subsection must be filed not later than one year from whichever of the following dates last occurs:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content><date date="1954-08-21">August 21, 1954</date>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The date the prisoner of war by whom the claim is filed returned to the jurisdiction of the Armed Forces of the United States; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The date upon which the Department of Defense makes a determination that the prisoner of war has actually died or is presumed to be dead, in the case of any prisoner of war who has not returned to the jurisdiction of the Armed Forces of the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> In the case of any person assigned to duty in the U.S.S. Pueblo referred to in paragraph (1) of this subsection, one year after <date date="1970-06-24">June 24, 1970</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">The Commission shall complete its determinations with respect to each claim filed under this subsection at the earliest practicable date, but in no event later than one year after the date on which such claim was filed.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Any claim allowed under the provisions of this subsection shall be paid from funds appropriated pursuant to paragraph (7) of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(7)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> There are authorized to be appropriated such amounts as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this subsection, including necessary administrative expenses.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Commission shall determine, from time to time, the share of its administrative expenses attributable to the performance of its functions under this subsection and make the appropriate adjustments in its accounts, and determinations and adjustments made pursuant to this subparagraph shall be final and conclusive.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Vietnam conflict; definitions; authority of Commission; classes of claims; rate of compensation; certification for payment; persons entitled to payments; filing date; determination of claims; fund for payment; appropriations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> As used in this subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the term “Vietnam conflict” relates to the period beginning <date date="1961-02-28">February 28, 1961</date>, and ending on such date as shall thereafter be determined by Presidential proclamation or concurrent resolution of the Congress; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the term “prisoner of war” means any regularly appointed, enrolled, enlisted, or inducted member of the Armed Forces of the United States who was held as a prisoner of war for any period of time during the Vietnam conflict by any force hostile to the United States, except any such member who, at any time, voluntarily, knowingly, and without duress, gave aid to or collaborated with, or in any manner served, such hostile force.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Commission is authorized to receive and to determine, according to law, the amount and validity, and provide for the payment of any claim filed by any prisoner of war for compensation for the failure of the hostile force by which he was held as a prisoner of war, or its agents, to furnish him the quantity or quality of food prescribed for prisoners of war under the terms of the Geneva Convention of <date date="1949-08-12">August 12, 1949</date>. The compensation allowed to any prisoner of war under the provisions of this paragraph shall be at the rate of $2 for each day on which he was held as a prisoner of war and on which such hostile force, or its agents, failed to furnish him such quantity or quality of food.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The Commission is authorized to receive and to determine, according to law, the amount and validity and provide for the payment of any claim filed by any prisoner of war for compensation—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> for the failure of the hostile force by which he was held as a prisoner of war, or its agents, to meet the conditions and requirements prescribed under chapter VIII, section III, of the Geneva Convention of <date date="1949-08-12">August 12, 1949</date>, relating to labor of prisoners of war; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for inhumane treatment by the hostile force by which he was held, or its agents. The term “inhumane treatment” as used in this subparagraph shall include, but not be limited to, failure of such hostile force, or its agents, to meet the conditions and requirements of one or more of the provisions of articles 3, 12, 13, 14, 17, 19, 22, 23, 24, 25, 27, 29, 43, 44, 45, 46, 47, 48, 84, 85, 86, 87, 88, 89, 90, 97, or 98 of the Geneva Convention of <date date="1949-08-12">August 12, 1949</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Compensation shall be allowed to any prisoner of war under this paragraph at the rate of $3 per day for each day on which he was held as a prisoner of war and with respect to which he alleges and proves in a manner acceptable to the Commission the failure to meet the conditions and requirements described in subparagraph (A) of this paragraph or the inhumane treatment described in subparagraph (B) of this paragraph. In no event shall the compensation allowed to any prisoner of war under this paragraph exceed the sum of $3 with respect to any one day.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Any claim allowed by the Commission under this subsection shall be certified to the Secretary of the Treasury for payment out of funds appropriated pursuant to this subsection and shall be paid by the Secretary of the Treasury to the person entitled thereto, and shall, in the case of death or determination of death of the persons who are entitled, be paid only to or for the benefit of the persons specified, and in the order established, by subsection (d)(4) of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> Each claim filed under this subsection must be filed not later than three years from whichever of the following dates last occurs:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content><date date="1970-06-24">June 24, 1970</date>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the date the prisoner of war by whom the claim is filed returned to the jurisdiction of the Armed Forces of the United States; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the date upon which the Department of Defense makes a determination that the prisoner of war has actually died or is presumed to be dead, in the case of any prisoner of war who has not returned to the jurisdiction of the Armed Forces of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">The Commission shall complete its determinations with respect to each claim filed under this subsection at the earliest practicable date, but in no event later than one year after the date on which such claim was filed.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Any claim allowed under the provisions of this subsection shall be paid from funds appropriated pursuant to paragraph (7) of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> There are authorized to be appropriated such amounts as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this subsection, including necessary administrative expenses.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Manner of payment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Where any person entitled to payment under this section is under any legal disability, payment may be made in accordance with the provisions of subsection (e) of <ref>section 4104 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 3, 1948, ch. 826</ref>, title I, § 6, <ref>62 Stat. 1244</ref>; <ref>Sept. 30, 1950, ch. 1116</ref>, <ref>64 Stat. 1090</ref>; <ref>Apr. 9, 1952, ch. 167, § 1</ref>, <ref>66 Stat. 47</ref>; <ref>Apr. 9, 1952, ch. 168, § 2</ref>, <ref>66 Stat. 49</ref>; <ref>Aug. 21, 1954, ch. 784, § 2</ref>, <ref>68 Stat. 761</ref>; <ref>Aug. 31, 1954, ch. 1162</ref>, title I, § 102(a)(1), <ref>68 Stat. 1034</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–846, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1962-10-22">Oct. 22, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 1107</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–289</ref>, §§ 1, 2, <date date="1970-06-24">June 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 323</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4106.</num>
<heading> Religious organizations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reimbursement for services furnished members of armed services and American civilians; certification of claims</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission is authorized to receive, adjudicate according to law, and provide for the payment of any claim filed by any religious organization functioning in the Philippine Islands and affiliated with a religious organization in the United States, or by the personnel of any such Philippine organization, for reimbursement of expenditures incurred, or for payment of the fair value of supplies used, by such organization or such personnel for the purpose of furnishing shelter, food, clothing, hospitalization, medicines and medical services, and other relief in the Philippines to members of the armed forces of the United States or to civilian American citizens (as defined in <ref>section 4104 of this title</ref>) at any time subsequent to <date date="1941-12-06">December 6, 1941</date>, and before <date date="1945-08-15">August 15, 1945</date>. Any claim allowed under the provisions of this section shall be certified to the Secretary of the Treasury for payment out of the War Claims Fund established by <ref>section 4110 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation for loss or damage to real property used in educational, medical, or welfare work</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any such religious organization or its personnel functioning in the Philippines and affiliated with a religious organization in the United States, which furnished relief in the Philippines to members of the Armed Forces of the United States or to civilian American citizens in accordance with the provisions of subsection (a) shall be compensated from the War Claims Fund, as hereinafter provided, for the loss and damage sustained as a consequence of the war to its schools, colleges, universities, scientific observatories, hospitals, dispensaries, orphanages, and other property or facilities connected with its educational, medical, or welfare work.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation to replace facilities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any such affiliated organization furnishing relief which possessed any interest in, and whose personnel of American citizens substantially composed the administrative staff of, any hospital whose prewar facilities and capacity have not been restored shall be compensated in an amount sufficient to enable such organization to replace the hospital’s facilities and capacity equal to that which existed at the time of the outbreak of the war, irrespective of what disposition was made subsequently of the land, buildings, and contents.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determination of claims</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Claims filed pursuant to subsection (b) shall be determined and paid upon the basis of postwar cost of replacement which shall be ascertained by the War Claims Commission. In making such determinations the Commission shall utilize but not be limited to the factual information and evidence contained in the records of the Philippine War Damage Commission; the technical advice of experts in the field; the substantiating evidence submitted by the claimants; and any other technical and legal means by which fair and equitable postwar replacement costs shall be determined.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Investigation; determination of replacement costs; basis used</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission is authorized and directed to proceed at once with the necessary investigation, study, and establishment of procedures in order to determine the replacement costs of the claims to be filed under subsections (b) and (c), using as a basis for beginning such investigation and study the evidence contained in the claims of those religious organizations or their personnel which have already filed and are eligible to be paid under the terms of subsection (a) of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Filing of claims; adjudication; place and use of payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All claims under subsections (b) and (c) must be filed on or before <date date="1952-10-01">October 1, 1952</date>; and not later than <date date="1953-03-31">March 31, 1953</date>, the Commission shall adjudicate according to law and provide for the payment of any claim filed pursuant to this section. In any case in which any money is payable as a result of subsections (b) and (c) to a religious organization or its personnel functioning in the Philippines, such money shall be paid upon request of such organization to its affiliate in the United States: <i>Provided</i>, That all money thus paid to such affiliated religious organization in the United States shall be used by such affiliate for the purpose of restoring the educational, medical, and welfare facilities described in subsections (b) and (c) and located in the Philippines.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Claims of internees and prisoners of war unaffected</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission shall expedite the payments under this section without reducing payment of claims of American civilian internees and prisoners of war filed before <date date="1953-03-31">March 31, 1953</date>, pursuant to the provisions of sections 4104 and 4105 of this title.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Denominational organizations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Any religious organization functioning in the Philippines and of the same denomination as a religious organization functioning in the United States which furnished relief (as described, and during the period designated, in subsection (a) of this section) in the Philippines to members of the Armed Forces of the United States or to civilian American citizens shall be compensated from the War Claims Fund (A) for expenditures incurred, or for payment of the fair value of supplies used by such organization, for the purpose of furnishing such relief and (B) for loss and damage sustained as a consequence of the war to its schools, colleges, universities, scientific observatories, hospitals, dispensaries, orphanages, and other property or facilities connected with its educational, medical, or welfare work. No payments shall be made to any organization under this subsection if such organization has received an award under subsection (a) or (b) of this section, and no payments shall be made to any organization pursuant to clause (B) of this paragraph unless such organization has received an award for war damages from the Philippine War Damage Commission under the provisions of the Philippine Rehabilitation Act of 1946, as amended.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002123">1</ref></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Commission is authorized to receive, determine according to law, and provide for the payment of claims filed under this subsection. Each claim allowed by the Commission under this subsection shall be certified to the Secretary of the Treasury for payment out of the War Claims Fund. All payments under this subsection shall be made to an organization or individual in the United States designated by the claimant, and, in the case of claims under clause (B) of paragraph (1) of this subsection such payments shall be used for the purpose of restoring the educational, medical, and welfare facilities described in such clause.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Claims for benefits under this subsection must be filed within six months after <date date="1956-08-06">August 6, 1956</date>. The Commission shall complete its determination with respect to each claim filed under this subsection at the earliest practicable date, but in no event later than one year after the date on which such claim was filed.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Claims filed pursuant to clause (B) of paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be determined and paid upon the basis of postwar cost of replacement for the twelve-month period ending <date date="1952-10-01">October 1, 1952</date>, as ascertained by the Commission.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 3, 1948, ch. 826</ref>, title I, § 7, <ref>62 Stat. 1245</ref>; <ref>Apr. 9, 1952, ch. 167, § 2</ref>, <ref>66 Stat. 48</ref>; <ref>Aug. 6, 1956, ch. 985</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 1063</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–846, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1962-10-22">Oct. 22, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 1107</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4107.</num>
<heading> Reports to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than six months after its organization, and every six months <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002124">1</ref> thereafter, the Commission shall make a report to the Congress concerning its operations under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 3, 1948, ch. 826</ref>, title I, § 9, <ref>62 Stat. 1246</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–846, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1962-10-22">Oct. 22, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 1107</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4108.</num>
<heading> Fee limitation for representing claimants; penalties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No remuneration on account of services rendered or to be rendered to or on behalf of any claimant in connection with any claim filed with the administering agency under this subchapter shall exceed 10 per centum (or such lesser per centum as may be fixed by the administering agency with respect to any class of claims) of the amount allowed by the administering agency on account of such claim. Any agreement to the contrary shall be unlawful and void. Whoever, in the United States or elsewhere, pays or offers to pay, or promises, to pay, or receives, on account of services rendered or to be rendered in connection with any such claim, any remuneration in excess of the maximum permitted by this section, shall be deemed guilty of a misdemeanor, and, upon conviction thereof, shall be fined not more than $5,000 or imprisoned not more than twelve months, or both, and, if any such payment shall have been made or granted, the administering agency shall take such action as may be necessary to recover the same, and, in addition thereto any such claimant shall forfeit all rights under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 3, 1948, ch. 826</ref>, title I, § 10, <ref>62 Stat. 1246</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–846, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1962-10-22">Oct. 22, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 1107</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4109.</num>
<heading> Hearings on claims; finality of decision</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission shall notify all claimants of the approval or denial of their claims, and, if approved, shall notify such claimants of the amount for which such claims are approved. Any claimant whose claim is denied, or is approved for less than the full allowable amount of such claim, shall be entitled, under such regulations as the Commission may prescribe, to a hearing before the Commission or its representatives with respect to such claim. Upon such hearing, the Commission may affirm, modify, or revise its former action with respect to such claim, including a denial or reduction in the amount theretofore allowed with respect to such claim. The action of the Commission in allowing or denying any claim under this subchapter shall be final and conclusive on all questions of law and fact and not subject to review by any other official of the United States or by any court by mandamus or otherwise, and the Comptroller General is authorized and directed to allow credit in the accounts of any certifying or disbursing officer for payments in accordance with such action.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 3, 1948, ch. 826</ref>, title I, § 11, <ref>62 Stat. 1246</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–846, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1962-10-22">Oct. 22, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 1107</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4110.</num>
<heading> War Claims Fund</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Composition; expenditure</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is hereby created on the books of the Treasury of the United States a trust fund to be known as the War Claims Fund. The War Claims Fund shall consist of all sums covered into the Treasury pursuant to the provisions of <ref>section 4336 of this title</ref>. The moneys in such fund shall be available for expenditure only as provided in this chapter or as may be provided hereafter by the Congress.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Estimation and certification to Treasury of total amount necessary under section 4104(f)</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Before <date date="1956-08-01">August 1, 1956</date>, the Secretary of Labor shall estimate and report to the President the total amount which will be required to pay all benefits payable by reason of <ref>section 4104(f) of this title</ref>. If the President approves the amount so estimated as reasonably accurate, the total amount so estimated and approved shall be certified to the Secretary of the Treasury; if the President does not so approve he shall determine such amount, and the amount so determined shall be certified to the Secretary of the Treasury. Such certification shall be made on or before <date date="1956-09-01">September 1, 1956</date>. The Secretary of the Treasury shall then transfer from the War Claims Fund to the general fund of the Treasury a sum equal to the total amount certified to him under this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Estimation and certification to Treasury of total amount necessary under section 4103(c)</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Before <date date="1956-08-01">August 1, 1956</date>, the Secretary of Labor shall estimate and report to the President the total amount which will be required to pay all additional benefits payable as a result of the enactment of <ref>section 4103(c) of this title</ref>. If the President approves the amount so estimated as reasonably accurate, the total amount so estimated and approved shall be certified to the Secretary of the Treasury; if the President does not so approve, he shall determine such amount, and the amount so determined shall be certified to the Secretary of the Treasury. Such certification shall be made on or before <date date="1956-09-01">September 1, 1956</date>. The Secretary of the Treasury shall then transfer from the War Claims Fund to the general fund of the Treasury a sum equal to the total amount certified to him under this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certification to Treasury of total canceled obligations under section 4103(b)(1)</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On or before <date date="1956-08-01">August 1, 1956</date>, the Secretary of State is authorized and directed to certify to the Secretary of the Treasury the total amount of all obligations canceled pursuant to the provisions of <ref>section 4103(b)(1) of this title</ref>. The Secretary of the Treasury shall transfer from the war claims fund to the general fund of the Treasury an amount equal to the total amount so certified.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations for Commission’s work</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are hereby authorized to be appropriated, out of any money in the war claims fund, such sums as may be necessary to enable the Commission to carry out its functions under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 3, 1948, ch. 826</ref>, title I, § 13, <ref>62 Stat. 1247</ref>; 1950 Reorg. Plan No. 19, § 1, eff. <date date="1950-05-24">May 24, 1950</date>, 15 F.R. 3178, <ref>64 Stat. 1271</ref>; <ref>Aug. 31, 1954, ch. 1162</ref>, title I, § 104, <ref>68 Stat. 1036</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–846, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1962-10-22">Oct. 22, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 1107</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4111.</num>
<heading> Payments to certain members of religious orders</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In any case in which any money is payable as a result of the enactment of this subchapter to any person who is prevented from accepting such money by the rules, regulations, or customs of the church or the religious order or organization of which he is a member, such money shall be paid, upon the request of such person, to such church or to such religious order or organization.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 3, 1948, ch. 826</ref>, title I, § 14, <ref>62 Stat. 1247</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–846, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1962-10-22">Oct. 22, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 1107</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4112.</num>
<heading> United States citizens serving in allied forces</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Right to compensation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission is authorized to receive and to determine, according to law, the amount and validity, and provide for the payment of any claim for compensation filed by or on behalf of any individual who, being then an American citizen, served in the military or naval forces of any government allied with the United States during World War II who was held as a prisoner of war for any period of time subsequent to <date date="1941-12-07">December 7, 1941</date>, by any government of any nation with which such allied government has been at war subsequent to such date. Compensation shall be payable under this section in accordance with the standards established by, and at the rates prescribed in, subsection (b) of <ref>section 4105 of this title</ref>, and paragraphs (2) and (3) of subsection (d) of such section 4105.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deductions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The amount payable under this section shall be reduced by such sum as the individual entitled to compensation under this section has received or is entitled to receive from any government by reason of the same detention.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payments on death</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the event of death of the individual entitled to compensation under this section, payment may be made to the persons specified in paragraph (4) of subsection (d) of <ref>section 4105 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Filing date for claims</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Claims for benefits under this section must be filed within one year after <date date="1954-08-31">August 31, 1954</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certification of claim for payment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any claim allowed under the provisions of this section shall be certified to the Secretary of the Treasury for payment out of the War Claims Fund established by <ref>section 4110 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 3, 1948, ch. 826</ref>, title I, § 15, as added <ref>Aug. 31, 1954, ch. 1162</ref>, title I, § 103, <ref>68 Stat. 1034</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 87–846, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1962-10-22">Oct. 22, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 1107</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4113.</num>
<heading> Detention benefits to merchant seamen</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> “Merchant seaman” defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As used in this section, the term “merchant seaman” means any individual who was employed as a seaman or crew member on any vessel registered under the laws of the United States, or under the laws of any government friendly to the United States during World War II, and who was a citizen of the United States on and after <date date="1941-12-07">December 7, 1941</date>, to the date of his death or the date of filing claim under this section; except any such individual who is entitled to, or who has received, benefits under <ref>section 4104 of this title</ref> as a “civilian American citizen”.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determination of claim; rate of payment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission is authorized to receive and determine, according to law, the amount and validity, and provide for the payment of any claim for detention benefits filed by or on behalf of any merchant seaman who, being then a merchant seaman, was captured or interned or held by the Government of Germany or the Imperial Japanese Government, its agents or instrumentalities in World War II for any period of time subsequent to <date date="1941-12-07">December 7, 1941</date>, during which he was held by either such government as a prisoner, internee, hostage, or in any other capacity. Detention benefits shall be paid under this section at the rates prescribed and in the manner provided in subsections (c) and (d) of <ref>section 4104 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Collaborationists excluded</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Payment of any claim filed under this section shall not be made to any merchant seaman, or to any survivor or survivors thereof, who, voluntarily, knowingly, and without duress, gave aid to or collaborated with or in any manner served any government hostile to the United States during World War II.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Time of filing claim</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Claims for benefits under this section must be filed within one year after <date date="1954-08-31">August 31, 1954</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certification of claim for payment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any claim allowed under the provisions of this section shall be certified to the Secretary of the Treasury for payment out of the War Claims Fund established by <ref>section 4110 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 3, 1948, ch. 826</ref>, title I, § 16, as added <ref>Aug. 31, 1954, ch. 1162</ref>, title I, § 103, <ref>68 Stat. 1034</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 87–846, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1962-10-22">Oct. 22, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 1107</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4114.</num>
<heading> Philippines</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Losses by individual from sequestered credits; loss by banks or other financial institutions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Commission is authorized to receive and to determine, according to law, the amount and validity, and provide for the payment of any claim filed by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> any individual who—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> on or after <date date="1941-12-07">December 7, 1941</date>, was a member of the military or naval forces of the United States;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> is the survivor of any deceased individual described in subparagraph (i);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> was a national of the United States on <date date="1941-12-07">December 7, 1941</date>, and is a national of the United States on <date date="1954-08-31">August 31, 1954</date>; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> is the survivor of any deceased individual who was a national of the United States on <date date="1941-12-07">December 7, 1941</date>, and would be a national of the United States on <date date="1954-08-31">August 31, 1954</date>, if living; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any partnership, firm, corporation, or other legal entity, in which more than 50 per centum of the ownership was vested, directly or indirectly, both on <date date="1941-12-07">December 7, 1941</date>, and on <date date="1954-08-31">August 31, 1954</date>, in individuals referred to in subparagraph (A) of this paragraph;</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">for losses arising as a result of the sequestration of accounts, deposits, or other credits of such individual or legal entity in the Philippines by the Imperial Japanese Government.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Commission is authorized to receive and to determine, according to law, the amount and validity, and provide for the payment of any claim filed by any bank or other financial institution doing business in the Philippines which reestablished sequestered accounts, deposits, or other credits of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any individual referred to in subparagraph (A) of paragraph (1) of this subsection; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any partnership, firm, corporation, or other legal entity, in which more than 50 per centum of the ownership was vested, directly or indirectly, both on <date date="1941-12-07">December 7, 1941</date>, and on the date of reestablishment of such sequestered credits, in individuals referred to in such subparagraph (A);</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">for reimbursement of the amounts of such sequestered credits paid by such bank or financial institution.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Filing date for claims</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Claims must be filed under this section within one year after <date date="1954-08-31">August 31, 1954</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Death or legal disability as affecting payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Where any individual entitled to payment under this section is under any legal disability, payment may be made in accordance with the provisions of subsection (e) of <ref>section 4104 of this title</ref>. In the case of the death of any individual entitled to payment of any claim under this section, payment of such claim shall be made to the individuals specified, and in the order provided, in subsection (d) of <ref>section 4105 of this title</ref>; except that no payment shall be made under this section to any individual who voluntarily, knowingly, and without duress, gave aid to or collaborated with or in any manner served any government hostile to the United States during World War II.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certification of claims for payment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each claim allowed under this section shall be certified to the Secretary of the Treasury for payment out of the War Claims Fund established under <ref>section 4110 of this title</ref>. The Secretary of the Treasury shall pay such claims as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In the case of each claim allowed in an amount equal to or less than $500, such claim shall be paid in full; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In the case of each claim allowed in an amount greater than $500, such claim shall be paid in two installments. The first installment shall be paid in an amount equal to $500 plus 66⅔ per centum of the amount of such claim allowed in excess of $500. The last installment shall be computed as of <date date="1956-09-01">September 1, 1956</date>, under the next sentence of this paragraph, and, as so computed, shall be paid from the sums remaining in the War Claims Fund on that date. If the sums remaining in the War Claims Fund on <date date="1956-09-01">September 1, 1956</date>, are sufficient to satisfy all claims allowed under this section and not paid in full, the unpaid portion of each such claim shall be paid in full; if the sums remaining in the War Claims Fund on <date date="1956-09-01">September 1, 1956</date>, are not sufficient to satisfy all claims allowed under this section and not paid in full, the last installment payable on each such claim shall be reduced ratably, and, as so reduced, shall be paid from the War Claims Fund.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 3, 1948, ch. 826</ref>, title I, § 17, as added <ref>Aug. 31, 1954, ch. 1162</ref>, title I, § 103, <ref>68 Stat. 1035</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 87–846, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1962-10-22">Oct. 22, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 1107</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>TITLE II OF WAR CLAIMS ACT OF 1948</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4131.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this subchapter the term or terms—</chapeau>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> “Albania”, “Austria”, “Czechoslovakia”, “the Free Territory of Danzig”, “Estonia”, “Germany”, “Greece”, “Latvia”, “Lithuania”, “Poland”, and “Yugoslavia”, when used in their respective geographical senses, mean the territorial limits of each such country or free territory, as the case may be, in continental Europe as such limits existed on <date date="1937-12-01">December 1, 1937</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> “Commission” means the Foreign Claims Settlement Commission of the United States established pursuant to Reorganization Plan Numbered 1 of 1954 (<ref>68 Stat. 1279</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> “National of the United States” means (1) a natural person who is a citizen of the United States, (2) a natural person who, though not a citizen of the United States, owes permanent allegiance to the United States, and (3) a corporation, partnership, unincorporated body, or other entity, organized under the laws of the United States, or of any State, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the District of Columbia, or any possession of the United States and in which more than 50 per centum of the outstanding capital stock or other proprietary or similar interest is owned, directly or indirectly, by persons referred to in clauses (1) and (2) of this subsection. It does not include aliens.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> “Property” means real property and such items of tangible personalty as can be identified and evaluated.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 3, 1948, ch. 826</ref>, title II, § 201, as added <ref>Pub. L. 87–846, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1962-10-22">Oct. 22, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 1107</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4132.</num>
<heading> Claims authorized</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Commission is directed to receive and to determine according to the provisions of this subchapter the validity and amount of claims of nationals of the United States for—</chapeau>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> loss or destruction of, or physical damage to, property located in Albania, Austria, Czechoslovakia, the Free Territory of Danzig, Estonia, Germany, Greece, Latvia, Lithuania, Poland, or Yugoslavia, or in territory which was part of Hungary or Rumania on <date date="1937-12-01">December 1, 1937</date>, but which was not included in such countries on <date date="1947-09-15">September 15, 1947</date>, which loss, destruction, or physical damage occurred during the period beginning <date date="1939-09-01">September 1, 1939</date>, and ending <date date="1945-05-08">May 8, 1945</date>, or which occurred in the period beginning <date date="1937-07-01">July 1, 1937</date>, and ending <date date="1945-09-02">September 2, 1945</date>, to property in territory occupied or attacked by the Imperial Japanese military forces (including territory to which Japan has renounced all right, title, and claim under article 2 of the Treaty of Peace Between the Allied Powers and Japan) except the island of Guam: <i>Provided</i>, That claims for loss, destruction, or damage occurring in the Commonwealth of the Philippines shall not be allowed except on behalf of nationals of the United States who have received no payment, and certify under oath or affirmation that they have received no payment, on account of the same loss, destruction, or damage under the Philippine Rehabilitation Act of 1946,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002125">1</ref> whether or not claim was filed thereunder: <i>Provided further</i>, That such loss, destruction, or damage must have occurred, as a direct consequence of (1) military operations of war or (2) special measures directed against property in such countries or territories during the respective periods specified, because of the enemy or alleged enemy character of the owner, which property was owned, directly or indirectly, by a national of the United States at the time of such loss, damage or destruction;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> damage to, or loss or destruction of, ships or ship cargoes directly or indirectly owned by a national of the United States at the time such damage, loss, or destruction occurred, which was a direct consequence of military action by Germany or Japan during the period beginning <date date="1939-09-01">September 1, 1939</date>, and ending <date date="1945-09-02">September 2, 1945</date>; no award shall be made under this subsection in favor of any insurer or reinsurer as assignee or otherwise as successor in interest to the right of the insured;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> net losses under war-risk insurance or reinsurance policies or contracts, incurred in the settlement of claims for insured losses of ships directly or indirectly owned by a national of the United States at the time of the loss, damage, or destruction of such ships and at the time of the settlement of such claims, which insured losses were a direct consequence of military action by Germany or Japan during the period beginning <date date="1939-09-01">September 1, 1939</date>, and ending <date date="1945-09-02">September 2, 1945</date>; such net losses shall be determined by deducting from the aggregate of all payments made in the settlement of such insured losses the aggregate of the net amounts received by any such insurance companies on all policies of contracts of war-risk insurance or reinsurance on ships under which the insured was a national of the United States, after deducting expenses; and</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> loss or damage on account of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent2">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the death of any person who, being then a civilian national of the United States and a passenger on any vessel engaged in commerce on the high seas, died or was killed as a result of military action by Germany or Japan which occurred during the period beginning <date date="1939-09-01">September 1, 1939</date>, and ending <date date="1941-12-11">December 11, 1941</date>; awards under this paragraph shall be made only to or for the benefit of the following persons in the order of priority named:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent3">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> widow or husband if there is no child or children of the deceased;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent3">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> widow or husband and child or children of the deceased, one-half to the widow or husband and the other half to the child or children of the deceased in equal shares;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent3">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> child or children of the deceased (in equal shares) if there is no widow or husband; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent3">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> parents of the deceased (in equal shares) if there is no widow, husband, or child;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> injury or permanent disability sustained by any person, who being then a civilian national of the United States and a passenger on any vessel engaged in commerce on the high seas, was injured or permanently disabled as a result of military action by Germany or Japan which occurred during the period beginning <date date="1939-09-01">September 1, 1939</date>, and ending <date date="1941-12-11">December 11, 1941</date>; awards under this paragraph shall be payable solely to the person so injured or disabled;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the loss or destruction, as a result of such action, of property on such vessel, as determined by the Commission to be reasonable, useful, necessary, or proper under the circumstances, which property was owned by any civilian national of the United States who was then a passenger on such vessel; and in the case of the death of any person suffering such loss, awards under this paragraph shall be made only to or for the benefit of the persons designated in paragraph (1) of this subsection and in the order of priority named therein.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 3, 1948, ch. 826</ref>, title II, § 202, as added <ref>Pub. L. 87–846, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1962-10-22">Oct. 22, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 1107</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4133.</num>
<heading> Transfers and assignments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The transfer or assignment for value of any property forming the subject matter of a claim under subsection (a) or (b) of <ref>section 4132 of this title</ref> subsequent to its damage, loss, or destruction shall not operate to extinguish any claim of the transferor otherwise compensable under either of such subsections. If a claim which could otherwise be allowed under subsection (a) or (b) of <ref>section 4132 of this title</ref> has been assigned for value prior to <date date="1962-10-22">October 22, 1962</date>, the assignee shall be the party entitled to claim thereunder.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 3, 1948, ch. 826</ref>, title II, § 203, as added <ref>Pub. L. 87–846, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1962-10-22">Oct. 22, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 1109</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4134.</num>
<heading> Nationality of claimants</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No claim shall be allowed under subsection (a), (b), or (c) of <ref>section 4132 of this title</ref> unless the property upon which it is based was owned by a national or nationals of the United States on the date of loss, damage, or destruction and unless the claim was owned by a national or nationals of the United States continuously thereafter until the date of filing with the Commission pursuant to this subchapter. Where any person who lost United States citizenship solely by reason of marriage to a citizen or subject of a foreign country reacquired such citizenship before <date date="1962-10-22">October 22, 1962</date>, then if such individual, but for such marriage would have been a national of the United States at all times on and after the date of such loss, damage, or destruction until the filing of the claim, such individual shall be treated for all purposes of this subchapter as having been a national of the United States at all such times.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 3, 1948, ch. 826</ref>, title II, § 204, as added <ref>Pub. L. 87–846, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1962-10-22">Oct. 22, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 1109</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4135.</num>
<heading> Claims of stockholders</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Ownership interest in entity which is a national of the United States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A claim under <ref>section 4132 of this title</ref> based upon an ownership interest in any corporation, association, or other entity which is a national of the United States shall be denied.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Ownership interest in entity which was not a national of the United States on date of loss</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A claim under <ref>section 4132 of this title</ref>, based upon a direct ownership interest in a corporation, association, or other entity which suffered a loss within the meaning of said section, shall be allowed, subject to other provisions of this subchapter, if such corporation, association, or other entity on the date of the loss was not a national of the United States, without regard to the per centum of ownership vested in the claimant in any such claim.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Indirect ownership interest; minimum requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A claim under <ref>section 4132 of this title</ref>, based upon an indirect ownership interest in a corporation, association, or other entity which suffered a loss within the meaning of said section, shall be allowed, subject to other provisions of this subchapter, only if at least 25 per centum of the entire ownership interest thereof at the time of such loss was vested in nationals of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Calculation of award</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any award on a claim under subsection (b) or (c) of this section shall be calculated on the basis of the total loss suffered by such corporation, association, or other entity, and shall bear the same proportion to such loss as the ownership interest of the claimant bears to the entire ownership interest thereof.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 3, 1948, ch. 826</ref>, title II, § 205, as added <ref>Pub. L. 87–846, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1962-10-22">Oct. 22, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 1109</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4136.</num>
<heading> Deductions in making awards</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> In determining the amount of any award there shall be deducted all amounts the claimant has received on account of the same loss or losses with respect to which an award is made under this subchapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Each claim in excess of $10,000 filed under this subchapter by a corporation shall include a statement under oath disclosing the aggregate amount of Federal tax benefits derived by such corporation in any prior taxable year or years resulting from any deduction or deductions claimed for the loss or losses with respect to which such claim is filed. In determining the amount of any award where the allowable loss exceeds $10,000 there shall be deducted an amount equal to the aggregate amount of Federal tax benefits so derived by the claimant. For the purposes of this subsection, such Federal tax benefits shall be the aggregate of the amounts by which the claimant’s taxes for such year or years under chapters 1, 2A, 2B, 2D, and 2E of the Internal Revenue Code of 1939, or subtitle A of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 [<ref>26 U.S.C. 1</ref> et seq.] were decreased with respect to such loss or losses. Any payments made on an award reduced by reason of this subsection shall be exempt from Federal income taxes.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 3, 1948, ch. 826</ref>, title II, § 206, as added <ref>Pub. L. 87–846, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1962-10-22">Oct. 22, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 1110</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 2095</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4137.</num>
<heading> Consolidated awards</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">With respect to any claim which, at the time of the award, is vested in persons other than the person by whom the loss was sustained, the Commission may issue a consolidated award in favor of all claimants then entitled thereto, which award shall indicate the respective interests of such claimant therein; and all such claimants shall participate, in proportion to their indicated interests, in the payments authorized by this subchapter in all respects as if the award had been in favor of a single person.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 3, 1948, ch. 826</ref>, title II, § 207, as added <ref>Pub. L. 87–846, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1962-10-22">Oct. 22, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 1110</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4138.</num>
<heading> Certain awards prohibited</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No award shall be made under this subchapter to or for the benefit of (1) any person who has been convicted of a violation of any provision of chapter 115, title 18, or of any other crime involving disloyalty to the United States, or (2) any claimant whose claim under this subchapter is within the scope of title III of the International Claims Settlement Act of 1949, as amended (<ref>69 Stat. 570</ref>) [<ref>22 U.S.C. 1641</ref> et seq.], except any claimant whose award under section 303(1) of title III of the International Claims Settlement Act of 1949, as amended [<ref>22 U.S.C. 1641b(1)</ref>], is recertified pursuant to subsection (b) of <ref>section 4139 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 3, 1948, ch. 826</ref>, title II, § 208, as added <ref>Pub. L. 87–846, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1962-10-22">Oct. 22, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 1110</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4139.</num>
<heading> Certification of awards</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Commission shall certify to the Secretary of the Treasury, in terms of United States currency, for payment out of the War Claims Fund each award made pursuant to <ref>section 4132 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Commission shall recertify to the Secretary of the Treasury, in terms of United States currency, for payment out of the War Claims Fund, awards heretofore made with respect to claims against the Government of Hungary under <ref>section 1641b(1) of title 22</ref>. Nothing contained in this subsection shall be construed as authorizing the filing of new claims against Hungary.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 3, 1948, ch. 826</ref>, title II, § 209, as added <ref>Pub. L. 87–846, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1962-10-22">Oct. 22, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 1111</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4140.</num>
<heading> Claim filing period</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Within sixty days after the enactment of this subchapter or of legislation making appropriations to the Commission for payment of administrative expenses incurred in carrying out its functions under this subchapter, whichever date is later, the Commission shall give public notice by publication in the Federal Register of the time when, and the limit of time within which claims may be filed, which limit shall not be more than eighteen months after such publication.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 3, 1948, ch. 826</ref>, title II, § 210, as added <ref>Pub. L. 87–846, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1962-10-22">Oct. 22, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 1111</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4141.</num>
<heading> Claims settlement period</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission shall complete its affairs in connection with the settlement of claims pursuant to this subchapter not later than four years following the enactment of legislation making appropriations to the Commission for payment of administrative expenses incurred in carrying out its functions under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 3, 1948, ch. 826</ref>, title II, § 211, as added <ref>Pub. L. 87–846, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1962-10-22">Oct. 22, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 1111</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4142.</num>
<heading> Notification to claimants</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each award or denial of a claim by the Commission, whether rendered before or after a hearing, shall include a specific statement of the facts and of the reasoning of the Commission in support of its conclusion.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 3, 1948, ch. 826</ref>, title II, § 212, as added <ref>Pub. L. 87–846, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1962-10-22">Oct. 22, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 1111</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4143.</num>
<heading> Payment of awards; priorities; limitations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Order of priority of payments</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of the Treasury shall pay out of the War Claims Fund on account of awards certified by the Commission pursuant to this subchapter as follows and in the following order of priority:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Payment in full of awards made pursuant to section 4132(d)(1) and (2) of this title, and thereafter of any award made pursuant to <ref>section 4132(a) of this title</ref> to any claimant (A) certified to the Commission by the Small Business Administration as having been, on the date of loss, damage, or destruction, a small business concern within the meaning now set forth in the Small Business Act, as amended [<ref>15 U.S.C. 631</ref> et seq.], or (B) determined by the Commission to have been, on the date of loss, damage, or destruction, a nonprofit organization operated exclusively for the promotion of social welfare, religious, charitable, or educational purposes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Thereafter, payments from time to time on account of the other awards made pursuant to <ref>section 4132 of this title</ref> in an amount which shall be the same for each award or in the amount of the award, whichever is less. The total payment made pursuant to this paragraph on account of any award shall not exceed $10,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Thereafter, payments from time to time on account of the other awards made to individuals and corporations pursuant to <ref>section 4132 of this title</ref> and not compensated in full under paragraph (1) or (2) of this subsection in an amount which shall be the same for each award or in the amount of the award, whichever is less. The total payment pursuant to this paragraph on account of any award shall not exceed $35,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Thereafter, payments from time to time on account of the unpaid balance of each remaining award made pursuant to <ref>section 4132 of this title</ref> or recertified pursuant to subsection (b) of <ref>section 4139 of this title</ref> which shall bear to such unpaid balance the same proportion as the total amount in the War Claims Fund and available for distribution at the time such payments are made bears to the aggregate unpaid balances of all such awards. No payment made pursuant to this paragraph on account of any award shall exceed the unpaid balance of such award. Payments heretofore made under <ref>section 1641i of title 22</ref>, on awards made against the Government of Hungary under <ref>section 1641b(1) of title 22</ref>, and recertified under subsection (b) of <ref>section 4139 of this title</ref>, shall be considered as payments under this paragraph and no payment shall be made on any recertified award until the percentage of distribution on awards made under <ref>section 4132 of this title</ref> exceeds the corresponding percentage of distribution on such recertified award: <i>Provided</i>, That no payment made on awards recertified under subsection (b) of <ref>section 4139 of this title</ref> shall exceed 40 per centum of the amount of the award recertified.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Such payments, and applications for such payments, shall be made in accordance with such regulations as the Secretary of the Treasury shall prescribe.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Aggregation of awards</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purpose of making any such payments, other than under subsection (a)(1), an “award” shall be deemed to mean the aggregate of all awards certified for payment in favor of the same claimant.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Death or disability of claimant</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If any person to whom any payment is to be made pursuant to this subchapter is deceased or is under a legal disability, payment shall be made to his legal representative, except that if any payment to be made is not over $1,000 and there is no qualified executor or administrator, payment may be made to the person or persons found by the Secretary of the Treasury to be entitled thereto, without the necessity of compliance with the requirements of law with respect to the administration of estates.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Partial payment; extinguishment of rights</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Payment on account of any award pursuant to this subchapter shall not, unless such payment is for the full amount of the award, extinguish any rights against any foreign government for the unpaid balance of the award.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Losses occurring in Commonwealth of the Philippines</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Payments made under this section on account of any award for loss, damage, or destruction occurring in the Commonwealth of the Philippines shall not exceed the amount paid on account of awards in the same amount under the Philippine Rehabilitation Act of 1946.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002126">1</ref></p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 3, 1948, ch. 826</ref>, title II, § 213, as added <ref>Pub. L. 87–846, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1962-10-22">Oct. 22, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 1111</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 91–571, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1970-12-24">Dec. 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1503</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–316, title I, § 128(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3841</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4144.</num>
<heading> Fees of attorneys and agents</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No remuneration on account of services rendered on behalf of any claimant in connection with any claim filed with the Commission under this subchapter shall exceed 10 per centum (or such lesser per centum as may be fixed by the Commission with respect to any class of claims) of the total amount paid pursuant to any award certified under the provisions of this subchapter on account of such claim. Any agreement to the contrary shall be unlawful and void. Whoever, in the United States or elsewhere, demands or receives, on account of services so rendered, any remuneration in excess of the maximum permitted by this section shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and, upon conviction thereof, shall be fined not more than $5,000 or imprisoned not more than twelve months, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 3, 1948, ch. 826</ref>, title II, § 214, as added <ref>Pub. L. 87–846, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1962-10-22">Oct. 22, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 1112</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4145.</num>
<heading> Application of other laws</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To the extent they are not inconsistent with the provisions of this subchapter, the following provisions of subchapter I and title I of the International Claims Settlement Act of 1949, as amended [<ref>22 U.S.C. 1621</ref> et seq.], shall apply to this subchapter: The first sentence of subsection (b) of <ref>section 4101 of this title</ref>, all of subsection (c) of <ref>section 4101 of this title</ref> and <ref>section 4109 of this title</ref>, and subsections (c), (d), (e), and (f) of section 7 of the International Claims Settlement Act of 1949, as amended [<ref>22 U.S.C. 1626</ref>].</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 3, 1948, ch. 826</ref>, title II, § 215, as added <ref>Pub. L. 87–846, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1962-10-22">Oct. 22, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 1112</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4146.</num>
<heading> Transfer of records</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of State is authorized and directed to transfer or otherwise make available to the Commission such records and documents relating to claims authorized by this subchapter as may be required by the Commission in carrying out its functions under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 3, 1948, ch. 826</ref>, title II, § 216, as added <ref>Pub. L. 87–846, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1962-10-22">Oct. 22, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 1113</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4147.</num>
<heading> Administrative expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated out of any moneys in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated such sums as may be necessary (but not to exceed the total covered into the Treasury to the credit of miscellaneous receipts under section 4336(d) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002127">1</ref> of this title) to enable the Commission and the Treasury Department to pay their administrative expenses in carrying out their respective functions under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 3, 1948, ch. 826</ref>, title II, § 217, as added <ref>Pub. L. 87–846, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1962-10-22">Oct. 22, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 1113</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>