<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 5—</num>
<heading>ARSENALS, ARMORIES, ARMS, AND WAR MATERIAL GENERALLY</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>ARSENALS, ARMORIES, ARMS, AND WAR MATERIALS</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 51 to 57.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041, § 53</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 641</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 58.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Sept. 1, 1954, ch. 1208</ref>, title III, § 305(d), <ref>68 Stat. 1114</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 59 to 66.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041, § 53</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 641</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 67.</num>
<heading> Transferred</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 68 to 71.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041, § 53</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 641</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 72.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>May 1, 1937, ch. 146, § 5(i)</ref>, <ref>50 Stat. 126</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 73.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Aug. 1, 1953, ch. 305</ref>, title VI, § 645, <ref>67 Stat. 357</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 74 to 81.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041, § 53</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 641</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 82.</num>
<heading> Procurement of ships and material during war</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The word “person” as used in subsections (b) and (c) shall include any individual, trustee, firm, association, company, or corporation. The word “ship” shall include any boat, vessel, submarine, or any form of aircraft, and the parts thereof. The words “war material” shall include arms, armament, ammunition, stores, supplies, and equipment for ships and airplanes, and everything required for or in connection with the production thereof. The word “factory” shall include any factory, workshop, engine works, building used for manufacture, assembling, construction, or any process, and any shipyard or dockyard. The words “United States” shall include the Canal Zone and all territory and waters, continental and insular, subject to the jurisdiction of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Presidential powers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In time of war the President is authorized and empowered, in addition to all other existing provisions of law:</p>
<p class="indent0">First. Within the limits of the amounts appropriated therefor, to place an order with any person for such ships or war material as the necessities of the Government, to be determined by the President, may require and which are of the nature, kind, and quantity usually produced or capable of being produced by such person. Compliance with all such orders shall be obligatory on any person to whom such order is given, and such order shall take precedence over all other orders and contracts theretofore placed with such person. If any person owning, leasing, or operating any factory equipped for the building or production of ships or war material for the Navy shall refuse or fail to give to the United States such preference in the execution of such an order, or shall refuse to build, supply, furnish, or manufacture the kind, quantity, or quality of ships or war material so ordered at such reasonable price as shall be determined by the President, the President may take immediate possession of any factory of such person, or of any part thereof without taking possession of the entire factory, and may use the same at such times and in such manner as he may consider necessary or expedient.</p>
<p class="indent0">Second. Within the limit of the amounts appropriated therefor, to modify or cancel any existing contract for the building, production, or purchase of ships or war material; and if any contractor shall refuse or fail to comply with the contract as so modified the President may take immediate possession of any factory of such contractor, or any part thereof without taking possession of the entire factory, and may use the same at such times and in such manner as he may consider necessary or expedient.</p>
<p class="indent0">Third. To require the owner or occupier of any factory in which ships or war material are built or produced to place at the disposal of the United States the whole or any part of the output of such factory, and, within the limit of the amounts appropriated therefor, to deliver such output or parts thereof in such quantities and at such times as may be specified in the order at such reasonable price as shall be determined by the President.</p>
<p class="indent0">Fourth. To requisition and take over for use or operation by the Government any factory, or any part thereof without taking possession of the entire factory, whether the United States has or has not any contract or agreement with the owner or occupier of such factory.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002000">1</ref> Compensation for commandeered material</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever the United States shall cancel or modify any contract, make use of, assume, occupy, requisition, or take over any factory or part thereof, or any ships or war material, in accordance with the provisions of subsection (b), it shall make just compensation therefor, to be determined by the President, and if the amount thereof so determined by the President is unsatisfactory to the person entitled to receive the same, such person shall be paid fifty per centum of the amount so determined by the President and shall be entitled to sue the United States to recover such further sum as added to said fifty per centum shall make up such amount as will be just compensation therefor, in the manner provided for by section 1346 or <ref>section 1491 of title 28</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 4, 1917, ch. 180</ref>, <ref>39 Stat. 1192</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 83 to 85.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041, § 53</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 641</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 86 to 88.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>EDUCATION AND EXPERIMENTATION IN DEVELOPMENT OF MUNITIONS AND MATERIALS FOR NATIONAL DEFENSE</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 91 to 94.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041, § 53</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 641</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 95.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 96.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041, § 53</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 641</ref></heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>ACQUISITION AND DEVELOPMENT OF STRATEGIC RAW MATERIALS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 98.</num>
<heading> Short title</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This subchapter may be cited as the “Strategic and Critical Materials Stock Piling Act”.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 7, 1939, ch. 190, § 1</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 96–41, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1979-07-30">July 30, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 319</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 98a.</num>
<heading> Congressional findings and declaration of purpose</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Congress finds that the natural resources of the United States in certain strategic and critical materials are deficient or insufficiently developed to supply the military, industrial, and essential civilian needs of the United States for national defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> It is the purpose of this subchapter to provide for the acquisition and retention of stocks of certain strategic and critical materials and to encourage the conservation and development of sources of such materials within the United States and thereby to decrease and to preclude, when possible, a dangerous and costly depend­ence by the United States upon foreign sources or a single point of failure for supplies of such materials in times of national emergency.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The purpose of the National Defense Stockpile is to serve the interest of national defense only. The National Defense Stockpile is not to be used for economic or budgetary purposes.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> To the maximum extent practicable and to reduce the reliance of the National Defense Stockpile program on appropriated funds, the National Defense Stockpile Manager shall seek to achieve positive cash flows from the recovery of strategic and critical materials pursuant to <ref>section 98e(a)(5) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 7, 1939, ch. 190, § 2</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 96–41, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1979-07-30">July 30, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 319</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–180, div. C, title II, § 3202(b)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1245</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. C, title XXXIII, § 3311</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1961</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. C, title XXXIII, § 3311(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2857</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title XIV, § 1412</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 2048</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XIV, § 1411(a)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 523</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 98b.</num>
<heading> National Defense Stockpile</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determination of materials; quantities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to subsection (c), the President shall determine from time to time (1) which materials are strategic and critical materials for the purposes of this subchapter, and (2) the quality and quantity of each such material to be acquired for the purposes of this subchapter and the form in which each such material shall be acquired and stored. Such materials when acquired, together with the other materials described in <ref>section 98c of this title</ref>, shall constitute and be collectively known as the National Defense Stockpile (hereinafter in this subchapter referred to as the “stockpile”).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Guidelines for exercise of Presidential authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall make the determinations required to be made under subsection (a) on the basis of the principles stated in <ref>section 98a(c) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Quantity change; notification to Congress</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The quantity of any material to be stockpiled under this subchapter, as in effect on <date date="1987-09-30">September 30, 1987</date>, may be changed only as provided in this subsection or as otherwise provided by law enacted after <date date="1987-12-04">December 4, 1987</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The President shall notify Congress in writing of any increase proposed to be made in the quantity of any material to be stockpiled that involves the acquisition of additional materials for the stockpile. The President may make the increase after the end of the 30-day period beginning on the date of the notification. The President shall include a full explanation and justification for the proposed increase with the notification.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 7, 1939, ch. 190, § 3</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 96–41, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1979-07-30">July 30, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 319</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–180, div. C, title II, § 3202(a)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1245</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–456, div. A, title XII, § 1233(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2057</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. C, title XXXIII, § 3311</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2653</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. C, title XXXIII, § 3312(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2857</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title XIV, § 1412(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2872</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 98c.</num>
<heading> Materials constituting the National Defense Stockpile</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The stockpile consists of the following materials:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Materials acquired under this subchapter and contained in the national stockpile on <date date="1979-07-29">July 29, 1979</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Materials acquired under this subchapter after <date date="1979-07-29">July 29, 1979</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Materials in the supplemental stockpile established by <ref>section 1704(b) of title 7</ref> (as in effect from <date date="1959-09-21">September 21, 1959</date>, through <date date="1966-12-31">December 31, 1966</date>) on <date date="1979-07-29">July 29, 1979</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Materials acquired by the United States under the provisions of <ref>section 4533 of this title</ref> and transferred to the stockpile by the President pursuant to subsection (f) of such section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Materials transferred to the United States under <ref>section 2423 of title 22</ref> that have been determined to be strategic and critical materials for the purposes of this subchapter and that are allocated by the President under subsection (b) of such section for stockpiling in the stockpile.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Materials acquired by the Commodity Credit Corporation and transferred to the stockpile under <ref>section 714b(h) of title 15</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Materials acquired by the Commodity Credit Corporation under paragraph (2) of <ref>section 1743(a) of title 7</ref>, and transferred to the stockpile under the third sentence of such section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Materials transferred to the stockpile by the President under paragraph (4) of <ref>section 1743(a) of title 7</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> Materials transferred to the stockpile under subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> Materials transferred to the stockpile under subsection (c).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer and reimbursement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any material that (1) is under the control of any department or agency of the United States, (2) is determined by the head of such department or agency to be excess to its needs and responsibilities, and (3) is suitable for transfer or disposal through the stockpile shall be transferred to the stockpile. Any such transfer shall be made without reimbursement to such department or agency, but all costs required to effect such transfer shall be paid or reimbursed from funds appropriated to carry out this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer and disposal</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Defense shall determine whether materials are suitable for transfer to the stockpile under subsection (b), are suitable for disposal through the stockpile, and are uncontaminated.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 7, 1939, ch. 190, § 4</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 96–41, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1979-07-30">July 30, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 320</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 99–661, div. C, title II, § 3207(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 4069</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. C, title XXXIII, § 3311</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 630</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, title III, § 3001(b)(1)(A)</ref>, (2)(Z), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1820</ref>, 1821; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XIV, § 1412(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2570</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 98d.</num>
<heading> Authority for stockpile operations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Funds appropriated for acquisitions; proposed stockpile transactions; significant changes therein</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except for acquisitions made under the authority of paragraph (3) of this section <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002001">1</ref> or under the authority of paragraph (3) or (4) of <ref>section 98e(a) of this title</ref>, no funds may be obligated or appropriated for acquisition of any material under this subchapter unless funds for such acquisition have been authorized by law. Funds appropriated for any acquisition of materials under this subchapter (and for transportation and other incidental expenses related to such acquisition) shall remain available until expended, unless otherwise provided in appropriation Acts.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If for any fiscal year the President proposes (or Congress requires) a significant change in any stockpile transactions proposed in the Annual Materials and Operations Plan for such fiscal year after the National Defense Stockpile Manager submits the report under <ref>section 98h–2(b)(2) of this title</ref> containing such plan, or a significant transaction not included in such plan, no amount may be obligated or expended for such transaction during such year until the President has submitted a full statement of the proposed transaction to the appropriate committees of Congress and a period of 45 days has passed from the date of the receipt of such statement by such committees.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Using funds appropriated for acquisition of materials under this subchapter, the National Defense Stockpile Manager may acquire materials determined to be strategic and critical under <ref>section 98b(a) of this title</ref> without regard to the requirement of the first sentence of paragraph (1) if the Stockpile Manager determines there is a shortfall of such materials in the stockpile.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disposal</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except for disposals made under the authority of paragraph (3), (4), or (5) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002002">2</ref> of <ref>section 98e(a) of this title</ref> or under <ref>section 98f(a) of this title</ref>, no disposal may be made from the stockpile unless such disposal, including the quantity of the material to be disposed of, has been specifically authorized by law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to provide for the transportation, processing, refining, storage, security, maintenance, rotation, and disposal of materials contained in or acquired for the stockpile. Funds appropriated for such purposes shall remain available until expended, unless otherwise provided in appropriations Acts.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 7, 1939, ch. 190, § 5</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 96–41, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1979-07-30">July 30, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 321</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 97–35, title II, § 203(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 381</ref>, 382; <ref>Pub. L. 98–525, title IX, § 903</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2573</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–661, div. C, title II, § 3207(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 4069</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–180, div. C, title II, § 3206(a)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1247</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. C, title XXXIII, § 3312</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2653</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. C, title XXXIII, § 3312</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1962</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title XIV</ref>, §§ 1411(d)(1)(A), 1412(a), <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2871</ref>, 2872; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XIV, § 1411(e)(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 527</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 98e.</num>
<heading> Stockpile management</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Presidential powers</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> acquire the materials determined under <ref>section 98b(a) of this title</ref> to be strategic and critical materials;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provide for the proper storage, security, and maintenance of materials in the stockpile;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> provide for the upgrading, refining, or processing of any material in the stockpile (notwithstanding any intermediate stockpile quantity established for such material) when necessary to convert such material into a form more suitable for storage, subsequent disposition, and immediate use in a national emergency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> provide for the rotation of any material in the stockpile when necessary to prevent deterioration or technological obsolescence of such material by replacement of such material with an equivalent quantity of substantially the same material or better material;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> provide for the appropriate recovery of any strategic and critical materials under <ref>section 98b(a) of this title</ref> that may be available from other Federal agencies, either directly as materials or embedded in excess-to-need, end-of-life items, or waste streams;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> subject to the notification required by subsection (d)(2), provide for the timely disposal of materials in the stockpile that (A) are excess to stockpile requirements, and (B) may cause a loss to the Government if allowed to deteriorate; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> subject to the provisions of <ref>section 98d(b) of this title</ref>, dispose of materials in the stockpile the disposal of which is specifically authorized by law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal procurement practices</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except as provided in subsections (c) and (d), acquisition of strategic and critical materials under this subchapter shall be made in accordance with established Federal procurement practices, and, except as provided in subsections (c) and (d) and in <ref>section 98f(a) of this title</ref>, disposal of strategic and critical materials from the stockpile shall be made in accordance with the next sentence. To the maximum extent feasible—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> competitive procedures shall be used in the acquisition and disposal of such materials; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> efforts shall be made in the acquisition and disposal of such materials to consult with producers and processors of such materials to avoid undue disruption of the usual markets of producers, processors, and consumers of such materials and to protect the United States against avoidable loss.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Barter; use of stockpile materials as payment for expenses of acquiring, refining, processing, or rotating materials</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The President shall encourage the use of barter in the acquisition under subsection (a)(1) of strategic and critical materials for, and the disposal under subsection (a)(6) or (a)(7) of materials from, the stockpile when acquisition or disposal by barter is authorized by law and is practical and in the best interest of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Materials in the stockpile (the disposition of which is authorized by paragraph (3) to finance the upgrading, refining, or processing of a material in the stockpile, or is otherwise authorized by law) shall be available for transfer at fair market value as payment for expenses (including transportation and other incidental expenses) of acquisition of materials, or of upgrading, refining, processing, or rotating materials, under this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding <ref>section 98b(c) of this title</ref> or any other provision of law, whenever the President provides under subsection (a)(3) for the upgrading, refining, or processing of a material in the stockpile to convert that material into a form more suitable for storage, subsequent disposition, and immediate use in a national emergency, the President may barter a portion of the same material (or any other material in the stockpile that is authorized for disposal) to finance that upgrading, refining, or processing.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> To the extent otherwise authorized by law, property owned by the United States may be bartered for materials needed for the stockpile.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Waiver; notification of proposed disposal of materials</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The President may waive the applicability of any provision of the first sentence of subsection (b) to any acquisition of material for, or disposal of material from, the stockpile. Whenever the President waives any such provision with respect to any such acquisition or disposal, or whenever the President determines that the application of paragraph (1) or (2) of such subsection to a particular acquisition or disposal is not feasible, the President shall notify the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives in writing of the proposed acquisition or disposal at least 45 days before any obligation of the United States is incurred in connection with such acquisition or disposal and shall include in such notification the reasons for not complying with any provision of such subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Materials in the stockpile may be disposed of under subsection (a)(6) only if such congressional committees are notified in writing of the proposed disposal at least 45 days before any obligation of the United States is incurred in connection with such disposal.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Leasehold interests in property</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President may acquire leasehold interests in property, for periods not in excess of twenty years, for storage, security, and maintenance of materials in the stockpile.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Loan of stockpile materials</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President may loan stockpile materials to the Department of Energy or the military departments if the President—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> has a reasonable assurance that stockpile materials of a similar or superior quantity and quality to the materials loaned will be returned to the stockpile or paid for;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> notifies the congressional defense committees (as defined in <ref>section 101(a) of title 10</ref>), in writing, not less than 30 days before making any such loan; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> includes in the written notification under paragraph (2) sufficient support for the assurance described in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Pilot program to use commercial best practices in acquiring and disposing of strategic and critical materials</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The National Defense Stockpile Manager shall establish a pilot program to use, to the maximum extent practicable, commercial best practices in the acquisition and disposal of strategic and critical materials for the stockpile.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> The Stockpile Manager shall brief the congressional defense committees (as defined in <ref>section 101(a) of title 10</ref>)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> as soon as practicable after the establishment of the pilot program under paragraph (1); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> annually thereafter until the termination of the pilot program under paragraph (3).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> The briefing required by subparagraph (A)(i) shall address—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the commercial best practices selected for use under the pilot program;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> how the Stockpile Manager determined which commercial best practices to select; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the plan of the Stockpile Manager for using such practices.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> Each briefing required by subparagraph (A)(ii) shall provide a summary of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> how the Stockpile Manager has used commercial best practices under the pilot program during the year preceding the briefing;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> how many times the Stockpile Manager has used such practices;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the outcome of each use of such practices; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> any savings achieved or lessons learned as a result of the use of such practices.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The pilot program established under paragraph (1) shall terminate effective on the date that is 5 years after <date date="2023-12-22">December 22, 2023</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Ensuring programs achieve positive cash flow</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except to the extent necessary for the national defense, the National Defense Stockpile Manager shall ensure that each program for the recovery of strategic and critical materials implemented under subsection (a)(5) operates in a manner designed to achieve positive cash flow.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 7, 1939, ch. 190, § 6</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 96–41, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1979-07-30">July 30, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 321</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 97–35, title II, § 203(c)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 382</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–661, div. C, title II, § 3207(b)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 4069</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. C, title XXXIII, § 3314</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1688</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. C, title XXXIII, § 3301(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1844</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. C, title XXXIII, § 3312</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1584</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. C, title XXXIII, § 3302</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3098</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1502(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 509</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. C, title XXXIII, § 3312(b)</ref>, (c), <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2857</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. C, title XXXIII, § 3306</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 2058</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1067(13)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 775</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title XIV, § 1411(a)</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 934</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XIV</ref>, §§ 1411(1), 1412, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2018</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XIV, § 1411(b)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 523</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 98e–1.</num>
<heading> Transferred</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 98e–2.</num>
<heading> Multiyear procurement authority for domestically processed critical minerals</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority for multiyear procurement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to <ref>section 3501 of title 10</ref> and from amounts made available by discretionary appropriations Acts from the National Defense Stockpile Transaction Fund (as established under section 9(a) of the Strategic and Critical Materials Stock Piling Act (<ref>50 U.S.C. 98h(a)</ref>)) after <date date="2023-12-22">December 22, 2023</date>, the Secretary of Defense may enter into one or more multiyear contracts for the procurement of critical minerals that are processed in the United States by domestic sources.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application of Strategic and Critical Materials Stock Piling Act</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A multiyear contract entered into under this section shall be deemed to be an acquisition under the Strategic and Critical Materials Stock Piling Act (<ref>50 U.S.C. 98</ref> et seq.).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority for advance procurement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Defense may enter into one or more contracts, beginning in fiscal year 2024, for advance procurement associated with the domestically processed critical minerals for which authorization to enter into a multiyear procurement contract is provided under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Condition for out-year contract payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A contract entered into under subsection (a) shall provide that any obligation of the United States to make a payment under the contract for a fiscal year after fiscal year 2024 is subject to the availability of appropriations or funds for that purpose for such later fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “critical mineral” means a mineral determined to be a strategic and critical material under section 3(a) of the Strategic and Critical Materials Stock Piling Act (<ref>50 U.S.C. 98b(a)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “processed” means the processing or recycling of a critical mineral or magnet, including the separation, reduction, metallization, alloying, milling, pressing, strip casting, and sintering of a critical mineral.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “domestic source” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 4552 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title I, § 152</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 180</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 98f.</num>
<heading> Special Presidential disposal authority</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Materials in the stockpile may be released for use, sale, or other disposition—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> on the order of the President, at any time the President determines the release of such materials is required for purposes of the national defense;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in time of war declared by the Congress or during a national emergency, on the order of any officer or employee of the United States designated by the President to have authority to issue disposal orders under this subsection, if such officer or employee determines that the release of such materials is required for purposes of the national defense; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> on the order of the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment, if the President has designated the Under Secretary to have authority to issue release orders under this subsection and, in the case of any such order, if the Under Secretary determines that the release of such materials is required for use, manufacture, or production for purposes of national defense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Any order issued under subsection (a) shall be promptly reported by the President, or by the officer or employee issuing such order, in writing, to the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 7, 1939, ch. 190, § 7</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 96–41, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1979-07-30">July 30, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 322</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1502(e)(2)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 509</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1067(13)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 775</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title XIV, § 1413(a)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 2048</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title IX, § 902(90)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1554</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 98g.</num>
<heading> Materials development and research</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Development, mining, preparation, treatment, and utilization of ores and other mineral substances</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The President shall make scientific, technologic, and economic investigations concerning the development, mining, preparation, treatment, and utilization of ores and other mineral substances that (A) are found in the United States, its territories or possessions, or in a reliable source <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002003">1</ref> (B) are essential to the national defense, industrial, and essential civilian needs of the United States, and (C) are found in known domestic sources in inadequate quantities or grades.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Such investigations shall be carried out in order to develop new sources of strategic and critical materials, develop substitutes, or conserve domestic sources and reliable sources of supply for such strategic and critical materials.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Investigations under paragraph (1) may be carried out on public lands and, with the consent of the owner, on privately owned lands for the purpose of exploring and determining the extent and quality of deposits of such minerals, the most suitable methods of mining and beneficiating such minerals, and the cost at which the minerals or metals may be produced.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Development of sources of supplies of agricultural materials; use of agricultural commodities for manufacture of materials</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall make scientific, technologic, and economic investigations of the feasibility of developing domestic sources of supplies of any agricultural material or for using agricultural commodities for the manufacture of any material determined pursuant to <ref>section 98b(a) of this title</ref> to be a strategic and critical material or substitutes therefor.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Development of sources of supply of other materials; development or use of alternative methods for refining or processing materials in stockpile</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President shall make scientific, technologic, and economic investigations concerning the feasibility of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> developing domestic sources of supply of materials (other than materials referred to in subsections (a) and (b)) determined pursuant to <ref>section 98b(a) of this title</ref> to be strategic and critical materials; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> developing or using alternative methods for the refining or processing of a material in the stockpile so as to convert such material into a form more suitable for use during an emergency or for storage.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grants and contracts to encourage conservation of strategic and critical materials</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President shall encourage the conservation of domestic sources of any material determined pursuant to <ref>section 98b(a) of this title</ref> to be a strategic and critical material by making grants or awarding contracts for research regarding the development of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> substitutes for such material; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> more efficient methods of production or use of such material.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 7, 1939, ch. 190, § 8</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 96–41, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1979-07-30">July 30, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 322</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. C, title XXXIII, § 3311</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1686</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XIV, § 1411(e)(2)(B)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 527</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 98h.</num>
<heading> National Defense Stockpile Transaction Fund</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established in the Treasury of the United States a separate fund to be known as the National Defense Stockpile Transaction Fund (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “fund”).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fund operations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> All moneys received from the sale of materials in the stockpile under paragraphs (5) and (6) of <ref>section 98e(a) of this title</ref> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002004">1</ref> shall be covered into the fund.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Subject to <ref>section 98d(a)(1) of this title</ref>, moneys covered into the fund under paragraph (1) are hereby made available (subject to such limitations as may be provided in appropriation Acts) for the following purposes:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The acquisition, maintenance, and disposal of strategic and critical materials under <ref>section 98e(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Transportation, storage, and other incidental expenses related to such acquisition, maintenance, and disposal.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Development of current specifications of stockpile materials and the upgrading of existing stockpile materials to meet current specifications (including transportation, when economical, related to such upgrading).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Encouraging the appropriate conservation of strategic and critical materials.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Testing and quality studies of stockpile materials.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Studying future material and mobilization requirements for the stockpile.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> Activities authorized under <ref>section 98h–6 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(H)</num>
<chapeau> Contracting under competitive procedures for materials development and research to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> improve the quality and availability of materials stockpiled from time to time in the stockpile; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> develop new materials for the stockpile.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> Improvement or rehabilitation of facilities, structures, and infrastructure needed to maintain the integrity of stockpile materials.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> Disposal of hazardous materials that are stored in the stockpile and authorized for disposal by law.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> Performance of environmental remediation, restoration, waste management, or compliance activities at locations of the stockpile that are required under a Federal law or are undertaken by the Government under an administrative decision or negotiated agreement.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(L)</num>
<content> Pay of employees of the National Defense Stockpile program.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(M)</num>
<content> Other expenses of the National Defense Stockpile program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Moneys in the fund shall remain available until expended.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Moneys received from sale of materials being rotated or disposed of</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All moneys received from the sale of materials being rotated under the provisions of <ref>section 98e(a)(4) of this title</ref> or disposed of under <ref>section 98f(a) of this title</ref> shall be covered into the fund and shall be available only for the acquisition of replacement materials.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect of bartering</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">If, during a fiscal year, the National Defense Stockpile Manager barters materials in the stockpile for the purpose of acquiring, upgrading, refining, or processing other materials (or for services directly related to that purpose), the contract value of the materials so bartered shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> be applied toward the total value of materials that are authorized to be disposed of from the stockpile during that fiscal year;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> be treated as an acquisition for purposes of satisfying any requirement imposed on the National Defense Stockpile Manager to enter into obligations during that fiscal year under subsection (b)(2); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> not increase or decrease the balance in the fund.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 7, 1939, ch. 190, § 9</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 96–41, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1979-07-30">July 30, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 323</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 97–35, title II, § 203(d)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 382</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–661, div. C, title II, § 3203(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 4067</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–180, div. C, title II, § 3204</ref>, <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1247</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. C, title XXXIII, § 3312(b)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1688</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. C, title XXXIII, § 3301(c)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1845</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. C, title XXXIII, § 3311(a)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1584</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. C, title XXXIII, § 3313</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2653</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. C, title XXXIII, § 3313</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1962</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–261, div. C, title XXXIII, § 3304</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2264</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title XIV, § 1411(b)</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 934</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 98h–1.</num>
<heading> Strategic and Critical Materials Board of Directors</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established a Strategic and Critical Materials Board of Directors (in this subchapter referred to as the “Board”).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Members</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Board shall be composed, at a minimum, of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Assistant Secretary of Defense for Industrial Base Policy, who shall serve as chairman of the Board.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> One designee of each of the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Energy, and the Secretary of the Interior.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> One designee of each of the Chairman and Ranking Member of the Readiness Subcommittee of the House Committee on Armed Services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> One designee of each of the Chairman and Ranking Member of the Readiness Subcommittee of the Senate Committee on Armed Services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Four designees of the chairman of the Board, who shall have expertise relating to military affairs, defense procurement, production of strategic and critical materials, finance, or any other disciplines deemed necessary by the chairman to conduct the business of the Board.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties of the Board</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In addition to other matters assigned to it by the chairman, the Board shall conduct the following, without power of delegation:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Adopt by-laws that ensure sufficient oversight, governance, and effectiveness of the National Defense Stockpile program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Elect or remove Board members.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Advise the National Defense Stockpile Manager.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Establish performance metrics and conduct an annual performance review of the management and operations of the National Defense Stockpile program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Review and approve the annual budget of the National Defense Stockpile program and conduct appropriate reviews of annual financial statements.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Re-allocate budget resources within the annual budget of the National Defense Stockpile program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Review and approve the Annual Materials and Operations Plan required by <ref>section 98h–2(a) of this title</ref>. The report required by <ref>section 98h–2(b)(2) of this title</ref> shall include the views and recommendations of the Board on the projected domestic and foreign economic effects of all acquisition of materials for and disposals of materials from the stockpile.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Complete and submit the annual Board Report, in accordance with <ref>section 98h–2(b)(2) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<chapeau> Recommend to the Secretary of Defense—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a strategy to ensure a secure supply of materials designated as critical to national security; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> such other strategies as the Board considers appropriate to strengthen the industrial base with respect to materials critical to national security.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Board meetings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Board shall meet as determined necessary by the chairman but not less frequently than once every year to fulfill the duties described in subsection (c).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application of provisions relating to Federal advisory committees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0"><ref>Section 1013(a) of title 5</ref> shall not apply to the Board.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Materials critical to national security</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “materials critical to national security” means materials—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> upon which the production or sustainment of military equipment is dependent; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the supply of which could be restricted by actions or events outside the control of the Government of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Military equipment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “military equipment” means equipment used directly by the Armed Forces to carry out military operations.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secure supply</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “secure supply”, with respect to a material, means the availability of a source or sources for the material, including the full supply chain for the material and components containing the material.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 7, 1939, ch. 190, § 10</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 96–41, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1979-07-30">July 30, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 323</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. C, title XXXIII, § 3314</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2654</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title XIV, § 1411(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2869</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XIV, § 1411(c)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 524</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 98h–2.</num>
<heading> Reports</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports to the Board</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The National Defense Stockpile Manager shall submit to the Board an Annual Materials and Operations Plan for the forthcoming year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports to Congress</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report by National Defense Stockpile Manager</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than February 15 of each fiscal year, the National Defense Stockpile Manager shall submit to the congressional defense committees (as defined in <ref>section 101(a) of title 10</ref>) an Annual Operations and Materials Plan that shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> information with respect to foreign and domestic purchases of materials for the stockpile during the preceding fiscal year;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> information with respect to the acquisition and disposal of materials under this subchapter by barter, during such fiscal year;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> information with respect to the activities by the National Defense Stockpile Manager to encourage the conservation, substitution, and development of strategic and critical materials;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> information with respect to the research and development activities conducted under <ref>section 98g of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> a statement and explanation of the financial status of the National Defense Stockpile Transaction Fund and anticipated appropriations to be made to the Fund, and obligations to be made from the fund, during the current fiscal year;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> other pertinent information on the administration of this subchapter as will enable the Congress to evaluate the effectiveness of the program;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<chapeau> an annual materials plan for the operation of the stockpile during the next fiscal year and the succeeding four fiscal years and planned expenditures from the National Defense Stockpile Transaction Fund and anticipated receipts from disposal of stockpile materials, which shall include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> details of all planned expenditures from the National Defense Stockpile Transaction Fund during such period and of anticipated receipts from the proposed disposals of stockpile materials during such period;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> details regarding materials development and research projects to be conducted during the fiscal years covered by the report using moneys in the National Defense Stockpile Transaction Fund pursuant to <ref>section 98h(b)(2)(G) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> with respect to each development and research project described in clause (ii), the report shall specify the amount planned to be expended from the National Defense Stockpile Transaction Fund, the material intended to be developed, the potential military or defense industrial applications for that material, and the development and research methodologies to be used;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> any proposed expenditure or disposal detailed in the annual materials plan for any such fiscal year, and any expenditure or disposal proposed in connection with any transaction submitted for such fiscal year to the appropriate committees of Congress pursuant to <ref>section 98d(a)(2) of this title</ref> that is not obligated or executed in that fiscal year may not be obligated or executed until such proposed expenditure or disposal is resubmitted in a subsequent annual materials plan or is resubmitted to the appropriate committees of Congress in accordance with <ref>section 98d(a)(2) of this title</ref>, as appropriate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<chapeau> a summary of the implementation and findings of the pilot program established under <ref>section 98e(g)(1) of this title</ref>, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the commercial best practices selected for use under the pilot program;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> how the National Defense Stockpile Manager determined which commercial best practices to select;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> how the National Defense Stockpile Manager has used commercial best practices under the pilot program during the year preceding the briefing;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the outcome of each use of such practices; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> any savings achieved or lessons learned as a result of the use of such practices.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report by the Board</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Board shall prepare a written report to accompany the report required by paragraph (1) which shall include the activities of the Board to carry out the duties listed in <ref>section 98h–1(c) of this title</ref> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002005">1</ref></p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 7, 1939, ch. 190, § 11</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 96–41, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1979-07-30">July 30, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 324</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 97–35, title II, § 203(e)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 382</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–661, div. C, title II, § 3207(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 4069</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–180, div. C, title II, § 3205</ref>, <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1247</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–456, div. A, title XV, § 1503</ref>, <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2086</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. C, title XXXIII, § 3315</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1688</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. C, title XXXIII</ref>, §§ 3311(b), 3313(a), <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1584</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–35, title II, § 204(d)</ref>, <date date="1993-05-31">May 31, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 103</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title X, § 1071(j)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3512</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title XIV, § 1423</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2093</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title XIV, § 1411(c)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2870</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XIV, § 1411(d)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 524</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 98h–3.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For the purposes of this subchapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “strategic and critical materials” means materials that (A) would be needed to supply the military, industrial, and essential civilian needs of the United States during a national emergency, and (B) are not found or produced in the United States in sufficient quantities to meet such need.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “national emergency” means a general declaration of emergency with respect to the national defense made by the President or by the Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The term “reliable source” mean a citizen or business entity organized under the laws of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the United States or any territory or possession of the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a country of the national technology and industrial base, as such term is defined in <ref>section 4801 of title 10</ref>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a qualifying country, as defined in section 225.003 of the Defense Federal Acquisition Regulation Supplement or any successor document.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 7, 1939, ch. 190, § 12</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 96–41, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1979-07-30">July 30, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 324</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XIV, § 1411(2)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2018</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XIV, § 1411(e)(2)(C)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 528</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 98h–4.</num>
<heading> Importation of strategic and critical ma­terials</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President may not prohibit or regulate the importation into the United States of any material determined to be strategic and critical pursuant to the provisions of this subchapter, if such material is the product of any foreign country or area not listed in general note 3(b) of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States (<ref>19 U.S.C. 1202</ref>), for so long as the importation into the United States of material of that kind which is the product of a country or area listed in such general note is not prohibited by any provision of law.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 7, 1939, ch. 190, § 13</ref>, formerly § 10, as added <ref>Pub. L. 92–156, title V, § 503(2)</ref>, <date date="1971-11-17">Nov. 17, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 427</ref>; renumbered § 13, <ref>Pub. L. 96–41, § 2(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1979-07-30">July 30, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 324</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–180, div. C, title II, § 3206(b)</ref>, (c), <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1247</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title I, § 1214</ref>(<i>o</i>), <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1159</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. C, title XXXIII, § 3313</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2857</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 98h–5.</num>
<heading> Biennial report on stockpile requirements</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than January 15 of every other year, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to Congress a report on stockpile requirements. Each such report shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Secretary’s recommendations with respect to stockpile requirements; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the matters required under subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National emergency planning assumptions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each report under this section shall set forth the national emergency planning assumptions used by the Secretary in making the Secretary’s recommendations under subsection (a)(1) with respect to stockpile requirements. The Secretary shall base the national emergency planning assumptions on a military conflict scenario consistent with the scenario used by the Secretary in budgeting and defense planning purposes. The assumptions to be set forth include assumptions relating to each of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The length and intensity of the assumed military conflict.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The military force structure to be mobilized.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The losses anticipated from enemy action.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The military, industrial, and essential civilian requirements to support the national emergency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The availability of supplies of strategic and critical materials from foreign sources during the mobilization period, the military conflict, and the subsequent period of replenishment, taking into consideration possible shipping losses.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The domestic production of strategic and critical materials during the mobilization period, the military conflict, and the subsequent period of replenishment, taking into consideration possible shipping losses.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Civilian austerity measures required during the mobilization period and military conflict.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Period within which to replace or replenish materials</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The stockpile requirements shall be based on those strategic and critical materials necessary for the United States to replenish or replace, within three years of the end of the military conflict scenario required under subsection (b), all munitions, combat support items, and weapons systems that would be required after such a military conflict.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect of alternative mobilization periods</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall also include in each report under this section an examination of the effect that alternative mobilization periods under the military conflict scenario required under subsection (b), as well as a range of other military conflict scenarios addressing potentially more serious threats to national security, would have on the Secretary’s recommendations under subsection (a)(1) with respect to stockpile requirements.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Plans of President</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall submit with each report under this section a statement of the plans of the President for meeting the recommendations of the Secretary set forth in the report.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Briefings on shortfalls in stockpile</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Not later than March 1 each year, the National Defense Stockpile Manager shall provide to the congressional defense committees a briefing on strategic and critical materials that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> are determined to be in shortfall in the most recent report on stockpile requirements submitted under subsection (a); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the acquisition or disposal of which is included in the Annual Materials and Operations Plan for the operation of the stockpile during the next fiscal year submitted under <ref>section 98h–2(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Each briefing required by paragraph (1) shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a description of each material described in that paragraph, including the objective to be achieved if funding is provided, in whole or in part, for the acquisition of the material to remedy the shortfall;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an estimate of additional amounts required to provide such funding, if any; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> an assessment of the supply chain for each such material, including any assessment of any relevant risk in any such supply chain.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 7, 1939, ch. 190, § 14</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 100–180, div. C, title II, § 3202(c)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1246</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. C, title XXXIII, § 3313(b)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1585</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. C, title XXXIII, § 3314</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1962</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. C, title XXXIII, § 3311(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2856</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title XIV, § 1413</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2872</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 98h–6.</num>
<heading> Development and conservation of reliable sources</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subject to subsection (d), the National Defense Stockpile Manager shall encourage the development and appropriate conservation of reliable sources of strategic and critical materials—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> by purchasing, or making a commitment to purchase, strategic and critical materials from reliable sources when such materials are needed for the stockpile;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> by contracting with facilities located in and owned and controlled by reliable sources, or making a commitment to contract with such facilities, for the processing or refining of strategic and critical materials in the stockpile when processing or refining is necessary to convert such materials into a form more suitable for storage or disposition or meeting stockpile requirements;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> by qualifying facilities located in and owned and controlled by reliable sources, or qualifying strategic and critical materials produced by such facilities, to meet stockpile requirements;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> by contracting with facilities located in and owned and controlled by reliable sources to recycle strategic and critical materials to meet stockpile requirements or increase the balance of the National Defense Stockpile Transaction Fund under <ref>section 98h of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> by entering into an agreement to co-fund a bankable feasibility study for a project for the development of strategic and critical materials located in and owned and controlled by a reliable source, if the agreement—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> limits the liability of the stockpile to not more than the total funding provided by the Federal Government;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> limits the funding contribution of the Federal Government to not more than 50 percent of the cost of the bankable feasibility study; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> does not obligate the Federal Government to purchase strategic and critical materials from the reliable source.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional authorities</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Extended contracting authority</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term of a contract or commitment made under subsection (a) may not exceed ten years.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Preexisting contracts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A contract entered into before <date date="2023-12-22">December 22, 2023</date>, for a term of more than ten years may be extended, on or after <date date="2023-12-22">December 22, 2023</date>, for a total of not more than an additional ten years pursuant to any option or options set forth in the contract.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Matters relating to co-funding of bankable feasibility studies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To the extent authorized by Congress pursuant to the Defense Production Act of 1950 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 4501</ref> et seq.) and determined to be required by the President pursuant to that Act, the National Defense Stockpile Manager may provide for loans or procure debt issued by other entities to carry out a project for the development of strategic and critical materials with respect to which a study was carried out under subsection (a)(5).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Proposed transactions included in annual materials plan</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Descriptions of proposed transactions under subsection (a) shall be included in the Annual Materials and Operations Plan. Changes to any such transaction, or the addition of a transaction not included in such plan, shall be made in accordance with <ref>section 98d(a)(2) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The authority of the National Defense Stockpile Manager to enter into obligations under this section is effective for any fiscal year only to the extent that funds in the National Defense Stockpile Transaction Fund under <ref>section 98h of this title</ref> are adequate to meet such obligations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Bankable feasibility study defined</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section, the term “bankable feasibility study” means a comprehensive technical and economic study—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> of the selected option for a strategic and critical materials development project that includes appropriately detailed assessments of realistically assumed extraction, processing, metallurgical, economic, marketing, legal, environmental, social, and governmental considerations and any other relevant operational factors and detailed financial analysis, that are necessary to demonstrate at the time of reporting that production is reasonably justified; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> that may reasonably serve as the basis for a final decision by a proponent of a project or financial institution to proceed with, or finance, the development of the project.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 7, 1939, ch. 190, § 15</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. C, title XXXIII, § 3312(a)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1687</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title XIV, § 1411(c)</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 934</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XIV, § 1412(b)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2570</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XIV, § 1411(3)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2018</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title XIV, § 1411(d)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2871</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XIV, § 1411(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 526</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 98h–7.</num>
<heading> National Defense Stockpile Manager</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall designate a single Federal office to have responsibility for performing the functions of the President under this subchapter, other than under sections 98f(a)(1) and 98h–4 of this title. The office designated shall be one to which appointment is made by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Title of designated officer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The individual holding the office designated by the President under subsection (a) shall be known for purposes of functions under this subchapter as the “National Defense Stockpile Manager”.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Delegation of functions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President may delegate functions of the President under this subchapter (other than under sections 98f(a)(1) and 98h–4 of this title) only to the National Defense Stockpile Manager. Any such delegation made by the President shall remain in effect until specifically revoked by law or Executive order. The President may not delegate functions of the President under sections 98f(a)(1) and 98h–4 of this title.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 7, 1939, ch. 190, § 16</ref>, formerly § 6A, as added <ref>Pub. L. 99–661, div. C, title II, § 3202(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 4067</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–180, div. C, title II, § 3203(a)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1246</ref>; renumbered § 16 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. C, title XXXIII, § 3313</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1688</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. C, title XXXIII, § 3314</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1585</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title XIV, § 1413(b)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 2049</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 98i.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 85–861, § 36A</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1570</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 99.</num>
<heading> Transferred</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 100.</num>
<heading> Nitrate plants</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Investigations; designation of sites; construction and operation of dams, locks, improvements to navigation, etc.</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President of the United States may make, or cause to be made, such investigation as in his judgment is necessary to determine the best, cheapest, and most available means for the production of nitrates and other products for munitions of war and useful in the manufacture of fertilizers and other useful products by water power or any other power as in his judgment is the best and cheapest to use; and is also authorized to designate for the exclusive use of the United States, if in his judgment such means is best and cheapest, such site or sites, upon any navigable or nonnavigable river or rivers or upon the public lands, as in his opinion will be necessary for national defense; and is further authorized to construct, maintain, and operate, at or on any site or sites so designated, dams, locks, improvements to navigation, power houses, and other plants and equipment or other means than water power as in his judgment is the best and cheapest, necessary or convenient for the generation of electrical or other power and for the production of nitrates or other products needed for munitions of war and useful in the manufacture of fertilizers and other useful products.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Lease, purchase, or acquisition of lands and rights of way; purchase or acquisition of materials, minerals, and processes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President is authorized to lease, buy, or acquire, by condemnation, gift, grant, or devise, such lands and rights of way as may be necessary for the construction and operation of such plants and to take from any lands of the United States, or to buy or acquire by condemnation materials, minerals, and processes, patented or otherwise, necessary for the construction and operation of such plants and for the manufacture of such products.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of products of plants; disposal of surplus</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The products of such plants shall be used by the President for military and naval purposes to the extent that he may deem necessary, and any surplus which he shall determine is not required shall be sold and disposed of by him under such regulations as he may prescribe.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Employment of officers, agents, or agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President is authorized to employ such officers, agents, or agencies as may in his discretion be necessary to enable him to carry out the purposes herein specified, and to authorize and require such officers, agents, or agencies to perform any and all of the duties imposed upon him by the provisions hereof.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Government construction and operation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The plant or plants provided for under this section shall be constructed and operated solely by the Government and not in conjunction with any other industry or enterprise carried on by private capital.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041, § 37</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 634</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 100a.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>