<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 39—</num>
<heading>SPOILS OF WAR</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2201.</num>
<heading> Transfers of spoils of war</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility for transfer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Spoils of war in the possession, custody, or control of the United States may be transferred to any other party, including any government, group, or person, by sale, grant, loan or in any other manner, only to the extent and in the same manner that property of the same type, if otherwise owned by the United States, may be so transferred.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Terms and conditions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any transfer pursuant to subsection (a) shall be subject to all of the terms, conditions, and requirements applicable to the transfer of property of the same type otherwise owned by the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–236, title V, § 552</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 482</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2202.</num>
<heading> Prohibition on transfers to countries which support terrorism</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Spoils of war in the possession, custody, or control of the United States may not be transferred to any country determined by the Secretary of State, for purposes of <ref>section 2780 of title 22</ref>, to be a nation whose government has repeatedly provided support for acts of international terrorism.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–236, title V, § 553</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 482</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2203.</num>
<heading> Report on previous transfers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 90 days after <date date="1994-04-30">April 30, 1994</date>, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report describing any spoils of war obtained subsequent to <date date="1990-08-02">August 2, 1990</date> that were transferred to any party, including any government, group, or person, before <date date="1994-04-30">April 30, 1994</date>. Such report shall be submitted in unclassified form to the extent possible.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–236, title V, § 554</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 482</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2204.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “appropriate congressional committees” means the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives, or, where required by law for certain reporting purposes, the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate and the Select <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002045">1</ref> Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “enemy” means any country, government, group, or person that has been engaged in hostilities, whether or not lawfully authorized, with the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> the term “person” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any natural person;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any corporation, partnership, or other legal entity; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any organization, association, or group; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the term “spoils of war” means enemy movable property lawfully captured, seized, confiscated, or found which has become United States property in accordance with the laws of war.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–236, title V, § 555</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 482</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2205.</num>
<heading> Construction</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall apply to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the abandonment or failure to take possession of spoils of war by troops in the field for valid military reasons related to the conduct of the immediate conflict, including the burden of transporting such property or a decision to allow allied forces to take immediate possession of certain property solely for use during an ongoing conflict;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the abandonment or return of any property obtained, borrowed, or requisitioned for temporary use during military operations without intent to retain possession of such property;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the destruction of spoils of war by troops in the field;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the return of spoils of war to previous owners from whom such property had been seized by enemy forces; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> minor articles of personal property which have lawfully become the property of individual members of the armed forces as war trophies pursuant to public written authorization from the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–236, title V, § 556</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 483</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>