<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 40—</num>
<heading>DEFENSE AGAINST WEAPONS OF MASS DESTRUCTION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2301.</num>
<heading> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Congress makes the following findings:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Weapons of mass destruction and related materials and technologies are increasingly available from worldwide sources. Technical information relating to such weapons is readily available on the Internet, and raw materials for chemical, biological, and radiological weapons are widely available for legitimate commercial purposes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The former Soviet Union produced and maintained a vast array of nuclear, biological, and chemical weapons of mass destruction.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Many of the states of the former Soviet Union retain the facilities, materials, and technologies capable of producing additional quantities of weapons of mass destruction.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The disintegration of the former Soviet Union was accompanied by disruptions of command and control systems, deficiencies in accountability for weapons, weapons-related materials and technologies, economic hardships, and significant gaps in border control among the states of the former Soviet Union. The problems of organized crime and corruption in the states of the former Soviet Union increase the potential for proliferation of nuclear, radiological, biological, and chemical weapons and related materials.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The conditions described in paragraph (4) have substantially increased the ability of potentially hostile nations, terrorist groups, and individuals to acquire weapons of mass destruction and related materials and technologies from within the states of the former Soviet Union and from unemployed scientists who worked on those programs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> As a result of such conditions, the capability of potentially hostile nations and terrorist groups to acquire nuclear, radiological, biological, and chemical weapons is greater than at any time in history.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The President has identified North Korea, Iraq, Iran, and Libya as hostile states which already possess some weapons of mass destruction and are developing others.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> The acquisition or the development and use of weapons of mass destruction is well within the capability of many extremist and terrorist movements, acting independently or as proxies for foreign states.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> Foreign states can transfer weapons to or otherwise aid extremist and terrorist movements indirectly and with plausible deniability.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> Terrorist groups have already conducted chemical attacks against civilian targets in the United States and Japan, and a radiological attack in Russia.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> The potential for the national security of the United States to be threatened by nuclear, radiological, chemical, or biological terrorism must be taken seriously.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> There is a significant and growing threat of attack by weapons of mass destruction on targets that are not military targets in the usual sense of the term.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> Concomitantly, the threat posed to the citizens of the United States by nuclear, radiological, biological, and chemical weapons delivered by unconventional means is significant and growing.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> Mass terror may result from terrorist incidents involving nuclear, radiological, biological, or chemical materials.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<content> Facilities required for production of radiological, biological, and chemical weapons are much smaller and harder to detect than nuclear weapons facilities, and biological and chemical weapons can be deployed by alternative delivery means other than long-range ballistic missiles.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(16)</num>
<content> Covert or unconventional means of delivery of nuclear, radiological, biological, and chemical weapons include cargo ships, passenger aircraft, commercial and private vehicles and vessels, and commercial cargo shipments routed through multiple destinations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(17)</num>
<content> Traditional arms control efforts assume large state efforts with detectable manufacturing programs and weapons production programs, but are ineffective in monitoring and controlling smaller, though potentially more dangerous, unconventional proliferation efforts.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(18)</num>
<content> Conventional counterproliferation efforts would do little to detect or prevent the rapid development of a capability to suddenly manufacture several hundred chemical or biological weapons with nothing but commercial supplies and equipment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(19)</num>
<content> The United States lacks adequate planning and countermeasures to address the threat of nuclear, radiological, biological, and chemical terrorism.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(20)</num>
<content> The Department of Energy has established a Nuclear Emergency Response Team which is available in case of nuclear or radiological emergencies, but no comparable units exist to deal with emergencies involving biological or chemical weapons or related materials.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(21)</num>
<content> State and local emergency response personnel are not adequately prepared or trained for incidents involving nuclear, radiological, biological, or chemical materials.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(22)</num>
<content> Exercises of the Federal, State, and local response to nuclear, radiological, biological, or chemical terrorism have revealed serious deficiencies in preparedness and severe problems of coordination.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(23)</num>
<content> The development of, and allocation of responsibilities for, effective countermeasures to nuclear, radiological, biological, or chemical terrorism in the United States requires well-coordinated participation of many Federal agencies, and careful planning by the Federal Government and State and local governments.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(24)</num>
<content> Training and exercises can significantly improve the preparedness of State and local emergency response personnel for emergencies involving nuclear, radiological, biological, or chemical weapons or related materials.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(25)</num>
<content> Sharing of the expertise and capabilities of the Department of Defense, which traditionally has provided assistance to Federal, State, and local officials in neutralizing, dismantling, and disposing of explosive ordnance, as well as radiological, biological, and chemical materials, can be a vital contribution to the development and deployment of countermeasures against nuclear, biological, and chemical weapons of mass destruction.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(26)</num>
<content> The United States lacks effective policy coordination regarding the threat posed by the proliferation of weapons of mass destruction.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XIV, § 1402</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2715</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2302.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The term “weapon of mass destruction” means any weapon or device that is intended, or has the capability, to cause death or serious bodily injury to a significant number of people through the release, dissemination, or impact of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> toxic or poisonous chemicals or their precursors;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a disease organism; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> radiation or radioactivity.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “independent states of the former Soviet Union” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 5801 of title 22</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “highly enriched uranium” means uranium enriched to 20 percent or more in the isotope U–235.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XIV, § 1403</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2717</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>DOMESTIC PREPAREDNESS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2311.</num>
<heading> Response to threats of terrorist use of weapons of mass destruction</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Enhanced response capability</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In light of the potential for terrorist use of weapons of mass destruction against the United States, the President shall take immediate action—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to enhance the capability of the Federal Government to prevent and respond to terrorist incidents involving weapons of mass destruction; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to provide enhanced support to improve the capabilities of State and local emergency response agencies to prevent and respond to such incidents at both the national and the local level.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report required</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than <date date="1997-01-31">January 31, 1997</date>, the President shall transmit to Congress a report containing—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an assessment of the capabilities of the Federal Government to prevent and respond to terrorist incidents involving weapons of mass destruction and to support State and local prevention and response efforts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> requirements for improvements in those capabilities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the measures that should be taken to achieve such improvements, including additional resources and legislative authorities that would be required.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XIV, § 1411</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2717</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2312.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title X, § 1034</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3429</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2313.</num>
<heading> Nuclear, chemical, and biological emergency response</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Department of Defense</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Assistant Secretary of Defense for Homeland Defense is responsible for the coordination of Department of Defense assistance to Federal, State, and local officials in responding to threats involving nuclear, radiological, biological, chemical weapons, or high-yield explosives or related materials or technologies, including assistance in identifying, neutralizing, dismantling, and disposing of nuclear, radiological, biological, chemical weapons, and high-yield explosives and related materials and technologies.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Department of Energy</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of Energy shall designate an official within the Department of Energy as the executive agent for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the coordination of Department of Energy assistance to Federal, State, and local officials in responding to threats involving nuclear, chemical, and biological weapons or related materials or technologies, including assistance in identifying, neutralizing, dismantling, and disposing of nuclear weapons and related materials and technologies; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the coordination of Department of Energy assistance to the Department of Defense in carrying out that department’s responsibilities under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Funding</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Of the total amount authorized to be appropriated under section 301,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002046">1</ref> $15,000,000 is available for providing assistance described in subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XIV, § 1413</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2719</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title X, § 1031</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3428</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2314.</num>
<heading> Chemical, biological, radiological, nuclear, and high-yield explosives response team</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Department of Defense rapid response team</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Defense shall develop and maintain at least one domestic terrorism rapid response team composed of members of the Armed Forces and employees of the Department of Defense who are capable of aiding Federal, State, and local officials in the detection, neutralization, containment, dismantlement, and disposal of weapons of mass destruction containing chemical, biological, radiological, nuclear, and high-yield explosives.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Addition to Federal response plans</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall incorporate into the National Response Plan prepared pursuant to section 502(6) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002047">1</ref> of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<ref>6 U.S.C. 312(6)</ref>), other existing Federal emergency response plans, and programs prepared under <ref>section 5196(b) of title 42</ref> guidance on the use and deployment of the rapid response teams established under this section to respond to emergencies involving weapons of mass destruction. The Secretary of Homeland Security shall carry out this subsection in coordination with the Secretary of Defense and the heads of other Federal agencies involved with the emergency response plans.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XIV, § 1414</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2720</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title X, § 1033</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3429</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2315.</num>
<heading> Testing of preparedness for emergencies involving nuclear, radiological, chemical, and biological weapons</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Emergencies involving nuclear, radiological, chemical, or biological weapons</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Homeland Security shall develop and carry out a program for testing and improving the responses of Federal, State, and local agencies to emergencies involving nuclear, radiological, biological, and chemical weapons and related materials.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The program shall include exercises to be carried out in accordance with sections 112(c) and 238(c)(1) of title 6.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> In developing and carrying out the program, the Secretary shall coordinate with the Secretary of Defense, the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the Secretary of Energy, and the heads of any other Federal, State, and local government agencies that have an expertise or responsibilities relevant to emergencies described in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual revisions of programs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall revise the program developed under subsection (a) not later than June 1 in each fiscal year covered by the program. The revisions shall include adjustments that the Secretary determines necessary or appropriate on the basis of the lessons learned from the exercise or exercises carried out under the program in the fiscal year, including lessons learned regarding coordination problems and equipment deficiencies.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XIV, § 1415</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2720</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. C, title XXXI, § 3154(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2738</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title X, § 1032</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3428</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2316.</num>
<heading> Actions to increase civilian expertise</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> to (c) Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Civilian expertise</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President shall take reasonable measures to reduce the reliance of civilian law enforcement officials on Department of Defense resources to counter the threat posed by the use or potential use of biological and chemical weapons of mass destruction within the United States. The measures shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> actions to increase civilian law enforcement expertise to counter such a threat; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> actions to improve coordination between civilian law enforcement officials and other civilian sources of expertise, within and outside the Federal Government, to counter such a threat.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President shall submit to Congress the following reports:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Not later than 90 days after <date date="1996-09-23">September 23, 1996</date>, a report describing the respective policy functions and operational roles of Federal agencies in countering the threat posed by the use or potential use of biological and chemical weapons of mass destruction within the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Not later than one year after <date date="1996-09-23">September 23, 1996</date>, a report describing—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the actions planned to be taken to carry out subsection (d); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the costs of such actions.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Not later than three years after <date date="1996-09-23">September 23, 1996</date>, a report updating the information provided in the reports submitted pursuant to paragraphs (1) and (2), including the measures taken pursuant to subsection (d).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XIV, § 1416</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2721</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2317.</num>
<heading> Rapid response information system</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inventory of rapid response assets</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The head of each Federal Response Plan agency shall develop and maintain an inventory of physical equipment and assets under the jurisdiction of that agency that could be made available to aid State and local officials in search and rescue and other disaster management and mitigation efforts associated with an emergency involving weapons of mass destruction. The agency head shall submit a copy of the inventory, and any updates of the inventory, to the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency for inclusion in the master inventory required under subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Each inventory shall include a separate listing of any equipment that is excess to the needs of that agency and could be considered for disposal as excess or surplus property for use for response and training with regard to emergencies involving weapons of mass destruction.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Master inventory</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall compile and maintain a comprehensive listing of all inventories prepared under subsection (a). The first such master list shall be completed not later than <date date="1997-12-31">December 31, 1997</date>, and shall be updated annually thereafter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Addition to Federal response plan</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than <date date="1997-12-31">December 31, 1997</date>, the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall develop and incorporate into existing Federal emergency response plans and programs prepared under <ref>section 5196(b) of title 42</ref> guidance on accessing and using the physical equipment and assets included in the master list developed under subsection <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002048">1</ref> to respond to emergencies involving weapons of mass destruction.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Database on chemical and biological materials</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, shall prepare a database on chemical and biological agents and munitions characteristics and safety precautions for civilian use. The initial design and compilation of the database shall be completed not later than <date date="1997-12-31">December 31, 1997</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Access to inventory and database</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall design and maintain a system to give Federal, State, and local officials access to the inventory listing and database maintained under this section in the event of an emergency involving weapons of mass destruction or to prepare and train to respond to such an emergency. The system shall include a secure but accessible emergency response hotline to access information and request assistance.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XIV, § 1417</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2724</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–295, title VI, § 612(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-04">Oct. 4, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1410</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>INTERDICTION OF WEAPONS OF MASS DESTRUCTION AND RELATED MATERIALS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2331.</num>
<heading> Procurement of detection equipment for United States border security</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Of the amount authorized to be appropriated by section 301,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002049">1</ref> $15,000,000 is available for the procurement of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> equipment capable of detecting the movement of weapons of mass destruction and related materials into the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> equipment capable of interdicting the movement of weapons of mass destruction and related materials into the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> materials and technologies related to use of equipment described in paragraph (1) or (2).</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XIV, § 1421</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2725</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2332.</num>
<heading> Sense of Congress concerning criminal penalties</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sense of Congress concerning inadequacy of sentencing guidelines</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is the sense of Congress that the sentencing guidelines prescribed by the United States Sentencing Commission for the offenses of importation, attempted importation, exportation, and attempted exportation of nuclear, biological, and chemical weapons materials constitute inadequate punishment for such offenses.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Urging of revision to guidelines</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Congress urges the United States Sentencing Commission to revise the relevant sentencing guidelines to provide for increased penalties for offenses relating to importation, attempted importation, exportation, and attempted exportation of nuclear, biological, or chemical weapons or related materials or technologies under the following provisions of law:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Section 4610 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002050">1</ref> of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Sections 2778 and 2780 of title 22.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<ref>50 U.S.C. 1701</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content><ref>Section 2139a(c) of title 42</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XIV, § 1423</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2725</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title X, § 1069(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2136</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2333.</num>
<heading> International border security</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary of Defense responsibility</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Defense, in consultation and cooperation with the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection, shall carry out programs for assisting customs officials and border guard officials in the independent states of the former Soviet Union, the Baltic states, and other countries of Eastern Europe in preventing unauthorized transfer and transportation of nuclear, biological, and chemical weapons and related materials. Training, expert advice, maintenance of equipment, loan of equipment, and audits may be provided under or in connection with the programs.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other countries</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Defense may carry out programs under subsection (a) in a country other than a country specified in that subsection if the Secretary determines that there exists in that country a significant threat of the unauthorized transfer and transportation of nuclear, biological, or chemical weapons or related materials.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistance to states of former Soviet Union</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Assistance under programs referred to in subsection (a) may (notwithstanding any provision of law prohibiting the extension of foreign assistance to any of the newly independent states of the former Soviet Union) be extended to include an independent state of the former Soviet Union if the President certifies to Congress that it is in the national interest of the United States to extend assistance under this section to that state.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XIV, § 1424</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2726</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title XII, § 1211(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2087</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–125, title VIII, § 802(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="2016-02-24">Feb. 24, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 210</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2334.</num>
<heading> Training program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Defense may participate in a training program carried out jointly by the Secretary of Defense and the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation in order to expand and improve United States efforts to deter the possible proliferation and acquisition of weapons of mass destruction by organized crime organizations in Eastern Europe, the Baltic countries, states of the former Soviet Union, and in other countries in which, as determined by the Secretary of Defense, there exists a significant threat of such proliferation and acquisition.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XV, § 1504(e)(3)(A)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2918</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title XII, § 1211(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2087</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>CONTROL AND DISPOSITION OF WEAPONS OF MASS DESTRUCTION AND RELATED MATERIALS THREATENING THE UNITED STATES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2341.</num>
<heading> Elimination of plutonium production</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Replacement program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Energy, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, shall develop a cooperative program with the Government of Russia to eliminate the production of weapons grade plutonium by modifying or replacing the reactor cores at Tomsk–7 and Krasnoyarsk–26 with reactor cores that are less suitable for the production of weapons-grade plutonium.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program requirements</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The program shall be designed to achieve completion of the modifications or replacements of the reactor cores within three years after the modification or replacement activities under the program are begun.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The plan for the program shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> specify—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> successive steps for the modification or replacement of the reactor cores; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> clearly defined milestones to be achieved; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> include estimates of the costs of the program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Submission of program plan to Congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after <date date="1996-09-23">September 23, 1996</date>, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to Congress—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a plan for the program under subsection (a);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an estimate of the United States funding that is necessary for carrying out the activities under the program for each fiscal year covered by the program; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a comparison of the benefits of the program with the benefits of other nonproliferation programs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XIV, § 1432</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2726</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2342.</num>
<heading> Cooperative program on research, development, and demonstration of technology regarding nuclear or radiological terrorism</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator for Nuclear Security shall carry out with the Russian Federation a cooperative program on the research, development, and demonstration of technologies for protection from and response to nuclear or radiological terrorism.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program elements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In carrying out the program required by subsection (a), the Administrator shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> conduct research and development of technology for protection from nuclear or radiological terrorism, including technology for the detection, identification, assessment, control, and disposition of radiological materials that could be used for nuclear terrorism; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> provide, where feasible, for the demonstration to other countries of technologies or methodologies on matters relating to nuclear or radiological terrorism, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the demonstration of technologies developed under the program to respond to nuclear or radiological terrorism;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the demonstration of technologies developed under the program for the disposal of radioactive materials;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the demonstration of methodologies developed under the program for use in evaluating the radiological threat of radiological sources identified as not under current accounting programs in the audit report of the Inspector General of the Department of Energy titled “Accounting for Sealed Sources of Nuclear Material Provided to Foreign Countries” (DOE/IG–0546);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> in coordination with the Nuclear Regulatory Commission, the demonstration of methodologies developed under the program to facilitate the development of a regulatory framework for licensing and controlling radioactive sources; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> in coordination with the Office of Environment, Safety, and Health of the Department of Energy, the demonstration of methodologies developed under the program to facilitate development of consistent criteria for screening international transfers of radiological materials.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In carrying out activities in accordance with subsection (b)(2), the Administrator shall consult with—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Defense, Secretary of State, and Secretary of Commerce; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the International Atomic Energy Agency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amount for activities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Of the amount authorized to be appropriated by section 3101(a)(2) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002051">1</ref> for the Department of Energy for the National Nuclear Security Administration for defense nuclear nonproliferation, up to $15,000,000 may be available for carrying out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. C, title XXXI, § 3155</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2739</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2343.</num>
<heading> Matters relating to the international materials protection, control, and accounting program of the Department of Energy</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Radiological dispersal device materials protection, control, and accounting</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of Energy may establish within the International Materials Protection, Control, and Accounting program of the Department of Energy a program on the protection, control, and accounting of materials usable in radiological dispersal devices. In establishing such program, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> identify the sites and radiological materials to be covered by such program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> carry out a risk assessment of such radiological materials; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> identify and establish the costs of and schedules for such program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Revised focus for materials protection, control, and accounting program of Russian Federation</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Energy shall work cooperatively with the Russian Federation to develop, as soon as practicable but not later than <date date="2018-01-01">January 1, 2018</date>, a sustainable nuclear materials protection, control, and accounting system for the nuclear materials of the Russian Federation that is supported solely by the Russian Federation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall work with the Russian Federation to identify various alternatives to provide the United States adequate transparency in the nuclear materials protection, control, and accounting program of the Russian Federation to assure that such program is meeting applicable goals for nuclear materials protection, control, and accounting.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amount for activities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Of the amount authorized to be appropriated by section 3101(a)(2) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002052">1</ref> for the Department of Energy for the National Nuclear Security Administration for defense nuclear nonproliferation, up to $5,000,000 may be available for carrying out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. C, title XXXI, § 3156</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2739</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. C, title XXXI, § 3119</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4514</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2344.</num>
<heading> Strengthened international security for nuclear materials and security of nuclear operations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report on options for international program to strengthen security</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Not later than 270 days after <date date="2002-12-02">December 2, 2002</date>, the Secretary of Energy shall submit to Congress a report on options for an international program to develop strengthened security for nuclear reactors and associated materials outside the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In evaluating options for purposes of the report, the Secretary shall consult with the Nuclear Regulatory Commission and the International Atomic Energy Agency on the feasibility and advisability of actions to reduce the risks associated with terrorist attacks on nuclear reactors outside the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Joint programs with Russia on proliferation-resistant nuclear energy technologies</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall pursue with the Ministry of Atomic Energy of the Russian Federation joint programs between the United States and the Russian Federation on the development of proliferation-resistant nuclear energy technologies, including advanced fuel cycles.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Of the amount authorized to be appropriated by section 3101(a)(2) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002053">1</ref> for the Department of Energy for the National Nuclear Security Administration for defense nuclear nonproliferation, up to $10,000,000 may be available for carrying out the joint programs referred to in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistance regarding hostile insiders</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may, utilizing appropriate expertise of the Department of Energy and the Nuclear Regulatory Commission, provide technical assistance to nuclear reactor facilities outside the United States with respect to the interdiction of hostile insiders at such facilities in order to prevent incidents arising from the disablement of the vital systems of such facilities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. C, title XXXI, § 3158</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2741</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2345.</num>
<heading> Export control programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority to pursue options for strengthening export control programs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Energy, in coordination with the Secretary of State, may pursue in the region of the former Soviet Union and other regions of concern options for accelerating programs that assist the countries in such regions in improving their domestic export control programs for materials, technologies, and expertise relevant to the construction or use of a nuclear or radiological dispersal device.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amount for activities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Of the amount authorized to be appropriated by section 3101(a)(2) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002054">1</ref> for the Department of Energy for the National Nuclear Security Administration for defense nuclear nonproliferation, up to $5,000,000 may be available for carrying out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. C, title XXXI, § 3159</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2741</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>COORDINATION OF POLICY AND COUNTERMEASURES AGAINST PROLIFERATION OF WEAPONS OF MASS DESTRUCTION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2351.</num>
<heading> National coordinator on nonproliferation</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Designation of position</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall designate an individual to serve in the Executive Office of the President as the National Coordinator for Nonproliferation Matters.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Coordinator, under the direction of the National Security Council, shall advise and assist the President by—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> advising the President on nonproliferation of weapons of mass destruction, including issues related to terrorism, arms control, and international organized crime;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> chairing the Committee on Nonproliferation of the National Security Council; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> taking such actions as are necessary to ensure that there is appropriate emphasis in, cooperation on, and coordination of, nonproliferation research efforts of the United States, including activities of Federal agencies as well as activities of contractors funded by the Federal Government.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Allocation of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Of the total amount authorized to be appropriated under section 301,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002055">1</ref> $2,000,000 is available to the Department of Defense for carrying out research referred to in subsection (b)(3).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XIV, § 1441</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2727</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title X, § 1069(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2136</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2352.</num>
<heading> National Security Council Committee on Nonproliferation</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Committee on Nonproliferation (in this section referred to as the “Committee”) is established as a committee of the National Security Council.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Membership</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Committee shall be composed of representatives of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Secretary of State.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The Director of Central Intelligence.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The Attorney General.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Energy.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> The Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Treasury.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Commerce.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> Such other members as the President may designate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The National Coordinator for Nonproliferation Matters shall chair the Committee on Nonproliferation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Responsibilities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Committee has the following responsibilities:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> To review and coordinate Federal programs, policies, and directives relating to the proliferation of weapons of mass destruction and related materials and technologies, including matters relating to terrorism and international organized crime.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> To make recommendations through the National Security Council to the President regarding the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Integrated national policies for countering the threats posed by weapons of mass destruction.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Options for integrating Federal agency budgets for countering such threats.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Means to ensure that Federal, State, and local governments have adequate capabilities to manage crises involving nuclear, radiological, biological, or chemical weapons or related materials or technologies, and to manage the consequences of a use of such weapon or related materials or technologies, and that use of those capabilities is coordinated.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> Means to ensure appropriate cooperation on, and coordination of, the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Preventing the smuggling of weapons of mass destruction and related materials and technologies.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Promoting domestic and international law enforcement efforts against proliferation-related efforts.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Countering the involvement of organized crime groups in proliferation-related activities.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> Safeguarding weapons of mass destruction materials and related technologies.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> Improving coordination and cooperation among intelligence activities, law enforcement, and the Departments of Defense, State, Commerce, and Energy in support of nonproliferation and counterproliferation efforts.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> Improving export controls over materials and technologies that can contribute to the acquisition of weapons of mass destruction.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> Reducing proliferation of weapons of mass destruction and related materials and technologies.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XIV, § 1442</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2727</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2353.</num>
<heading> Comprehensive preparedness program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President, acting through the Committee on Nonproliferation established under <ref>section 2352 of this title</ref>, shall develop a comprehensive program for carrying out this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Content of program</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The program set forth in the report shall include specific plans as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Plans for countering proliferation of weapons of mass destruction and related materials and technologies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Plans for training and equipping Federal, State, and local officials for managing a crisis involving a use or threatened use of a weapon of mass destruction, including the consequences of the use of such a weapon.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Plans for providing for regular sharing of information among intelligence, law enforcement, and customs agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Plans for training and equipping law enforcement units, customs services, and border security personnel to counter the smuggling of weapons of mass destruction and related materials and technologies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Plans for establishing appropriate centers for analyzing seized nuclear, radiological, biological, and chemical weapons, and related materials and technologies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Plans for establishing in the United States appropriate legal controls and authorities relating to the exporting of nuclear, radiological, biological, and chemical weapons, and related materials and technologies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Plans for encouraging and assisting governments of foreign countries to implement and enforce laws that set forth appropriate penalties for offenses regarding the smuggling of weapons of mass destruction and related materials and technologies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Plans for building the confidence of the United States and Russia in each other’s controls over United States and Russian nuclear weapons and fissile materials, including plans for verifying the dismantlement of nuclear weapons.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<chapeau> Plans for reducing United States and Russian stockpiles of excess plutonium, reflecting—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> consideration of the desirability and feasibility of a United States-Russian agreement governing fissile material disposition and the specific technologies and approaches to be used for disposition of excess plutonium; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an assessment of the options for United States cooperation with Russia in the disposition of Russian plutonium.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> Plans for studying the merits and costs of establishing a global network of means for detecting and responding to terroristic or other criminal use of biological agents against people or other forms of life in the United States or any foreign country.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> At the same time that the President submits the budget for fiscal year 1998 to Congress pursuant to <ref>section 1105(a) of title 31</ref>, the President shall submit to Congress a report that sets forth the comprehensive program developed under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The report shall include the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The specific plans for the program that are required under subsection (b).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Estimates of the funds necessary, by agency or department, for carrying out such plans in fiscal year 1998 and the following five fiscal years.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The report shall be in an unclassified form. If there is a classified version of the report, the President shall submit the classified version at the same time.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XIV, § 1443</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2728</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2354.</num>
<heading> Termination</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">After <date date="1999-09-30">September 30, 1999</date>, the President—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> is not required to maintain a National Coordinator for Nonproliferation Matters under <ref>section 2351 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> may terminate the Committee on Nonproliferation established under <ref>section 2352 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XIV, § 1444</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2730</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title X, § 1069(c)(3)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2136</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV–A—</num>
<heading>NONPROLIFERATION ASSISTANCE COORDINATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2357.</num>
<heading> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Congress finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> United States nonproliferation efforts in the independent states of the former Soviet Union have achieved important results in ensuring that weapons of mass destruction, weapons-usable material and technology, and weapons-related knowledge remain beyond the reach of terrorists and weapons-proliferating states;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> although these efforts are in the United States national security interest, the effectiveness of these efforts has suffered from a lack of coordination within and among United States Government agencies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> increased spending and investment by the United States private sector on nonproliferation efforts in the independent states of the former Soviet Union, specifically, spending and investment by the United States private sector in job creation initiatives and proposals for unemployed Russian Federation weapons scientists and technicians, are making an important contribution in ensuring that knowledge related to weapons of mass destruction remains beyond the reach of terrorists and weapons-proliferating states; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> increased spending and investment by the United States private sector on nonproliferation efforts in the independent states of the former Soviet Union make advisable the establishment of a coordinating body to ensure that United States public and private efforts are not in conflict, and to ensure that public spending on efforts by the independent states of the former Soviet Union is maximized to ensure efficiency and further United States national security interests.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–228, div. B, title XIII, § 1332</ref>, <date date="2002-09-30">Sept. 30, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1448</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2357a.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Independent states of the former Soviet Union</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this subchapter, the term “independent states of the former Soviet Union” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 5801 of title 22</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appropriate committees of Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this subchapter, the term “the appropriate committees of Congress” means the Committees on Foreign Relations, Armed Services, and Appropriations of the Senate and the Committees on International Relations, Armed Services, and Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–228, div. B, title XIII, § 1333</ref>, <date date="2002-09-30">Sept. 30, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1449</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2357b.</num>
<heading> Establishment of Committee on Nonproliferation Assistance</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall establish a mechanism to coordinate, with the maximum possible effectiveness and efficiency, the efforts of United States Government departments and agencies engaged in formulating policy and carrying out programs for achieving nonproliferation and threat reduction.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Membership</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The coordination mechanism established pursuant to subsection (a) shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> representatives designated by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Secretary of State;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Defense;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Energy;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Commerce;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the Attorney General; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the Director of the Office of Homeland Security, or the head of a successor department or agency; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> such other executive branch officials as the President may select.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Level of representation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To the maximum extent possible, each department <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002056">1</ref> or agency’s representative designated pursuant to subsection (b)(1) shall be an official of that department or agency who has been appointed by the President with the advice and consent of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Chair</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall designate an official to direct the coordination mechanism established pursuant to subsection (a). The official so designated may invite the head of any other department or agency of the United States to designate a representative of that department or agency to participate from time to time in the activities of the Committee.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–228, div. B, title XIII, § 1334</ref>, <date date="2002-09-30">Sept. 30, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1449</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2357c.</num>
<heading> Purposes and authority</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purposes</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The primary purpose of the coordination mechanism established pursuant to <ref>section 2357b of this title</ref> should be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to exercise continuing responsibility for coordinating worldwide United States nonproliferation and threat reduction efforts to ensure that they effectively implement United States policy; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to enhance the ability of participating departments and agencies to anticipate growing nonproliferation areas of concern.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program monitoring and coordination</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The coordination mechanism established pursuant to <ref>section 2357b of this title</ref> should have primary continuing responsibility within the executive branch of the Government for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> United States nonproliferation and threat reduction efforts, and particularly such efforts in the independent states of the former Soviet Union; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> coordinating the implementation of United States policy with respect to such efforts.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In carrying out the responsibilities described in subsection (a), the coordination mechanism established pursuant to <ref>section 2357b of this title</ref> should have, at a minimum, the authority to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> establish such subcommittees and working groups as it deems necessary;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> direct the preparation of analyses on issues and problems relating to coordination within and among United States departments and agencies on nonproliferation and threat reduction efforts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> direct the preparation of analyses on issues and problems relating to coordination between the United States public and private sectors on nonproliferation and threat reduction efforts, including coordination between public and private spending on nonproliferation and threat reduction programs and coordination between public spending and private investment in defense conversion activities of the independent states of the former Soviet Union;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> provide guidance on arrangements that will coordinate, deconflict, and maximize the utility of United States public spending on nonproliferation and threat reduction programs, and particularly such efforts in the independent states of the former Soviet Union;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> encourage companies and nongovernmental organizations involved in nonproliferation efforts of the independent states of the former Soviet Union or other countries of concern to voluntarily report these efforts to it;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> direct the preparation of analyses on issues and problems relating to the coordination between the United States and other countries with respect to nonproliferation efforts, and particularly such efforts in the independent states of the former Soviet Union; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> consider, and make recommendations to the President with respect to, proposals for such new legislation or regulations relating to United States nonproliferation efforts as may be necessary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–228, div. B, title XIII, § 1335</ref>, <date date="2002-09-30">Sept. 30, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1450</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2357d.</num>
<heading> Administrative support</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All United States departments and agencies shall provide, to the extent permitted by law, such information and assistance as may be requested by the coordination mechanism established pursuant to <ref>section 2357b of this title</ref>, in carrying out its functions and activities under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–228, div. B, title XIII, § 1336</ref>, <date date="2002-09-30">Sept. 30, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1451</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2357e.</num>
<heading> Confidentiality of information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Information which has been submitted to or received by the coordination mechanism established pursuant to <ref>section 2357b of this title</ref> in confidence shall not be publicly disclosed, except to the extent required by law, and such information shall be used by it only for the purpose of carrying out the functions set forth in this subchapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–228, div. B, title XIII, § 1337</ref>, <date date="2002-09-30">Sept. 30, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1451</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2357f.</num>
<heading> Statutory construction</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Nothing in this subchapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> applies to the data-gathering, regulatory, or enforcement authority of any existing United States department or agency over nonproliferation efforts in the independent states of the former Soviet Union, and the review of those efforts undertaken by the coordination mechanism established pursuant to <ref>section 2357b of this title</ref> shall not in any way supersede or prejudice any other process provided by law; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> applies to any activity that is reportable pursuant to title V of the National Security Act of 1947 [<ref>50 U.S.C. 3091</ref> et seq.].</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–228, div. B, title XIII, § 1338</ref>, <date date="2002-09-30">Sept. 30, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1451</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2357g.</num>
<heading> Reporting and consultation</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Presidential report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 120 days after each inauguration of a President, the President shall submit a report to the Congress on his general and specific nonproliferation and threat reduction objectives and how the efforts of executive branch agencies will be coordinated most effectively, pursuant to <ref>section 2357b of this title</ref>, to achieve those objectives.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President should consult with and brief, from time to time, the appropriate committees of Congress regarding the efficacy of the coordination mechanism established pursuant to <ref>section 2357b of this title</ref> in achieving its stated objectives.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–228, div. B, title XIII, § 1339</ref>, <date date="2002-09-30">Sept. 30, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1451</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER V—</num>
<heading>MISCELLANEOUS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2361.</num>
<heading> Sense of Congress concerning contracting policy</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the sense of Congress that the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Energy, the Secretary of the Treasury, and the Secretary of State, to the extent authorized by law, should—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> contract directly with suppliers in independent states of the former Soviet Union when such action would—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> result in significant savings of the programs referred to in subchapter III; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> substantially expedite completion of the programs referred to in subchapter III; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> seek means to use innovative contracting approaches to avoid delay and increase the effectiveness of such programs and of the exercise of such authorities.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XIV, § 1451</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2730</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2362.</num>
<heading> Transfers of allocations among cooperative threat reduction programs</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Congress finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the various Cooperative Threat Reduction programs are being carried out at different rates in the various countries covered by such programs; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> it is necessary to authorize transfers of funding allocations among the various programs in order to maximize the effectiveness of United States efforts under such programs.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XIV, § 1452</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2730</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2363.</num>
<heading> Sense of Congress concerning assistance to states of former Soviet Union</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the sense of Congress that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Cooperative Threat Reduction programs and other United States programs authorized in title XIV of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1993 (<ref>Public Law 102–484</ref>; <ref>22 U.S.C. 5901</ref> et seq.) should be expanded by offering assistance under those programs to other independent states of the former Soviet Union in addition to Russia, Ukraine, Kazakstan, and Belarus; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the President should offer assistance to additional independent states of the former Soviet Union in each case in which the participation of such states would benefit national security interests of the United States by improving border controls and safeguards over materials and technology associated with weapons of mass destruction.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XIV, § 1453</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2730</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title X, § 1069(c)(4)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2136</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2364.</num>
<heading> Purchase of low-enriched uranium derived from Russian highly enriched uranium</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sense of Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is the sense of Congress that the allies of the United States and other nations should participate in efforts to ensure that stockpiles of weapons-grade nuclear material are reduced.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Actions by Secretary of State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Congress urges the Secretary of State to encourage, in consultation with the Secretary of Energy, other countries to purchase low-enriched uranium that is derived from highly enriched uranium extracted from Russian nuclear weapons.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XIV, § 1454</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2730</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2365.</num>
<heading> Sense of Congress concerning purchase, packaging, and transportation of fissile materials at risk of theft</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the sense of Congress that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Energy, the Secretary of the Treasury, and the Secretary of State should purchase, package, and transport to secure locations weapons-grade nuclear materials from a stockpile of such materials if such officials determine that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> there is a significant risk of theft of such materials; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> there is no reasonable and economically feasible alternative for securing such materials; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> if it is necessary to do so in order to secure the materials, the materials should be imported into the United States, subject to the laws and regulations that are applicable to the importation of such materials into the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XIV, § 1455</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2731</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2366.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title X, § 1065(c)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1943</ref>, and <ref>Pub. L. 112–277, title III, § 310(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-14">Jan. 14, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 2474</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2367.</num>
<heading> Reports on acquisition of technology relating to weapons of mass destruction and the threat posed by weapons of mass destruction, ballistic missiles, and cruise missiles</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than January 30 of each year, the Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Director of National Intelligence, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The threats posed to the United States and allies of the United States—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> by weapons of mass destruction, ballistic missiles, and cruise missiles; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> by the proliferation of weapons of mass destruction, ballistic missiles, and cruise missiles.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The acquisition by foreign countries during the preceding 12 months of dual-use and other technology useful for the development or production of weapons of mass destruction (including nuclear weapons, chemical weapons, and biological weapons) and advanced conventional munitions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Any trends with respect to the acquisition described in paragraph (2).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Matters included</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each report submitted under subsection (a) shall include the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Identification of each foreign country and non-State organization that possesses weapons of mass destruction, ballistic missiles, or cruise missiles, and a description of such weapons and missiles with respect to each such foreign country and non-State organization.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A description of the means by which any foreign country and non-State organization that has achieved, or is making progress toward achieving, capability with respect to weapons of mass destruction, ballistic missiles, or cruise missiles has achieved, or is making progress toward achieving, that capability, including a description of the international network of foreign countries and private entities that provide assistance to foreign countries and non-State organizations in achieving that capability.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> An examination of the doctrines that guide the use of weapons of mass destruction in each foreign country that possesses such weapons.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> An examination of the existence and implementation of the control mechanisms that exist with respect to nuclear weapons in each foreign country that possesses such weapons.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Identification of each foreign country and non-State organization that seeks to acquire or develop (indigenously or with foreign assistance) weapons of mass destruction, ballistic missiles, or cruise missiles, and a description of such weapons and missiles with respect to each such foreign country and non-State organization.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> An assessment of various possible timelines for the achievement by foreign countries and non-State organizations of capability with respect to weapons of mass destruction, ballistic missiles, and cruise missiles, taking into account the probability of whether foreign countries that are a party to the Missile Technology Control Regime will comply with and enforce the regime, the potential availability of assistance from foreign technical specialists, and the potential for independent sales by foreign private entities without authorization from their national governments.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> For each foreign country or non-State organization that has not achieved the capability to target the United States or its territories with weapons of mass destruction, ballistic missiles, or cruise missiles as of <date date="2013-01-02">January 2, 2013</date>, an estimate of how far in advance the United States is likely to be warned before such foreign country or non-State organization achieves that capability.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> For each foreign country or non-State organization that has not achieved the capability to target members of the Armed Forces of the United States deployed abroad with weapons of mass destruction, ballistic missiles, or cruise missiles as of <date date="2013-01-02">January 2, 2013</date>, an estimate of how far in advance the United States is likely to be warned before such foreign country or non-State organization achieves that capability.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Classification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each report submitted under subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appropriate congressional committees defined</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section, the term “appropriate congressional committees” means the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The congressional defense committees.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The congressional intelligence committees (as defined in <ref>section 3003 of this title</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Speaker and the minority leader of the House of Representatives and the majority leader and the minority leader of the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title II, § 234</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1664</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title X, § 1065(a)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1941</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2368.</num>
<heading> Annual reports on the proliferation of missiles and essential components of nuclear, biological, chemical, and radiological weapons</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than <date date="2003-03-01">March 1, 2003</date>, and annually thereafter, the President shall transmit to the designated congressional committees an annual report on the transfer by any country of weapons, technology, components, or materials that can be used to deliver, manufacture (including research and experimentation), or weaponize nuclear, biological, chemical or radiological weapons (in this section referred to as “NBC weapons”) to any country other than a country referred to in subsection (d) that is seeking to possess or otherwise acquire such weapons, technology, or materials, or other system that the Secretary or the Secretary of Defense has reason to believe could be used to develop, acquire, or deliver NBC weapons.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Matters to be included</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each such report shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the transfer of all aircraft, cruise missiles, artillery weapons, unguided rockets and multiple rocket systems, and related bombs, shells, warheads and other weaponization technology and materials that the Secretary or the Secretary of Defense has reason to believe may be intended for the delivery of NBC weapons;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> international transfers of MTCR equipment or technology to any country that is seeking to acquire such equipment or any other system that the Secretary or the Secretary of Defense has reason to believe may be used to deliver NBC weapons; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the transfer of technology, test equipment, radioactive materials, feedstocks and cultures, and all other specialized materials that the Secretary or the Secretary of Defense has reason to believe could be used to manufacture NBC weapons.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Content of report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each such report shall include the following with respect to preceding <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002057">1</ref> calendar year:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The status of missile, aircraft, and other NBC weapons delivery and weaponization programs in any such country, including efforts by such country or by any subnational group to acquire MTCR-controlled equipment, NBC-capable aircraft, or any other weapon or major weapon component which may be utilized in the delivery of NBC weapons, whose primary use is the delivery of NBC weapons, or that the Secretary or the Secretary of Defense has reason to believe could be used to deliver NBC weapons.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The status of NBC weapons development, acquisition, manufacture, stockpiling, and deployment programs in any such country, including efforts by such country or by any subnational group to acquire essential test equipment, manufacturing equipment and technology, weaponization equipment and technology, and radioactive material, feedstocks or components of feedstocks, and biological cultures and toxins.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> A description of assistance provided by any person or government, after <date date="2002-09-30">September 30, 2002</date>, to any such country or subnational group in the acquisition or development of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> NBC weapons;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> missile systems, as defined in the MTCR or that the Secretary or the Secretary of Defense has reason to believe may be used to deliver NBC weapons; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> aircraft and other delivery systems and weapons that the Secretary or the Secretary of Defense has reason to believe could be used to deliver NBC weapons.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> A listing of those persons and countries that continue to provide such equipment or technology described in paragraph (3) to any country or subnational group as of the date of submission of the report, including the extent to which foreign persons and countries were found to have knowingly and materially assisted such programs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> A description of the use of, or substantial preparations to use, the equipment of technology described in paragraph (3) by any foreign country or subnational group.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> A description of the diplomatic measures that the United States, and that other adherents to the MTCR and other arrangements affecting the acquisition and delivery of NBC weapons, have made with respect to activities and private persons and governments suspected of violating the MTCR and such other arrangements.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> An analysis of the effectiveness of the regulatory and enforcement regimes of the United States and other countries that adhere to the MTCR and other arrangements affecting the acquisition and delivery of NBC weapons in controlling the export of MTCR and other NBC weapons and delivery system equipment or technology.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> A summary of advisory opinions issued under <ref>section 4612(b)(4) of this title</ref> and under <ref>section 2797b(d) of title 22</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> An explanation of United States policy regarding the transfer of MTCR equipment or technology to foreign missile programs, including programs involving launches of space vehicles.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> A description of each transfer by any person or government during the preceding 12-month period which is subject to sanctions under the Iran-Iraq Arms Non-Proliferation Act of 1992 (title XVI of <ref>Public Law 102–484</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exclusions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The countries excluded under subsection (a) are Australia, Belgium, Canada, the Czech Republic, Denmark, France, Germany, Greece, Hungary, Iceland, Italy, Japan, Luxembourg, the Netherlands, New Zealand, Norway, Poland, Portugal, Spain, Turkey, the United Kingdom, and the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Classification of report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall make every effort to submit all of the information required by this section in unclassified form. Whenever the Secretary submits any such information in classified form, the Secretary shall submit such classified information in an addendum and shall also submit concurrently a detailed summary, in unclassified form, of that classified information.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Designated congressional committees</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “designated congressional committees” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Committee on Appropriations, the Committee on Armed Services, and the Committee on International Relations of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Committee on Appropriations, the Committee on Armed Services, and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Missile; MTCR; MTCR equipment or technology</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The terms “missile”, “MTCR”, and “MTCR equipment or technology” have the meanings given those terms in <ref>section 2797c of title 22</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Person</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “person” means any United States or foreign individual, partnership, corporation, or other form of association, or any of its successor entities, parents, or subsidiaries.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Weaponize; weaponization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “weaponize” or “weaponization” means to incorporate into, or the incorporation into, usable ordnance or other militarily useful means of delivery.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–228, div. B, title XIII, § 1308</ref>, <date date="2002-09-30">Sept. 30, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1439</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2369.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title X, § 1055(f)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2462</ref>, as amended by <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title X, § 1075(d)(13)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4373</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2370.</num>
<heading> Notification of Committees on Armed Services with respect to certain nonproliferation and proliferation activities</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification with respect to nonproliferation activities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Energy, the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of State, and the Nuclear Regulatory Commission shall keep the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives informed with respect to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any activities undertaken by any such Secretary or the Commission to carry out the purposes and policies of the Secretaries and the Commission with respect to nonproliferation programs; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any other activities undertaken by any such Secretary or the Commission to prevent the proliferation of nuclear, chemical, or biological weapons or the means of delivery of such weapons.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification with respect to proliferation activities in foreign nations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Director of National Intelligence shall keep the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives fully and currently informed with respect to any activities of foreign nations that are significant with respect to the proliferation of nuclear, chemical, or biological weapons or the means of delivery of such weapons.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fully and currently informed defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of paragraph (1), the term “fully and currently informed” means the transmittal of credible information with respect to an activity described in such paragraph not later than 60 days after becoming aware of the activity.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title X, § 1062, <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4614</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2371.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 114–113, div. M, title VII, § 701(d)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-18">Dec. 18, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 2930</ref></heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>