<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 11—</num>
<heading>REORGANIZATION</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>OFFICERS AND ADMINISTRATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1101.</num>
<heading> Definitions for this chapter</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “debtor in possession” means debtor except when a person that has qualified under <ref>section 322 of this title</ref> is serving as trustee in the case;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> “substantial consummation” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> transfer of all or substantially all of the property proposed by the plan to be transferred;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> assumption by the debtor or by the successor to the debtor under the plan of the business or of the management of all or substantially all of the property dealt with by the plan; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> commencement of distribution under the plan.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2626</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1102.</num>
<heading> Creditors’ and equity security holders’ committees</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraph (3), as soon as practicable after the order for relief under chapter 11 of this title, the United States trustee shall appoint a committee of creditors holding unsecured claims and may appoint additional committees of creditors or of equity security holders as the United States trustee deems appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> On request of a party in interest, the court may order the appointment of additional committees of creditors or of equity security holders if necessary to assure adequate representation of creditors or of equity security holders. The United States trustee shall appoint any such committee.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Unless the court for cause orders otherwise, a committee of creditors may not be appointed in a small business case or a case under subchapter V of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> On request of a party in interest and after notice and a hearing, the court may order the United States trustee to change the membership of a committee appointed under this subsection, if the court determines that the change is necessary to ensure adequate representation of creditors or equity security holders. The court may order the United States trustee to increase the number of members of a committee to include a creditor that is a small business concern (as described in section 3(a)(1) of the Small Business Act), if the court determines that the creditor holds claims (of the kind represented by the committee) the aggregate amount of which, in comparison to the annual gross revenue of that creditor, is disproportionately large.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A committee of creditors appointed under subsection (a) of this section shall ordinarily consist of the persons, willing to serve, that hold the seven largest claims against the debtor of the kinds represented on such committee, or of the members of a committee organized by creditors before the commencement of the case under this chapter, if such committee was fairly chosen and is representative of the different kinds of claims to be represented.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A committee of equity security holders appointed under subsection (a)(2) of this section shall ordinarily consist of the persons, willing to serve, that hold the seven largest amounts of equity securities of the debtor of the kinds represented on such committee.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> A committee appointed under subsection (a) shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> provide access to information for creditors who—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> hold claims of the kind represented by that committee; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> are not appointed to the committee;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> solicit and receive comments from the creditors described in subparagraph (A); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> be subject to a court order that compels any additional report or disclosure to be made to the creditors described in subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2626</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–353, title III, § 499</ref>, <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 384</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–554, title II, § 221</ref>, <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3101</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–394, title II, § 217(b)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-22">Oct. 22, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4127</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–8, title IV</ref>, §§ 405, 432(b), <date date="2005-04-20">Apr. 20, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 105</ref>, 110; <ref>Pub. L. 116–54, § 4(a)(11)</ref>, <date date="2019-08-23">Aug. 23, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1086</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1103.</num>
<heading> Powers and duties of committees</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> At a scheduled meeting of a committee appointed under <ref>section 1102 of this title</ref>, at which a majority of the members of such committee are present, and with the court’s approval, such committee may select and authorize the employment by such committee of one or more attorneys, accountants, or other agents, to represent or perform services for such committee.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> An attorney or accountant employed to represent a committee appointed under <ref>section 1102 of this title</ref> may not, while employed by such committee, represent any other entity having an adverse interest in connection with the case. Representation of one or more creditors of the same class as represented by the committee shall not per se constitute the representation of an adverse interest.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> A committee appointed under <ref>section 1102 of this title</ref> may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> consult with the trustee or debtor in possession concerning the administration of the case;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> investigate the acts, conduct, assets, liabilities, and financial condition of the debtor, the operation of the debtor’s business and the desirability of the continuance of such business, and any other matter relevant to the case or to the formulation of a plan;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> participate in the formulation of a plan, advise those represented by such committee of such committee’s determinations as to any plan formulated, and collect and file with the court acceptances or rejections of a plan;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> request the appointment of a trustee or examiner under <ref>section 1104 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> perform such other services as are in the interest of those represented.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> As soon as practicable after the appointment of a committee under <ref>section 1102 of this title</ref>, the trustee shall meet with such committee to transact such business as may be necessary and proper.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2627</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–353, title III</ref>, §§ 324, 500, <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 358</ref>, 384.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1104.</num>
<heading> Appointment of trustee or examiner</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> At any time after the commencement of the case but before confirmation of a plan, on request of a party in interest or the United States trustee, and after notice and a hearing, the court shall order the appointment of a trustee—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> for cause, including fraud, dishonesty, incompetence, or gross mismanagement of the affairs of the debtor by current management, either before or after the commencement of the case, or similar cause, but not including the number of holders of securities of the debtor or the amount of assets or liabilities of the debtor; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> if such appointment is in the interests of creditors, any equity security holders, and other interests of the estate, without regard to the number of holders of securities of the debtor or the amount of assets or liabilities of the debtor.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in <ref>section 1163 of this title</ref>, on the request of a party in interest made not later than 30 days after the court orders the appointment of a trustee under subsection (a), the United States trustee shall convene a meeting of creditors for the purpose of electing one disinterested person to serve as trustee in the case. The election of a trustee shall be conducted in the manner provided in subsections (a), (b), and (c) of <ref>section 702 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> If an eligible, disinterested trustee is elected at a meeting of creditors under paragraph (1), the United States trustee shall file a report certifying that election.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> Upon the filing of a report under subparagraph (A)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the trustee elected under paragraph (1) shall be considered to have been selected and appointed for purposes of this section; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the service of any trustee appointed under subsection (a) shall terminate.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The court shall resolve any dispute arising out of an election described in subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> If the court does not order the appointment of a trustee under this section, then at any time before the confirmation of a plan, on request of a party in interest or the United States trustee, and after notice and a hearing, the court shall order the appointment of an examiner to conduct such an investigation of the debtor as is appropriate, including an investigation of any allegations of fraud, dishonesty, incompetence, misconduct, mismanagement, or irregularity in the management of the affairs of the debtor of or by current or former management of the debtor, if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> such appointment is in the interests of creditors, any equity security holders, and other interests of the estate; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the debtor’s fixed, liquidated, unsecured debts, other than debts for goods, services, or taxes, or owing to an insider, exceed $5,000,000.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> If the court orders the appointment of a trustee or an examiner, if a trustee or an examiner dies or resigns during the case or is removed under <ref>section 324 of this title</ref>, or if a trustee fails to qualify under <ref>section 322 of this title</ref>, then the United States trustee, after consultation with parties in interest, shall appoint, subject to the court’s approval, one disinterested person other than the United States trustee to serve as trustee or examiner, as the case may be, in the case.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> The United States trustee shall move for the appointment of a trustee under subsection (a) if there are reasonable grounds to suspect that current members of the governing body of the debtor, the debtor’s chief executive or chief financial officer, or members of the governing body who selected the debtor’s chief executive or chief financial officer, participated in actual fraud, dishonesty, or criminal conduct in the management of the debtor or the debtor’s public financial reporting.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2627</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–554, title II, § 222</ref>, <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3102</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–394, title II, § 211(a)</ref>, title V, § 501(d)(30), <date date="1994-10-22">Oct. 22, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4125</ref>, 4146; <ref>Pub. L. 109–8, title IV</ref>, §§ 416, 442(b), title XIV, § 1405, <date date="2005-04-20">Apr. 20, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 107</ref>, 116, 215; <ref>Pub. L. 111–327, § 2(a)(30)</ref>, <date date="2010-12-22">Dec. 22, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3560</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1105.</num>
<heading> Termination of trustee’s appointment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">At any time before confirmation of a plan, on request of a party in interest or the United States trustee, and after notice and a hearing, the court may terminate the trustee’s appointment and restore the debtor to possession and management of the property of the estate and of the operation of the debtor’s business.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2628</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–353, title III, § 501</ref>, <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 384</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–554, title II, § 223</ref>, <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3102</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1106.</num>
<heading> Duties of trustee and examiner</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> A trustee shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> perform the duties of the trustee, as specified in paragraphs (2), (5), (7), (8), (9), (10), (11), and (12) of section 704(a);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> if the debtor has not done so, file the list, schedule, and statement required under <ref>section 521(a)(1) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> except to the extent that the court orders otherwise, investigate the acts, conduct, assets, liabilities, and financial condition of the debtor, the operation of the debtor’s business and the desirability of the continuance of such business, and any other matter relevant to the case or to the formulation of a plan;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> as soon as practicable—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> file a statement of any investigation conducted under paragraph (3) of this subsection, including any fact ascertained pertaining to fraud, dishonesty, incompetence, misconduct, mismanagement, or irregularity in the management of the affairs of the debtor, or to a cause of action available to the estate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> transmit a copy or a summary of any such statement to any creditors’ committee or equity security holders’ committee, to any indenture trustee, and to such other entity as the court designates;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> as soon as practicable, file a plan under <ref>section 1121 of this title</ref>, file a report of why the trustee will not file a plan, or recommend conversion of the case to a case under chapter 7, 12, or 13 of this title or dismissal of the case;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> for any year for which the debtor has not filed a tax return required by law, furnish, without personal liability, such information as may be required by the governmental unit with which such tax return was to be filed, in light of the condition of the debtor’s books and records and the availability of such information;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> after confirmation of a plan, file such reports as are necessary or as the court orders; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> if with respect to the debtor there is a claim for a domestic support obligation, provide the applicable notice specified in subsection (c).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> An examiner appointed under <ref>section 1104(d) of this title</ref> shall perform the duties specified in paragraphs (3) and (4) of subsection (a) of this section, and, except to the extent that the court orders otherwise, any other duties of the trustee that the court orders the debtor in possession not to perform.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> In a case described in subsection (a)(8) to which subsection (a)(8) applies, the trustee shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> provide written notice to the holder of the claim described in subsection (a)(8) of such claim and of the right of such holder to use the services of the State child support enforcement agency established under sections 464 and 466 of the Social Security Act for the State in which such holder resides, for assistance in collecting child support during and after the case under this title; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> include in the notice required by clause (i) the address and telephone number of such State child support enforcement agency;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> provide written notice to such State child support enforcement agency of such claim; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> include in the notice required by clause (i) the name, address, and telephone number of such holder; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> at such time as the debtor is granted a discharge under section 1141, provide written notice to such holder and to such State child support enforcement agency of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the granting of the discharge;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the last recent known address of the debtor;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the last recent known name and address of the debtor’s employer; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<chapeau> the name of each creditor that holds a claim that—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> is not discharged under paragraph (2), (4), or (14A) of section 523(a); or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> was reaffirmed by the debtor under section 524(c).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The holder of a claim described in subsection (a)(8) or the State child enforcement support agency of the State in which such holder resides may request from a creditor described in paragraph (1)(C)(iv) the last known address of the debtor.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a creditor that makes a disclosure of a last known address of a debtor in connection with a request made under subparagraph (A) shall not be liable by reason of making such disclosure.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2628</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–353, title III</ref>, §§ 311(b)(1), 502, <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 355</ref>, 384; <ref>Pub. L. 99–554, title II, § 257(c)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3114</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–394, title II, § 211(b)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-22">Oct. 22, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4125</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–8, title II, § 219(b)</ref>, title IV, § 446(c), title XI, § 1105(b), <date date="2005-04-20">Apr. 20, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 56</ref>, 118, 192; <ref>Pub. L. 111–327, § 2(a)(31)</ref>, <date date="2010-12-22">Dec. 22, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3560</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1107.</num>
<heading> Rights, powers, and duties of debtor in possession</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Subject to any limitations on a trustee serving in a case under this chapter, and to such limitations or conditions as the court prescribes, a debtor in possession shall have all the rights, other than the right to compensation under <ref>section 330 of this title</ref>, and powers, and shall perform all the functions and duties, except the duties specified in sections 1106(a)(2), (3), and (4) of this title, of a trustee serving in a case under this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding <ref>section 327(a) of this title</ref>, a person is not disqualified for employment under <ref>section 327 of this title</ref> by a debtor in possession solely because of such person’s employment by or representation of the debtor before the commencement of the case.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2628</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–353, title III, § 503</ref>, <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 384</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1108.</num>
<heading> Authorization to operate business</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Unless the court, on request of a party in interest and after notice and a hearing, orders otherwise, the trustee may operate the debtor’s business.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2629</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–353, title III, § 504</ref>, <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 384</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1109.</num>
<heading> Right to be heard</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Securities and Exchange Commission may raise and may appear and be heard on any issue in a case under this chapter, but the Securities and Exchange Commission may not appeal from any judgment, order, or decree entered in the case.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> A party in interest, including the debtor, the trustee, a creditors’ committee, an equity security holders’ committee, a creditor, an equity security holder, or any indenture trustee, may raise and may appear and be heard on any issue in a case under this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2629</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1110.</num>
<heading> Aircraft equipment and vessels</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraph (2) and subject to subsection (b), the right of a secured party with a security interest in equipment described in paragraph (3), or of a lessor or conditional vendor of such equipment, to take possession of such equipment in compliance with a security agreement, lease, or conditional sale contract, and to enforce any of its other rights or remedies, under such security agreement, lease, or conditional sale contract, to sell, lease, or otherwise retain or dispose of such equipment, is not limited or otherwise affected by any other provision of this title or by any power of the court.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The right to take possession and to enforce the other rights and remedies described in paragraph (1) shall be subject to section 362 if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> before the date that is 60 days after the date of the order for relief under this chapter, the trustee, subject to the approval of the court, agrees to perform all obligations of the debtor under such security agreement, lease, or conditional sale contract; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> any default, other than a default of a kind specified in section 365(b)(2), under such security agreement, lease, or conditional sale contract—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> that occurs before the date of the order is cured before the expiration of such 60-day period;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> that occurs after the date of the order and before the expiration of such 60-day period is cured before the later of—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the date that is 30 days after the date of the default; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the expiration of such 60-day period; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> that occurs on or after the expiration of such 60-day period is cured in compliance with the terms of such security agreement, lease, or conditional sale contract, if a cure is permitted under that agreement, lease, or contract.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The equipment described in this paragraph—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> is—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an aircraft, aircraft engine, propeller, appliance, or spare part (as defined in <ref>section 40102 of title 49</ref>) that is subject to a security interest granted by, leased to, or conditionally sold to a debtor that, at the time such transaction is entered into, holds an air carrier operating certificate issued pursuant to chapter 447 of title 49 for aircraft capable of carrying 10 or more individuals or 6,000 pounds or more of cargo; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a vessel documented under chapter 121 of title 46 that is subject to a security interest granted by, leased to, or conditionally sold to a debtor that is a water carrier that, at the time such transaction is entered into, holds a certificate of public convenience and necessity or permit issued by the Department of Transportation; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> includes all records and documents relating to such equipment that are required, under the terms of the security agreement, lease, or conditional sale contract, to be surrendered or returned by the debtor in connection with the surrender or return of such equipment.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Paragraph (1) applies to a secured party, lessor, or conditional vendor acting in its own behalf or acting as trustee or otherwise in behalf of another party.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The trustee and the secured party, lessor, or conditional vendor whose right to take possession is protected under subsection (a) may agree, subject to the approval of the court, to extend the 60-day period specified in subsection (a)(1).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In any case under this chapter, the trustee shall immediately surrender and return to a secured party, lessor, or conditional vendor, described in subsection (a)(1), equipment described in subsection (a)(3), if at any time after the date of the order for relief under this chapter such secured party, lessor, or conditional vendor is entitled pursuant to subsection (a)(1) to take possession of such equipment and makes a written demand for such possession to the trustee.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> At such time as the trustee is required under paragraph (1) to surrender and return equipment described in subsection (a)(3), any lease of such equipment, and any security agreement or conditional sale contract relating to such equipment, if such security agreement or conditional sale contract is an executory contract, shall be deemed rejected.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> With respect to equipment first placed in service on or before <date date="1994-10-22">October 22, 1994</date>, for purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “lease” includes any written agreement with respect to which the lessor and the debtor, as lessee, have expressed in the agreement or in a substantially contemporaneous writing that the agreement is to be treated as a lease for Federal income tax purposes; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “security interest” means a purchase-money equipment security interest.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2629</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 5(c)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1373</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–394, title II, § 201(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-22">Oct. 22, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4119</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–181, title VII, § 744(b)</ref>, <date date="2000-04-05">Apr. 5, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 177</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 17(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1707</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1111.</num>
<heading> Claims and interests</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> A proof of claim or interest is deemed filed under <ref>section 501 of this title</ref> for any claim or interest that appears in the schedules filed under section 521(a)(1) or 1106(a)(2) of this title, except a claim or interest that is scheduled as disputed, contingent, or unliquidated.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> A claim secured by a lien on property of the estate shall be allowed or disallowed under <ref>section 502 of this title</ref> the same as if the holder of such claim had recourse against the debtor on account of such claim, whether or not such holder has such recourse, unless—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the class of which such claim is a part elects, by at least two-thirds in amount and more than half in number of allowed claims of such class, application of paragraph (2) of this subsection; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> such holder does not have such recourse and such property is sold under <ref>section 363 of this title</ref> or is to be sold under the plan.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> A class of claims may not elect application of paragraph (2) of this subsection if—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the interest on account of such claims of the holders of such claims in such property is of inconsequential value; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the holder of a claim of such class has recourse against the debtor on account of such claim and such property is sold under <ref>section 363 of this title</ref> or is to be sold under the plan.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If such an election is made, then notwithstanding <ref>section 506(a) of this title</ref>, such claim is a secured claim to the extent that such claim is allowed.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2630</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–327, § 2(a)(32)</ref>, <date date="2010-12-22">Dec. 22, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3561</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1112.</num>
<heading> Conversion or dismissal</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The debtor may convert a case under this chapter to a case under chapter 7 of this title unless—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the debtor is not a debtor in possession;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the case originally was commenced as an involuntary case under this chapter; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the case was converted to a case under this chapter other than on the debtor’s request.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraph (2) and subsection (c), on request of a party in interest, and after notice and a hearing, the court shall convert a case under this chapter to a case under chapter 7 or dismiss a case under this chapter, whichever is in the best interests of creditors and the estate, for cause unless the court determines that the appointment under section 1104(a) of a trustee or an examiner is in the best interests of creditors and the estate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The court may not convert a case under this chapter to a case under chapter 7 or dismiss a case under this chapter if the court finds and specifically identifies unusual circumstances establishing that converting or dismissing the case is not in the best interests of creditors and the estate, and the debtor or any other party in interest establishes that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> there is a reasonable likelihood that a plan will be confirmed within the timeframes established in sections 1121(e) and 1129(e) of this title, or if such sections do not apply, within a reasonable period of time; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> the grounds for converting or dismissing the case include an act or omission of the debtor other than under paragraph (4)(A)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> for which there exists a reasonable justification for the act or omission; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> that will be cured within a reasonable period of time fixed by the court.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The court shall commence the hearing on a motion under this subsection not later than 30 days after filing of the motion, and shall decide the motion not later than 15 days after commencement of such hearing, unless the movant expressly consents to a continuance for a specific period of time or compelling circumstances prevent the court from meeting the time limits established by this paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of this subsection, the term “cause” includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> substantial or continuing loss to or diminution of the estate and the absence of a reasonable likelihood of rehabilitation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> gross mismanagement of the estate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> failure to maintain appropriate insurance that poses a risk to the estate or to the public;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> unauthorized use of cash collateral substantially harmful to 1 or more creditors;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> failure to comply with an order of the court;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> unexcused failure to satisfy timely any filing or reporting requirement established by this title or by any rule applicable to a case under this chapter;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> failure to attend the meeting of creditors convened under section 341(a) or an examination ordered under rule 2004 of the Federal Rules of Bankruptcy Procedure without good cause shown by the debtor;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> failure timely to provide information or attend meetings reasonably requested by the United States trustee (or the bankruptcy administrator, if any);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> failure timely to pay taxes owed after the date of the order for relief or to file tax returns due after the date of the order for relief;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> failure to file a disclosure statement, or to file or confirm a plan, within the time fixed by this title or by order of the court;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> failure to pay any fees or charges required under chapter 123 of title 28;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(L)</num>
<content> revocation of an order of confirmation under section 1144;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(M)</num>
<content> inability to effectuate substantial consummation of a confirmed plan;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(N)</num>
<content> material default by the debtor with respect to a confirmed plan;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(O)</num>
<content> termination of a confirmed plan by reason of the occurrence of a condition specified in the plan; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(P)</num>
<content> failure of the debtor to pay any domestic support obligation that first becomes payable after the date of the filing of the petition.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The court may not convert a case under this chapter to a case under chapter 7 of this title if the debtor is a farmer or a corporation that is not a moneyed, business, or commercial corporation, unless the debtor requests such conversion.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> The court may convert a case under this chapter to a case under chapter 12 or 13 of this title only if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the debtor requests such conversion;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the debtor has not been discharged under <ref>section 1141(d) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> if the debtor requests conversion to chapter 12 of this title, such conversion is equitable.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> Except as provided in subsections (c) and (f), the court, on request of the United States trustee, may convert a case under this chapter to a case under chapter 7 of this title or may dismiss a case under this chapter, whichever is in the best interest of creditors and the estate if the debtor in a voluntary case fails to file, within fifteen days after the filing of the petition commencing such case or such additional time as the court may allow, the information required by paragraph (1) of section 521(a), including a list containing the names and addresses of the holders of the twenty largest unsecured claims (or of all unsecured claims if there are fewer than twenty unsecured claims), and the approximate dollar amounts of each of such claims.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, a case may not be converted to a case under another chapter of this title unless the debtor may be a debtor under such chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2630</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–353, title III, § 505</ref>, <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 384</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–554, title II</ref>, §§ 224, 256, <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3102</ref>, 3114; <ref>Pub. L. 103–394, title II, § 217(c)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-22">Oct. 22, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4127</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–8, title IV, § 442(a)</ref>, <date date="2005-04-20">Apr. 20, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 115</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–327, § 2(a)(33)</ref>, <date date="2010-12-22">Dec. 22, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3561</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1113.</num>
<heading> Rejection of collective bargaining agreements</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The debtor in possession, or the trustee if one has been appointed under the provisions of this chapter, other than a trustee in a case covered by subchapter IV of this chapter and by title I of the Railway Labor Act, may assume or reject a collective bargaining agreement only in accordance with the provisions of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Subsequent to filing a petition and prior to filing an application seeking rejection of a collective bargaining agreement, the debtor in possession or trustee (hereinafter in this section “trustee” shall include a debtor in possession), shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> make a proposal to the authorized representative of the employees covered by such agreement, based on the most complete and reliable information available at the time of such proposal, which provides for those necessary modifications in the employees benefits and protections that are necessary to permit the reorganization of the debtor and assures that all creditors, the debtor and all of the affected parties are treated fairly and equitably; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provide, subject to subsection (d)(3), the representative of the employees with such relevant information as is necessary to evaluate the proposal.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> During the period beginning on the date of the making of a proposal provided for in paragraph (1) and ending on the date of the hearing provided for in subsection (d)(1), the trustee shall meet, at reasonable times, with the authorized representative to confer in good faith in attempting to reach mutually satisfactory modifications of such agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> The court shall approve an application for rejection of a collective bargaining agreement only if the court finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the trustee has, prior to the hearing, made a proposal that fulfills the requirements of subsection (b)(1);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the authorized representative of the employees has refused to accept such proposal without good cause; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the balance of the equities clearly favors rejection of such agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Upon the filing of an application for rejection the court shall schedule a hearing to be held not later than fourteen days after the date of the filing of such application. All interested parties may appear and be heard at such hearing. Adequate notice shall be provided to such parties at least ten days before the date of such hearing. The court may extend the time for the commencement of such hearing for a period not exceeding seven days where the circumstances of the case, and the interests of justice require such extension, or for additional periods of time to which the trustee and representative agree.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The court shall rule on such application for rejection within thirty days after the date of the commencement of the hearing. In the interests of justice, the court may extend such time for ruling for such additional period as the trustee and the employees’ representative may agree to. If the court does not rule on such application within thirty days after the date of the commencement of the hearing, or within such additional time as the trustee and the employees’ representative may agree to, the trustee may terminate or alter any provisions of the collective bargaining agreement pending the ruling of the court on such application.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The court may enter such protective orders, consistent with the need of the authorized representative of the employee to evaluate the trustee’s proposal and the application for rejection, as may be necessary to prevent disclosure of information provided to such representative where such disclosure could compromise the position of the debtor with respect to its competitors in the industry in which it is engaged.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> If during a period when the collective bargaining agreement continues in effect, and if essential to the continuation of the debtor’s business, or in order to avoid irreparable damage to the estate, the court, after notice and a hearing, may authorize the trustee to implement interim changes in the terms, conditions, wages, benefits, or work rules provided by a collective bargaining agreement. Any hearing under this paragraph shall be scheduled in accordance with the needs of the trustee. The implementation of such interim changes shall not render the application for rejection moot.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> No provision of this title shall be construed to permit a trustee to unilaterally terminate or alter any provisions of a collective bargaining agreement prior to compliance with the provisions of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 98–353, title III, § 541(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 390</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1114.</num>
<heading> Payment of insurance benefits to retired employees</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> For purposes of this section, the term “retiree benefits” means payments to any entity or person for the purpose of providing or reimbursing payments for retired employees and their spouses and dependents, for medical, surgical, or hospital care benefits, or benefits in the event of sickness, accident, disability, or death under any plan, fund, or program (through the purchase of insurance or otherwise) maintained or established in whole or in part by the debtor prior to filing a petition commencing a case under this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> For purposes of this section, the term “authorized representative” means the authorized representative designated pursuant to subsection (c) for persons receiving any retiree benefits covered by a collective bargaining agreement or subsection (d) in the case of persons receiving retiree benefits not covered by such an agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Committees of retired employees appointed by the court pursuant to this section shall have the same rights, powers, and duties as committees appointed under sections 1102 and 1103 of this title for the purpose of carrying out the purposes of sections 1114 and 1129(a)(13) and, as permitted by the court, shall have the power to enforce the rights of persons under this title as they relate to retiree benefits.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A labor organization shall be, for purposes of this section, the authorized representative of those persons receiving any retiree benefits covered by any collective bargaining agreement to which that labor organization is signatory, unless (A) such labor organization elects not to serve as the authorized representative of such persons, or (B) the court, upon a motion by any party in interest, after notice and hearing, determines that different representation of such persons is appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In cases where the labor organization referred to in paragraph (1) elects not to serve as the authorized representative of those persons receiving any retiree benefits covered by any collective bargaining agreement to which that labor organization is signatory, or in cases where the court, pursuant to paragraph (1) finds different representation of such persons appropriate, the court, upon a motion by any party in interest, and after notice and a hearing, shall appoint a committee of retired employees if the debtor seeks to modify or not pay the retiree benefits or if the court otherwise determines that it is appropriate, from among such persons, to serve as the authorized representative of such persons under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The court, upon a motion by any party in interest, and after notice and a hearing, shall order the appointment of a committee of retired employees if the debtor seeks to modify or not pay the retiree benefits or if the court otherwise determines that it is appropriate, to serve as the authorized representative, under this section, of those persons receiving any retiree benefits not covered by a collective bargaining agreement. The United States trustee shall appoint any such committee.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Notwithstanding any other provision of this title, the debtor in possession, or the trustee if one has been appointed under the provisions of this chapter (hereinafter in this section “trustee” shall include a debtor in possession), shall timely pay and shall not modify any retiree benefits, except that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the court, on motion of the trustee or authorized representative, and after notice and a hearing, may order modification of such payments, pursuant to the provisions of subsections (g) and (h) of this section, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the trustee and the authorized representative of the recipients of those benefits may agree to modification of such payments,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">after which such benefits as modified shall continue to be paid by the trustee.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any payment for retiree benefits required to be made before a plan confirmed under <ref>section 1129 of this title</ref> is effective has the status of an allowed administrative expense as provided in <ref>section 503 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Subsequent to filing a petition and prior to filing an application seeking modification of the retiree benefits, the trustee shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> make a proposal to the authorized representative of the retirees, based on the most complete and reliable information available at the time of such proposal, which provides for those necessary modifications in the retiree benefits that are necessary to permit the reorganization of the debtor and assures that all creditors, the debtor and all of the affected parties are treated fairly and equitably; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provide, subject to subsection (k)(3), the representative of the retirees with such relevant information as is necessary to evaluate the proposal.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> During the period beginning on the date of the making of a proposal provided for in paragraph (1), and ending on the date of the hearing provided for in subsection (k)(1), the trustee shall meet, at reasonable times, with the authorized representative to confer in good faith in attempting to reach mutually satisfactory modifications of such retiree benefits.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<chapeau> The court shall enter an order providing for modification in the payment of retiree benefits if the court finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the trustee has, prior to the hearing, made a proposal that fulfills the requirements of subsection (f);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the authorized representative of the retirees has refused to accept such proposal without good cause; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> such modification is necessary to permit the reorganization of the debtor and assures that all creditors, the debtor, and all of the affected parties are treated fairly and equitably, and is clearly favored by the balance of the equities;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">except that in no case shall the court enter an order providing for such modification which provides for a modification to a level lower than that proposed by the trustee in the proposal found by the court to have complied with the requirements of this subsection and subsection (f): <i>Provided, however</i>, That at any time after an order is entered providing for modification in the payment of retiree benefits, or at any time after an agreement modifying such benefits is made between the trustee and the authorized representative of the recipients of such benefits, the authorized representative may apply to the court for an order increasing those benefits which order shall be granted if the increase in retiree benefits sought is consistent with the standard set forth in paragraph (3): <i>Provided further</i>, That neither the trustee nor the authorized representative is precluded from making more than one motion for a modification order governed by this subsection.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Prior to a court issuing a final order under subsection (g) of this section, if essential to the continuation of the debtor’s business, or in order to avoid irreparable damage to the estate, the court, after notice and a hearing, may authorize the trustee to implement interim modifications in retiree benefits.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any hearing under this subsection shall be scheduled in accordance with the needs of the trustee.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The implementation of such interim changes does not render the motion for modification moot.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> No retiree benefits paid between the filing of the petition and the time a plan confirmed under <ref>section 1129 of this title</ref> becomes effective shall be deducted or offset from the amounts allowed as claims for any benefits which remain unpaid, or from the amounts to be paid under the plan with respect to such claims for unpaid benefits, whether such claims for unpaid benefits are based upon or arise from a right to future unpaid benefits or from any benefits not paid as a result of modifications allowed pursuant to this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<content> No claim for retiree benefits shall be limited by <ref>section 502(b)(7) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(k)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Upon the filing of an application for modifying retiree benefits, the court shall schedule a hearing to be held not later than fourteen days after the date of the filing of such application. All interested parties may appear and be heard at such hearing. Adequate notice shall be provided to such parties at least ten days before the date of such hearing. The court may extend the time for the commencement of such hearing for a period not exceeding seven days where the circumstances of the case, and the interests of justice require such extension, or for additional periods of time to which the trustee and the authorized representative agree.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The court shall rule on such application for modification within ninety days after the date of the commencement of the hearing. In the interests of justice, the court may extend such time for ruling for such additional period as the trustee and the authorized representative may agree to. If the court does not rule on such application within ninety days after the date of the commencement of the hearing, or within such additional time as the trustee and the authorized representative may agree to, the trustee may implement the proposed modifications pending the ruling of the court on such application.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The court may enter such protective orders, consistent with the need of the authorized representative of the retirees to evaluate the trustee’s proposal and the application for modification, as may be necessary to prevent disclosure of information provided to such representative where such disclosure could compromise the position of the debtor with respect to its competitors in the industry in which it is engaged.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(l)</num>
<chapeau> If the debtor, during the 180-day period ending on the date of the filing of the petition—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> modified retiree benefits; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> was insolvent on the date such benefits were modified;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">the court, on motion of a party in interest, and after notice and a hearing, shall issue an order reinstating as of the date the modification was made, such benefits as in effect immediately before such date unless the court finds that the balance of the equities clearly favors such modification.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(m)</num>
<content> This section shall not apply to any retiree, or the spouse or dependents of such retiree, if such retiree’s gross income for the twelve months preceding the filing of the bankruptcy petition equals or exceeds $250,000, unless such retiree can demonstrate to the satisfaction of the court that he is unable to obtain health, medical, life, and disability coverage for himself, his spouse, and his dependents who would otherwise be covered by the employer’s insurance plan, comparable to the coverage provided by the employer on the day before the filing of a petition under this title.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–334, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-06-16">June 16, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 610</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 109–8, title IV, § 447</ref>, title XIV, § 1403, <date date="2005-04-20">Apr. 20, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 118</ref>, 215.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1115.</num>
<heading> Property of the estate</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> In a case in which the debtor is an individual, property of the estate includes, in addition to the property specified in section 541—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> all property of the kind specified in section 541 that the debtor acquires after the commencement of the case but before the case is closed, dismissed, or converted to a case under chapter 7, 12, or 13, whichever occurs first; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> earnings from services performed by the debtor after the commencement of the case but before the case is closed, dismissed, or converted to a case under chapter 7, 12, or 13, whichever occurs first.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Except as provided in section 1104 or a confirmed plan or order confirming a plan, the debtor shall remain in possession of all property of the estate.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–8, title III, § 321(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2005-04-20">Apr. 20, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 94</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1116.</num>
<heading> Duties of trustee or debtor in possession in small business cases</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In a small business case, a trustee or the debtor in possession, in addition to the duties provided in this title and as otherwise required by law, shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> append to the voluntary petition or, in an involuntary case, file not later than 7 days after the date of the order for relief—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> its most recent balance sheet, statement of operations, cash-flow statement, and Federal income tax return; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a statement made under penalty of perjury that no balance sheet, statement of operations, or cash-flow statement has been prepared and no Federal tax return has been filed;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> attend, through its senior management personnel and counsel, meetings scheduled by the court or the United States trustee, including initial debtor interviews, scheduling conferences, and meetings of creditors convened under section 341 unless the court, after notice and a hearing, waives that requirement upon a finding of extraordinary and compelling circumstances;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> timely file all schedules and statements of financial affairs, unless the court, after notice and a hearing, grants an extension, which shall not extend such time period to a date later than 30 days after the date of the order for relief, absent extraordinary and compelling circumstances;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> file all postpetition financial and other reports required by the Federal Rules of Bankruptcy Procedure or by local rule of the district court;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> subject to section 363(c)(2), maintain insurance customary and appropriate to the industry;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> timely file tax returns and other required government filings; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> subject to section 363(c)(2), timely pay all taxes entitled to administrative expense priority except those being contested by appropriate proceedings being diligently prosecuted; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> allow the United States trustee, or a designated representative of the United States trustee, to inspect the debtor’s business premises, books, and records at reasonable times, after reasonable prior written notice, unless notice is waived by the debtor.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–8, title IV, § 436(a)</ref>, <date date="2005-04-20">Apr. 20, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 112</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>THE PLAN</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1121.</num>
<heading> Who may file a plan</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The debtor may file a plan with a petition commencing a voluntary case, or at any time in a voluntary case or an involuntary case.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Except as otherwise provided in this section, only the debtor may file a plan until after 120 days after the date of the order for relief under this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> Any party in interest, including the debtor, the trustee, a creditors’ committee, an equity security holders’ committee, a creditor, an equity security holder, or any indenture trustee, may file a plan if and only if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a trustee has been appointed under this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the debtor has not filed a plan before 120 days after the date of the order for relief under this chapter; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the debtor has not filed a plan that has been accepted, before 180 days after the date of the order for relief under this chapter, by each class of claims or interests that is impaired under the plan.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Subject to paragraph (2), on request of a party in interest made within the respective periods specified in subsections (b) and (c) of this section and after notice and a hearing, the court may for cause reduce or increase the 120-day period or the 180-day period referred to in this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The 120-day period specified in paragraph (1) may not be extended beyond a date that is 18 months after the date of the order for relief under this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The 180-day period specified in paragraph (1) may not be extended beyond a date that is 20 months after the date of the order for relief under this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<chapeau> In a small business case—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> only the debtor may file a plan until after 180 days after the date of the order for relief, unless that period is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> extended as provided by this subsection, after notice and a hearing; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the court, for cause, orders otherwise;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the plan and a disclosure statement (if any) shall be filed not later than 300 days after the date of the order for relief; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> the time periods specified in paragraphs (1) and (2), and the time fixed in section 1129(e) within which the plan shall be confirmed, may be extended only if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the debtor, after providing notice to parties in interest (including the United States trustee), demonstrates by a preponderance of the evidence that it is more likely than not that the court will confirm a plan within a reasonable period of time;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a new deadline is imposed at the time the extension is granted; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the order extending time is signed before the existing deadline has expired.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2631</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–353, title III, § 506</ref>, <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 385</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–554, title II, § 283(u)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3118</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–394, title II, § 217(d)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-22">Oct. 22, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4127</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–8, title IV</ref>, §§ 411, 437, <date date="2005-04-20">Apr. 20, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 106</ref>, 113.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1122.</num>
<heading> Classification of claims or interests</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, a plan may place a claim or an interest in a particular class only if such claim or interest is substantially similar to the other claims or interests of such class.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> A plan may designate a separate class of claims consisting only of every unsecured claim that is less than or reduced to an amount that the court approves as reasonable and necessary for administrative convenience.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2631</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1123.</num>
<heading> Contents of plan</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Notwithstanding any otherwise applicable nonbankruptcy law, a plan shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> designate, subject to <ref>section 1122 of this title</ref>, classes of claims, other than claims of a kind specified in section 507(a)(2), 507(a)(3), or 507(a)(8) of this title, and classes of interests;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> specify any class of claims or interests that is not impaired under the plan;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> specify the treatment of any class of claims or interests that is impaired under the plan;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> provide the same treatment for each claim or interest of a particular class, unless the holder of a particular claim or interest agrees to a less favorable treatment of such particular claim or interest;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> provide adequate means for the plan’s implementation, such as—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> retention by the debtor of all or any part of the property of the estate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> transfer of all or any part of the property of the estate to one or more entities, whether organized before or after the confirmation of such plan;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> merger or consolidation of the debtor with one or more persons;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> sale of all or any part of the property of the estate, either subject to or free of any lien, or the distribution of all or any part of the property of the estate among those having an interest in such property of the estate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> satisfaction or modification of any lien;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> cancellation or modification of any indenture or similar instrument;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> curing or waiving of any default;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> extension of a maturity date or a change in an interest rate or other term of outstanding securities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> amendment of the debtor’s charter; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> issuance of securities of the debtor, or of any entity referred to in subparagraph (B) or (C) of this paragraph, for cash, for property, for existing securities, or in exchange for claims or interests, or for any other appropriate purpose;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> provide for the inclusion in the charter of the debtor, if the debtor is a corporation, or of any corporation referred to in paragraph (5)(B) or (5)(C) of this subsection, of a provision prohibiting the issuance of nonvoting equity securities, and providing, as to the several classes of securities possessing voting power, an appropriate distribution of such power among such classes, including, in the case of any class of equity securities having a preference over another class of equity securities with respect to dividends, adequate provisions for the election of directors representing such preferred class in the event of default in the payment of such dividends;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> contain only provisions that are consistent with the interests of creditors and equity security holders and with public policy with respect to the manner of selection of any officer, director, or trustee under the plan and any successor to such officer, director, or trustee; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> in a case in which the debtor is an individual, provide for the payment to creditors under the plan of all or such portion of earnings from personal services performed by the debtor after the commencement of the case or other future income of the debtor as is necessary for the execution of the plan.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Subject to subsection (a) of this section, a plan may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> impair or leave unimpaired any class of claims, secured or unsecured, or of interests;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> subject to <ref>section 365 of this title</ref>, provide for the assumption, rejection, or assignment of any executory contract or unexpired lease of the debtor not previously rejected under such section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> provide for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the settlement or adjustment of any claim or interest belonging to the debtor or to the estate; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the retention and enforcement by the debtor, by the trustee, or by a representative of the estate appointed for such purpose, of any such claim or interest;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> provide for the sale of all or substantially all of the property of the estate, and the distribution of the proceeds of such sale among holders of claims or interests;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> modify the rights of holders of secured claims, other than a claim secured only by a security interest in real property that is the debtor’s principal residence, or of holders of unsecured claims, or leave unaffected the rights of holders of any class of claims; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> include any other appropriate provision not inconsistent with the applicable provisions of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> In a case concerning an individual, a plan proposed by an entity other than the debtor may not provide for the use, sale, or lease of property exempted under <ref>section 522 of this title</ref>, unless the debtor consents to such use, sale, or lease.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding subsection (a) of this section and sections 506(b), 1129(a)(7), and 1129(b) of this title, if it is proposed in a plan to cure a default the amount necessary to cure the default shall be determined in accordance with the underlying agreement and applicable nonbankruptcy law.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2631</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–353, title III, § 507</ref>, <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 385</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–394, title II, § 206</ref>, title III, §§ 304(h)(6), 305(a), title V, § 501(d)(31), <date date="1994-10-22">Oct. 22, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4123</ref>, 4134, 4146; <ref>Pub. L. 109–8, title III, § 321(b)</ref>, title XV, § 1502(a)(7), <date date="2005-04-20">Apr. 20, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 95</ref>, 216.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1124.</num>
<heading> Impairment of claims or interests</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except as provided in <ref>section 1123(a)(4) of this title</ref>, a class of claims or interests is impaired under a plan unless, with respect to each claim or interest of such class, the plan—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> leaves unaltered the legal, equitable, and contractual rights to which such claim or interest entitles the holder of such claim or interest; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> notwithstanding any contractual provision or applicable law that entitles the holder of such claim or interest to demand or receive accelerated payment of such claim or interest after the occurrence of a default—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> cures any such default that occurred before or after the commencement of the case under this title, other than a default of a kind specified in <ref>section 365(b)(2) of this title</ref> or of a kind that section 365(b)(2) expressly does not require to be cured;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> reinstates the maturity of such claim or interest as such maturity existed before such default;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> compensates the holder of such claim or interest for any damages incurred as a result of any reasonable reliance by such holder on such contractual provision or such applicable law;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> if such claim or such interest arises from any failure to perform a nonmonetary obligation, other than a default arising from failure to operate a nonresidential real property lease subject to section 365(b)(1)(A), compensates the holder of such claim or such interest (other than the debtor or an insider) for any actual pecuniary loss incurred by such holder as a result of such failure; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> does not otherwise alter the legal, equitable, or contractual rights to which such claim or interest entitles the holder of such claim or interest.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2633</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–353, title III, § 508</ref>, <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 385</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–394, title II, § 213(d)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-22">Oct. 22, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4126</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–8, title III, § 328(b)</ref>, <date date="2005-04-20">Apr. 20, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 100</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1125.</num>
<heading> Postpetition disclosure and solicitation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> In this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “adequate information” means information of a kind, and in sufficient detail, as far as is reasonably practicable in light of the nature and history of the debtor and the condition of the debtor’s books and records, including a discussion of the potential material Federal tax consequences of the plan to the debtor, any successor to the debtor, and a hypothetical investor typical of the holders of claims or interests in the case, that would enable such a hypothetical investor of the relevant class to make an informed judgment about the plan, but adequate information need not include such information about any other possible or proposed plan and in determining whether a disclosure statement provides adequate information, the court shall consider the complexity of the case, the benefit of additional information to creditors and other parties in interest, and the cost of providing additional information; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> “investor typical of holders of claims or interests of the relevant class” means investor having—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a claim or interest of the relevant class;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> such a relationship with the debtor as the holders of other claims or interests of such class generally have; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> such ability to obtain such information from sources other than the disclosure required by this section as holders of claims or interests in such class generally have.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> An acceptance or rejection of a plan may not be solicited after the commencement of the case under this title from a holder of a claim or interest with respect to such claim or interest, unless, at the time of or before such solicitation, there is transmitted to such holder the plan or a summary of the plan, and a written disclosure statement approved, after notice and a hearing, by the court as containing adequate information. The court may approve a disclosure statement without a valuation of the debtor or an appraisal of the debtor’s assets.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The same disclosure statement shall be transmitted to each holder of a claim or interest of a particular class, but there may be transmitted different disclosure statements, differing in amount, detail, or kind of information, as between classes.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Whether a disclosure statement required under subsection (b) of this section contains adequate information is not governed by any otherwise applicable nonbankruptcy law, rule, or regulation, but an agency or official whose duty is to administer or enforce such a law, rule, or regulation may be heard on the issue of whether a disclosure statement contains adequate information. Such an agency or official may not appeal from, or otherwise seek review of, an order approving a disclosure statement.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> A person that solicits acceptance or rejection of a plan, in good faith and in compliance with the applicable provisions of this title, or that participates, in good faith and in compliance with the applicable provisions of this title, in the offer, issuance, sale, or purchase of a security, offered or sold under the plan, of the debtor, of an affiliate participating in a joint plan with the debtor, or of a newly organized successor to the debtor under the plan, is not liable, on account of such solicitation or participation, for violation of any applicable law, rule, or regulation governing solicitation of acceptance or rejection of a plan or the offer, issuance, sale, or purchase of securities.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<chapeau> Notwithstanding subsection (b), in a small business case—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the court may determine that the plan itself provides adequate information and that a separate disclosure statement is not necessary;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the court may approve a disclosure statement submitted on standard forms approved by the court or adopted under <ref>section 2075 of title 28</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the court may conditionally approve a disclosure statement subject to final approval after notice and a hearing;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> acceptances and rejections of a plan may be solicited based on a conditionally approved disclosure statement if the debtor provides adequate information to each holder of a claim or interest that is solicited, but a conditionally approved disclosure statement shall be mailed not later than 25 days before the date of the hearing on confirmation of the plan; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the hearing on the disclosure statement may be combined with the hearing on confirmation of a plan.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding subsection (b), an acceptance or rejection of the plan may be solicited from a holder of a claim or interest if such solicitation complies with applicable nonbankruptcy law and if such holder was solicited before the commencement of the case in a manner complying with applicable nonbankruptcy law.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2633</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–353, title III, § 509</ref>, <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 385</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–394, title II, § 217(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-22">Oct. 22, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4127</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–8, title IV</ref>, §§ 408, 431, title VII, § 717, <date date="2005-04-20">Apr. 20, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 106</ref>, 109, 131.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1126.</num>
<heading> Acceptance of plan</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The holder of a claim or interest allowed under <ref>section 502 of this title</ref> may accept or reject a plan. If the United States is a creditor or equity security holder, the Secretary of the Treasury may accept or reject the plan on behalf of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> For the purposes of subsections (c) and (d) of this section, a holder of a claim or interest that has accepted or rejected the plan before the commencement of the case under this title is deemed to have accepted or rejected such plan, as the case may be, if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the solicitation of such acceptance or rejection was in compliance with any applicable nonbankruptcy law, rule, or regulation governing the adequacy of disclosure in connection with such solicitation; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> if there is not any such law, rule, or regulation, such acceptance or rejection was solicited after disclosure to such holder of adequate information, as defined in <ref>section 1125(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> A class of claims has accepted a plan if such plan has been accepted by creditors, other than any entity designated under subsection (e) of this section, that hold at least two-thirds in amount and more than one-half in number of the allowed claims of such class held by creditors, other than any entity designated under subsection (e) of this section, that have accepted or rejected such plan.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> A class of interests has accepted a plan if such plan has been accepted by holders of such interests, other than any entity designated under subsection (e) of this section, that hold at least two-thirds in amount of the allowed interests of such class held by holders of such interests, other than any entity designated under subsection (e) of this section, that have accepted or rejected such plan.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> On request of a party in interest, and after notice and a hearing, the court may designate any entity whose acceptance or rejection of such plan was not in good faith, or was not solicited or procured in good faith or in accordance with the provisions of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, a class that is not impaired under a plan, and each holder of a claim or interest of such class, are conclusively presumed to have accepted the plan, and solicitation of acceptances with respect to such class from the holders of claims or interests of such class is not required.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, a class is deemed not to have accepted a plan if such plan provides that the claims or interests of such class do not entitle the holders of such claims or interests to receive or retain any property under the plan on account of such claims or interests.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2634</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–353, title III, § 510</ref>, <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 386</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1127.</num>
<heading> Modification of plan</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The proponent of a plan may modify such plan at any time before confirmation, but may not modify such plan so that such plan as modified fails to meet the requirements of sections 1122 and 1123 of this title. After the proponent of a plan files a modification of such plan with the court, the plan as modified becomes the plan.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The proponent of a plan or the reorganized debtor may modify such plan at any time after confirmation of such plan and before substantial consummation of such plan, but may not modify such plan so that such plan as modified fails to meet the requirements of sections 1122 and 1123 of this title. Such plan as modified under this subsection becomes the plan only if circumstances warrant such modification and the court, after notice and a hearing, confirms such plan as modified, under <ref>section 1129 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The proponent of a modification shall comply with <ref>section 1125 of this title</ref> with respect to the plan as modified.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Any holder of a claim or interest that has accepted or rejected a plan is deemed to have accepted or rejected, as the case may be, such plan as modified, unless, within the time fixed by the court, such holder changes such holder’s previous acceptance or rejection.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<chapeau> If the debtor is an individual, the plan may be modified at any time after confirmation of the plan but before the completion of payments under the plan, whether or not the plan has been substantially consummated, upon request of the debtor, the trustee, the United States trustee, or the holder of an allowed unsecured claim, to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> increase or reduce the amount of payments on claims of a particular class provided for by the plan;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> extend or reduce the time period for such payments; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> alter the amount of the distribution to a creditor whose claim is provided for by the plan to the extent necessary to take account of any payment of such claim made other than under the plan.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Sections 1121 through 1128 and the requirements of section 1129 apply to any modification under subsection (e).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The plan, as modified, shall become the plan only after there has been disclosure under section 1125 as the court may direct, notice and a hearing, and such modification is approved.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2635</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–353, title III, § 511</ref>, <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 386</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–8, title III, § 321(e)</ref>, <date date="2005-04-20">Apr. 20, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 96</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–327, § 2(a)(34)</ref>, <date date="2010-12-22">Dec. 22, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3561</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1128.</num>
<heading> Confirmation hearing</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> After notice, the court shall hold a hearing on confirmation of a plan.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> A party in interest may object to confirmation of a plan.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2635</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1129.</num>
<heading> Confirmation of plan</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The court shall confirm a plan only if all of the following requirements are met:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The plan complies with the applicable provisions of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The proponent of the plan complies with the applicable provisions of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The plan has been proposed in good faith and not by any means forbidden by law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Any payment made or to be made by the proponent, by the debtor, or by a person issuing securities or acquiring property under the plan, for services or for costs and expenses in or in connection with the case, or in connection with the plan and incident to the case, has been approved by, or is subject to the approval of, the court as reasonable.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The proponent of the plan has disclosed the identity and affiliations of any individual proposed to serve, after confirmation of the plan, as a director, officer, or voting trustee of the debtor, an affiliate of the debtor participating in a joint plan with the debtor, or a successor to the debtor under the plan; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the appointment to, or continuance in, such office of such individual, is consistent with the interests of creditors and equity security holders and with public policy; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the proponent of the plan has disclosed the identity of any insider that will be employed or retained by the reorganized debtor, and the nature of any compensation for such insider.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Any governmental regulatory commission with jurisdiction, after confirmation of the plan, over the rates of the debtor has approved any rate change provided for in the plan, or such rate change is expressly conditioned on such approval.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<chapeau> With respect to each impaired class of claims or interests—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> each holder of a claim or interest of such class—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> has accepted the plan; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> will receive or retain under the plan on account of such claim or interest property of a value, as of the effective date of the plan, that is not less than the amount that such holder would so receive or retain if the debtor were liquidated under chapter 7 of this title on such date; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> if <ref>section 1111(b)(2) of this title</ref> applies to the claims of such class, each holder of a claim of such class will receive or retain under the plan on account of such claim property of a value, as of the effective date of the plan, that is not less than the value of such holder’s interest in the estate’s interest in the property that secures such claims.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<chapeau> With respect to each class of claims or interests—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> such class has accepted the plan; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> such class is not impaired under the plan.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<chapeau> Except to the extent that the holder of a particular claim has agreed to a different treatment of such claim, the plan provides that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> with respect to a claim of a kind specified in section 507(a)(2) or 507(a)(3) of this title, on the effective date of the plan, the holder of such claim will receive on account of such claim cash equal to the allowed amount of such claim;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> with respect to a class of claims of a kind specified in section 507(a)(1), 507(a)(4), 507(a)(5), 507(a)(6), or 507(a)(7) of this title, each holder of a claim of such class will receive—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> if such class has accepted the plan, deferred cash payments of a value, as of the effective date of the plan, equal to the allowed amount of such claim; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> if such class has not accepted the plan, cash on the effective date of the plan equal to the allowed amount of such claim;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> with respect to a claim of a kind specified in <ref>section 507(a)(8) of this title</ref>, the holder of such claim will receive on account of such claim regular installment payments in cash—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> of a total value, as of the effective date of the plan, equal to the allowed amount of such claim;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> over a period ending not later than 5 years after the date of the order for relief under section 301, 302, or 303; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> in a manner not less favorable than the most favored nonpriority unsecured claim provided for by the plan (other than cash payments made to a class of creditors under section 1122(b)); and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> with respect to a secured claim which would otherwise meet the description of an unsecured claim of a governmental unit under section 507(a)(8), but for the secured status of that claim, the holder of that claim will receive on account of that claim, cash payments, in the same manner and over the same period, as prescribed in subparagraph (C).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> If a class of claims is impaired under the plan, at least one class of claims that is impaired under the plan has accepted the plan, determined without including any acceptance of the plan by any insider.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> Confirmation of the plan is not likely to be followed by the liquidation, or the need for further financial reorganization, of the debtor or any successor to the debtor under the plan, unless such liquidation or reorganization is proposed in the plan.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> All fees payable under <ref>section 1930 of title 28</ref>, as determined by the court at the hearing on confirmation of the plan, have been paid or the plan provides for the payment of all such fees on the effective date of the plan.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> The plan provides for the continuation after its effective date of payment of all retiree benefits, as that term is defined in <ref>section 1114 of this title</ref>, at the level established pursuant to subsection (e)(1)(B) or (g) of <ref>section 1114 of this title</ref>, at any time prior to confirmation of the plan, for the duration of the period the debtor has obligated itself to provide such benefits.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> If the debtor is required by a judicial or administrative order, or by statute, to pay a domestic support obligation, the debtor has paid all amounts payable under such order or such statute for such obligation that first become payable after the date of the filing of the petition.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<chapeau> In a case in which the debtor is an individual and in which the holder of an allowed unsecured claim objects to the confirmation of the plan—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the value, as of the effective date of the plan, of the property to be distributed under the plan on account of such claim is not less than the amount of such claim; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the value of the property to be distributed under the plan is not less than the projected disposable income of the debtor (as defined in section 1325(b)(2)) to be received during the 5-year period beginning on the date that the first payment is due under the plan, or during the period for which the plan provides payments, whichever is longer.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(16)</num>
<content> All transfers of property under the plan shall be made in accordance with any applicable provisions of nonbankruptcy law that govern the transfer of property by a corporation or trust that is not a moneyed, business, or commercial corporation or trust.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding <ref>section 510(a) of this title</ref>, if all of the applicable requirements of subsection (a) of this section other than paragraph (8) are met with respect to a plan, the court, on request of the proponent of the plan, shall confirm the plan notwithstanding the requirements of such paragraph if the plan does not discriminate unfairly, and is fair and equitable, with respect to each class of claims or interests that is impaired under, and has not accepted, the plan.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> For the purpose of this subsection, the condition that a plan be fair and equitable with respect to a class includes the following requirements:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> With respect to a class of secured claims, the plan provides—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> that the holders of such claims retain the liens securing such claims, whether the property subject to such liens is retained by the debtor or transferred to another entity, to the extent of the allowed amount of such claims; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> that each holder of a claim of such class receive on account of such claim deferred cash payments totaling at least the allowed amount of such claim, of a value, as of the effective date of the plan, of at least the value of such holder’s interest in the estate’s interest in such property;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> for the sale, subject to <ref>section 363(k) of this title</ref>, of any property that is subject to the liens securing such claims, free and clear of such liens, with such liens to attach to the proceeds of such sale, and the treatment of such liens on proceeds under clause (i) or (iii) of this subparagraph; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> for the realization by such holders of the indubitable equivalent of such claims.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> With respect to a class of unsecured claims—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the plan provides that each holder of a claim of such class receive or retain on account of such claim property of a value, as of the effective date of the plan, equal to the allowed amount of such claim; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the holder of any claim or interest that is junior to the claims of such class will not receive or retain under the plan on account of such junior claim or interest any property, except that in a case in which the debtor is an individual, the debtor may retain property included in the estate under section 1115, subject to the requirements of subsection (a)(14) of this section.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> With respect to a class of interests—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the plan provides that each holder of an interest of such class receive or retain on account of such interest property of a value, as of the effective date of the plan, equal to the greatest of the allowed amount of any fixed liquidation preference to which such holder is entitled, any fixed redemption price to which such holder is entitled, or the value of such interest; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the holder of any interest that is junior to the interests of such class will not receive or retain under the plan on account of such junior interest any property.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding subsections (a) and (b) of this section and except as provided in <ref>section 1127(b) of this title</ref>, the court may confirm only one plan, unless the order of confirmation in the case has been revoked under <ref>section 1144 of this title</ref>. If the requirements of subsections (a) and (b) of this section are met with respect to more than one plan, the court shall consider the preferences of creditors and equity security holders in determining which plan to confirm.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, on request of a party in interest that is a governmental unit, the court may not confirm a plan if the principal purpose of the plan is the avoidance of taxes or the avoidance of the application of section 5 of the Securities Act of 1933. In any hearing under this subsection, the governmental unit has the burden of proof on the issue of avoidance.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> In a small business case, the court shall confirm a plan that complies with the applicable provisions of this title and that is filed in accordance with section 1121(e) not later than 45 days after the plan is filed unless the time for confirmation is extended in accordance with section 1121(e)(3).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2635</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–353, title III, § 512</ref>, <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 386</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–554, title II</ref>, §§ 225, 283(v), <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3102</ref>, 3118; <ref>Pub. L. 100–334, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="1988-06-16">June 16, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 613</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–394, title III, § 304(h)(7)</ref>, title V, § 501(d)(32), <date date="1994-10-22">Oct. 22, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4134</ref>, 4146; <ref>Pub. L. 109–8, title II, § 213(1)</ref>, title III, § 321(c), title IV, § 438, title VII, § 710, title XII, § 1221(b), title XV, § 1502(a)(8), <date date="2005-04-20">Apr. 20, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 52</ref>, 95, 113, 127, 196, 216; <ref>Pub. L. 111–327, § 2(a)(35)</ref>, <date date="2010-12-22">Dec. 22, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3561</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>POSTCONFIRMATION MATTERS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1141.</num>
<heading> Effect of confirmation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Except as provided in subsections (d)(2) and (d)(3) of this section, the provisions of a confirmed plan bind the debtor, any entity issuing securities under the plan, any entity acquiring property under the plan, and any creditor, equity security holder, or general partner in the debtor, whether or not the claim or interest of such creditor, equity security holder, or general partner is impaired under the plan and whether or not such creditor, equity security holder, or general partner has accepted the plan.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Except as otherwise provided in the plan or the order confirming the plan, the confirmation of a plan vests all of the property of the estate in the debtor.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Except as provided in subsections (d)(2) and (d)(3) of this section and except as otherwise provided in the plan or in the order confirming the plan, after confirmation of a plan, the property dealt with by the plan is free and clear of all claims and interests of creditors, equity security holders, and of general partners in the debtor.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, in the plan, or in the order confirming the plan, the confirmation of a plan—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> discharges the debtor from any debt that arose before the date of such confirmation, and any debt of a kind specified in section 502(g), 502(h), or 502(i) of this title, whether or not—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a proof of the claim based on such debt is filed or deemed filed under <ref>section 501 of this title</ref>;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> such claim is allowed under <ref>section 502 of this title</ref>; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the holder of such claim has accepted the plan; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> terminates all rights and interests of equity security holders and general partners provided for by the plan.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A discharge under this chapter does not discharge a debtor who is an individual from any debt excepted from discharge under <ref>section 523 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The confirmation of a plan does not discharge a debtor if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the plan provides for the liquidation of all or substantially all of the property of the estate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the debtor does not engage in business after consummation of the plan; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the debtor would be denied a discharge under <ref>section 727(a) of this title</ref> if the case were a case under chapter 7 of this title.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The court may approve a written waiver of discharge executed by the debtor after the order for relief under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> In a case in which the debtor is an individual—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> unless after notice and a hearing the court orders otherwise for cause, confirmation of the plan does not discharge any debt provided for in the plan until the court grants a discharge on completion of all payments under the plan;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> at any time after the confirmation of the plan, and after notice and a hearing, the court may grant a discharge to the debtor who has not completed payments under the plan if—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the value, as of the effective date of the plan, of property actually distributed under the plan on account of each allowed unsecured claim is not less than the amount that would have been paid on such claim if the estate of the debtor had been liquidated under chapter 7 on such date;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> modification of the plan under section 1127 is not practicable; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> subparagraph (C) permits the court to grant a discharge; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> the court may grant a discharge if, after notice and a hearing held not more than 10 days before the date of the entry of the order granting the discharge, the court finds that there is no reasonable cause to believe that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> section 522(q)(1) may be applicable to the debtor; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> there is pending any proceeding in which the debtor may be found guilty of a felony of the kind described in section 522(q)(1)(A) or liable for a debt of the kind described in section 522(q)(1)(B);</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">and if the requirements of subparagraph (A) or (B) are met.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> Notwithstanding paragraph (1), the confirmation of a plan does not discharge a debtor that is a corporation from any debt—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> of a kind specified in paragraph (2)(A) or (2)(B) of section 523(a) that is owed to a domestic governmental unit, or owed to a person as the result of an action filed under subchapter III of chapter 37 of title 31 or any similar State statute; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> for a tax or customs duty with respect to which the debtor—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> made a fraudulent return; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> willfully attempted in any manner to evade or to defeat such tax or such customs duty.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2638</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–353, title III, § 513</ref>, <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 387</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–8, title III</ref>, §§ 321(d), 330(b), title VII, § 708, <date date="2005-04-20">Apr. 20, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 95</ref>, 101, 126; <ref>Pub. L. 111–327, § 2(a)(36)</ref>, <date date="2010-12-22">Dec. 22, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3561</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1142.</num>
<heading> Implementation of plan</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any otherwise applicable nonbankruptcy law, rule, or regulation relating to financial condition, the debtor and any entity organized or to be organized for the purpose of carrying out the plan shall carry out the plan and shall comply with any orders of the court.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The court may direct the debtor and any other necessary party to execute or deliver or to join in the execution or delivery of any instrument required to effect a transfer of property dealt with by a confirmed plan, and to perform any other act, including the satisfaction of any lien, that is necessary for the consummation of the plan.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2639</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–353, title III, § 514(a)</ref>, (c), (d), <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 387</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1143.</num>
<heading> Distribution</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If a plan requires presentment or surrender of a security or the performance of any other act as a condition to participation in distribution under the plan, such action shall be taken not later than five years after the date of the entry of the order of confirmation. Any entity that has not within such time presented or surrendered such entity’s security or taken any such other action that the plan requires may not participate in distribution under the plan.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2639</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1144.</num>
<heading> Revocation of an order of confirmation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">On request of a party in interest at any time before 180 days after the date of the entry of the order of confirmation, and after notice and a hearing, the court may revoke such order if and only if such order was procured by fraud. An order under this section revoking an order of confirmation shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> contain such provisions as are necessary to protect any entity acquiring rights in good faith reliance on the order of confirmation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> revoke the discharge of the debtor.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2639</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–353, title III, § 515</ref>, <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 387</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1145.</num>
<heading> Exemption from securities laws</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Except with respect to an entity that is an underwriter as defined in subsection (b) of this section, section 5 of the Securities Act of 1933 and any State or local law requiring registration for offer or sale of a security or registration or licensing of an issuer of, underwriter of, or broker or dealer in, a security do not apply to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the offer or sale under a plan of a security of the debtor, of an affiliate participating in a joint plan with the debtor, or of a successor to the debtor under the plan—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in exchange for a claim against, an interest in, or a claim for an administrative expense in the case concerning, the debtor or such affiliate; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> principally in such exchange and partly for cash or property;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the offer of a security through any warrant, option, right to subscribe, or conversion privilege that was sold in the manner specified in paragraph (1) of this subsection, or the sale of a security upon the exercise of such a warrant, option, right, or privilege;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> the offer or sale, other than under a plan, of a security of an issuer other than the debtor or an affiliate, if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> such security was owned by the debtor on the date of the filing of the petition;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> the issuer of such security is—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> required to file reports under section 13 or 15(d) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in compliance with the disclosure and reporting provision of such applicable section; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> such offer or sale is of securities that do not exceed—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> during the two-year period immediately following the date of the filing of the petition, four percent of the securities of such class outstanding on such date; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> during any 180-day period following such two-year period, one percent of the securities outstanding at the beginning of such 180-day period; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> a transaction by a stockbroker in a security that is executed after a transaction of a kind specified in paragraph (1) or (2) of this subsection in such security and before the expiration of 40 days after the first date on which such security was bona fide offered to the public by the issuer or by or through an underwriter, if such stockbroker provides, at the time of or before such transaction by such stockbroker, a disclosure statement approved under <ref>section 1125 of this title</ref>, and, if the court orders, information supplementing such disclosure statement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection and except with respect to ordinary trading transactions of an entity that is not an issuer, an entity is an underwriter under section 2(a)(11) of the Securities Act of 1933, if such entity—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> purchases a claim against, interest in, or claim for an administrative expense in the case concerning, the debtor, if such purchase is with a view to distribution of any security received or to be received in exchange for such a claim or interest;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> offers to sell securities offered or sold under the plan for the holders of such securities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> offers to buy securities offered or sold under the plan from the holders of such securities, if such offer to buy is—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> with a view to distribution of such securities; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> under an agreement made in connection with the plan, with the consummation of the plan, or with the offer or sale of securities under the plan; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> is an issuer, as used in such section 2(a)(11), with respect to such securities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> An entity is not an underwriter under section 2(a)(11) of the Securities Act of 1933 or under paragraph (1) of this subsection with respect to an agreement that provides only for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the matching or combining of fractional interests in securities offered or sold under the plan into whole interests; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the purchase or sale of such fractional interests from or to entities receiving such fractional interests under the plan; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the purchase or sale for such entities of such fractional or whole interests as are necessary to adjust for any remaining fractional interests after such matching.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> An entity other than an entity of the kind specified in paragraph (1) of this subsection is not an underwriter under section 2(a)(11) of the Securities Act of 1933 with respect to any securities offered or sold to such entity in the manner specified in subsection (a)(1) of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> An offer or sale of securities of the kind and in the manner specified under subsection (a)(1) of this section is deemed to be a public offering.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The Trust Indenture Act of 1939 does not apply to a note issued under the plan that matures not later than one year after the effective date of the plan.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2639</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–353, title III, § 516</ref>, <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 387</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–394, title V, § 501(d)(33)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-22">Oct. 22, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4146</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–327, § 2(a)(37)</ref>, <date date="2010-12-22">Dec. 22, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3561</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1146.</num>
<heading> Special tax provisions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The issuance, transfer, or exchange of a security, or the making or delivery of an instrument of transfer under a plan confirmed under section 1129 or 1191 of this title, may not be taxed under any law imposing a stamp tax or similar tax.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> The court may authorize the proponent of a plan to request a determination, limited to questions of law, by a State or local governmental unit charged with responsibility for collection or determination of a tax on or measured by income, of the tax effects, under <ref>section 346 of this title</ref> and under the law imposing such tax, of the plan. In the event of an actual controversy, the court may declare such effects after the earlier of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the date on which such governmental unit responds to the request under this subsection; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> 270 days after such request.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2641</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–353, title III, § 517</ref>, <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 388</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–8, title VII, § 719(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="2005-04-20">Apr. 20, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 133</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–54, § 4(a)(12)</ref>, <date date="2019-08-23">Aug. 23, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1086</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>RAILROAD REORGANIZATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1161.</num>
<heading> Inapplicability of other sections</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Sections 341, 343, 1102(a)(1), 1104, 1105, 1107, 1129(a)(7), and 1129(c) of this title do not apply in a case concerning a railroad.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2641</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1162.</num>
<heading> Definition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this subchapter, “Board” means the “Surface Transportation Board”.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title III, § 302(1)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 943</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1163.</num>
<heading> Appointment of trustee</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As soon as practicable after the order for relief the Secretary of Transportation shall submit a list of five disinterested persons that are qualified and willing to serve as trustees in the case. The United States trustee shall appoint one of such persons to serve as trustee in the case.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2641</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–554, title II, § 226</ref>, <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3102</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1164.</num>
<heading> Right to be heard</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Board, the Department of Transportation, and any State or local commission having regulatory jurisdiction over the debtor may raise and may appear and be heard on any issue in a case under this chapter, but may not appeal from any judgment, order, or decree entered in the case.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2641</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title III, § 302(2)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 943</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1165.</num>
<heading> Protection of the public interest</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In applying sections 1166, 1167, 1169, 1170, 1171, 1172, 1173, and 1174 of this title, the court and the trustee shall consider the public interest in addition to the interests of the debtor, creditors, and equity security holders.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2641</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1166.</num>
<heading> Effect of subtitle IV of title 49 and of Federal, State, or local regulations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except with respect to abandonment under <ref>section 1170 of this title</ref>, or merger, modification of the financial structure of the debtor, or issuance or sale of securities under a plan, the trustee and the debtor are subject to the provisions of subtitle IV of title 49 that are applicable to railroads, and the trustee is subject to orders of any Federal, State, or local regulatory body to the same extent as the debtor would be if a petition commencing the case under this chapter had not been filed, but—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any such order that would require the expenditure, or the incurring of an obligation for the expenditure, of money from the estate is not effective unless approved by the court; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the provisions of this chapter are subject to section 601(b) of the Regional Rail Reorganization Act of 1973.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2642</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–449, § 5(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1983-01-12">Jan. 12, 1983</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2442</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–353, title III, § 518</ref>, <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 388</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–394, title V, § 501(d)(34)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-22">Oct. 22, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4146</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1167.</num>
<heading> Collective bargaining agreements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding <ref>section 365 of this title</ref>, neither the court nor the trustee may change the wages or working conditions of employees of the debtor established by a collective bargaining agreement that is subject to the Railway Labor Act except in accordance with section 6 of such Act.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2642</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–394, title V, § 501(d)(35)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-22">Oct. 22, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4146</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1168.</num>
<heading> Rolling stock equipment</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The right of a secured party with a security interest in or of a lessor or conditional vendor of equipment described in paragraph (2) to take possession of such equipment in compliance with an equipment security agreement, lease, or conditional sale contract, and to enforce any of its other rights or remedies under such security agreement, lease, or conditional sale contract, to sell, lease, or otherwise retain or dispose of such equipment, is not limited or otherwise affected by any other provision of this title or by any power of the court, except that right to take possession and enforce those other rights and remedies shall be subject to section 362, if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> before the date that is 60 days after the date of commencement of a case under this chapter, the trustee, subject to the court’s approval, agrees to perform all obligations of the debtor under such security agreement, lease, or conditional sale contract; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> any default, other than a default of a kind described in section 365(b)(2), under such security agreement, lease, or conditional sale contract—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> that occurs before the date of commencement of the case and is an event of default therewith is cured before the expiration of such 60-day period;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> that occurs or becomes an event of default after the date of commencement of the case and before the expiration of such 60-day period is cured before the later of—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the date that is 30 days after the date of the default or event of the default; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the expiration of such 60-day period; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> that occurs on or after the expiration of such 60-day period is cured in accordance with the terms of such security agreement, lease, or conditional sale contract, if cure is permitted under that agreement, lease, or conditional sale contract.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The equipment described in this paragraph—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is rolling stock equipment or accessories used on rolling stock equipment, including superstructures or racks, that is subject to a security interest granted by, leased to, or conditionally sold to a debtor; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> includes all records and documents relating to such equipment that are required, under the terms of the security agreement, lease, or conditional sale contract, that is to be surrendered or returned by the debtor in connection with the surrender or return of such equipment.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Paragraph (1) applies to a secured party, lessor, or conditional vendor acting in its own behalf or acting as trustee or otherwise in behalf of another party.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The trustee and the secured party, lessor, or conditional vendor whose right to take possession is protected under subsection (a) may agree, subject to the court’s approval, to extend the 60-day period specified in subsection (a)(1).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In any case under this chapter, the trustee shall immediately surrender and return to a secured party, lessor, or conditional vendor, described in subsection (a)(1), equipment described in subsection (a)(2), if at any time after the date of commencement of the case under this chapter such secured party, lessor, or conditional vendor is entitled pursuant to subsection (a)(1) to take possession of such equipment and makes a written demand for such possession of the trustee.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> At such time as the trustee is required under paragraph (1) to surrender and return equipment described in subsection (a)(2), any lease of such equipment, and any security agreement or conditional sale contract relating to such equipment, if such security agreement or conditional sale contract is an executory contract, shall be deemed rejected.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> With respect to equipment first placed in service on or prior to <date date="1994-10-22">October 22, 1994</date>, for purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “lease” includes any written agreement with respect to which the lessor and the debtor, as lessee, have expressed in the agreement or in a substantially contemporaneous writing that the agreement is to be treated as a lease for Federal income tax purposes; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “security interest” means a purchase-money equipment security interest.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> With respect to equipment first placed in service after <date date="1994-10-22">October 22, 1994</date>, for purposes of this section, the term “rolling stock equipment” includes rolling stock equipment that is substantially rebuilt and accessories used on such equipment.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2642</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–353, title III, § 519</ref>, <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 388</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–394, title II, § 201(b)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-22">Oct. 22, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4120</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–181, title VII, § 744(a)</ref>, <date date="2000-04-05">Apr. 5, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 175</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1169.</num>
<heading> Effect of rejection of lease of railroad line</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, if a lease of a line of railroad under which the debtor is the lessee is rejected under <ref>section 365 of this title</ref>, and if the trustee, within such time as the court fixes, and with the court’s approval, elects not to operate the leased line, the lessor under such lease, after such approval, shall operate the line.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> If operation of such line by such lessor is impracticable or contrary to the public interest, the court, on request of such lessor, and after notice and a hearing, shall order the trustee to continue operation of such line for the account of such lessor until abandonment is ordered under <ref>section 1170 of this title</ref>, or until such operation is otherwise lawfully terminated, whichever occurs first.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> During any such operation, such lessor is deemed a carrier subject to the provisions of subtitle IV of title 49 that are applicable to railroads.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2643</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–449, § 5(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1983-01-12">Jan. 12, 1983</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2442</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–353, title III, § 520</ref>, <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 388</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1170.</num>
<heading> Abandonment of railroad line</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The court, after notice and a hearing, may authorize the abandonment of all or a portion of a railroad line if such abandonment is—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the best interest of the estate; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> essential to the formulation of a plan; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> consistent with the public interest.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> If, except for the pendency of the case under this chapter, such abandonment would require approval by the Board under a law of the United States, the trustee shall initiate an appropriate application for such abandonment with the Board. The court may fix a time within which the Board shall report to the court on such application.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> After the court receives the report of the Board, or the expiration of the time fixed under subsection (b) of this section, whichever occurs first, the court may authorize such abandonment, after notice to the Board, the Secretary of Transportation, the trustee, any party in interest that has requested notice, any affected shipper or community, and any other entity prescribed by the court, and a hearing.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Enforcement of an order authorizing such abandonment shall be stayed until the time for taking an appeal has expired, or, if an appeal is timely taken, until such order has become final.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If an order authorizing such abandonment is appealed, the court, on request of a party in interest, may authorize suspension of service on a line or a portion of a line pending the determination of such appeal, after notice to the Board, the Secretary of Transportation, the trustee, any party in interest that has requested notice, any affected shipper or community, and any other entity prescribed by the court, and a hearing. An appellant may not obtain a stay of the enforcement of an order authorizing such suspension by the giving of a supersedeas bond or otherwise, during the pendency of such appeal.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In authorizing any abandonment of a railroad line under this section, the court shall require the rail carrier to provide a fair arrangement at least as protective of the interests of employees as that established under <ref>section 11326(a) of title 49</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Nothing in this subsection shall be deemed to affect the priorities or timing of payment of employee protection which might have existed in the absence of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2643</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–448, title II, § 227(a)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-14">Oct. 14, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1931</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–353, title III, § 521</ref>, <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 388</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title III, § 302(2)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 943</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–8, title XII, § 1217</ref>, <date date="2005-04-20">Apr. 20, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 195</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1171.</num>
<heading> Priority claims</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> There shall be paid as an administrative expense any claim of an individual or of the personal representative of a deceased individual against the debtor or the estate, for personal injury to or death of such individual arising out of the operation of the debtor or the estate, whether such claim arose before or after the commencement of the case.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Any unsecured claim against the debtor that would have been entitled to priority if a receiver in equity of the property of the debtor had been appointed by a Federal court on the date of the order for relief under this title shall be entitled to the same priority in the case under this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2643</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–353, title III, § 522</ref>, <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 388</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1172.</num>
<heading> Contents of plan</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> In addition to the provisions required or permitted under <ref>section 1123 of this title</ref>, a plan—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall specify the extent to and the means by which the debtor’s rail service is proposed to be continued, and the extent to which any of the debtor’s rail service is proposed to be terminated; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> may include a provision for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the transfer of any or all of the operating railroad lines of the debtor to another operating railroad; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> abandonment of any railroad line in accordance with <ref>section 1170 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> If, except for the pendency of the case under this chapter, transfer of, or operation of or over, any of the debtor’s rail lines by an entity other than the debtor or a successor to the debtor under the plan would require approval by the Board under a law of the United States, then a plan may not propose such a transfer or such operation unless the proponent of the plan initiates an appropriate application for such a transfer or such operation with the Board and, within such time as the court may fix, not exceeding 180 days, the Board, with or without a hearing, as the Board may determine, and with or without modification or condition, approves such application, or does not act on such application. Any action or order of the Board approving, modifying, conditioning, or disapproving such application is subject to review by the court only under sections 706(2)(A), 706(2)(B), 706(2)(C), and 706(2)(D) of title 5.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In approving an application under subsection (b) of this section, the Board shall require the rail carrier to provide a fair arrangement at least as protective of the interests of employees as that established under <ref>section 11326(a) of title 49</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Nothing in this subsection shall be deemed to affect the priorities or timing of payment of employee protection which might have existed in the absence of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2644</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–448, title II, § 227(b)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-14">Oct. 14, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1931</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title III, § 302(2)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 943</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–8, title XII, § 1218</ref>, <date date="2005-04-20">Apr. 20, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 195</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1173.</num>
<heading> Confirmation of plan</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The court shall confirm a plan if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the applicable requirements of <ref>section 1129 of this title</ref> have been met;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> each creditor or equity security holder will receive or retain under the plan property of a value, as of the effective date of the plan, that is not less than the value of property that each such creditor or equity security holder would so receive or retain if all of the operating railroad lines of the debtor were sold, and the proceeds of such sale, and the other property of the estate, were distributed under chapter 7 of this title on such date;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> in light of the debtor’s past earnings and the probable prospective earnings of the reorganized debtor, there will be adequate coverage by such prospective earnings of any fixed charges, such as interest on debt, amortization of funded debt, and rent for leased railroads, provided for by the plan; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the plan is consistent with the public interest.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> If the requirements of subsection (a) of this section are met with respect to more than one plan, the court shall confirm the plan that is most likely to maintain adequate rail service in the public interest.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2644</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–353, title III, § 523</ref>, <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 388</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1174.</num>
<heading> Liquidation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On request of a party in interest and after notice and a hearing, the court may, or, if a plan has not been confirmed under <ref>section 1173 of this title</ref> before five years after the date of the order for relief, the court shall, order the trustee to cease the debtor’s operation and to collect and reduce to money all of the property of the estate in the same manner as if the case were a case under chapter 7 of this title.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2644</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER V—</num>
<heading>SMALL BUSINESS DEBTOR REORGANIZATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1181.</num>
<heading> Inapplicability of other sections</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Sections 105(d), 1101(1), 1104, 1105, 1106, 1107, 1108, 1115, 1116, 1121, 1123(a)(8), 1123(c), 1127, 1129(a)(15), 1129(b), 1129(c), 1129(e), and 1141(d)(5) of this title do not apply in a case under this subchapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Court Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Unless the court for cause orders otherwise, paragraphs (1), (2), and (4) of section 1102(a) and sections 1102(b), 1103, and 1125 of this title do not apply in a case under this subchapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Special Rule for Discharge</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If a plan is confirmed under <ref>section 1191(b) of this title</ref>, <ref>section 1141(d) of this title</ref> shall not apply, except as provided in <ref>section 1192 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–54, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-08-23">Aug. 23, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1079</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1182.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this subchapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Debtor</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “debtor” means a small business debtor.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Debtor in possession</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “debtor in possession” means the debtor, unless removed as debtor in possession under <ref>section 1185(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–54, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-08-23">Aug. 23, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1079</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–136, div. A, title I, § 1113(a)(1)</ref>, (5), <date date="2020-03-27">Mar. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 310</ref>, 311; <ref>Pub. L. 117–151, § 2(d)</ref>, (i)(1)(B), <date date="2022-06-21">June 21, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 1298</ref>, 1300.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1183.</num>
<heading> Trustee</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the United States trustee has appointed an individual under <ref>section 586(b) of title 28</ref> to serve as standing trustee in cases under this subchapter, and if such individual qualifies as a trustee under <ref>section 322 of this title</ref>, then that individual shall serve as trustee in any case under this subchapter. Otherwise, the United States trustee shall appoint one disinterested person to serve as trustee in the case or the United States trustee may serve as trustee in the case, as necessary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duties</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The trustee shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> perform the duties specified in paragraphs (2), (5), (6), (7), and (9) of <ref>section 704(a) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> perform the duties specified in paragraphs (3), (4), and (7) of <ref>section 1106(a) of this title</ref>, if the court, for cause and on request of a party in interest, the trustee, or the United States trustee, so orders;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> appear and be heard at the status conference under <ref>section 1188 of this title</ref> and any hearing that concerns—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the value of property subject to a lien;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> confirmation of a plan filed under this subchapter;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> modification of the plan after confirmation; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the sale of property of the estate;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> ensure that the debtor commences making timely payments required by a plan confirmed under this subchapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> if the debtor ceases to be a debtor in possession—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> perform the duties specified in section 704(a)(8) and paragraphs (1), (2), and (6) of <ref>section 1106(a) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> be authorized to operate the business of the debtor;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> if there is a claim for a domestic support obligation with respect to the debtor, perform the duties specified in <ref>section 704(c) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> facilitate the development of a consensual plan of reorganization.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Termination of Trustee Service.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the plan of the debtor is confirmed under <ref>section 1191(a) of this title</ref>, the service of the trustee in the case shall terminate when the plan has been substantially consummated, except that the United States trustee may reappoint a trustee as needed for performance of duties under subsection (b)(3)(C) of this section and <ref>section 1185(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Service of notice of substantial consummation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 14 days after the plan of the debtor is substantially consummated, the debtor shall file with the court and serve on the trustee, the United States trustee, and all parties in interest notice of such substantial consummation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–54, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-08-23">Aug. 23, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1079</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 117–151, § 2(e)</ref>, <date date="2022-06-21">June 21, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 1299</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1184.</num>
<heading> Rights and powers of a debtor in possession</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to such limitations or conditions as the court may prescribe, a debtor in possession shall have all the rights, other than the right to compensation under <ref>section 330 of this title</ref>, and powers, and shall perform all functions and duties, except the duties specified in paragraphs (2), (3), and (4) of <ref>section 1106(a) of this title</ref>, of a trustee serving in a case under this chapter, including operating the business of the debtor.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–54, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-08-23">Aug. 23, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1080</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1185.</num>
<heading> Removal of debtor in possession</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>On request of a party in interest, and after notice and a hearing, the court shall order that the debtor shall not be a debtor in possession for cause, including fraud, dishonesty, incompetence, or gross mismanagement of the affairs of the debtor, either before or after the date of commencement of the case, or for failure to perform the obligations of the debtor under a plan confirmed under this subchapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reinstatement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>On request of a party in interest, and after notice and a hearing, the court may reinstate the debtor in possession.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–54, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-08-23">Aug. 23, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1080</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1186.</num>
<heading> Property of the estate</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inclusions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>If a plan is confirmed under <ref>section 1191(b) of this title</ref>, property of the estate includes, in addition to the property specified in <ref>section 541 of this title</ref>—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> all property of the kind specified in that section that the debtor acquires after the date of commencement of the case but before the case is closed, dismissed, or converted to a case under chapter 7, 12, or 13 of this title, whichever occurs first; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> earnings from services performed by the debtor after the date of commencement of the case but before the case is closed, dismissed, or converted to a case under chapter 7, 12, or 13 of this title, whichever occurs first.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Debtor Remaining in Possession</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in <ref>section 1185 of this title</ref>, a plan confirmed under this subchapter, or an order confirming a plan under this subchapter, the debtor shall remain in possession of all property of the estate.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–54, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-08-23">Aug. 23, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1081</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1187.</num>
<heading> Duties and reporting requirements of debtors</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Filing Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Upon electing to be a debtor under this subchapter, the debtor shall file the documents required by subparagraphs (A) and (B) of <ref>section 1116(1) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Other Applicable Provisions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A debtor, in addition to the duties provided in this title and as otherwise required by law, shall comply with the requirements of section 308 and paragraphs (2), (3), (4), (5), (6), and (7) of <ref>section 1116 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Separate Disclosure Statement Exemption</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the court orders under <ref>section 1181(b) of this title</ref> that <ref>section 1125 of this title</ref> applies, <ref>section 1125(f) of this title</ref> shall apply.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–54, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-08-23">Aug. 23, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1081</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1188.</num>
<heading> Status conference</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in subsection (b), not later than 60 days after the entry of the order for relief under this chapter, the court shall hold a status conference to further the expeditious and economical resolution of a case under this subchapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The court may extend the period of time for holding a status conference under subsection (a) if the need for an extension is attributable to circumstances for which the debtor should not justly be held accountable.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 14 days before the date of the status conference under subsection (a), the debtor shall file with the court and serve on the trustee and all parties in interest a report that details the efforts the debtor has undertaken and will undertake to attain a consensual plan of reorganization.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–54, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-08-23">Aug. 23, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1081</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1189.</num>
<heading> Filing of the plan</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Who May File a Plan</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Only the debtor may file a plan under this subchapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Deadline</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The debtor shall file a plan not later than 90 days after the order for relief under this chapter, except that the court may extend the period if the need for the extension is attributable to circumstances for which the debtor should not justly be held accountable.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–54, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-08-23">Aug. 23, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1081</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1190.</num>
<heading> Contents of plan</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A plan filed under this subchapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a brief history of the business operations of the debtor;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a liquidation analysis; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> projections with respect to the ability of the debtor to make payments under the proposed plan of reorganization;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall provide for the submission of all or such portion of the future earnings or other future income of the debtor to the supervision and control of the trustee as is necessary for the execution of the plan; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> notwithstanding <ref>section 1123(b)(5) of this title</ref>, may modify the rights of the holder of a claim secured only by a security interest in real property that is the principal residence of the debtor if the new value received in connection with the granting of the security interest was—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> not used primarily to acquire the real property; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> used primarily in connection with the small business of the debtor.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–54, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-08-23">Aug. 23, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1082</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1191.</num>
<heading> Confirmation of plan</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Terms</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The court shall confirm a plan under this subchapter only if all of the requirements of section 1129(a), other than paragraph (15) of that section, of this title <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002040">1</ref> are met.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding <ref>section 510(a) of this title</ref>, if all of the applicable requirements of <ref>section 1129(a) of this title</ref>, other than paragraphs (8), (10), and (15) of that section, are met with respect to a plan, the court, on request of the debtor, shall confirm the plan notwithstanding the requirements of such paragraphs if the plan does not discriminate unfairly, and is fair and equitable, with respect to each class of claims or interests that is impaired under, and has not accepted, the plan.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rule of Construction</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For purposes of this section, the condition that a plan be fair and equitable with respect to each class of claims or interests includes the following requirements:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> With respect to a class of secured claims, the plan meets the requirements of <ref>section 1129(b)(2)(A) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> As of the effective date of the plan—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the plan provides that all of the projected disposable income of the debtor to be received in the 3-year period, or such longer period not to exceed 5 years as the court may fix, beginning on the date that the first payment is due under the plan will be applied to make payments under the plan; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the value of the property to be distributed under the plan in the 3-year period, or such longer period not to exceed 5 years as the court may fix, beginning on the date on which the first distribution is due under the plan is not less than the projected disposable income of the debtor.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The debtor will be able to make all payments under the plan; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> there is a reasonable likelihood that the debtor will be able to make all payments under the plan; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the plan provides appropriate remedies, which may include the liquidation of nonexempt assets, to protect the holders of claims or interests in the event that the payments are not made.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Disposable Income</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For purposes of this section, the term “disposable income” means the income that is received by the debtor and that is not reasonably necessary to be expended—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the maintenance or support of the debtor or a dependent of the debtor; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a domestic support obligation that first becomes payable after the date of the filing of the petition; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> for the payment of expenditures necessary for the continuation, preservation, or operation of the business of the debtor.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Special Rule</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding <ref>section 1129(a)(9)(A) of this title</ref>, a plan that provides for the payment through the plan of a claim of a kind specified in paragraph (2) or (3) of <ref>section 507(a) of this title</ref> may be confirmed under subsection (b) of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–54, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-08-23">Aug. 23, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1082</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–260, div. N, title III, § 320(c)</ref>, (f)(2)(A)(iii), <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 2016</ref>, 2017; <ref>Pub. L. 117–151, § 2(f)</ref>, <date date="2022-06-21">June 21, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 1299</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1192.</num>
<heading> Discharge</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">If the plan of the debtor is confirmed under <ref>section 1191(b) of this title</ref>, as soon as practicable after completion by the debtor of all payments due within the first 3 years of the plan, or such longer period not to exceed 5 years as the court may fix, unless the court approves a written waiver of discharge executed by the debtor after the order for relief under this chapter, the court shall grant the debtor a discharge of all debts provided in <ref>section 1141(d)(1)(A) of this title</ref>, and all other debts allowed under <ref>section 503 of this title</ref> and provided for in the plan, except any debt—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> on which the last payment is due after the first 3 years of the plan, or such other time not to exceed 5 years fixed by the court; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> of the kind specified in <ref>section 523(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–54, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-08-23">Aug. 23, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1083</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1193.</num>
<heading> Modification of plan</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Modification Before Confirmation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The debtor may modify a plan at any time before confirmation, but may not modify the plan so that the plan as modified fails to meet the requirements of sections 1122 and 1123 of this title, with the exception of subsection (a)(8) of such section 1123. After the modification is filed with the court, the plan as modified becomes the plan.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Modification After Confirmation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If a plan has been confirmed under <ref>section 1191(a) of this title</ref>, the debtor may modify the plan at any time after confirmation of the plan and before substantial consummation of the plan, but may not modify the plan so that the plan as modified fails to meet the requirements of sections 1122 and 1123 of this title, with the exception of subsection (a)(8) of such section 1123. The plan, as modified under this subsection, becomes the plan only if circumstances warrant the modification and the court, after notice and a hearing, confirms the plan as modified under <ref>section 1191(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Certain Other Modifications</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If a plan has been confirmed under <ref>section 1191(b) of this title</ref>, the debtor may modify the plan at any time within 3 years, or such longer time not to exceed 5 years, as fixed by the court, but may not modify the plan so that the plan as modified fails to meet the requirements of <ref>section 1191(b) of this title</ref>. The plan as modified under this subsection becomes the plan only if circumstances warrant such modification and the court, after notice and a hearing, confirms such plan, as modified, under <ref>section 1191(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Holders of a Claim or Interest</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If a plan has been confirmed under <ref>section 1191(a) of this title</ref>, any holder of a claim or interest that has accepted or rejected the plan is deemed to have accepted or rejected, as the case may be, the plan as modified, unless, within the time fixed by the court, such holder changes the previous acceptance or rejection of the holder.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–54, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-08-23">Aug. 23, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1083</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1194.</num>
<heading> Payments</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Retention and Distribution by Trustee</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Payments and funds received by the trustee shall be retained by the trustee until confirmation or denial of confirmation of a plan. If a plan is confirmed, the trustee shall distribute any such payment in accordance with the plan. If a plan is not confirmed, the trustee shall return any such payments to the debtor after deducting—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any unpaid claim allowed under <ref>section 503(b) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any payment made for the purpose of providing adequate protection of an interest in property due to the holder of a secured claim; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> any fee owing to the trustee.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Other Plans</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If a plan is confirmed under <ref>section 1191(b) of this title</ref>, except as otherwise provided in the plan or in the order confirming the plan, the trustee shall make payments to creditors under the plan.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Payments Prior to Confirmation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Prior to confirmation of a plan, the court, after notice and a hearing, may authorize the trustee to make payments to the holder of a secured claim for the purpose of providing adequate protection of an interest in property.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–54, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-08-23">Aug. 23, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1084</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1195.</num>
<heading> Transactions with professionals</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding <ref>section 327(a) of this title</ref>, a person is not disqualified for employment under <ref>section 327 of this title</ref>, by a debtor solely because that person holds a claim of less than $10,000 that arose prior to commencement of the case.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–54, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-08-23">Aug. 23, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1084</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>