<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 9—</num>
<heading>ADJUSTMENT OF DEBTS OF A MUNICIPALITY</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 901.</num>
<heading> Applicability of other sections of this title</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Sections 301, 333, 344, 347(b), 349, 350(b) 351,,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002036">1</ref> 361, 362, 364(c), 364(d), 364(e), 364(f), 365, 366, 501, 502, 503, 504, 506, 507(a)(2), 509, 510, 524(a)(1), 524(a)(2), 544, 545, 546, 547, 548, 549(a), 549(c), 549(d), 550, 551, 552, 553, 555, 556, 557, 559, 560, 561, 562, 1102, 1103, 1109, 1111(b), 1122, 1123(a)(1), 1123(a)(2), 1123(a)(3), 1123(a)(4), 1123(a)(5), 1123(b), 1123(d), 1124, 1125, 1126(a), 1126(b), 1126(c), 1126(e), 1126(f), 1126(g), 1127(d), 1128, 1129(a)(2), 1129(a)(3), 1129(a)(6), 1129(a)(8), 1129(a)(10), 1129(b)(1), 1129(b)(2)(A), 1129(b)(2)(B), 1142(b), 1143, 1144, and 1145 of this title apply in a case under this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> A term used in a section of this title made applicable in a case under this chapter by subsection (a) of this section or section 103(e) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002037">2</ref> of this title has the meaning defined for such term for the purpose of such applicable section, unless such term is otherwise defined in <ref>section 902 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> A section made applicable in a case under this chapter by subsection (a) of this section that is operative if the business of the debtor is authorized to be operated is operative in a case under this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2621</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–353, title III</ref>, §§ 353, 490, <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 361</ref>, 383; <ref>Pub. L. 100–597, § 3</ref>, <date date="1988-11-03">Nov. 3, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3028</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–8, title V, § 502</ref>, title XII, § 1216, title XV, § 1502(a)(5), <date date="2005-04-20">Apr. 20, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 118</ref>, 195, 216; <ref>Pub. L. 111–327, § 2(a)(29)</ref>, <date date="2010-12-22">Dec. 22, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3560</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 902.</num>
<heading> Definitions for this chapter</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “property of the estate”, when used in a section that is made applicable in a case under this chapter by section 103(e) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002038">1</ref> or 901 of this title, means property of the debtor;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> “special revenues” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> receipts derived from the ownership, operation, or disposition of projects or systems of the debtor that are primarily used or intended to be used primarily to provide transportation, utility, or other services, including the proceeds of borrowings to finance the projects or systems;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> special excise taxes imposed on particular activities or transactions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> incremental tax receipts from the benefited area in the case of tax-increment financing;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> other revenues or receipts derived from particular functions of the debtor, whether or not the debtor has other functions; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> taxes specifically levied to finance one or more projects or systems, excluding receipts from general property, sales, or income taxes (other than tax-increment financing) levied to finance the general purposes of the debtor;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> “special tax payer” means record owner or holder of legal or equitable title to real property against which a special assessment or special tax has been levied the proceeds of which are the sole source of payment of an obligation issued by the debtor to defray the cost of an improvement relating to such real property;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> “special tax payer affected by the plan” means special tax payer with respect to whose real property the plan proposes to increase the proportion of special assessments or special taxes referred to in paragraph (2) of this section assessed against such real property; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> “trustee”, when used in a section that is made applicable in a case under this chapter by section 103(e) <sup>1</sup> or 901 of this title, means debtor, except as provided in <ref>section 926 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2622</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–353, title III, § 491</ref>, <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 383</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–597, § 4</ref>, <date date="1988-11-03">Nov. 3, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3028</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 903.</num>
<heading> Reservation of State power to control municipalities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">This chapter does not limit or impair the power of a State to control, by legislation or otherwise, a municipality of or in such State in the exercise of the political or governmental powers of such municipality, including expenditures for such exercise, but—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a State law prescribing a method of composition of indebtedness of such municipality may not bind any creditor that does not consent to such composition; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a judgment entered under such a law may not bind a creditor that does not consent to such composition.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2622</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–353, title III, § 492</ref>, <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 383</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 904.</num>
<heading> Limitation on jurisdiction and powers of court</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Notwithstanding any power of the court, unless the debtor consents or the plan so provides, the court may not, by any stay, order, or decree, in the case or otherwise, interfere with—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any of the political or governmental powers of the debtor;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any of the property or revenues of the debtor; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the debtor’s use or enjoyment of any income-producing property.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2622</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>ADMINISTRATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 921.</num>
<heading> Petition and proceedings relating to petition</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding sections 109(d) and 301 of this title, a case under this chapter concerning an unincorporated tax or special assessment district that does not have such district’s own officials is commenced by the filing under <ref>section 301 of this title</ref> of a petition under this chapter by such district’s governing authority or the board or body having authority to levy taxes or assessments to meet the obligations of such district.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The chief judge of the court of appeals for the circuit embracing the district in which the case is commenced shall designate the bankruptcy judge to conduct the case.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> After any objection to the petition, the court, after notice and a hearing, may dismiss the petition if the debtor did not file the petition in good faith or if the petition does not meet the requirements of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> If the petition is not dismissed under subsection (c) of this section, the court shall order relief under this chapter notwithstanding section 301(b).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> The court may not, on account of an appeal from an order for relief, delay any proceeding under this chapter in the case in which the appeal is being taken; nor shall any court order a stay of such proceeding pending such appeal. The reversal on appeal of a finding of jurisdiction does not affect the validity of any debt incurred that is authorized by the court under section 364(c) or 364(d) of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2622</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–353, title III, § 494</ref>, <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 383</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–8, title V, § 501(a)</ref>, <date date="2005-04-20">Apr. 20, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 118</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 922.</num>
<heading> Automatic stay of enforcement of claims against the debtor</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> A petition filed under this chapter operates as a stay, in addition to the stay provided by <ref>section 362 of this title</ref>, applicable to all entities, of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the commencement or continuation, including the issuance or employment of process, of a judicial, administrative, or other action or proceeding against an officer or inhabitant of the debtor that seeks to enforce a claim against the debtor; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the enforcement of a lien on or arising out of taxes or assessments owed to the debtor.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Subsections (c), (d), (e), (f), and (g) of <ref>section 362 of this title</ref> apply to a stay under subsection (a) of this section the same as such subsections apply to a stay under <ref>section 362(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> If the debtor provides, under section 362, 364, or 922 of this title, adequate protection of the interest of the holder of a claim secured by a lien on property of the debtor and if, notwithstanding such protection such creditor has a claim arising from the stay of action against such property under section 362 or 922 of this title or from the granting of a lien under <ref>section 364(d) of this title</ref>, then such claim shall be allowable as an administrative expense under <ref>section 503(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding <ref>section 362 of this title</ref> and subsection (a) of this section, a petition filed under this chapter does not operate as a stay of application of pledged special revenues in a manner consistent with <ref>section 927 of this title</ref> to payment of indebtedness secured by such revenues.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2623</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–353, title III, § 495</ref>, <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 384</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–597, § 5</ref>, <date date="1988-11-03">Nov. 3, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3029</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 923.</num>
<heading> Notice</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There shall be given notice of the commencement of a case under this chapter, notice of an order for relief under this chapter, and notice of the dismissal of a case under this chapter. Such notice shall also be published at least once a week for three successive weeks in at least one newspaper of general circulation published within the district in which the case is commenced, and in such other newspaper having a general circulation among bond dealers and bondholders as the court designates.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2623</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 924.</num>
<heading> List of creditors</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The debtor shall file a list of creditors.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2623</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 925.</num>
<heading> Effect of list of claims</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A proof of claim is deemed filed under <ref>section 501 of this title</ref> for any claim that appears in the list filed under <ref>section 924 of this title</ref>, except a claim that is listed as disputed, contingent, or unliquidated.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2623</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 926.</num>
<heading> Avoiding powers</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> If the debtor refuses to pursue a cause of action under section 544, 545, 547, 548, 549(a), or 550 of this title, then on request of a creditor, the court may appoint a trustee to pursue such cause of action.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> A transfer of property of the debtor to or for the benefit of any holder of a bond or note, on account of such bond or note, may not be avoided under <ref>section 547 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2623</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–597, § 6</ref>, <date date="1988-11-03">Nov. 3, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3029</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 927.</num>
<heading> Limitation on recourse</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The holder of a claim payable solely from special revenues of the debtor under applicable nonbankruptcy law shall not be treated as having recourse against the debtor on account of such claim pursuant to <ref>section 1111(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–597, § 7(2)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-03">Nov. 3, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3029</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 928.</num>
<heading> Post petition effect of security interest</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding <ref>section 552(a) of this title</ref> and subject to subsection (b) of this section, special revenues acquired by the debtor after the commencement of the case shall remain subject to any lien resulting from any security agreement entered into by the debtor before the commencement of the case.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Any such lien on special revenues, other than municipal betterment assessments, derived from a project or system shall be subject to the necessary operating expenses of such project or system, as the case may be.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–597, § 8</ref>, <date date="1988-11-03">Nov. 3, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3029</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 929.</num>
<heading> Municipal leases</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A lease to a municipality shall not be treated as an executory contract or unexpired lease for the purposes of section 365 or 502(b)(6) of this title solely by reason of its being subject to termination in the event the debtor fails to appropriate rent.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–597, § 9</ref>, <date date="1988-11-03">Nov. 3, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3030</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 930.</num>
<heading> Dismissal</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> After notice and a hearing, the court may dismiss a case under this chapter for cause, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> want of prosecution;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> unreasonable delay by the debtor that is prejudicial to creditors;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> failure to propose a plan within the time fixed under <ref>section 941 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> if a plan is not accepted within any time fixed by the court;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> denial of confirmation of a plan under <ref>section 943(b) of this title</ref> and denial of additional time for filing another plan or a modification of a plan; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> if the court has retained jurisdiction after confirmation of a plan—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> material default by the debtor with respect to a term of such plan; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> termination of such plan by reason of the occurrence of a condition specified in such plan.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The court shall dismiss a case under this chapter if confirmation of a plan under this chapter is refused.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2623</ref>, § 927; <ref>Pub. L. 98–353, title III, § 496</ref>, <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 384</ref>; renumbered § 930, <ref>Pub. L. 100–597, § 7(1)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-03">Nov. 3, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3029</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>THE PLAN</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 941.</num>
<heading> Filing of plan</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The debtor shall file a plan for the adjustment of the debtor’s debts. If such a plan is not filed with the petition, the debtor shall file such a plan at such later time as the court fixes.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2624</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 942.</num>
<heading> Modification of plan</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The debtor may modify the plan at any time before confirmation, but may not modify the plan so that the plan as modified fails to meet the requirements of this chapter. After the debtor files a modification, the plan as modified becomes the plan.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2624</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 943.</num>
<heading> Confirmation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> A special tax payer may object to confirmation of a plan.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> The court shall confirm the plan if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the plan complies with the provisions of this title made applicable by sections 103(e) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002039">1</ref> and 901 of this title;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the plan complies with the provisions of this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> all amounts to be paid by the debtor or by any person for services or expenses in the case or incident to the plan have been fully disclosed and are reasonable;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the debtor is not prohibited by law from taking any action necessary to carry out the plan;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> except to the extent that the holder of a particular claim has agreed to a different treatment of such claim, the plan provides that on the effective date of the plan each holder of a claim of a kind specified in <ref>section 507(a)(2) of this title</ref> will receive on account of such claim cash equal to the allowed amount of such claim;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> any regulatory or electoral approval necessary under applicable nonbankruptcy law in order to carry out any provision of the plan has been obtained, or such provision is expressly conditioned on such approval; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the plan is in the best interests of creditors and is feasible.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2624</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–353, title III, § 497</ref>, <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 384</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–597, § 10</ref>, <date date="1988-11-03">Nov. 3, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3030</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–8, title XV, § 1502(a)(6)</ref>, <date date="2005-04-20">Apr. 20, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 216</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 944.</num>
<heading> Effect of confirmation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The provisions of a confirmed plan bind the debtor and any creditor, whether or not—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a proof of such creditor’s claim is filed or deemed filed under <ref>section 501 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> such claim is allowed under <ref>section 502 of this title</ref>; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> such creditor has accepted the plan.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, the debtor is discharged from all debts as of the time when—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the plan is confirmed;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the debtor deposits any consideration to be distributed under the plan with a disbursing agent appointed by the court; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> the court has determined—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> that any security so deposited will constitute, after distribution, a valid legal obligation of the debtor; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> that any provision made to pay or secure payment of such obligation is valid.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> The debtor is not discharged under subsection (b) of this section from any debt—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> excepted from discharge by the plan or order confirming the plan; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> owed to an entity that, before confirmation of the plan, had neither notice nor actual knowledge of the case.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2624</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 945.</num>
<heading> Continuing jurisdiction and closing of the case</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The court may retain jurisdiction over the case for such period of time as is necessary for the successful implementation of the plan.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Except as provided in subsection (a) of this section, the court shall close the case when administration of the case has been completed.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2625</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–353, title III, § 498</ref>, <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 384</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 946.</num>
<heading> Effect of exchange of securities before the date of the filing of the petition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The exchange of a new security under the plan for a claim covered by the plan, whether such exchange occurred before or after the date of the filing of the petition, does not limit or impair the effectiveness of the plan or of any provision of this chapter. The amount and number specified in <ref>section 1126(c) of this title</ref> include the amount and number of claims formerly held by a creditor that has participated in any such exchange.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2625</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>