<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 13—</num>
<heading>EASTERN SAMOA</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1661.</num>
<heading> Islands of eastern Samoa</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Ceded to and accepted by United States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The cessions by certain chiefs of the islands of Tutuila and Manua and certain other islands of the Samoan group lying between the thirteenth and fifteenth degrees of latitude south of the Equator and between the one hundred and sixty-seventh and one hundred and seventy-first degrees of longitude west of Greenwich, herein referred to as the islands of eastern Samoa, are accepted, ratified, and confirmed, as of <date date="1900-04-10">April 10, 1900</date>, and <date date="1904-07-16">July 16, 1904</date>, respectively.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public land laws; revenue</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The existing laws of the United States relative to public lands shall not apply to such lands in the said islands of eastern Samoa; but the Congress of the United States shall enact special laws for their management and disposition: <i>Provided</i>, That all revenue from or proceeds of the same, except as regards such part thereof as may be used or occupied for the civil, military, or naval purposes of the United States or may be assigned for the use of the local government, shall be used solely for the benefit of the inhabitants of the said islands of eastern Samoa for educational and other public purposes.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Government</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Until Congress shall provide for the government of such islands, all civil, judicial, and military powers shall be vested in such person or persons and shall be exercised in such manner as the President of the United States shall direct; and the President shall have power to remove said officers and fill the vacancies so occasioned.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Feb. 20, 1929, ch. 281</ref>, <ref>45 Stat. 1253</ref>; <ref>May 22, 1929, ch. 6</ref>, <ref>46 Stat. 4</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1662.</num>
<heading> Sovereignty of United States extended over Swains Island</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The sovereignty of the United States over American Samoa is extended over Swains Island, which is made a part of American Samoa and placed under the jurisdiction of the administrative and judicial authorities of the government established therein by the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 4, 1925, ch. 563</ref>, <ref>43 Stat. 1357</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1662a.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 118–232, § 1</ref>, <date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2834</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1663.</num>
<heading> Acknowledgment of deeds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Deeds and other instruments affecting land situate in the District of Columbia or any Territory of the United States may be acknowledged in the islands of Guam and Samoa or in the Canal Zone before any notary public or judge, appointed therein by proper authority, or by any officer therein who has ex officio the powers of a notary public: <i>Provided</i>, That the certificate by such notary in Guam, Samoa, or the Canal Zone, as the case may be, shall be accompanied by the certificate of the governor or acting governor of such place to the effect that the notary taking said acknowledgment was in fact the officer he purported to be; and any deeds or other instruments affecting lands so situate, so acknowledged since the first day of January, 1905, and accompanied by such certificate shall have the same effect as such deeds or other instruments hereafter so acknowledged and certified.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 28, 1906, ch. 3585</ref>, <ref>34 Stat. 552</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1664.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 19</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1710</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1665.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1666.</num>
<heading> Extension of scientific, technical, and other assistance; grant-in-aid program restriction; limitations on expenditures</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Upon request of the Secretary of the Interior—</chapeau>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> the head of any Federal department, agency, or corporation may, notwithstanding any other provision of law, extend to American Samoa, without reimbursement, such scientific, technical, and other assistance under any program which it administers as, in the judgment of the Secretary of the Interior, will promote the welfare of American Samoa. The provisions of the preceding sentence shall not apply to financial assistance under any grant-in-aid program. The Secretary of the Interior shall not request assistance pursuant to this subsection which will involve nonreimbursable costs as estimated for him in advance by the heads of the departments, agencies, and corporations concerned in excess of an aggregate of $150,000 in any one fiscal year;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Agriculture may extend to American Samoa the benefits of the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act, as amended [<ref>42 U.S.C. 1751</ref> et seq.]; and</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare may extend to American Samoa the benefits of the Vocational Education Act of 1946, the Hospital Survey and Construction Act [<ref>42 U.S.C. 291</ref> et seq.], and <ref>section 246 of title 42</ref>, all as amended.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–688, § 1</ref>, <date date="1962-09-25">Sept. 25, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 586</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–208, div. A, title I, § 101(e) [title VII, § 709(a)(7)]</ref>, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3009–233</ref>, 3009–312; <ref>Pub. L. 106–78, title VII, § 752(b)(18)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-22">Oct. 22, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1170</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1667.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 90–576, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1968-10-16">Oct. 16, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1091</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1668.</num>
<heading> Reporting duties of Governor and transfer of functions from government comptroller for American Samoa to Inspector General, Department of the Interior</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Comprehensive annual financial report; contents; other reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Governor of American Samoa shall prepare, publish, and submit to the Congress and the Secretary of the Interior a comprehensive annual financial report in conformance with the standards of the National Council on Governmental Accounting within one hundred and twenty days after the close of the fiscal year. The comprehensive annual financial report shall include statistical data as set forth in the standards of the National Council of Governmental Accounting relating to the physical, economic, social, and political characteristics of the government, and any other information required by the Congress. The Governor shall also make such other reports at such other times as may be required by the Congress or under applicable Federal law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Functions, powers, and duties transferred</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The following functions, powers, and duties heretofore vested in the government comptroller for American Samoa are hereby transferred to the Inspector General, Department of the Interior, for the purpose of establishing an organization which will maintain a satisfactory level of independent audit oversight of the government of American Samoa:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The authority to audit all accounts pertaining to the revenue and receipts of the government of American Samoa, and of funds derived from bond issues, and the authority to audit, in accordance with law and administrative regulations, all expenditures of funds and property pertaining to the government of American Samoa including those pertaining to trust funds held by the government of American Samoa.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The authority to report to the Secretary of the Interior and the Governor of American Samoa all failures to collect amounts due the government, and expenditures of funds or uses or property which are irregular or not pursuant to law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Scope of authority transferred</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The authority granted in paragraph (b) shall extend to all activities of the government of American Samoa, and shall be in addition to the authority conferred upon the Inspector General by chapter 4 of title 5.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer of personnel, assets, etc., of office of government comptroller for American Samoa to Office of Inspector General, Department of the Interior</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In order to carry out the provisions of this section, the personnel, assets, liabilities, contracts, property, records, and unexpended balances of appropriations, authorizations, allocations, and other funds employed, held, used, arising from, available or to be made available, of the office of the government comptroller for American Samoa relating to its audit function are hereby transferred to the Office of Inspector General, Department of the Interior.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–205, title V, § 501</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 97–357, title IV, § 402</ref>, <date date="1982-10-19">Oct. 19, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1711</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–362, title IX, § 901</ref>(<i>o</i>), <date date="1998-11-10">Nov. 10, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3291</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(b)(93)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4352</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1669.</num>
<heading> Administration and enforcement of collection of customs duties; employment and training of residents</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Treasury shall, upon the request of the Governor of American Samoa, administer and enforce the collection of all customs duties derived from American Samoa, without cost to the government of American Samoa. The Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Governor of American Samoa, shall make every effort to employ and train the residents of American Samoa to carry out the provisions of this section. The administration and enforcement of this section shall commence <date date="1980-10-01">October 1, 1980</date>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–205, title V, § 502</ref>, <date date="1980-03-12">Mar. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 90</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1670.</num>
<heading> Industrial development bonds</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Issuance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The legislature of the government of American Samoa may cause to be issued after <date date="1984-09-20">September 20, 1984</date>, industrial development bonds (within the meaning of section 103(b)(2) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002015">1</ref> of title 26).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exemption of all bonds from income taxation by State and local governments</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The interest on any bond or other obligation issued by or on behalf of the Government of American Samoa shall be exempt from taxation by the Government of American Samoa and the governments of any of the several States, the District of Columbia, any territory or possession of the United States, and any subdivision thereof.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exemption applicable only to income taxes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The exemption provided by paragraph (1) shall not apply to gift, estate, inheritance, legacy, succession, or other wealth transfer taxes.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cross reference</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For exclusion of interest for purposes of Federal income taxation, see <ref>section 103 of title 26</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–454, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="1984-10-05">Oct. 5, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1733</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 2095</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–326, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-16">Oct. 16, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1270</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>