<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 16—</num>
<heading>DELEGATES TO CONGRESS</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>GUAM AND VIRGIN ISLANDS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1711.</num>
<heading> Delegate to House of Representatives from Guam and Virgin Islands</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The territory of Guam and the territory of the Virgin Islands each shall be represented in the United States Congress by a nonvoting Delegate to the House of Representatives, elected as hereinafter provided.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–271, § 1</ref>, <date date="1972-04-10">Apr. 10, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 118</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1712.</num>
<heading> Election of delegates; majority; runoff election; vacancy; commencement of term</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Delegate shall be elected by the people qualified to vote for the members of the legislature of the territory he is to represent at the general election of 1972, and thereafter at such general election every second year thereafter. The Delegate from the Virgin Islands shall be elected at large, by separate ballot and by a majority of the votes cast for the office of Delegate. The Delegate from Guam shall be elected at large and by a majority of the votes cast for the office of Delegate. If no candidate receives such majority, on the fourteenth day following such election a runoff election shall be held between the candidates receiving the highest and the second highest number of votes cast for the office of Delegate. In case of a permanent vacancy in the office of Delegate, by reason of death, resignation, or permanent disability, the office of Delegate shall remain vacant until a successor shall have been elected and qualified.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The term of the Delegate shall commence on the third day of January following the date of the election.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–271, § 2</ref>, <date date="1972-04-10">Apr. 10, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 119</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–209, § 1</ref>, <date date="1998-07-29">July 29, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 880</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1713.</num>
<heading> Qualifications for Office of Delegate</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">To be eligible for the Office of Delegate a candidate must—</chapeau>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> be at least twenty-five years of age on the date of the election,</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> have been a citizen of the United States for at least seven years prior to the date of the election,</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> be an inhabitant of the territory from which he is elected, and</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> not be, on the date of the election, a candidate for any other office.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–271, § 3</ref>, <date date="1972-04-10">Apr. 10, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 119</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1714.</num>
<heading> Territorial legislature; determination of election procedure</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The legislature of each territory may determine the order of names on the ballot for election of Delegate, the method by which a special election to fill a vacancy in the office of Delegate shall be conducted, the method by which ties between candidates for the office of Delegate shall be resolved, and all other matters of local application pertaining to the election and the office of Delegate not otherwise expressly provided for herein.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–271, § 4</ref>, <date date="1972-04-10">Apr. 10, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 119</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1715.</num>
<heading> Operation of Office; House privileges; compensation, allowances, and benefits; privileges and immunities; voting in committee</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Delegate from Guam and the Delegate from the Virgin Islands shall have such privileges in the House of Representatives as may be afforded him under the Rules of the House of Representatives. Until the Rules of the House of Representatives are amended to provide otherwise, the Delegate from each territory shall receive the same compensation, allowances, and benefits as a Member of the House of Representatives, and shall be entitled to whatever privileges and immunities are, or hereinafter may be, granted to the Resident Commissioner for Puerto Rico: <i>Provided</i>, That the right to vote in committee shall be as provided by the Rules of the House of Representatives.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–271, § 5</ref>, <date date="1972-04-10">Apr. 10, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 119</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–186, title II, § 224(4)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1752</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>AMERICAN SAMOA</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1731.</num>
<heading> Delegate to House of Representatives from American Samoa</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Territory of American Samoa shall be represented in the United States Congress by a nonvoting Delegate to the House of Representatives, elected as hereinafter provided.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–556, § 1</ref>, <date date="1978-10-31">Oct. 31, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2078</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1732.</num>
<heading> Election of delegates</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general; plurality vote; vacancy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Delegate shall be elected by the people qualified to vote for the popularly elected officials of the Territory of American Samoa at the general Federal election of 1980, and thereafter at such general election every second year thereafter. The Delegate shall be elected at large, by separate ballot, and by a plurality of the votes cast for the office of Delegate. In case of a permanent vacancy in the office of Delegate, by reason of death, resignation, or permanent disability, the office of Delegate shall remain vacant until a successor shall have been elected and qualified.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Commencement of term</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The term of the Delegate shall commence on the third day of January following the date of the election.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of primary elections</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The legislature of American Samoa may, but is not required to, provide for primary elections for the election of Delegate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect of establishment of primary elections</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding subsection (a), if the legislature of American Samoa provides for primary elections for the election of Delegate, the Delegate shall be elected by a majority of votes cast in any subsequent general election for the office of Delegate for which such primary elections were held.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–556, § 2</ref>, <date date="1978-10-31">Oct. 31, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2078</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–376, § 2</ref>, <date date="2004-10-30">Oct. 30, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2200</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1733.</num>
<heading> Qualifications for Office of Delegate</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">To be eligible for the office of Delegate a candidate shall—</chapeau>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> be at least twenty-five years of age on the date of the election;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> owe allegiance to the United States;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> be an inhabitant of the Territory of American Samoa; and</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> not be, on the date of the election, a candidate for any other office.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–556, § 3</ref>, <date date="1978-10-31">Oct. 31, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2078</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–584, § 3</ref>, <date date="1978-11-02">Nov. 2, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2483</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1734.</num>
<heading> Territorial government; determination of election procedure</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Acting pursuant to legislation enacted in accordance with section 9, article II of the American Samoan Revised Constitution, the territorial government will determine the order of names on the ballot for election of Delegate, the method by which a special election to fill a vacancy in the office of Delegate shall be conducted, the method by which ties between candidates for the office of Delegate shall be resolved, and all other matters of local application pertaining to the election and the office of Delegate not otherwise expressly provided for herein.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–556, § 4</ref>, <date date="1978-10-31">Oct. 31, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2078</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1735.</num>
<heading> Operation of Office; compensation, allowances, and benefits; privileges and immunities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Until the Rules of the House of Representatives are amended to provide otherwise, the Delegate from American Samoa shall receive the same compensation, allowances, and benefits as a Member of the House of Representatives, and shall be entitled to whatever privileges and immunities that are, or hereinafter may be, granted to the nonvoting Delegate from the Territory of Guam.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–556, § 5</ref>, <date date="1978-10-31">Oct. 31, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2078</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–357, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="1982-10-19">Oct. 19, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1711</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>NORTHERN MARIANA ISLANDS DELEGATE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1751.</num>
<heading> Delegate to House of Representatives from Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands shall be represented in the United States Congress by the Resident Representative to the United States authorized by section 901 of the Covenant To Establish a Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands in Political Union With the United States of America (approved by <ref>Public Law 94–241</ref> (<ref>48 U.S.C. 1801</ref> et seq.)). The Resident Representative shall be a nonvoting Delegate to the House of Representatives, elected as provided in this subchapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–229, title VII, § 711</ref>, <date date="2008-05-08">May 8, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 868</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1752.</num>
<heading> Election of Delegate</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Electors and time of election</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Delegate shall be elected—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> by the people qualified to vote for the popularly elected officials of the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> at the Federal general election of 2008 and at such Federal general election every 2d year thereafter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Manner of election</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Delegate shall be elected at large and by a plurality of the votes cast for the office of Delegate.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect of establishment of primary elections</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding paragraph (1), if the Government of the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, acting pursuant to legislation enacted in accordance with the Constitution of the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, provides for primary elections for the election of the Delegate, the Delegate shall be elected by a majority of the votes cast in any general election for the office of Delegate for which such primary elections were held.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Vacancy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In case of a permanent vacancy in the office of Delegate, the office of Delegate shall remain vacant until a successor is elected and qualified.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Commencement of term</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The term of the Delegate shall commence on the 3d day of January following the date of the election.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–229, title VII, § 712</ref>, <date date="2008-05-08">May 8, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 868</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1753.</num>
<heading> Qualifications for office of Delegate</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">To be eligible for the office of Delegate a candidate shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> be at least 25 years of age on the date of the election;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> have been a citizen of the United States for at least 7 years prior to the date of the election;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> be a resident and domiciliary of the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands for at least 7 years prior to the date of the election;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> be qualified to vote in the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands on the date of the election; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> not be, on the date of the election, a candidate for any other office.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–229, title VII, § 713</ref>, <date date="2008-05-08">May 8, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 868</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1754.</num>
<heading> Determination of election procedure</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Acting pursuant to legislation enacted in accordance with the Constitution of the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, the Government of the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands may determine the order of names on the ballot for election of Delegate, the method by which a special election to fill a permanent vacancy in the office of Delegate shall be conducted, the method by which ties between candidates for the office of Delegate shall be resolved, and all other matters of local application pertaining to the election and the office of Delegate not otherwise expressly provided for in this subchapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–229, title VII, § 714</ref>, <date date="2008-05-08">May 8, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 869</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1755.</num>
<heading> Compensation, privileges, and immunities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Until the Rules of the House of Representatives are amended to provide otherwise, the Delegate from the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands shall receive the same compensation, allowances, and benefits as a Member of the House of Representatives, and shall be entitled to whatever privileges and immunities are, or hereinafter may be, granted to any other nonvoting Delegate to the House of Representatives.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–229, title VII, § 715</ref>, <date date="2008-05-08">May 8, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 869</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1756.</num>
<heading> Lack of effect on covenant</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No provision of this subchapter shall be construed to alter, amend, or abrogate any provision of the covenant referred to in <ref>section 1751 of this title</ref> except section 901 of the covenant.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–229, title VII, § 716</ref>, <date date="2008-05-08">May 8, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 869</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1757.</num>
<heading> Definition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this subchapter, the term “Delegate” means the Resident Representative referred to in <ref>section 1751 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–229, title VII, § 717</ref>, <date date="2008-05-08">May 8, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 869</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>