<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 10—</num>
<heading>TERRITORIAL PROVISIONS OF A GENERAL NATURE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1451.</num>
<heading> Rights of Indians not impaired; boundaries</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in title 23 of the Revised Statutes shall be construed to impair the rights of person or property pertaining to the Indians in any Territory, so long as such rights remain unextinguished by treaty between the United States and such Indians, or to include any Territory which, by treaty with any Indian tribe, is not, without the consent of such tribe, embraced within the territorial limits or jurisdiction of any State or Territory; but all such territory shall be excepted out of the boundaries, and constitute no part of any Territory now or hereafter organized until such tribe signifies its assent to the President to be embraced within a particular Territory. As used herein, the term “Territory” does not include the Virgin Islands, Puerto Rico, American Samoa, Guam, or the Northern Mariana Islands.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(R.S. § 1839; <ref>Pub. L. 98–213, § 15(a)</ref>, <date date="1983-12-08">Dec. 8, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 1462</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1452.</num>
<heading> Regulation of Indians</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nor shall anything in title 23 of the Revised Statutes be construed to affect the authority of the United States to make any regulations respecting the Indians of any Territory, their lands, property, or rights, by treaty, law, or otherwise, in the same manner as might be made if no temporary government existed, or is hereafter established, in any such Territory. As used herein, the term “Territory” does not include the Virgin Islands, Puerto Rico, American Samoa, Guam, or the Northern Mariana Islands.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(R.S. § 1840; <ref>Pub. L. 98–213, § 15(b)</ref>, <date date="1983-12-08">Dec. 8, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 1462</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 1453 to 1455.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 98–213, § 16(c)</ref>–(f), <date date="1983-12-08">Dec. 8, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 1462</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1456.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Sept. 12, 1950, ch. 946</ref>, title III, § 301(106), <ref>64 Stat. 844</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 1457 to 1469–1.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 98–213, § 16(a)</ref>, (g)–(u), <date date="1983-12-08">Dec. 8, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 1462</ref>, 1463</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1469a.</num>
<heading> Congressional declaration of policy respecting “Insular Areas”</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In order to minimize the burden caused by existing application and reporting procedures for certain grant-in-aid programs available to the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, and the Government of the Northern Mariana Islands (hereafter referred to as “Insular Areas”) it is declared to be the policy of the Congress, notwithstanding any provision of law to the contrary, that:</chapeau>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Any department or agency of the Government of the United States which administers any Act of Congress which specifically provides for making grants to any Insular Area under which payments received may be used by such Insular Area only for certain specified purposes (other than direct payments to classes of individuals) may, acting through appropriate administrative authorities of such department or agency, consolidate any or all grants made to such area for any fiscal year or years.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Any consolidated grant for any insular area shall not be less than the sum of all grants which such area would otherwise be entitled to receive for such year.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The funds received under a consolidated grant shall be expended in furtherance of the programs and purposes authorized for any of the grants which are being consolidated, which are authorized under any of the Acts administered by the department or agency making the grant, and which would be applicable to grants for such programs and purposes in the absence of the consolidation, but the Insular Areas shall determine the proportion of the funds granted which shall be allocated to such programs and purposes.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Each department or agency making grants-in-aid shall, by regulations published in the Federal Register, provide the method by which any Insular Area may submit (i) a single application for a consolidated grant for any fiscal year period, but not more than one such application for a consolidated grant shall be required by any department or agency unless notice of such requirement is transmitted to the appropriate committees of the United States Congress together with a complete explanation of the necessity for requiring such additional applications and (ii) a single report to such department or agency with respect to each such consolidated grant: <i>Provided</i>, That nothing in this paragraph shall preclude such department or agency from providing adequate procedures for accounting, auditing, evaluating, and reviewing any programs or activities receiving benefits from any consolidated grant. The administering authority of any department or agency, in its discretion, may <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002006">1</ref> (i) waive any requirement for matching funds otherwise required by law to be provided by the Insular Area involved and (ii) waive the requirement that any Insular Area submit an application or report in writing with respect to any consolidated grant.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–134, title V, § 501</ref>, <date date="1977-10-15">Oct. 15, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 1164</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–348, § 9</ref>, <date date="1978-08-18">Aug. 18, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 495</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1469a–1.</num>
<heading> Full amounts to be covered into treasuries of Guam, Northern Mariana Islands, Puerto Rico, and Virgin Islands; reductions prohibited</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Pursuant to the terms of the Organic Act of Guam (<ref>64 Stat. 384</ref>), as amended [<ref>48 U.S.C. 1421</ref> et seq.]; the Joint resolution to Approve the Covenant to Establish a Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands in Political Union With the United States of America (<ref>90 Stat. 263</ref>), as amended [<ref>48 U.S.C. 1801</ref> et seq.]; the Puerto Rican Federal Relations Act (<ref>64 Stat. 319</ref>), as amended and supplemented [<ref>48 U.S.C. 731</ref> et seq.]; and the Revised Organic Act of the Virgin Islands (86 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002007">1</ref> Stat. 497), as amended and supplemented [<ref>48 U.S.C. 1541</ref> et seq.] and an Act to authorize appropriations for certain insular areas of the United States, and for other purposes (<ref>92 Stat. 487</ref>), as amended; there shall be paid into the treasuries of Guam, the Northern Mariana Islands, Puerto Rico, and the Virgin Islands respectively the full amounts which are to be covered into the treasuries of said islands or paid pursuant to said laws as amended and supplemented and such amounts shall not be reduced, notwithstanding <ref>Public Law 99–177</ref>, <ref>Public Law 99–366</ref>, or any other provision of law.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–396, § 19(b)</ref>, <date date="1986-08-27">Aug. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 844</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1469b.</num>
<heading> Auditing of transactions of territorial and local governments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All financial transactions of the territorial and local governments herein provided for, including such transactions of all agencies or instrumentalities established or used by such governments, may be audited by the Government Accountability Office, at its discretion, in accordance with chapter 35 of title 31.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 118–42, div. E, title I</ref>, <date date="2024-03-09">Mar. 9, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 238</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1469c.</num>
<heading> Availability of services, facilities, and equipment of agencies and instrumentalities of United States; reimbursement requirements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To the extent practicable, services, facilities, and equipment of agencies and instrumentalities of the United States Government may be made available, on a reimbursable basis, to the governments of the territories and possessions of the United States and the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands. Reimbursements may be credited to the appropriation or fund of the agency or instrumentality through which the services, facilities, and equipment are provided. If otherwise authorized by law, such services, facilities, and equipment may be made available without reimbursement.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–205, title VI, § 603</ref>, <date date="1980-03-12">Mar. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 90</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1469d.</num>
<heading> General technical assistance</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistance with matters generally within responsibility of governments; methods of assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior is authorized to extend to the governments of American Samoa, Guam, the Northern Mariana Islands, the Virgin Islands, and the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, and their agencies and instrumentalities, with or without reimbursement, technical assistance on subjects within the responsibility of the respective territorial governments. Such assistance may be provided by the Secretary of the Interior through members of his staff, reimbursements to other departments or agencies of the Federal Government under sections 1535 and 1536 of title 31, grants to or cooperative agreements with such governments, agreements with Federal agencies or agencies of State or local governments, or the employment of private individuals, partnerships, or corporations. Technical assistance may include research, planning assistance, studies, and demonstration projects.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agricultural plantings and physical facilities, assistance for peoples of Enewetak Atoll and Bikini Atoll</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior is further authorized to provide technical assistance to, and maintenance of agricultural plantings and physical facilities for, the peoples from Enewetak Atoll and Bikini Atoll, as well as for the purchase of food and equipment and for the transportation of such food, equipment and persons as he deems necessary and appropriate until such areas produce sufficient food to fully sustain the residents after resettlement. This provision shall not cease to be applicable either before or after the termination of the trusteeship without the express approval of the United States Congress.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Extension of programs administered by Department of Agriculture to Guam, Northern Mariana Islands, etc.</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture is authorized to extend, in his discretion, programs administered by the Department of Agriculture to Guam, the Northern Mariana Islands, the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, the Virgin Islands, and American Samoa (hereinafter called the territories). Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of Agriculture is authorized to waive or modify any statutory requirements relating to the provision of assistance under such programs when he deems it necessary in order to adapt the programs to the needs of the respective territory: <i>Provided</i>, That not less than sixty days prior to extending any program pursuant to this section or waiving or modifying any statutory requirement pursuant to this section, the Secretary of Agriculture shall notify the Committee on Agriculture and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate of his proposed action together with an explanation of why his action is necessary and the anticipated benefits to each territory affected. Such programs shall be carried out in cooperation with the respective governments of the territories and shall be covered by a memorandum of understanding between the respective territorial government and the Department of Agriculture. Any sums appropriated pursuant to this paragraph shall be allocated to the agencies of the Department of Agriculture concerned with the administration of programs in the territories.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Effective <date date="1981-10-01">October 1, 1981</date>, there are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–597, title VI, § 601</ref>, <date date="1980-12-24">Dec. 24, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 3479</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–437, § 17(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4595</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1469e.</num>
<heading> Insular government purchases</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Governments of the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, and the United States Virgin Islands are authorized to make purchases through the General Services Administration.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–247, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="1992-02-24">Feb. 24, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 38</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–187, title IV, § 406</ref>, <date date="2016-06-30">June 30, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 592</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1470.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 98–213, § 16(v)</ref>, <date date="1983-12-08">Dec. 8, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 1463</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1470a.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 1471 to 1479.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 98–213, § 16(w)</ref>–(ee), <date date="1983-12-08">Dec. 8, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 1463</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 1480 to 1480b.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 95–584, § 1</ref>, <date date="1978-11-02">Nov. 2, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2483</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 1481 to 1485.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 98–213, § 16(ff)</ref>–(jj), <date date="1983-12-08">Dec. 8, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 1463</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1486.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 87–826, § 3</ref>, <date date="1962-10-15">Oct. 15, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 953</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 1487, 1488.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 98–213, § 16(b)</ref>, (kk), <date date="1983-12-08">Dec. 8, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 1462</ref>, 1463</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1489.</num>
<heading> Loss of title of United States to lands in territories through adverse possession or prescription forbidden</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On and after <date date="1934-03-27">March 27, 1934</date>, no prescription or statute of limitations shall run, or continue to run, against the title of the United States to lands in any territory or possession or place or territory under the jurisdiction or control of the United States; and no title to any such lands of the United States or any right therein shall be acquired by adverse possession or prescription, or otherwise than by conveyance from the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 27, 1934, ch. 99</ref>, <ref>48 Stat. 507</ref>; Proc. No. 2695, eff. <date date="1946-07-04">July 4, 1946</date>, 11 F.R. 7517, <ref>60 Stat. 1352</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1490.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Mar. 3, 1933, ch. 202, § 1</ref>, <ref>47 Stat. 1428</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1491.</num>
<heading> License, permit, etc., for transportation for storage or storage of spent nuclear fuel or high-level radioactive waste; prerequisites; applicability; “territory or possession” defined</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Prior to the granting of any license, permit, or other authorization or permission by any agency or instrumentality of the United States to any person for the transportation of spent nuclear fuel or high-level radioactive waste for interim, long-term, or permanent storage to or for the storage of such fuel or waste on any territory or possession of the United States, the Secretary of the Interior is directed to transmit to the Congress a detailed report on the proposed transportation or storage plan, and no such license, permit, or other authorization or permission may be granted nor may any such transportation or storage occur unless the proposed transportation or storage plan has been specifically authorized by Act of Congress: <i>Provided</i>, That the provisions of this section shall not apply to the cleanup and rehabilitation of Bikini and Enewetak Atolls.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> For the purpose of this section the words “territory or possession” include the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands and any area not within the boundaries of the several States over which the United States claims or exercises sovereignty.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–205, title VI, § 605</ref>, <date date="1980-03-12">Mar. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 90</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1492.</num>
<heading> Energy resources of Caribbean and Pacific insular areas</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Congressional findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Caribbean and Pacific insular areas of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, the Northern Mariana Islands, the Federated States of Micronesia, the Marshall Islands, and Palau are virtually completely dependent on imported sources of energy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the dependence of such areas on imported sources of energy coupled with the increasing cost and the uncertain availability and supply of such sources of energy will continue to frustrate the political, social, and economic development of such areas by placing increasingly severe fiscal burdens on the local governments of these areas;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> these insular areas are endowed with a variety of renewable sources of energy which, if developed, would alleviate their dependence on imported sources of energy, relieve the fiscal burden on local governments imposed by the costs of imported fuel, and strengthen the base for political, social, and economic development;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> appropriate technologies are presently available to develop the renewable energy resources of these insular areas but that comprehensive energy plans have not been adequately developed to meet the energy demands of these areas from renewable energy resources;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> electric power transmission and distribution lines in insular areas are inadequate to withstand damage caused by the hurricanes and typhoons which frequently occur in insular areas and such damage often costs millions of dollars to repair; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the refinement of renewable energy technologies since the publication of the 1982 Territorial Energy Assessment prepared pursuant to subsection (c) reveals the need to reassess the state of energy production, consumption, infrastructure, reliance on imported energy, opportunities for energy conservation and increased energy efficiency, and indigenous sources in regard to the insular areas.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Congressional declaration of policy</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress declares that it is the policy of the Federal Government to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> develop the renewable energy resources of the Caribbean and Pacific insular areas of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, the Northern Mariana Islands, the Federated States of Micronesia, the Marshall Islands, and Palau; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to assist other insular areas in the Caribbean and Pacific Basin in the development of their renewable energy resources.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Comprehensive energy plan</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of Energy or any administrative official who may succeed him shall prepare a comprehensive energy plan with emphasis on indigenous renewable sources of energy for Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, the Northern Mariana Islands, the Federated States of Micronesia, the Marshall Islands and Palau. The plan shall be prepared with the approval of the Secretary of the Interior and in cooperation with the chief executive officer of each insular area by—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> surveying existing sources and uses of energy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> estimating future energy needs to the year 2020, giving due consideration to a range of economic development possibilities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> assessing, in depth, the availability and potential for development of indigenous energy sources, including solar, wind, hydropower, ocean current and tidal, biogas, biofuel, geothermal and ocean thermal energy conversion;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> assessing the mix of energy sources (including fossil fuels) and identifying those technologies that are needed to meet the projected demands for energy; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> drafting long-term energy plans for such insular areas with the objective of minimizing their reliance on energy imports and making maximum use of their indigenous energy resources.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Demonstration of cost effective renewable energy technologies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Energy or any administrative official who may succeed him, with the approval of the Secretary of the Interior, as part of the comprehensive energy planning may demonstrate those indigenous renewable energy technologies which are determined to be most cost effective through the use of existing programs and may implement any projects or programs contained in recommendations of the plan.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Updating of plans; submission to Congress</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of the Interior, in consultation with the Secretary of Energy and the head of government of each insular area, shall update the plans required under subsection (c) by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> updating the contents required by subsection (c);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> drafting long-term energy plans for such insular areas with the objective of reducing, to the extent feasible, their reliance on energy imports by the year 2012, increasing energy conservation and energy efficiency, and maximizing, to the extent feasible, use of indigenous energy sources; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> drafting long-term energy transmission line plans for such insular areas with the objective that the maximum percentage feasible of electric power transmission and distribution lines in each insular area be protected from damage caused by hurricanes and typhoons.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> In carrying out this subsection, the Secretary of Energy shall identify and evaluate the strategies or projects with the greatest potential for reducing the dependence on imported fossil fuels as used for the generation of electricity, including strategies and projects for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> improved supply-side efficiency of centralized electrical generation, transmission, and distribution systems;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> improved demand-side management through—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the application of established standards for energy efficiency for appliances;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the conduct of energy audits for business and industrial customers; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the use of energy savings performance contracts;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> increased use of renewable energy, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> solar thermal energy for electric generation;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> solar thermal energy for water heating in large buildings, such as hotels, hospitals, government buildings, and residences;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> photovoltaic energy;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> wind energy;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> hydroelectric energy;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> wave energy;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> energy from ocean thermal resources, including ocean thermal-cooling for community air conditioning;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> water vapor condensation for the production of potable water;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ix)</num>
<content> fossil fuel and renewable hybrid electrical generation systems; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(x)</num>
<content> other strategies or projects that the Secretary may identify as having significant potential; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> fuel substitution and minimization with indigenous biofuels, such as coconut oil.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> In carrying out this subsection, for each insular area with a significant need for distributed generation, the Secretary of Energy shall identify and evaluate the most promising strategies and projects described in subparagraphs (C) and (D) of paragraph (2) for meeting that need.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> In assessing the potential of any strategy or project under paragraphs (2) and (3), the Secretary of Energy shall consider—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> the estimated cost of the power or energy to be produced, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any additional costs associated with the distribution of the generation; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the long-term availability of the generation source;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the capacity of the local electrical utility to manage, operate, and maintain any project that may be undertaken; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> other factors the Secretary of Energy considers to be appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Not later than 1 year after <date date="2005-08-08">August 8, 2005</date>, the Secretary of the Interior shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate, the Committee on Resources of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives, the updated plans for each insular area required by this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are hereby authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Financial assistance</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Energy may grant financial assistance, not to exceed $2,000,000 annually, to insular area governments or private sector persons working in cooperation with insular area governments to carry out projects to evaluate the feasibility of, develop options for, and encourage the adoption of energy efficiency and renewable energy measures which reduce the dependency of the insular areas on imported fuels, improve the quality of the environment, and promote development in the insular areas.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any applicant for financial assistance under this subsection must evidence coordination and cooperation with, and support from, the affected local energy institutions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> In determining the amount of financial assistance to be provided for a proposed project, the Secretary shall consider—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> whether the measure will reduce the relative dependence of the insular area on imported fuels;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the ease and costs of operation and maintenance of any facilities contemplated as a part of the project;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> whether the project will rely on the use of conservation measures or indigenous, renewable energy resources that were identified in the 1982 Territorial Energy Assessment or that are identified by the Secretary as consistent with the purposes of this subsection;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> whether the measure will contribute significantly to development and the quality of the environment in the insular area; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> any other factors which the Secretary may determine to be relevant to a particular project.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Power line grants for insular areas.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the Interior is authorized to make grants to governments of insular areas of the United States to carry out eligible projects to protect electric power transmission and distribution lines in such insular areas from damage caused by hurricanes and typhoons.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Eligible projects</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of the Interior may award grants under subparagraph (A) only to governments of insular areas of the United States that submit written project plans to the Secretary for projects that meet the following criteria:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The project is designed to protect electric power transmission and distribution lines located in 1 or more of the insular areas of the United States from damage caused by hurricanes and typhoons.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The project is likely to substantially reduce the risk of future damage, hardship, loss, or suffering.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> The project addresses 1 or more problems that have been repetitive or that pose a significant risk to public health and safety.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> The project is not likely to cost more than the value of the reduction in direct damage and other negative impacts that the project is designed to prevent or mitigate. The cost benefit analysis required by this criterion shall be computed on a net present value basis.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> The project design has taken into consideration long-term changes to the areas and persons it is designed to protect and has manageable future maintenance and modification requirements.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> The project plan includes an analysis of a range of options to address the problem it is designed to prevent or mitigate and a justification for the selection of the project in light of that analysis.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> The applicant has demonstrated to the Secretary that the matching funds required by subparagraph (D) are available.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Priority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>When making grants under this paragraph, the Secretary of the Interior shall give priority to grants for projects which are likely to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> have the greatest impact on reducing future disaster losses; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> best conform with plans that have been approved by the Federal Government or the government of the insular area where the project is to be carried out for development or hazard mitigation for that insular area.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Matching requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Federal share of the cost for a project for which a grant is provided under this paragraph shall not exceed 75 percent of the total cost of that project. The non-Federal share of the cost may be provided in the form of cash or services.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Treatment of funds for certain purposes</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Grants provided under this paragraph shall not be considered as income, a resource, or a duplicative program when determining eligibility or benefit levels for Federal major disaster and emergency assistance.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authorization of appropriations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this paragraph $6,000,000 for each fiscal year beginning after <date date="2005-08-08">August 8, 2005</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> For the purposes of this subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the term “insular area” means American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Federated States of Micronesia, Guam, the Republic of the Marshall Islands, the Republic of Palau, and the Virgin Islands; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the term “1982 Territorial Energy Assessment” means the comprehensive energy plan prepared by the Secretary of Energy pursuant to subsection (c).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–597, title VI, § 604</ref>, <date date="1980-12-24">Dec. 24, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 3480</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–213, § 7</ref>, <date date="1983-12-08">Dec. 8, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 1460</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–486, title XXVII, § 2701</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 3118</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–58, title II, § 251</ref>, <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 679</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1492a.</num>
<heading> Study of electric rates in the insular areas</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Comprehensive energy plan</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “comprehensive energy plan” means a comprehensive energy plan prepared and updated under subsections (c) and (e) of <ref>section 1492 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Energy action plan</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “energy action plan” means the plan required by subsection (d).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Freely Associated States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Freely Associated States” means the Federated States of Micronesia, the Republic of the Marshall Islands, and the Republic of Palau.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Insular areas</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “insular areas” means American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, Puerto Rico, Guam, and the Virgin Islands.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of the Interior, except that, with respect to Puerto Rico, the term means, the Secretary of Energy.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Team</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “team” means the team established by the Secretary under subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2014-12-16">December 16, 2014</date> (except in the case of Puerto Rico, in which case not later than 270 days after <date date="2016-06-30">June 30, 2016</date>), the Secretary shall, within the Empowering Insular Communities activity (except in the case of Puerto Rico), establish a team of technical, policy, and financial experts—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to develop an energy action plan addressing the energy needs of each of the insular areas and Freely Associated States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to assist each of the insular areas and Freely Associated States in implementing such plan.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Participation of regional utility organizations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In establishing the team, the Secretary shall consider including regional utility organizations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Energy action plan</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In accordance with subsection (b), the energy action plan shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> recommendations, based on the comprehensive energy plan where applicable, to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> reduce reliance and expenditures on fuel shipped to the insular areas and Freely Associated States from ports outside the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> develop and utilize domestic fuel energy sources; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> improve performance of energy infrastructure and overall energy efficiency;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a schedule for implementation of such recommendations and identification and prioritization of specific projects;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a financial and engineering plan for implementing and sustaining projects; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> benchmarks for measuring progress toward implementation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports to Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after the date on which the Secretary establishes the team and annually thereafter, the team shall submit to the Secretary a report detailing progress made in fulfilling its charge and in implementing the energy action plan.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual reports to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 30 days after the date on which the Secretary receives a report submitted by the team under subsection (e), the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a summary of the report of the team.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Approval of Secretary required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The energy action plan shall not be implemented until the Secretary approves the energy action plan.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–235, § 9</ref>, <date date="2014-12-16">Dec. 16, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 2133</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–187, title V, § 505(d)</ref>, <date date="2016-06-30">June 30, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 602</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1493.</num>
<heading> Prosecution; authorization to seek review; local or Federal appellate courts; decisions, judgments or orders</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The prosecution in a territory or Commonwealth is authorized—unless precluded by local law—to seek review or other suitable relief in the appropriate local or Federal appellate court, or, where applicable, in the Supreme Court of the United States from—</chapeau>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> a decision, judgment, or order of a trial court dismissing an indictment or information as to any one or more counts, except that no review shall lie where the constitutional prohibition against double jeopardy would further prosecution;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> a decision or order of a trial court suppressing or excluding evidence or requiring the return of seized property in a criminal proceeding, not made after the defendant has been put in jeopardy and before the verdict or finding on an indictment or information, if the prosecution certifies to the trial court that the appeal is not taken for purpose of delay and that the evidence is a substantial proof of a fact material in the proceeding; and</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> an adverse decision, judgment, or order of an appellate court.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–454, title X, § 1003</ref>, <date date="1984-10-05">Oct. 5, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1746</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1494.</num>
<heading> Purposes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The purposes of sections 1494 to 1494c of this title are to improve enforcement of drug laws and enhance interdiction of illicit drug shipments in the Caribbean and Pacific territories and commonwealths of the United States and the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands (or successor governments) and to assist public and private sector drug abuse and other substance prevention and treatment programs in United States associated insular areas.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–570, title V, § 5002</ref>, <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3207–154</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title IX, § 9308</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4538</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1494a.</num>
<heading> Annual reports to Congress</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President shall report annually to the Congress as to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the efforts and success of Federal agencies in preventing the illegal entry into the United States of controlled substances from the insular areas of the United States outside the customs territory of the United States, the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, and states freely associated with the United States and the nature and extent of such illegal entry, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the efforts and success of Federal agencies in preventing the illegal entry from other nations, including states freely associated with the United States, of controlled substances into the United States territories, the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, and the commonwealths for use in the territories, the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, and commonwealths or for transshipment to the United States and the nature and extent of such illegal entry and use.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transmission date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The annual reports required by subsection (a) shall be transmitted to the Committee on Natural Resources of the United States House of Representatives and to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the United States Senate not later than the first day of October each year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–570, title V, § 5003</ref>, <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3207–155</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title IX, § 9309</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4539</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–437, § 17(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4595</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1494b.</num>
<heading> Enforcement and administration in insular areas</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> American Samoa</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> With the approval of the Attorney General of the United States or his designee, law enforcement officers of the Government of American Samoa are authorized to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> execute and serve warrants, subpoenas, and summons issued under the authority of the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> make arrests without warrant; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> make seizures of property to carry out the purposes of sections 1494 to 1494c of this title, the Controlled Substances Import and Export Act (<ref>21 U.S.C. 951–970</ref>), and any other applicable narcotics laws of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Attorney General and the Secretaries of Education and Health and Human Services of the United States, as appropriate, are authorized to and, upon request of the Government of American Samoa, shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> train law enforcement officers and other personnel of the Government of American Samoa, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provide by purchase or lease law enforcement equipment and technical assistance to the Government of American Samoa to carry out the purposes of sections 1494 to 1494c of this title and any other Federal or territorial drug or other substance abuse laws.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> There are authorized to be appropriated $350,000 for fiscal year 1989 and annually thereafter for grants to the Government of American Samoa to be expended in accordance with a plan approved by the Secretary of the Interior in consultation with the Attorney General and the Secretaries of Education and Health and Human Services to carry out the purposes of sections 1494 to 1494c of this title, to remain available until expended.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Treasury in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior shall provide the Government of American Samoa with a vessel to be used in the enforcement of narcotics and other laws. There are authorized to be appropriated $500,000 for this purpose.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Guam</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Attorney General and the Secretaries of Education and Health and Human Services of the United States may provide and, upon request of the Government of Guam, shall provide appropriate training, technical assistance and equipment to the Government of Guam to carry out the purposes of sections 1494 to 1494c of this title and any other Federal or territorial drug or other substance abuse law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> There are authorized to be appropriated $500,000 for fiscal year 1989 and annually thereafter for grants to the Government of Guam to be expended in accordance with a plan approved by the Secretary of the Interior in consultation with the Attorney General and the Secretaries of Education and Health and Human Services, to carry out the purposes of sections 1494 to 1494c of this title, to remain available until expended.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> There are authorized to be appropriated to the Government of Guam $500,000 for grants to be expended in accordance with a plan approved by the Secretary of the Interior in consultation with the Attorney General for drug abuse law enforcement equipment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Northern Mariana Islands</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> With the approval of the Attorney General of the United States or his designee, law enforcement officers of the Government of the Northern Mariana Islands are authorized to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> execute and serve warrants, subpoenas, and summons issued under the authority of the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> make arrests without warrant; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> make seizures of property to carry out the purposes of sections 1494 to 1494c of this title, the Controlled Substances Import and Export Act (<ref>21 U.S.C. 951–970</ref>), and any other applicable narcotics laws of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Attorney General and the Secretaries of Education and Health and Human Services of the United States, as appropriate, are authorized to and, upon request of the Government of the Northern Mariana Islands, shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> train law enforcement officers and other personnel of the Government of the Northern Mariana Islands, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provide, by purchase or lease, law enforcement equipment and technical assistance to the Government of the Northern Mariana Islands to carry out the purposes of sections 1494 to 1494c of this title and any other Federal or commonwealth drug or other substance abuse law.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> There are authorized to be appropriated $125,000 for fiscal year 1989 and annually thereafter for grants to the Government of the Northern Mariana Islands to be expended in accordance with a plan approved by the Secretary of the Interior in consultation with the Attorney General and the Secretaries of Education and Health and Human Services to carry out the purposes of sections 1494 to 1494c of this title, to remain available until expended.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Federal personnel and equipment assigned to Guam pursuant to subsection (b) of this section shall also be available to carry out the purposes of sections 1494 to 1494c of this title in the Northern Mariana Islands.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Puerto Rico</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> There are authorized to be appropriated for grants to the Government of Puerto Rico $7,000,000 for fiscal year 1989 and $2,000,000 annually thereafter for grants to the Government of Puerto Rico to carry out the purposes of sections 1494 to 1494c of this title to be expended in accordance with a plan approved by the Executive Director of the White House Task Force on Puerto Rico in consultation with the Attorney General and the Secretaries of Education and Health and Human Services, to remain available until expended.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The United States Customs Service should station an aerostat in Puerto Rico.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Equipment provided to the Government of Puerto Rico pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be made available upon request to the Federal agencies involved in drug interdiction in Puerto Rico.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Attorney General and the Secretaries of Education and Health and Human Services of the United States may provide and, upon request of the Government of Puerto Rico, shall provide appropriate training, technical assistance and equipment to the Government of Puerto Rico to carry out the purposes of sections 1494 to 1494c of this title and any other Federal or commonwealth drug or other substance abuse law.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out subparagraph (A). Funds appropriated under this subparagraph shall remain available until expended.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Virgin Islands</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> There are authorized to be appropriated for grants to the Government of the Virgin Islands, $2,000,000 for fiscal year 1990 and annually thereafter to carry out the purposes of sections 1494 to 1494c of this title to be expended in accordance with a plan approved by the Secretary of the Interior in consultation with the Attorney General and the Secretaries of Education and Health and Human Services, to remain available until expended.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The United States Coast Guard shall station a patrol vessel in St. Croix, Virgin Islands.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Attorney General and the Secretaries of Education and Health and Human Services of the United States may provide and, upon request of the Government of the Virgin Islands, shall provide appropriate training, technical assistance and equipment to the Government of the United States Virgin Islands to carry out the purposes of sections 1494 to 1494c of this title and any other Federal or territorial drug or other substance abuse law.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out subparagraph (A). Funds appropriated under this subparagraph shall remain available until expended.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> To assist in the prosecution of the violation of the narcotics laws of the United States, the Attorney General of the United States shall assign the necessary personnel to serve in the office of the United States Attorney for the Virgin Islands appointed pursuant to <ref>section 1617 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Effective fiscal year 1989, there are authorized to be appropriated for a grant to the Government of the Virgin Islands $2,500,000 to be expended in accordance with a plan approved by the Secretary of the Interior in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services for a substance abuse facility.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Palau</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Attorney General and the Secretaries of Education and Health and Human Services are authorized to and, upon request of the Government of Palau, shall provide appropriate training, technical assistance, and equipment to carry out the purposes of sections 1494 to 1494c of this title and any other applicable Federal or insular drug or other substance abuse laws.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> There are authorized to be appropriated $500,000 for fiscal year 1989 and annually thereafter for grants to the Government of Palau to be expended in accordance with a plan to be approved by the Secretary of the Interior in consultation with the Attorney General and the Secretaries of Education, State, and Health and Human Services to carry out the purposes of sections 1494 to 1494c of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> To the extent not prohibited under the Constitution of Palau, upon written request of the President of Palau, the Drug Enforcement Administration, the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the Secret Service, the Immigration and Naturalization Service, and the Customs Service are authorized to investigate any United States criminal laws which are applicable in Palau in cooperation with law enforcement agencies of Palau.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–570, title V, § 5004</ref>, <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3207–155</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title IX</ref>, §§ 9302–9305, 9306(b), 9307, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4536–4538</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1494c.</num>
<heading> Drug Enforcement Agency personnel assignments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To assist in the enforcement of the controlled substances laws of the United States in coordination with law enforcement officers in insular areas in the eastern Caribbean and in the central and western Pacific, the Administrator of the Drug Enforcement Administration shall assign appropriate personnel and other resources to the Virgin Islands and Guam.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–570, title V, § 5005</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title IX, § 9310</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4539</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>