<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 31—</num>
<heading>NATIVE AMERICAN LANGUAGES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2901.</num>
<heading> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the status of the cultures and languages of Native Americans is unique and the United States has the responsibility to act together with Native Americans to ensure the survival of these unique cultures and languages;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> special status is accorded Native Americans in the United States, a status that recognizes distinct cultural and political rights, including the right to continue separate identities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the traditional languages of Native Americans are an integral part of their cultures and identities and form the basic medium for the transmission, and thus survival, of Native American cultures, literatures, histories, religions, political institutions, and values;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> there is a widespread practice of treating Native Americans <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002194">1</ref> languages as if they were anachronisms;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> there is a lack of clear, comprehensive, and consistent Federal policy on treatment of Native American languages which has often resulted in acts of suppression and extermination of Native American languages and cultures;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> there is convincing evidence that student achievement and performance, community and school pride, and educational opportunity is clearly and directly tied to respect for, and support of, the first language of the child or student;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> it is clearly in the interests of the United States, individual States, and territories to encourage the full academic and human potential achievements of all students and citizens and to take steps to realize these ends;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> acts of suppression and extermination directed against Native American languages and cultures are in conflict with the United States policy of self-determination for Native Americans;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> languages are the means of communication for the full range of human experiences and are critical to the survival of cultural and political integrity of any people; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> language provides a direct and powerful means of promoting international communication by people who share languages.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–477, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1990-10-30">Oct. 30, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1153</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2902.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “Native American” means an Indian, Native Hawaiian, or Native American Pacific Islander.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “Indian” has the meaning given to such term under <ref>section 7491(3) of title 20</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “Native Hawaiian” has the meaning given to such term by <ref>section 7517 of title 20</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “Native American Pacific Islander” means any descendent of the aboriginal people of any island in the Pacific Ocean that is a territory or possession of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The terms “Indian tribe” and “tribal organization” have the respective meaning given to each of such terms under <ref>section 5304 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The term “Native American language” means the historical, traditional languages spoken by Native Americans.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The term “traditional leaders” includes Native Americans who have special expertise in Native American culture and Native American languages.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> The term “Indian reservation” has the same meaning given to the term “reservation” under <ref>section 1452 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–477, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1990-10-30">Oct. 30, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1154</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–109, § 11</ref>, <date date="1996-02-12">Feb. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 765</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–110, title VII, § 702(f)</ref>, <date date="2002-01-08">Jan. 8, 2002</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1947</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–95, title IX, § 9215(iii)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-10">Dec. 10, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 2187</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2903.</num>
<heading> Declaration of policy</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the policy of the United States to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> preserve, protect, and promote the rights and freedom of Native Americans to use, practice, and develop Native American languages;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> allow exceptions to teacher certification requirements for Federal programs, and programs funded in whole or in part by the Federal Government, for instruction in Native American languages when such teacher certification requirements hinder the employment of qualified teachers who teach in Native American languages, and to encourage State and territorial governments to make similar exceptions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> encourage and support the use of Native American languages as a medium of instruction in order to encourage and support—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Native American language survival,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> educational opportunity,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> increased student success and performance,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> increased student awareness and knowledge of their culture and history, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> increased student and community pride;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> encourage State and local education programs to work with Native American parents, educators, Indian tribes, and other Native American governing bodies in the implementation of programs to put this policy into effect;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> recognize the right of Indian tribes and other Native American governing bodies to use the Native American languages as a medium of instruction in all schools funded by the Secretary of the Interior;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> fully recognize the inherent right of Indian tribes and other Native American governing bodies, States, territories, and possessions of the United States to take action on, and give official status to, their Native American languages for the purpose of conducting their own business;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> support the granting of comparable proficiency achieved through course work in a Native American language the same academic credit as comparable proficiency achieved through course work in a foreign language, with recognition of such Native American language proficiency by institutions of higher education as fulfilling foreign language entrance or degree requirements; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> encourage all institutions of elementary, secondary and higher education, where appropriate, to include Native American languages in the curriculum in the same manner as foreign languages and to grant proficiency in Native American languages the same full academic credit as proficiency in foreign languages.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–477, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="1990-10-30">Oct. 30, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1155</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2904.</num>
<heading> No restrictions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The right of Native Americans to express themselves through the use of Native American languages shall not be restricted in any public proceeding, including publicly supported education programs.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–477, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1990-10-30">Oct. 30, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1155</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2905.</num>
<heading> Evaluations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The President shall direct the heads of the various Federal departments, agencies, and instrumentalities to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> evaluate their policies and procedures in consultation with Indian tribes and other Native American governing bodies as well as traditional leaders and educators in order to determine and implement changes needed to bring the policies and procedures into compliance with the provisions of this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> give the greatest effect possible in making such evaluations, absent a clear specific Federal statutory requirement to the contrary, to the policies and procedures which will give the broadest effect to the provisions of this chapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> evaluate the laws which they administer and make recommendations to the President on amendments needed to bring such laws into compliance with the provisions of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> By no later than the date that is 1 year after <date date="1990-10-30">October 30, 1990</date>, the President shall submit to the Congress a report containing recommendations for amendments to Federal laws that are needed to bring such laws into compliance with the provisions of this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Evaluation; report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2023-01-05">January 5, 2023</date>, the President shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> require the heads of the various Federal departments, agencies, and instrumentalities to carry out an evaluation described in subsection (a)(1); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> submit to Congress a report that describes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the results of the evaluations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> the recommendations of the Secretary of the Interior, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, and the Secretary of Education, after consultation with Indian tribes, traditional leaders, and representatives of Native American language communities, for amendments to Federal laws that are needed—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> to bring the Federal laws into compliance with this chapter;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> to improve interagency coordination for purposes of supporting revitalization, maintenance, and use of Native American languages; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> to reduce duplication, inefficiencies, and barriers Native American language communities face in accessing Federal programs to support efforts to revitalize, maintain, or increase the use of Native American languages.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–477, title I, § 106</ref>, <date date="1990-10-30">Oct. 30, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1156</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–337, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2023-01-05">Jan. 5, 2023</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 6153</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2906.</num>
<heading> Use of English</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed as precluding the use of Federal funds to teach English to Native Americans.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–477, title I, § 107</ref>, <date date="1990-10-30">Oct. 30, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1156</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2907.</num>
<heading> Survey on Native American languages</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 18 months after <date date="2023-01-05">January 5, 2023</date>, and every 5 years thereafter, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Commissioner of the Administration for Native Americans (referred to in this section as the “Secretary”), shall undertake a survey of the use of all Native American languages in the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Updates</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Prior to conducting each subsequent survey after the initial survey under subsection (a), the Secretary shall update the survey in accordance with this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation required</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall design the initial survey under subsection (a) and each updated survey under subsection (b)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in consultation with Indian tribes; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> after considering feedback received from Native American language speakers and experts.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each survey under subsection (a) shall solicit—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> information on which Native American languages are currently spoken;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> estimates of the number of speakers of each Native American language;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> any language usage statistics or information that the Secretary, in consultation with Indian tribes and Native American language speakers and experts, determines to be relevant and appropriate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> information on the types of Native American language maintenance and revitalization projects and practices that are currently being carried out;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> information on any unmet Native American language resource needs of Indian tribes and Native American language communities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> any other information that the Secretary, in consultation with Indian tribes and Native American language speakers and experts, determines to be necessary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may coordinate, and enter into cooperative agreements with, the Director of the Bureau of the Census for the purposes of carrying out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Outreach and engagement</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary shall carry out outreach and engagement activities to provide Indian tribes, Native American language communities, and the public information about—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> opportunities to provide input on the development and design of each survey under subsection (a), including information on the consultations required under subsection (c);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the goals and purpose of the surveys conducted under subsection (a); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the benefits and importance of participation in surveys under subsection (a).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grants, contracts, and cooperative agreements authorized</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary may carry out the outreach and engagement activities required under paragraph (1)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> directly;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in partnership with the Bureau of the Census; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> through grants to, or contracts or cooperative agreements with—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Indian tribes;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> tribal organizations; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> nonprofit organizations that work with Indian tribes, Native American language programs, and Native American language communities.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Nothing in this section requires an Indian tribe, Native American language community, or Native American language speaker—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to participate in a survey under subsection (a); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to provide specific or culturally sensitive information in completing such a survey.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability of survey materials and findings</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2023-01-05">January 5, 2023</date>, and prior to conducting each survey under subsection (a), the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Indian Affairs of the Senate and the Committees on Education and Labor and Natural Resources of the House of Representatives, and make publicly available, a description of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the feedback received under subsection (c) on the design of the survey;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the form and content of the survey;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the plan for deploying the survey to ensure a robust response; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> how the Secretary will ensure any survey enumeration efforts are culturally informed and appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Results</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 90 days after the date on which analysis of each survey under subsection (a) is completed, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Indian Affairs of the Senate and the Committees on Education and Labor and Natural Resources of the House of Representatives, and make publicly available, the results of the survey.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $1,500,000 for each fiscal year—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> preceding a fiscal year during which a survey under subsection (a) is conducted; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> during which a survey under that subsection is conducted.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–477, title I, § 108</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 117–337, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="2023-01-05">Jan. 5, 2023</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 6153</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>