<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 33—</num>
<heading>NATIONAL INDIAN FOREST RESOURCES MANAGEMENT</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3101.</num>
<heading> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress finds and declares that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the forest lands of Indians are among their most valuable resources and Indian forest lands—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> encompass more than 15,990,000 acres, including more than 5,700,000 acres of commercial forest land and 8,700,000 acres of woodland,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> are a perpetually renewable and manageable resource,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> provide economic benefits, including income, employment, and subsistence, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> provide natural benefits, including ecological, cultural, and esthetic values;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the United States has a trust responsibility toward Indian forest lands;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> existing Federal laws do not sufficiently assure the adequate and necessary trust management of Indian forest lands;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the Federal investment in, and the management of, Indian forest land is significantly below the level of investment in, and management of, National Forest Service forest land, Bureau of Land Management forest land, or private forest land;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> tribal governments make substantial contributions to the overall management of Indian forest land; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> there is a serious threat to Indian forest lands arising from trespass and unauthorized harvesting of Indian forest land resources.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–630, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4532</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3102.</num>
<heading> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes of this chapter are to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> allow the Secretary of the Interior to take part in the management of Indian forest lands, with the participation of the lands’ beneficial owners, in a manner consistent with the Secretary’s trust responsibility and with the objectives of the beneficial owners;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> clarify the authority of the Secretary to make deductions from the proceeds of sale of Indian forest products, assure the use of such deductions on the reservation from which they are derived solely for use in forest land management activities, and assure that no other deductions shall be collected;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> increase the number of professional Indian foresters and related staff in forestry programs on Indian forest land; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> provide for the authorization of necessary appropriations to carry out this chapter for the protection, conservation, utilization, management, and enhancement of Indian forest lands.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–630, title III, § 303</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4532</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3103.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For the purposes of this chapter, the term—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “Alaska Native” means Native as defined in <ref>section 1602(b) of title 43</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> “forest” means an ecosystem of at least one acre in size, including timberland and woodland, which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is characterized by a more or less dense and extensive tree cover,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> contains, or once contained, at least ten percent tree crown cover, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> is not developed or planned for exclusive nonforest use;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> “Indian forest land” means Indian lands, including commercial and non-commercial timberland and woodland, that are considered chiefly valuable for the production of forest products or to maintain watershed or other land values enhanced by a forest cover, regardless whether a formal inspection and land classification action has been taken;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> “forest land management activities” means all activities performed in the management of Indian forest lands, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> all aspects of program administration and executive direction such as—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> development and maintenance of policy and operational procedures, program oversight, and evaluation,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> securing of legal assistance and handling of legal matters,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> budget, finance, and personnel management, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> development and maintenance of necessary data bases and program reports;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> all aspects of the development, preparation and revision of forest inventory and management plans, including aerial photography, mapping, field management inventories and re-inventories, inventory analysis, growth studies, allowable annual cut calculations, environmental assessment, and forest history, consistent with and reflective of tribal integrated resource management plans;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> forest land development, including forestation, thinning, tree improvement activities, and the use of silvicultural treatments to restore or increase growth and yield to the full productive capacity of the forest environment;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> protection against losses from wildfire, including acquisition and maintenance of fire fighting equipment and fire detection systems, construction of firebreaks, hazard reduction, prescribed burning, and the development of cooperative wildfire management agreements;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<chapeau> protection against insects and disease, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> all aspects of detection and evaluation,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> preparation of project proposals containing project description, environmental assessments and statements, and cost-benefit analyses necessary to secure funding,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> field suppression operations, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> reporting;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> assessment of damage caused by forest trespass, infestation or fire, including field examination and survey, damage appraisal, investigation assistance, and report, demand letter, and testimony preparation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<chapeau> all aspects of the preparation, administration, and supervision of timber sale contracts, paid and free use permits, and other Indian forest product harvest sale documents including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> cruising, product marking, silvicultural prescription, appraisal and harvest supervision,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> forest product marketing assistance, including evaluation of marketing and development opportunities related to Indian forest products and consultation and advice to tribes, tribal and Indian enterprises on maximization of return on forest products,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> archeological, historical, environmental and other land management reviews, clearances, and analyses,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> advertising, executing, and supervising contracts,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> marking and scaling of timber, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> collecting, recording and distributing receipts from sales;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> provision of financial assistance for the education of Indians enrolled in accredited programs of postsecondary and postgraduate forestry and forestry-related fields of study, including the provision of scholarships, internships, relocation assistance, and other forms of assistance to cover educational expenses;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> participation in the development and implementation of tribal integrated resource management plans, including activities to coordinate current and future multiple uses of Indian forest lands;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> improvement and maintenance of extended season primary and secondary Indian forest land road systems; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> research activities to improve the basis for determining appropriate management measures to apply to Indian forest lands;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> “forest management plan” means the principal document, approved by the Secretary, reflecting and consistent with a tribal integrated resource management plan, which provides for the regulation of the detailed, multiple-use operation of Indian forest land by methods assuring that such lands remain in a continuously productive state while meeting the objectives of the tribe and which shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> standards setting forth the funding and staffing requirements necessary to carry out each management plan, with a report of current forestry funding and staffing levels; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> standards providing quantitative criteria to evaluate performance against the objectives set forth in the plan;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> “forest product” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> timber,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a timber product, including lumber, lath, crating, ties, bolts, logs, pulpwood, fuelwood, posts, poles and split products,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> bark,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Christmas trees, stays, branches, firewood, berries, mosses, pinyon nuts, roots, acorns, syrups, wild rice, and herbs,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> other marketable material, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> gravel which is extracted from, and utilized on, Indian forest lands;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> “forest resources” means all the benefits derived from Indian forest lands, including forest products, soil productivity, water, fisheries, wildlife, recreation, and aesthetic or other traditional values of Indian forest lands;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> “forest trespass” means the act of illegally removing forest products from, or illegally damaging forest products on, forest lands;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> “Indian” means a member of an Indian tribe;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<chapeau> “Indian land” means land title to which is held by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the United States in trust for an Indian, an individual of Indian or Alaska Native ancestry who is not a member of a federally-recognized Indian tribe, or an Indian tribe, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an Indian, an individual of Indian or Alaska Native ancestry who is not a member of a federally recognized tribe, or an Indian tribe subject to a restriction by the United States against alienation;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> “Indian tribe” or “tribe” means any Indian tribe, band, nation, Pueblo or other organized group or community which is recognized as eligible for the special programs and services provided by the United States to Indians because of their status as Indians and shall mean, where appropriate, the recognized tribal government of such tribe’s reservation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> “reservation” includes Indian reservations established pursuant to treaties, Acts of Congress or Executive orders, public domain Indian allotments, and former Indian reservations in Oklahoma;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> “Secretary” means the Secretary of the Interior;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> “sustained yield” means the yield of forest products that a forest can produce continuously at a given intensity of management; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<content> “tribal integrated resource management plan” means a document, approved by an Indian tribe and the Secretary, which provides coordination for the comprehensive management of such tribe’s natural resources.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–630, title III, § 304</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4533</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3104.</num>
<heading> Management of Indian forest land</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Management activities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall undertake forest land management activities on Indian forest land, either directly or through contracts, cooperative agreements, or grants under the Indian Self-Determination Act [<ref>25 U.S.C. 5321</ref> et seq.].</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Management objectives</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Indian forest land management activities undertaken by the Secretary shall be designed to achieve the following objectives—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the development, maintenance, and enhancement of Indian forest land in a perpetually productive state in accordance with the principles of sustained yield and with the standards and objectives set forth in forest management plans by providing effective management and protection through the application of sound silvicultural and economic principles to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the harvesting of forest products,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> forestation,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> timber stand improvement, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> other forestry practices;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the regulation of Indian forest lands through the development and implementation, with the full and active consultation and participation of the appropriate Indian tribe, of forest management plans which are supported by written tribal objectives and forest marketing programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the regulation of Indian forest lands in a manner that will ensure the use of good method and order in harvesting so as to make possible, on a sustained yield basis, continuous productivity and a perpetual forest business;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the development of Indian forest lands and associated value-added industries by Indians and Indian tribes to promote self-sustaining communities, so that Indians may receive from their Indian forest land not only stumpage value, but also the benefit of all the labor and profit that such Indian forest land is capable of yielding;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the retention of Indian forest land in its natural state when an Indian tribe determines that the recreational, cultural, aesthetic, or traditional values of the Indian forest land represents the highest and best use of the land;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the management and protection of forest resources to retain the beneficial effects to Indian forest lands of regulating water run-off and minimizing soil erosion; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the maintenance and improvement of timber productivity, grazing, wildlife, fisheries, recreation, aesthetic, cultural and other traditional values.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–630, title III, § 305</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4535</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3105.</num>
<heading> Forest management deduction</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Withholding of deduction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Pursuant to the authority of <ref>section 413 of this title</ref>, the Secretary shall withhold a reasonable deduction from the gross proceeds of sales of forest products harvested from Indian forest land under a timber sale contract, permit, or other harvest sale document, which has been approved by the Secretary, to cover in whole or part the cost of managing and protecting such Indian forest land.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amount of deduction</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Deductions made pursuant to subsection (a) shall not exceed the lesser amount of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> 10 percent of gross proceeds, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the percentage of gross proceeds collected on <date date="1990-11-28">November 28, 1990</date>, as forest management deductions by the Secretary on such sales of Indian forest products,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">unless the appropriate Indian tribe consents to an increase in the deductions.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of deduction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The full amount of any deduction collected by the Secretary shall be expended according to an approved expenditure plan, approved by the Secretary and the appropriate Indian tribe, for the performance of forest land management activities on the reservation from which such deductions are collected and shall be made available to the tribe, upon its request, by contract or agreement for the performance of such activities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Forest management deductions withheld pursuant to this section shall not be available to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> cover the costs that are paid from funds appropriated specifically for fire suppression or pest control, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> otherwise offset Federal appropriations for meeting the Federal trust responsibility for management of Indian forest lands.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> No other forest management deductions derived from Indian forest lands shall be collected to be covered into the general funds of the United States Treasury.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–630, title III, § 306</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4536</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3106.</num>
<heading> Forest trespass</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Civil penalties; regulations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 18 months from <date date="1990-11-28">November 28, 1990</date>, the Secretary shall issue regulations that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> establish civil penalties for the commission of forest trespass which provide for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> collection of the value of the products illegally removed plus a penalty of double their value,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> collection of the costs associated with damage to the Indian forest land caused by the act of trespass, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> collection of the costs associated with enforcement of the regulations, including field examination and survey, damage appraisal, investigation assistance and reports, witness expenses, demand letters, court costs, and attorney fees;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> designate responsibility with the Department of the Interior for the detection and investigation of forest trespass; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> set forth responsibilities and procedures for the assessment and collection of civil penalties.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment of proceeds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The proceeds of civil penalties collected under this section shall be treated as proceeds from the sale of forest products from the Indian forest lands upon which such trespass occurred.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Concurrent jurisdiction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Indian tribes which adopt the regulations promulgated by the Secretary pursuant to subsection (a) shall have concurrent civil jurisdiction to enforce the provisions of this section and the regulation promulgated thereunder. The Bureau of Indian Affairs and other agencies of the Federal Government shall, at the request of the tribe, defer to tribal prosecutions of forest trespass cases. Tribal court judgments regarding forest trespass shall be entitled to full faith and credit in Federal and State courts to the same extent as a Federal court judgment obtained under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–630, title III, § 307</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4537</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3107.</num>
<heading> Direct payment of forest products receipts</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other law, the Secretary shall, within 1 year from <date date="1990-11-28">November 28, 1990</date>, promulgate regulations providing for the payment of the receipts from the sale of Indian forest products as provided in this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payment into a bank depository</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon the request of an Indian tribe, the Secretary shall provide that the purchaser of the forest products of such tribe, which are harvested under a timber sale contract, permit or other harvest sale document which has been approved by the Secretary, shall make prompt direct payments of the gross proceeds of sales of such forest products, less any amounts segregated as forest management deductions pursuant to <ref>section 3105 of this title</ref>, into a bank depository account designated by such Indian tribe.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–630, title III, § 308</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4537</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3108.</num>
<heading> Secretarial recognition of tribal laws</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subject to the Secretary’s responsibilities as reflected in sections 3101(2) and 3102(1) of this title and unless otherwise prohibited by Federal statutory law, the Secretary shall comply with tribal laws pertaining to Indian forest lands, including laws regulating the environment or historic or cultural preservation, and shall cooperate with the enforcement of such laws on Indian forest lands. Such cooperation shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> assistance in the enforcement of such laws;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provision of notice of such laws to persons or entities undertaking activities on Indian forest lands; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> upon the request of an Indian tribe, the appearance in tribal forums.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–630, title III, § 309</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4538</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3109.</num>
<heading> Indian forest land assistance account</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">At the request of an Indian tribe, the Secretary may establish a special Indian forest land assistance account within the tribe’s trust fund account to fund the Indian forest land management activities of such tribe.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deposits and expenditures</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary may deposit into the Indian forest land assistance account established pursuant to subsection (a) any funds received by the Secretary or in the Secretary’s possession from—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> non-Federal sources, if such funds are related to activities on or for the Indian forest lands of such tribe’s reservation,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> donations and contributions,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> unobligated forestry appropriations for the benefit of such Indian tribe, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> user fees or other funds transferred under Federal interagency agreements if otherwise authorized by Federal law and, if such funds are related to activities on or for the Indian forest lands of such tribe’s reservation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Funds deposited in such account shall be for the purpose of conducting forest land management activities on the Indian forest lands of such tribe.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Funds in the Indian forest land assistance account and any interest or other income earned thereon shall remain available until expended and shall not be available to otherwise offset Federal appropriations for meeting the Federal responsibility for management of Indian forest lands.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Audits</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">At the request of an Indian tribe or upon the Secretary’s own volition, the Secretary may conduct audits of the Indian forest land assistance account and shall publish the results of such audit.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–630, title III, § 310</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4538</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3110.</num>
<heading> Tribal forestry programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish within the Bureau of Indian Affairs a program to provide financial support to forestry programs established by an Indian tribe.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Support allocation formula; criteria</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary, with the participation of Indian tribes with Indian forest lands, shall establish, and promulgate by regulations, a formula—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> for the determination of Indian tribes eligible for such support,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for the provision of levels of assistance for the forestry programs of such tribes, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the allocation of base support funds to such tribes under the program established pursuant to subsection (a).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The formula established pursuant to this subsection shall provide funding necessary to support—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> one professional forester, including fringe benefits and support costs, for each eligible tribe, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> one additional professional forester or forest technician, including fringe benefits and support costs, for each level of assistance for which an eligible Indian tribe qualifies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> In any fiscal year that appropriations are not sufficient to fully fund tribal forestry programs at each level of assistance under the formula required to be established in this section, available funds for each level of assistance shall be evenly divided among the tribes qualifying for that level of assistance.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–630, title III, § 311</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4538</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3111.</num>
<heading> Assessment of Indian forest land and management programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initial assessment</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Within 1 year after <date date="1990-11-28">November 28, 1990</date>, the Secretary, in consultation with affected Indian tribes, shall enter into a contract with a non-Federal entity knowledgeable in forest management practices on Federal and private lands to conduct an independent assessment of Indian forest lands and Indian forest land management practices.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Such assessment shall be national in scope and shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an in-depth analysis of management practices on, and the level of funding for, specific Indian forest land compared with similar Federal and private forest lands,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a survey of the condition of Indian forest lands, including health and productivity levels,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> an evaluation of the staffing patterns of forestry organizations of the Bureau of Indian Affairs and of Indian tribes,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> an evaluation of procedures employed in timber sales administration, including preparation, field supervision, and accountability for proceeds,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> an analysis of the potential for reducing or eliminating relevant administrative procedures, rules and policies of the Bureau of Indian Affairs consistent with the Federal trust responsibility,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> a comprehensive review of the adequacy of Indian forest land management plans, including their compatibility with applicable tribal integrated resource management plans and their ability to meet tribal needs and priorities,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> an evaluation of the feasibility and desirability of establishing minimum standards against which the adequacy of the forestry programs of the Bureau of Indian Affairs in fulfilling its trust responsibility to Indian tribes can be measured, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> a recommendation of any reforms and increased funding levels necessary to bring Indian forest land management programs to a state-of-the-art condition.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Such assessment shall include specific examples and comparisons from each of the regions of the United States where Indian forest lands are located.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The initial assessment required by this subsection shall be completed no later than 36 months following <date date="1990-11-28">November 28, 1990</date>. Upon completion, the assessment shall be submitted to the Committee on Natural Resources of the United States House of Representatives and the Committee on Indian Affairs of the United States Senate and shall be made available to Indian tribes.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Periodic assessments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On each 10-year anniversary of <date date="1990-11-28">November 28, 1990</date>, the Secretary shall provide for an independent assessment of Indian forest lands and Indian forest land management practices under the criteria established in subsection (a) which shall include analyses measured against findings in previous assessments.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Status report to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall submit, within 1 year of the first full fiscal year after <date date="1990-11-28">November 28, 1990</date>, and within 6 months of the end of each succeeding fiscal year, a report to the Committee on Natural Resources of the United States House of Representatives, the Committee on Indian Affairs of the United States Senate, and to the affected Indian tribes a report on the status of Indian forest lands with respect to standards, goals and objectives set forth in approved forest management plans for each Indian tribe with Indian forest lands. The report shall identify the amount of Indian forest land in need of forestation or other silviculture treatment and the quantity of timber available for sale, offered for sale, and sold for each Indian tribe.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistance from Secretary of Agriculture</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture, through the Forest Service, is authorized to provide, upon the request of the Secretary of the Interior, on a nonreimbursable basis, technical assistance in the conduct of such research and evaluation activities as may be necessary for the completion of any reports or assessments required by this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–630, title III, § 312</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4539</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–437, § 10(f)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4589</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3112.</num>
<heading> Alaska Native technical assistance program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary, in consultation with the village and regional corporations established pursuant to the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<ref>43 U.S.C. 1601</ref> et seq.), shall establish a program of technical assistance for such corporations to promote the sustained yield management of their forest resources. Such technical assistance shall also be available to promote local processing and other value-added activities with such forest resources.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Indian Self-Determination Act</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The technical assistance to be provided by the Secretary pursuant to subsection (a) shall be made available through contracts, grants or agreements entered into in accordance with, and made available to entities eligible for, such contracts, grants, or agreements under the Indian Self-Determination Act [<ref>25 U.S.C. 5321</ref> et seq.].</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–630, title III, § 313</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4540</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3113.</num>
<heading> Establishment of Indian and Alaska Native forestry education assistance</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Forester intern program</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding the provisions of title 5 governing appointments in the competitive service, the Secretary shall establish and maintain in the Bureau of Indian Affairs at least 20 forester intern positions for Indian and Alaska Native students.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of this subsection, the term “forester intern” means an Indian or Alaska Native who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is acquiring necessary academic qualifications to become a forester or a professional trained in forestry-related fields, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is appointed to one of the positions established under paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall pay all costs for tuition, books, fees and living expenses incurred by a forester intern while attending an approved post-secondary or graduate school in a full-time forestry-related curriculum.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> A forester intern shall be required to enter into an obligated service agreement to serve as a professional forester or other forestry-related professional with the Bureau of Indian Affairs, an Indian tribe, or a tribal forest-related enterprise for 2 years for each year of education for which the Secretary pays the intern’s educational costs under paragraph (3) of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> A forester intern shall be required to report for service with the Bureau of Indian Affairs during any break in attendance at school of more than 3 weeks duration. Time spent in such service shall be counted toward satisfaction of the intern’s obligated service agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cooperative education program</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall maintain, through the Bureau of Indian Affairs, a cooperative education program for the purpose of recruiting promising Indian and Alaska Native students who are enrolled in secondary schools, tribally-controlled community colleges, and other post-secondary or graduate schools for employment as a professional forester or other forestry-related professional with the Bureau of Indian Affairs, an Indian tribe, or a tribal forest-related enterprise.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The cooperative educational program that is to be maintained under paragraph (1) shall be modeled on and shall have essentially the same features of the program operated on <date date="1990-11-28">November 28, 1990</date>, pursuant to chapter 308 of the Federal Personnel Manual of the Office of Personnel Management.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> Under the cooperative agreement program that is to be maintained under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall pay all costs for tuition, books, and fees of an Indian or Alaska Native student who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is enrolled in a course of study at an education institution with which the Secretary has entered into a cooperative agreement, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is interested in a career with the Bureau of Indian Affairs, an Indian tribe or a tribal enterprise in the management of Indian forest land.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Financial need shall not be a requirement to receive assistance under the cooperative agreement program that is to be maintained under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> A recipient of assistance under the cooperative education program that is to be maintained under this subsection shall be required to enter into an obligated service agreement to serve as a professional forester or other forestry-related professional with the Bureau of Indian Affairs, an Indian tribe, or a tribal forest-related enterprise for one year for each year for which the Secretary pays the recipient’s educational costs pursuant to paragraph (3).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Scholarship program</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary is authorized to grant forestry scholarships to Indians and Alaska Natives enrolled in accredited programs for post-secondary and graduate forestry and forestry-related programs of study as full-time students.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> A recipient of a scholarship under paragraph (1) shall be required to enter into an obligated service agreement with the Secretary in which the recipient agrees to accept employment for one year for each year the recipient received a scholarship, following completion of the recipient’s forestry or forestry-related course of study, with</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Bureau of Indian Affairs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a forestry program conducted under a contract, grant, or cooperative agreement entered into under the Indian Self-Determination Act [<ref>25 U.S.C. 5321</ref> et seq.];</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> an Indian enterprise engaged in a forestry or forestry-related business; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> an Indian tribe’s forestry-related program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall not deny scholarship assistance under this subsection solely on the basis of an applicant’s scholastic achievement if the applicant has been admitted to and remains in good standing in an accredited postsecondary or graduate institution.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Forestry education outreach</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall conduct, through the Bureau of Indian Affairs, and in consultation with other appropriate local, State and Federal agencies, and in consultation and coordination with Indian tribes, a forestry education outreach program for Indian and Alaska Native youth to explain and stimulate interest in all aspects of Indian forest land management and careers in forestry.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adequacy of programs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall administer the programs described in this section until a sufficient number of Indians and Alaska Natives are trained to ensure that there is an adequate number of qualified, professional Indian foresters to manage the Bureau of Indian Affairs forestry programs and forestry programs maintained by or for Indian tribes.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–630, title III, § 314</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4540</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3114.</num>
<heading> Postgraduation recruitment, education and training programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Postgraduation recruitment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish and maintain a program to attract Indian and Alaska Native professional foresters and forester technicians who have already graduated from their course of postsecondary or graduate education for employment in either the Bureau of Indian Affairs forestry programs or, subject to the approval of the tribe, in tribal forestry programs. According to such regulations as the Secretary may prescribe, such program shall provide for the employment of Indian and Alaska Native professional foresters or forestry technicians in exchange for the Secretary’s assumption of the employee’s outstanding student loans. The period of employment shall be determined by the amount of the loan that is assumed.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Postgraduate intergovernmental internships</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For the purposes of training, skill development and orientation of Indian, Alaska native,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002206">1</ref> and Federal forestry personnel, and the enhancement of tribal and Bureau of Indian Affairs forestry programs, the Secretary shall establish and actively conduct a program for the cooperative internship of Federal, Indian, and Alaska Native forestry personnel. Such program shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> for agencies within the Department of the Interior—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> provide for the internship of Bureau of Indian Affairs, Alaska Native, and Indian forestry employees in the forestry-related programs of other agencies of the Department of the Interior, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provide for the internship of forestry personnel from other Department of the Interior agencies within the Bureau of Indian Affairs and, with the consent of the tribe, within tribal forestry programs;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> for agencies not within the Department of the Interior, provide, pursuant to an interagency agreement, internships within the Bureau of Indian Affairs and, with the consent of the tribe, within a tribal forestry program of other forestry personnel of such agencies who are above their sixth year of Federal service;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> provide for the continuation of salary and benefits for participating Federal employees by their originating agency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> provide for salaries and benefits of participating Indian and Alaska Native forestry employees by the host agency; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> provide for a bonus pay incentive at the conclusion of the internship for any participant.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Continuing education and training</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall maintain a program within the Division of Forestry of the Bureau of Indian Affairs for the ongoing education and training of Bureau of Indian Affairs, Alaska Native, and Indian forestry personnel. Such program shall provide for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> orientation training for Bureau of Indian Affairs forestry personnel in tribal-Federal relations and responsibilities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> continuing technical forestry education for Bureau of Indian Affairs, Alaska Native, and tribal forestry personnel; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> developmental training of Indian and Alaska Native personnel in forest land based enterprises and marketing.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–630, title III, § 315</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4542</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3115.</num>
<heading> Cooperative agreement between Department of the Interior and Indian tribes</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cooperative agreements</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> To facilitate the administration of the programs and activities of the Department of the Interior, the Secretary is authorized to negotiate and enter into cooperative agreements with Indian tribes to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> engage in cooperative manpower and job training and development programs,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to develop and publish cooperative environmental education and natural resource planning materials, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to perform land and facility improvements, including forestry and other natural resources protection, fire protection, reforestation, timber stand improvement, debris removal, and other activities related to land and natural resource management.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">The Secretary may enter into such agreements when the Secretary determines the public interest will be benefited.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In such cooperative agreements, the Secretary is authorized to advance or reimburse funds to contractors from any appropriated funds available for similar kinds of work or by furnishing or sharing materials, supplies, facilities or equipment without regard to the provisions of section 3324, title 31, relating to the advance of public moneys.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Supervision</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In any agreement authorized by this section, Indian tribes and their employees may perform cooperative work under the supervision of the Department of the Interior in emergencies or otherwise as mutually agreed to, but shall not be deemed to be Federal employees other than for purposes of section <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002207">1</ref> 2671 through 2680 of title 28 and section <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002207">1</ref> 8101 through 8193 of title 5.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Savings provision</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to limit the authority of the Secretary to enter into cooperative agreements otherwise authorized by law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–630, title III, § 316</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4543</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3115a.</num>
<heading> Tribal forest assets protection</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this Act:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal land</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “Federal land” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> land of the National Forest System (as defined in <ref>section 1609(a) of title 16</ref>) administered by the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Chief of the Forest Service; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> public lands (as defined in <ref>section 1702 of title 43</ref>), the surface of which is administered by the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the Bureau of Land Management.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Indian forest land or rangeland</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “Indian forest land or rangeland” means land that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is held in trust by, or with a restriction against alienation by, the United States for an Indian tribe or a member of an Indian tribe; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> is Indian forest land (as defined in <ref>section 3103 of this title</ref>); or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> has a cover of grasses, brush, or any similar vegetation; or</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> formerly had a forest cover or vegetative cover that is capable of restoration.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Indian tribe</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Indian tribe” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 5304 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “Secretary” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Agriculture, with respect to land under the jurisdiction of the Forest Service; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Secretary of the Interior, with respect to land under the jurisdiction of the Bureau of Land Management.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority to protect Indian forest land or rangeland</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 120 days after the date on which an Indian tribe submits to the Secretary a request to enter into an agreement or contract to carry out a project to protect Indian forest land or rangeland (including a project to restore Federal land that borders on or is adjacent to Indian forest land or rangeland) that meets the criteria described in subsection (c), the Secretary may issue public notice of initiation of any necessary environmental review or of the potential of entering into an agreement or contract with the Indian tribe pursuant to section 347 of the Department of the Interior and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1999 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 2104</ref> note; <ref>Public Law 105–277</ref>) (as amended by section 323 of the Department of the Interior and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2003 (<ref>117 Stat. 275</ref>)), or such other authority as appropriate, under which the Indian tribe would carry out activities described in paragraph (3).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Environmental analysis</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Following completion of any necessary environmental analysis, the Secretary may enter into an agreement or contract with the Indian tribe as described in paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Activities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Under an agreement or contract entered into under paragraph (2), the Indian tribe may carry out activities to achieve land management goals for Federal land that is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> under the jurisdiction of the Secretary; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> bordering or adjacent to the Indian forest land or rangeland under the jurisdiction of the Indian tribe.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Selection criteria</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The criteria referred to in subsection (b), with respect to an Indian tribe, are whether—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Indian forest land or rangeland under the jurisdiction of the Indian tribe borders on or is adjacent to land under the jurisdiction of the Forest Service or the Bureau of Land Management;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Forest Service or Bureau of Land Management land bordering on or adjacent to the Indian forest land or rangeland under the jurisdiction of the Indian tribe—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> poses a fire, disease, or other threat to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Indian forest land or rangeland under the jurisdiction of the Indian tribe; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a tribal community; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is in need of land restoration activities;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the agreement or contracting activities applied for by the Indian tribe are not already covered by a stewardship contract or other instrument that would present a conflict on the subject land; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the Forest Service or Bureau of Land Management land described in the application of the Indian tribe presents or involves a feature or circumstance unique to that Indian tribe (including treaty rights or biological, archaeological, historical, or cultural circumstances).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice of denial</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">If the Secretary denies a tribal request under subsection (b)(1), the Secretary may issue a notice of denial to the Indian tribe, which—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> identifies the specific factors that caused, and explains the reasons that support, the denial;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> identifies potential courses of action for overcoming specific issues that led to the denial; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> proposes a schedule of consultation with the Indian tribe for the purpose of developing a strategy for protecting the Indian forest land or rangeland of the Indian tribe and interests of the Indian tribe in Federal land.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Proposal evaluation and determination factors</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In entering into an agreement or contract in response to a request of an Indian tribe under subsection (b)(1), the Secretary may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> use a best-value basis; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> give specific consideration to tribally-related factors in the proposal of the Indian tribe, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the status of the Indian tribe as an Indian tribe;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the trust status of the Indian forest land or rangeland of the Indian tribe;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the cultural, traditional, and historical affiliation of the Indian tribe with the land subject to the proposal;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the treaty rights or other reserved rights of the Indian tribe relating to the land subject to the proposal;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the indigenous knowledge and skills of members of the Indian tribe;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the features of the landscape of the land subject to the proposal, including watersheds and vegetation types;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> the working relationships between the Indian tribe and Federal agencies in coordinating activities affecting the land subject to the proposal; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> the access by members of the Indian tribe to the land subject to the proposal.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> No effect on existing authority</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Nothing in this Act—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> prohibits, restricts, or otherwise adversely affects the participation of any Indian tribe in stewardship agreements or contracting under the authority of section 347 of the Department of the Interior and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1999 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 2104</ref> note; <ref>Public Law 105–277</ref>) (as amended by section 323 of the Department of the Interior and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2003 (<ref>117 Stat. 275</ref>)) or other authority invoked pursuant to this Act; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> invalidates any agreement or contract under that authority.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 4 years after <date date="2004-07-22">July 22, 2004</date>, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report that describes the Indian tribal requests received and agreements or contracts that have been entered into under this Act.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–278, § 2</ref>, <date date="2004-07-22">July 22, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 868</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–325, title II, § 202(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-18">Dec. 18, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4459</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3115b.</num>
<heading> Tribal forest management demonstration project</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary may carry out demonstration projects by which federally recognized Indian Tribes or Tribal organizations may contract to perform administrative, management, and other functions of programs of the Tribal Forest Protection Act of 2004 (<ref>25 U.S.C. 3115a</ref> et seq.) through contracts entered into under the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<ref>25 U.S.C. 5304</ref> et seq.).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">With respect to any contract or project carried out under subsection (a)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> on National Forest System land, the Secretary shall carry out all functions delegated to the Secretary of the Interior under the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<ref>25 U.S.C. 5304</ref> et seq.);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the Secretary or the Secretary of the Interior, as applicable, shall make any decisions required to be made under—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Tribal Forest Protection Act of 2004 (<ref>25 U.S.C. 3115a</ref> et seq.); and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the contract or project shall be entered into under, and in accordance with, section 403(b)(2) of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<ref>25 U.S.C. 5363(b)(2)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title VIII, § 8703</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4877</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3116.</num>
<heading> Obligated service; breach of contract</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Obligated service</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Where an individual enters into an agreement for obligated service in return for financial assistance under any provision of this chapter, the Secretary shall adopt such regulations as are necessary to provide for the offer of employment to the recipient of such assistance as required by such provision. Where an offer of employment is not reasonably made, the regulations shall provide that such service shall no longer be required.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Breach of contract; repayment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Where an individual fails to accept a reasonable offer of employment in fulfillment of such obligated service or unreasonably terminates or fails to perform the duties of such employment, the Secretary shall require a repayment of the financial assistance provided, prorated for the amount of time of obligated service performed, together with interest on such amount which would be payable if at the time the amounts were paid they were loans bearing interest at the maximum legal prevailing rate, as determined by the Treasurer of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–630, title III, § 317</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4544</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3117.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–630, title III, § 318</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4544</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3118.</num>
<heading> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided by this chapter, the Secretary is directed to promulgate final regulations for the implementation of the <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002208">1</ref> chapter within eighteen months from <date date="1990-11-28">November 28, 1990</date>. All regulations promulgated pursuant to this chapter shall be developed by the Secretary with the participation of the affected Indian tribes.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–630, title III, § 319</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4544</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3119.</num>
<heading> Severability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If any provision of this chapter, or the application of any provision of this chapter to any person or circumstance, is held invalid, the application of such provision or circumstance and the remainder of this chapter shall not be affected thereby.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–630, title III, § 320</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4544</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3120.</num>
<heading> Trust responsibility</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to diminish or expand the trust responsibility of the United States toward Indian forest lands, or any legal obligation or remedy resulting therefrom.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–630, title III, § 321</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4544</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>