<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 7A—</num>
<heading>PROMOTION OF SOCIAL AND ECONOMIC WELFARE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 305.</num>
<heading> Indian Arts and Crafts Board; creation and composition; per diem payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A board is created in the Department of the Interior to be known as “Indian Arts and Crafts Board”, and hereinafter referred to as the Board. The Board shall be composed of five commissioners, who shall be appointed by the Secretary of the Interior as soon as possible after <date date="1935-08-27">August 27, 1935</date> and shall continue in office, two for a term of two years, one for a term of three years, and two for a term of four years from the date of their appointment, the term of each to be designated by the Secretary of the Interior, but their successors shall be appointed for a term of four years except that any person chosen to fill a vacancy shall be appointed for the unexpired term of the commissioner whom he succeeds. Both public officers and private citizens shall be eligible for membership on the Board. The Board shall elect one of the commissioners as chairman. One or two vacancies on the Board shall not impair the right of the remaining commissioners to exercise all the powers of the Board.</p>
<p class="indent0">The commissioner shall serve without compensation: <i>Provided</i>, That each Commissioner shall be paid per diem in lieu of subsistence and other expenses at a rate that does not exceed the rate authorized by <ref>section 5703 of title 5</ref> to be paid to persons serving without compensation.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 27, 1935, ch. 748, § 1</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 891</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–23, § 1</ref>, <date date="1961-04-24">Apr. 24, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 45</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 305a.</num>
<heading> Promotion of economic welfare through development of arts and crafts; powers of Board</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It shall be the function and the duty of the Secretary of the Interior through the Board to promote the economic welfare of the Indian tribes and Indian individuals through the development of Indian arts and crafts and the expansion of the market for the products of Indian art and craftsmanship. In the execution of this function the Board shall have the following powers: (a) To undertake market research to determine the best opportunity for the sale of various products; (b) to engage in technical research and give technical advice and assistance; (c) to engage in experimentation directly or through selected agencies; (d) to correlate and encourage the activities of the various governmental and private agencies in the field; (e) to offer assistance in the management of operating groups for the furtherance of specific projects; (f) to make recommendations to appropriate agencies for loans in furtherance of the production and sale of Indian products; (g)(1) to create for the Board, or for an individual Indian or Indian tribe or Indian arts and crafts organization, trademarks of genuineness and quality for Indian products and the products of an individual Indian or particular Indian tribe or Indian arts and crafts organization; (2) to establish standards and regulations for the use of Government-owned trademarks by corporations, associations, or individuals, and to charge for such use under such licenses; (3) to register any such trademark owned by the Government in the United States Patent and Trademark Office without charge and assign it and the goodwill associated with it to an individual Indian or Indian tribe without charge; and (4) to pursue or defend in the courts any appeal or proceeding with respect to any final determination of that office; (h) to employ executive officers, including a general manager, and such other permanent and temporary personnel as may be found necessary, and prescribe the authorities, duties, responsibilities, and tenure and fix the compensation of such officers and other employees: <i>Provided</i>, That chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5 shall be applicable to all permanent employees and that all employees shall be appointed in accordance with the civil-service laws from lists of eligibles to be supplied by the Director of the Office of Personnel Management; (i) as a Government agency to negotiate and execute in its own name contracts with operating groups to supply management, personnel, and supervision at cost, and to negotiate and execute in its own name such other contracts and to carry on such other business as may be necessary for the accomplishment of the duties and purposes of the Board: <i>Provided</i>, That nothing in the foregoing enumeration of powers shall be construed to authorize the Board to borrow or lend money or to deal in Indian goods. For the purposes of this section, the term “Indian arts and crafts organization” means any legally established arts and crafts marketing organization composed of members of Indian tribes.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 27, 1935, ch. 748, § 2</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 891</ref>; <ref>Oct. 28, 1949, ch. 782</ref>, title XI, § 1106(a), <ref>63 Stat. 972</ref>; 1978 Reorg. Plan No. 2, § 102, eff. <date date="1979-01-01">Jan. 1, 1979</date>, 43 F.R. 36037, <ref>92 Stat. 3784</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–644, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4662</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 305a–1.</num>
<heading> Additional powers of Board; admission fees, rent, franchise fees and other fund­raising activities; volunteers; transfer of revenues into special fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In fiscal year 1997 and thereafter, the Indian Arts and Crafts Board may charge admission fees at its museums; charge rent and/or franchise fees for shops located in its museums; publish and sell publications; sell or rent or license use of photographs or other images in hard copy or other forms; license the use of designs, in whole or in part, by others; charge for consulting services provided to others; and may accept the services of volunteers to carry out its mission: <i>Provided</i>, That all revenue derived from such activities is covered into the special fund established by <ref>section 305c of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–208, div. A, title I, § 101(d) [title I, § 118]</ref>, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3009–181</ref>, 3009–202.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 305b.</num>
<heading> Rules and regulations; submission to Secretary of the Interior</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Board shall prescribe from time to time rules and regulations governing the conduct of its business and containing such provisions as it may deem appropriate for the effective execution and administration of the powers conferred upon it by this Act: <i>Provided</i>, That before prescribing any procedure for the disbursement of money the Board shall advise and consult with the Government Accountability Office: <i>Provided further</i>, That all rules and regulations proposed by the Board shall be submitted to the Secretary of the Interior and shall become effective upon his approval.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 27, 1935, ch. 748, § 3</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 892</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–271, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-07-07">July 7, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 814</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 305c.</num>
<heading> Appropriation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated out of any sums in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated such sums as may be necessary to defray the expenses of the Board and carry out the purposes and provisions of this Act. All income derived by the Board from any source shall be covered into the Treasury of the United States and shall constitute a special fund which is appropriated and made available until expended for carrying out the purposes and provisions of this Act. Out of the funds available to it at any time the Board may authorize such expenditures, consistent with the provisions of this Act, as it may determine to be necessary for the accomplishment of the purposes and objectives of this Act.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 27, 1935, ch. 748, § 4</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 892</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 305c–1.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 87–23, § 2</ref>, <date date="1961-04-24">Apr. 24, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 45</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 305d.</num>
<heading> Criminal proceedings; civil actions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition of Federal law enforcement officer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this section, the term “Federal law enforcement officer” includes a Federal law enforcement officer (as defined in <ref>section 115(c) of title 18</ref>).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority to conduct investigations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any Federal law enforcement officer shall have the authority to conduct an investigation relating to an alleged violation of this Act occurring within the jurisdiction of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Criminal proceedings</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Investigation</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Board may refer an alleged violation of <ref>section 1159 of title 18</ref> to any Federal law enforcement officer for appropriate investigation.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Referral not required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A Federal law enforcement officer may investigate an alleged violation of section 1159 of that title regardless of whether the Federal law enforcement officer receives a referral under subparagraph (A).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The findings of an investigation of an alleged violation of <ref>section 1159 of title 18</ref> by any Federal department or agency under paragraph (1)(A) shall be submitted, as appropriate, to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a Federal or State prosecuting authority; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Board.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recommendations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">On receiving the findings of an investigation under paragraph (2), the Board may—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> recommend to the Attorney General that criminal proceedings be initiated under <ref>section 1159 of title 18</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provide such support to the Attorney General relating to the criminal proceedings as the Attorney General determines to be appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Civil actions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In lieu of, or in addition to, any criminal proceeding under subsection (c), the Board may recommend that the Attorney General initiate a civil action under <ref>section 305e of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 27, 1935, ch. 748, § 5</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 101–644, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4662</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 111–211, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-07-29">July 29, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2258</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 305e.</num>
<heading> Cause of action for misrepresentation of Indian produced goods</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Indian</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “Indian” means an individual that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is a member of an Indian tribe; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is certified as an Indian artisan by an Indian tribe.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Indian product</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Indian product” has the meaning given the term in any regulation promulgated by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Indian tribe</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “Indian tribe” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 5304 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inclusion</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “Indian tribe” includes, for purposes of this section only, an Indian group that has been formally recognized as an Indian tribe by—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a State legislature;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a State commission; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> another similar organization vested with State legislative tribal recognition authority.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of the Interior.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Injunctive or equitable relief; damages</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A person specified in subsection (d) may, in a civil action in a court of competent jurisdiction, bring an action against a person who, directly or indirectly, offers or displays for sale or sells a good, with or without a Government trademark, in a manner that falsely suggests it is Indian produced, an Indian product, or the product of a particular Indian or Indian tribe or Indian arts and crafts organization, resident within the United States, to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> obtain injunctive or other equitable relief; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> recover the greater of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> treble damages; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of each aggrieved individual Indian, Indian tribe, or Indian arts and crafts organization, not less than $1,000 for each day on which the offer or display for sale or sale continues.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">For purposes of paragraph (2)(A), damages shall include any and all gross profits accrued by the defendant as a result of the activities found to violate this subsection.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Punitive damages; attorney’s fee</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In addition to the relief specified in subsection (b), the court may award punitive damages and the costs of the civil action and a reasonable attorney’s fee.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Persons that may initiate civil actions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A civil action under subsection (b) may be initiated by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> the Attorney General, at the request of the Secretary acting on behalf of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an Indian tribe;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> an Indian; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> an Indian arts and crafts organization;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> an Indian tribe, acting on behalf of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Indian tribe;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a member of that Indian tribe; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> an Indian arts and crafts organization;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> an Indian; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> an Indian arts and crafts organization.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disposition of amounts recovered</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), an amount recovered in a civil action under this section shall be paid to the Indian tribe, the Indian, or the Indian arts and crafts organization on the behalf of which the civil action was initiated.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Attorney General</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">In the case of a civil action initiated under paragraph (1)(A), the Attorney General may deduct from the amount—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the amount of the cost of the civil action and reasonable attorney’s fees awarded under subsection (c), to be deposited in the Treasury and credited to appropriations available to the Attorney General on the date on which the amount is recovered; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the amount of the costs of investigation awarded under subsection (c), to reimburse the Board for the activities of the Board relating to the civil action.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Indian tribe</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">In the case of a civil action initiated under paragraph (1)(B), the Indian tribe may deduct from the amount—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the amount of the cost of the civil action; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> reasonable attorney’s fees.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Savings provision</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If any provision of this section is held invalid, it is the intent of Congress that the remaining provisions of this section shall continue in full force and effect.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2000-11-09">November 9, 2000</date>, the Board shall promulgate regulations to include in the definition of the term “Indian product” specific examples of such product to provide guidance to Indian artisans as well as to purveyors and consumers of Indian arts and crafts, as defined under this Act.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 27, 1935, ch. 748, § 6</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 101–644, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4664</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–497, § 2</ref>, <date date="2000-11-09">Nov. 9, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2219</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–211, title I, § 102(b)</ref>, <date date="2010-07-29">July 29, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2259</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 305f.</num>
<heading> Indian Arts and Crafts Board art collection</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer of art collection and costs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of the Interior is directed to transfer all right, title and interest in that portion of the Indian Arts and Crafts Board art collection maintained permanently by the Indian Arts and Crafts Board in Washington, District of Columbia, to the Secretary of the Smithsonian Institution to be a part of the collection of the National Museum of the American Indian, subject to subsection (b). Transfer of the collection and costs thereof shall be carried out in accordance with terms, conditions, and standards mutually agreed upon by the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of the Smithsonian Institution.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Retention of permanent license to use of images</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Indian Arts and Crafts Board shall retain a permanent license to the use of images of the collection for promotional, economic development, educational and related nonprofit purposes. The Indian Arts and Crafts Board shall not be required to pay any royalty or fee for such license.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 27, 1935, ch. 748, § 7</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. A, § 101(e) [title III, § 356(a)]</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–231</ref>, 2681–304.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 306.</num>
<heading> Expenditures for encouragement of industry and self-support; repayment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On and after <date date="1938-05-09">May 9, 1938</date>, the expenditures for the purpose of encouraging industry and self-support among the Indians and to aid them in the culture of fruits, grains, and other crops shall be under conditions to be prescribed by the Secretary of the Interior for repayment to the United States on or before the expiration of five years, except in the case of loans on irrigable lands for permanent improvement of said lands, in which the period for repayment may run for not exceeding twenty years, in the discretion of the Secretary of the Interior.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 9, 1938, ch. 187, § 1</ref>, <ref>52 Stat. 302</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 306a.</num>
<heading> Advances for support of old, disabled, or indigent allottees; lien against land</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On and after <date date="1938-05-09">May 9, 1938</date>, the Secretary of the Interior is authorized, in his discretion and under such rules and regulations as he may prescribe, to make advances to old, disabled, or indigent Indian allottees, for their support, to remain a charge and lien against their land until paid; such advances for the fiscal year 1939 to be made from the appropriations in this paragraph and those for fiscal years thereafter to be made from appropriations specifically available for such purposes.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 9, 1938, ch. 187, § 1</ref>, <ref>52 Stat. 302</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 307, 308.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 309.</num>
<heading> Vocational training program; eligibility; contracts or agreements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In order to help adult Indians who reside on or near Indian reservations to obtain reasonable and satisfactory employment, the Secretary of the Interior is authorized to undertake a program of vocational training that provides for vocational counseling or guidance, institutional training in any recognized vocation or trade, apprenticeship, and on the job training, for periods that do not exceed twenty-four months, and, for nurses’ training, for periods that do not exceed thirty-six months, transportation to the place of training, and subsistence during the course of training. The program shall be available primarily to Indians who are not less than eighteen and not more than thirty-five years of age and who reside on or near an Indian reservation, and the program shall be conducted under such rules and regulations as the Secretary may prescribe. For the purposes of this program the Secretary is authorized to enter into contracts or agreements with any Federal, State, or local governmental agency, or with any private school which has a recognized reputation in the field of vocational education and has successfully obtained employment for its graduates in their respective fields of training, or with any corporation or association which has an existing apprenticeship or on-the-job training program which is recognized by industry and labor as leading to skilled employment, or with any school of nursing offering a three-year course of study leading to a diploma in nursing which is accredited by a recognized body or bodies approved for such purpose by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 3, 1956, ch. 930, § 1</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 986</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–230, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1963-12-23">Dec. 23, 1963</date>, <ref>77 Stat. 471</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 309a.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated for the purposes of sections 309 and 309a of this title the sum of $25,000,000 for each fiscal year, and not to exceed $1,500,000 of such sum shall be available for administrative purposes.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 3, 1956, ch. 930, § 2</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 986</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–273</ref>, <date date="1961-09-22">Sept. 22, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 571</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–230, § 1(b)</ref>, <date date="1963-12-23">Dec. 23, 1963</date>, <ref>77 Stat. 471</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–14</ref>, <date date="1965-04-22">Apr. 22, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 74</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–252</ref>, <date date="1968-02-03">Feb. 3, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 4</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 309b.</num>
<heading> Vocational education funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, funds provided by the Bureau for adult vocational education to any vocational school (as defined for purposes of any program of assistance to students under the Higher Education Act of 1965 [<ref>20 U.S.C. 1001</ref> et seq.]) may be treated as non-Federal, private funds of such school for purposes of any provision of Federal law which requires that non-Federal or private funds of such school be used in a project or for a specific purpose.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–297, title V, § 5403(c)</ref>, <date date="1988-04-28">Apr. 28, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 416</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 310.</num>
<heading> Institute of American Indian and Alaska Native Culture and Arts Development</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> To the extent of the availability of funds for such purpose, the Secretary of the Interior shall:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> enter into a thirty-year agreement with the College of Santa Fe, Santa Fe, New Mexico, to provide educational facilities for the use of, and to develop cooperative educational/arts programs to be carried out with the postsecondary fine arts and museum services programs of, the Institute of American Indian and Alaska Native Culture and Arts Development administered by the Bureau of Indian Affairs; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> conduct such activities as are necessary to improve the facilities used by the Institute of American Indian and Alaska Native Culture and Arts Development at the College of Santa Fe.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The provisions of this subsection shall take effect on <date date="1984-10-01">October 1, 1984</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Bureau of Indian Affairs, is directed to conduct a study for the purpose of determining the need, if any, for a museum facility to be established for the benefit of the Institute of American Indian and Alaska Native Culture and Arts Development, the feasibility of establishing such museum, and the need or desirability, if any, to establish any such museum in close proximity to the facilities currently being used by such Institute at the College of Santa Fe.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> On or before <date date="1985-02-01">February 1, 1985</date>, the Secretary of the Interior shall report the results of such study, together with his recommendations, to the Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Should the study recommend establishment of a museum, and should the College of Santa Fe be selected as the best site, any agreement entered into by the Secretary of the Interior for construction of such museum shall contain assurances, satisfactory to the Secretary, that appropriate lands at the College of Santa Fe will be available at no cost to the Federal Government for the establishment of a museum facility.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–306, § 14</ref>, <date date="1984-05-31">May 31, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 226</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–498, title XV, § 1514(c)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-17">Oct. 17, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1608</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>