<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 41—</num>
<heading>INDIAN LANDS OPEN DUMP CLEANUP</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3901.</num>
<heading> Findings and purposes</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> there are at least 600 open dumps on Indian and Alaska Native lands;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> these dumps threaten the health and safety of residents of Indian and Alaska Native lands and contiguous areas;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> many of these dumps were established or are used by Federal agencies such as the Bureau of Indian Affairs and the Indian Health Service;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> these dumps threaten the environment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the United States holds most Indian lands in trust for the benefit of Indian tribes and Indian individuals; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> most Indian tribal governments and Alaska Native entities lack the financial and technical resources necessary to close and maintain these dumps in compliance with applicable Federal laws.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes of this chapter are to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> identify the location of open dumps on Indian lands and Alaska Native lands;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> assess the relative health and environmental hazards posed by such dumps; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> provide financial and technical assistance to Indian tribal governments and Alaska Native entities, either directly or by contract, to close such dumps in compliance with applicable Federal standards and regulations, or standards promulgated by an Indian tribal government or Alaska Native entity, if such standards are more stringent than the Federal standards.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–399, § 2</ref>, <date date="1994-10-22">Oct. 22, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4164</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3902.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For the purposes of this chapter, the following definitions shall apply:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Closure or close</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “closure or close” means the termination of operations at open dumps on Indian land or Alaska Native land and bringing such dumps into compliance with applicable Federal standards and regulations, or standards promulgated by an Indian tribal government or Alaska Native entity, if such standards are more stringent than the Federal standards and regulations.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Director</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Director” means the Director of the Indian Health Service.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Indian land</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “Indian land” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> land within the limits of any Indian reservation under the jurisdiction of the United States Government, notwithstanding the issuance of any patent, and including rights-of-way running through the reservation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> dependent Indian communities within the borders of the United States whether within the original or subsequently acquired territory thereof, and whether within or without the limits of a State; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Indian allotments, the Indian titles to which have not been extinguished, including rights-of-way running through such allotments.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Alaska Native land</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Alaska Native land” means (A) land conveyed or to be conveyed pursuant to the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act [<ref>43 U.S.C. 1601</ref> et seq.], including any land reconveyed under section 14(c)(3) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002227">1</ref> of that Act (<ref>43 U.S.C. 1613(c)(3)</ref>), and (B) land conveyed pursuant to the Act of <date date="1966-11-02">November 2, 1966</date> (<ref>16 U.S.C. 1151</ref> et seq.; commonly known as the “Fur Seal Act of 1966”).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Indian tribal government</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Indian tribal government” means the governing body of any Indian tribe, band, nation, pueblo, or other organized group or community which is recognized as eligible for the special programs and services provided by the United States to Indians because of their status as Indians.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Alaska Native entity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Alaska Native entity” includes native corporations established pursuant to the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act [<ref>43 U.S.C. 1601</ref> et seq.] and any Alaska Native village or municipal entity which owns Alaska Native land.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Open dump</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “open dump” means any facility or site where solid waste is disposed of which is not a sanitary landfill which meets the criteria promulgated under section 4004 of the Solid Waste Disposal Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 6944</ref>) and which is not a facility for disposal of hazardous waste.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Postclosure maintenance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “postclosure maintenance” means any activity undertaken at a closed solid waste management facility on Indian land or on Alaska Native land to maintain the integrity of containment features, monitor compliance with applicable performance standards, or remedy any situation or occurrence that violates regulations promulgated pursuant to subtitle D of the Solid Waste Disposal Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 6941</ref> et seq.).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Service</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Service” means the Indian Health Service.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(10)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Solid waste</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “solid waste” has the meaning provided that term by section 1004(27) of the Solid Waste Disposal Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 6903</ref>) and any regulations promulgated thereunder.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–399, § 3</ref>, <date date="1994-10-22">Oct. 22, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4164</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–109, § 5</ref>, <date date="1996-02-12">Feb. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 764</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3903.</num>
<heading> Inventory of open dumps</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Study and inventory</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 12 months after <date date="1994-10-22">October 22, 1994</date>, the Director shall conduct a study and inventory of open dumps on Indian lands and Alaska Native lands. The inventory shall list the geographic location of all open dumps, an evaluation of the contents of each dump, and an assessment of the relative severity of the threat to public health and the environment posed by each dump. Such assessment shall be carried out cooperatively with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency. The Director shall obtain the concurrence of the Administrator in the determination of relative severity made by any such assessment.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual reports</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Upon completion of the study and inventory under subsection (a), the Director shall report to the Congress, and update such report annually—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the current priority of Indian and Alaska Native solid waste deficiencies,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the methodology of determining the priority listing,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the level of funding needed to effectively close or bring into compliance all open dumps on Indian lands or Alaska Native lands, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the progress made in addressing Indian and Alaska Native solid waste deficiencies.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> 10-year plan</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Director shall develop and begin implementation of a 10-year plan to address solid waste disposal needs on Indian lands and Alaska Native lands. This 10-year plan shall identify—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the level of funding needed to effectively close or bring into compliance with applicable Federal standards any open dumps located on Indian lands and Alaska Native lands; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the level of funding needed to develop comprehensive solid waste management plans for every Indian tribal government and Alaska Native entity.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–399, § 4</ref>, <date date="1994-10-22">Oct. 22, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4166</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3904.</num>
<heading> Authority of Director of Indian Health Service</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reservation inventory</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Upon request by an Indian tribal government or Alaska Native entity, the Director shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> conduct an inventory and evaluation of the contents of open dumps on the Indian lands or Alaska Native lands which are subject to the authority of the Indian tribal government or Alaska Native entity;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> determine the relative severity of the threat to public health and the environment posed by each dump based on information available to the Director and the Indian tribal government or Alaska Native entity unless the Director, in consultation with the Indian tribal government or Alaska Native entity, determines that additional actions such as soil testing or water monitoring would be appropriate in the circumstances; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> develop cost estimates for the closure and postclosure maintenance of such dumps.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The inventory and evaluation authorized under paragraph (1)(A) shall be carried out cooperatively with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency. The Director shall obtain the concurrence of the Administrator in the determination of relative severity made under paragraph (1)(B).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Upon completion of the activities required to be performed pursuant to subsection (a), the Director shall, subject to subsection (c), provide financial and technical assistance to the Indian tribal government or Alaska Native entity to carry out the activities necessary to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> close such dumps; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provide for postclosure maintenance of such dumps.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conditions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All assistance provided pursuant to subsection (b) shall be made available on a site-specific basis in accordance with priorities developed by the Director. Priorities on specific Indian lands or Alaska Native lands shall be developed in consultation with the Indian tribal government or Alaska Native entity. The priorities shall take into account the relative severity of the threat to public health and the environment posed by each open dump and the availability of funds necessary for closure and postclosure maintenance.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–399, § 5</ref>, <date date="1994-10-22">Oct. 22, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4166</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3905.</num>
<heading> Contract authority</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority of Director</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To the maximum extent feasible, the Director shall carry out duties under this chapter through contracts, compacts, or memoranda of agreement with Indian tribal governments or Alaska Native entities pursuant to the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<ref>25 U.S.C. 450</ref> et seq.),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002228">1</ref> <ref>section 2004a of title 42</ref>, or <ref>section 1632 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cooperative agreements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director is authorized, for purposes of carrying out the duties of the Director under this chapter, to contract with or enter into such cooperative agreements with such other Federal agencies as is considered necessary to provide cost-sharing for closure and postclosure activities, to obtain necessary technical and financial assistance and expertise, and for such other purposes as the Director considers necessary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–399, § 6</ref>, <date date="1994-10-22">Oct. 22, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4167</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3906.</num>
<heading> Tribal demonstration project</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director may establish and carry out a program providing for demonstration projects involving open dumps on Indian land or Alaska Native land. It shall be the purpose of such projects to determine if there are unique cost factors involved in the cleanup and maintenance of open dumps on such land, and the extent to which advanced closure planning is necessary. Under the program, the Director is authorized to select no less than three Indian tribal governments or Alaska Native entities to participate in such demonstration projects.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Criteria</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Criteria established by the Director for the selection and participation of an Indian tribal government or Alaska Native entity in the demonstration project shall provide that in order to be eligible to participate, an Indian tribal government or Alaska Native entity must—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> have one or more existing open dumps on Indian lands or Alaska Native lands which are under its authority;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> have developed a comprehensive solid waste management plan for such lands; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> have developed a closure and postclosure maintenance plan for each dump located on such lands.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duration of funding for project</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No demonstration project shall be funded for more than three fiscal years.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–399, § 7</ref>, <date date="1994-10-22">Oct. 22, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4167</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3907.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General authorization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The activities required to be performed by the Director under this chapter shall be coordinated with activities related to solid waste and sanitation facilities funded pursuant to other authorizations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–399, § 8</ref>, <date date="1994-10-22">Oct. 22, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4168</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3908.</num>
<heading> Disclaimers</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority of Director</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to alter, diminish, repeal, or supersede any authority conferred on the Director pursuant to <ref>section 1632 of this title</ref>, and <ref>section 2004a of title 42</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exempted lands and facilities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">This chapter shall not apply to open dump sites on Indian lands or Alaska Native lands—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> that comprise an area of one-half acre or less and that are used by individual families on lands to which they hold legal or beneficial title;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> of any size that have been or are being operated for a profit; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> where solid waste from an industrial process is being or has been routinely disposed of at a privately owned facility in compliance with applicable Federal laws.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rules of construction</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to amend or modify the authority or responsibility of the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency under the Solid Waste Disposal Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 6901</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Nothing in this chapter is intended to amend, repeal, or supersede any provision of the Solid Waste Disposal Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 6901</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–399, § 9</ref>, <date date="1994-10-22">Oct. 22, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4168</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>