<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 32A—</num>
<heading>CULTURAL AND HERITAGE COOPERATION AUTHORITY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3051.</num>
<heading> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes of this chapter are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to authorize the reburial of human remains and cultural items on National Forest System land, including human remains and cultural items repatriated under the Native American Graves Protection and Repatriation Act (<ref>25 U.S.C. 3001</ref> et seq.);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to prevent the unauthorized disclosure of information regarding reburial sites, including the quantity and identity of human remains and cultural items on sites and the location of sites;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to authorize the Secretary of Agriculture to ensure access to National Forest System land, to the maximum extent practicable, by Indians and Indian tribes for traditional and cultural purposes;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to authorize the Secretary to provide forest products, without consideration, to Indian tribes for traditional and cultural purposes;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to authorize the Secretary to protect the confidentiality of certain information, including information that is culturally sensitive to Indian tribes;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> to increase the availability of Forest Service programs and resources to Indian tribes in support of the policy of the United States to promote tribal sovereignty and self-determination; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> to strengthen support for the policy of the United States of protecting and preserving the traditional, cultural, and ceremonial rites and practices of Indian tribes, in accordance with <ref>Public Law 95–341</ref> (commonly known as the American Indian Religious Freedom Act; <ref>42 U.S.C. 1996</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title VIII, § 8101</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1286</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title VIII, § 8101, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2048.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3052.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adjacent site</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “adjacent site” means a site that borders a boundary line of National Forest System land.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cultural items</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “cultural items” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 3001 of this title</ref>, except that the term does not include human remains.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Human remains</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “human remains” means the physical remains of the body of a person of Indian ancestry.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Indian</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Indian” means an individual who is a member of an Indian tribe.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Indian tribe</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Indian tribe” means any Indian or Alaska Native tribe, band, nation, pueblo, village, or other community the name of which is included on a list published by the Secretary of the Interior pursuant to <ref>section 5131 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Lineal descendant</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “lineal descendant” means an individual that can trace, directly and without interruption, the ancestry of the individual through the traditional kinship system of an Indian tribe, or through the common law system of descent, to a known Indian, the human remains, funerary objects, or other sacred objects of whom are claimed by the individual.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National Forest System</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “National Forest System” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 1609(a) of title 16</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reburial site</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “reburial site” means a specific physical location at which cultural items or human remains are reburied.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Traditional and cultural purpose</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “traditional and cultural purpose”, with respect to a definable use, area, or practice, means that the use, area, or practice is identified by an Indian tribe as traditional or cultural because of the long-established significance or ceremonial nature of the use, area, or practice to the Indian tribe.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title VIII, § 8102</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1287</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title VIII, § 8102, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2048.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3053.</num>
<heading> Reburial of human remains and cultural items</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reburial sites</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In consultation with an affected Indian tribe or lineal descendant, the Secretary may authorize the use of National Forest System land by the Indian tribe or lineal descendant for the reburial of human remains or cultural items in the possession of the Indian tribe or lineal descendant that have been disinterred from National Forest System land or an adjacent site.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reburial</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">With the consent of the affected Indian tribe or lineal descendent, the Secretary may recover and rebury, at Federal expense or using other available funds, human remains and cultural items described in subsection (a) at the National Forest System land identified under that subsection.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of use</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subject to paragraph (2), the Secretary may authorize such uses of reburial sites on National Forest System land, or on the National Forest System land immediately surrounding a reburial site, as the Secretary determines to be necessary for management of the National Forest System.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Avoidance of adverse impacts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In carrying out paragraph (1), the Secretary shall avoid adverse impacts to cultural items and human remains, to the maximum extent practicable.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title VIII, § 8103</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1287</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title VIII, § 8103, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2049.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3054.</num>
<heading> Temporary closure for traditional and cultural purposes</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recognition of historic use</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To the maximum extent practicable, the Secretary shall ensure access to National Forest System land by Indians for traditional and cultural purposes, in accordance with subsection (b), in recognition of the historic use by Indians of National Forest System land.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Closing land from public access</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority to close</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Upon the approval by the Secretary of a request from an Indian tribe, the Secretary may temporarily close from public access specifically identified National Forest System land to protect the privacy of tribal activities for traditional and cultural purposes.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A closure of National Forest System land under paragraph (1) shall affect the smallest practicable area for the minimum period necessary for activities of the applicable Indian tribe.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consistency</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Access by Indian tribes to National Forest System land under this subsection shall be consistent with the purposes of <ref>Public Law 95–341</ref> (commonly known as the American Indian Religious Freedom Act; <ref>42 U.S.C. 1996</ref>).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title VIII, § 8104</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1288</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title VIII, § 8104, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2049.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3055.</num>
<heading> Forest products for traditional and cultural purposes</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding <ref>section 472a of title 16</ref>, the Secretary may provide free of charge to Indian tribes any trees, portions of trees, or forest products from National Forest System land for traditional and cultural purposes.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Trees, portions of trees, or forest products provided under subsection (a) may not be used for commercial purposes.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title VIII, § 8105</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1288</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title VIII, § 8105, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2050.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3056.</num>
<heading> Prohibition on disclosure</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nondisclosure of information</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary shall not disclose under <ref>section 552 of title 5</ref> (commonly known as the “Freedom of Information Act”), information relating to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> subject to subsection (b)(l),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002203">1</ref> human remains or cultural items reburied on National Forest System land under <ref>section 3053 of this title</ref>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> subject to subsection (b)(2), resources, cultural items, uses, or activities that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> have a traditional and cultural purpose; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> are provided to the Secretary by an Indian or Indian tribe under an express expectation of confidentiality in the context of forest and rangeland research activities carried out under the authority of the Forest Service.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations on disclosure</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Subject to subsection (b)(2), the Secretary shall not be required to disclose information under <ref>section 552 of title 5</ref> (commonly known as the “Freedom of Information Act”), concerning the identity, use, or specific location in the National Forest System of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a site or resource used for traditional and cultural purposes by an Indian tribe; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any cultural items not covered under <ref>section 3053 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limited release of information</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reburial</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary may disclose information described in subsection (a)(l)(A) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002204">2</ref> if, before the disclosure, the Secretary—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> consults with an affected Indian tribe or lineal descendent;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> determines that disclosure of the information—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> would advance the purposes of this chapter; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> is necessary to protect the human remains or cultural items from harm, theft, or destruction; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> attempts to mitigate any adverse impacts identified by an Indian tribe or lineal descendant that reasonably could be expected to result from disclosure of the information.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other information</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary, in consultation with appropriate Indian tribes, may disclose information described under paragraph (1)(B) or (2) of subsection (a) if the Secretary determines that disclosure of the information to the public—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> would advance the purposes of this chapter;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> would not create an unreasonable risk of harm, theft, or destruction of the resource, site, or object, including individual organic or inorganic specimens; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> would be consistent with other applicable laws.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title VIII, § 8106</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1288</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title VIII, § 8106, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2050.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3057.</num>
<heading> Severability and savings provisions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Severability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If any provision of this chapter, or the application of any provision of this chapter to any person or circumstance is held invalid, the application of such provision or circumstance and the remainder of this chapter shall not be affected thereby.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Savings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> diminishes or expands the trust responsibility of the United States to Indian tribes, or any legal obligation or remedy resulting from that responsibility;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> alters, abridges, repeals, or affects any valid agreement between the Forest Service and an Indian tribe;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> alters, abridges, diminishes, repeals, or affects any reserved or other right of an Indian tribe; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> alters, abridges, diminishes, repeals, or affects any other valid existing right relating to National Forest System land or other public land.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title VIII, § 8107</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1289</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title VIII, § 8107, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2051.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>