<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 50—</num>
<heading>NATIVE AMERICAN BUSINESS INCUBATORS PROGRAM</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5801.</num>
<heading> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Congress finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> entrepreneurs face specific challenges when transforming ideas into profitable business enterprises;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> entrepreneurs that want to provide products and services in reservation communities face an additional set of challenges that requires special knowledge;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> a business incubator is an organization that assists entrepreneurs in navigating obstacles that prevent innovative ideas from becoming viable businesses by providing services that include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> workspace and facilities resources;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> access to capital, business education, and counseling;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> networking opportunities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> mentorship opportunities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> an environment intended to help establish and expand business operations;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the business incubator model is suited to accelerating entrepreneurship in reservation communities because the business incubator model promotes collaboration to address shared challenges and provides individually tailored services for the purpose of overcoming obstacles unique to each participating business; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> business incubators will stimulate economic development by providing Native entrepreneurs with the tools necessary to grow businesses that offer products and services to reservation communities.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–174, § 2</ref>, <date date="2020-10-20">Oct. 20, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 839</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5802.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Business incubator</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “business incubator” means an organization that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> provides physical workspace and facilities resources to startups and established businesses; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> is designed to accelerate the growth and success of businesses through a variety of business support resources and services, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> access to capital, business education, and counseling;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> networking opportunities;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> mentorship opportunities; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> other services intended to aid in developing a business.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible applicant</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “eligible applicant” means an applicant eligible to apply for a grant under <ref>section 5803(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Indian tribe</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Indian tribe” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 5304 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Institution of higher education</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “institution of higher education” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 1001 of title 20</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Native American; Native</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The terms “Native American” and “Native” have the meaning given the term “Indian” in <ref>section 5304 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Native business</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Native business” means a business concern that is at least 51-percent owned and controlled by 1 or more Native Americans.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Native entrepreneur</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Native entrepreneur” means an entrepreneur who is a Native American.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “program” means the program established under <ref>section 5803(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reservation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “reservation” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 1452 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(10)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of the Interior.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(11)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tribal college or university</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “tribal college or university” has the meaning given the term “Tribal College or University” in <ref>section 1059c(b) of title 20</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–174, § 3</ref>, <date date="2020-10-20">Oct. 20, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 839</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5803.</num>
<heading> Establishment of program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish a program in the Office of Indian Energy and Economic Development under which the Secretary shall provide financial assistance in the form of competitive grants to eligible applicants for the establishment and operation of business incubators that serve reservation communities by providing business incubation and other business services to Native businesses and Native entrepreneurs.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible applicants</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">To be eligible to receive a grant under the program, an applicant shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> be—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an Indian tribe;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a tribal college or university;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> an institution of higher education; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<chapeau> a private nonprofit organization or tribal nonprofit organization that—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> provides business and financial technical assistance; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> will commit to serving 1 or more reservation communities;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> be able to provide the physical workspace, equipment, and connectivity necessary for Native businesses and Native entrepreneurs to collaborate and conduct business on a local, regional, national, and international level; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> in the case of an entity described in clauses (ii) through (iv) of subparagraph (A), have been operational for not less than 1 year before receiving a grant under the program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Joint project</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Two or more entities may submit a joint application for a project that combines the resources and expertise of those entities at a physical location dedicated to assisting Native businesses and Native entrepreneurs under the program.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">A joint application submitted under subparagraph (A) shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> contain a certification that each participant of the joint project is one of the eligible entities described in paragraph (1)(A); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> demonstrate that together the participants meet the requirements of subparagraphs (B) and (C) of paragraph (1).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application and selection process</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Each eligible applicant desiring a grant under the program shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> a certification that the applicant—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is an eligible applicant;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> will designate an executive director or program manager, if such director or manager has not been designated, to manage the business incubator; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> agrees—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> to a site evaluation by the Secretary as part of the final selection process;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> to an annual programmatic and financial examination for the duration of the grant; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> to the maximum extent practicable, to remedy any problems identified pursuant to the site evaluation under subclause (I) or an examination under subclause (II);</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a description of the 1 or more reservation communities to be served by the business incubator;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> a 3-year plan that describes—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the number of Native businesses and Native entrepreneurs to be participating in the business incubator;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> whether the business incubator will focus on a particular type of business or industry;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a detailed breakdown of the services to be offered to Native businesses and Native entrepreneurs participating in the business incubator; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> a detailed breakdown of the services, if any, to be offered to Native businesses and Native entrepreneurs not participating in the business incubator;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> information demonstrating the effectiveness and experience of the eligible applicant in—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> conducting financial, management, and marketing assistance programs designed to educate or improve the business skills of current or prospective businesses;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> working in and providing services to Native American communities;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> providing assistance to entities conducting business in reservation communities;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> providing technical assistance under Federal business and entrepreneurial development programs for which Native businesses and Native entrepreneurs are eligible; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> managing finances and staff effectively; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> a site description of the location at which the eligible applicant will provide physical workspace, including a description of the technologies, equipment, and other resources that will be available to Native businesses and Native entrepreneurs participating in the business incubator.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Evaluation considerations</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In evaluating each application, the Secretary shall consider—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> the ability of the eligible applicant—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> to operate a business incubator that effectively imparts entrepreneurship and business skills to Native businesses and Native entrepreneurs, as demonstrated by the experience and qualifications of the eligible applicant;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> to commence providing services within a minimum period of time, to be determined by the Secretary; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> to provide quality incubation services to a significant number of Native businesses and Native entrepreneurs;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the experience of the eligible applicant in providing services in Native American communities, including in the 1 or more reservation communities described in the application; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the proposed location of the business incubator.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Priority</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">In evaluating the proposed location of the business incubator under subparagraph (A)(iii), the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> consider the program goal of achieving broad geographic distribution of business incubators; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> except as provided in clause (ii), give priority to eligible applicants that will provide business incubation services on or near the reservation of the 1 or more communities that were described in the application.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">The Secretary may give priority to an eligible applicant that is not located on or near the reservation of the 1 or more communities that were described in the application if the Secretary determines that—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the location of the business incubator will not prevent the eligible applicant from providing quality business incubation services to Native businesses and Native entrepreneurs from the 1 or more reservation communities to be served; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> siting the business incubator in the identified location will serve the interests of the 1 or more reservation communities to be served.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Site evaluation</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Before making a grant to an eligible applicant, the Secretary shall conduct a site visit, evaluate a video submission, or evaluate a written site proposal (if the applicant is not yet in possession of the site) of the proposed site to ensure the proposed site will permit the eligible applicant to meet the requirements of the program.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Written site proposal</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">A written site proposal shall meet the requirements described in paragraph (1)(E) and contain—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> sufficient detail for the Secretary to ensure in the absence of a site visit or video submission that the proposed site will permit the eligible applicant to meet the requirements of the program; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> a timeline describing when the eligible applicant will be—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> in possession of the proposed site; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> operating the business incubator at the proposed site.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Followup</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Not later than 1 year after awarding a grant to an eligible applicant that submits an application with a written site proposal, the Secretary shall conduct a site visit or evaluate a video submission of the site to ensure the site is consistent with the written site proposal.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administration</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Each grant awarded under the program shall be for a term of 3 years.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payment</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the Secretary shall disburse grant funds awarded to an eligible applicant in annual installments.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> More frequent disbursements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">On request by the applicant, the Secretary may make disbursements of grant funds more frequently than annually, on the condition that disbursements shall be made not more frequently than quarterly.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Non-Federal contributions for initial assistance</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), an eligible applicant that receives a grant under the program shall provide non-Federal contributions in an amount equal to not less than 25 percent of the grant amount disbursed each year.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Waiver</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Secretary may waive, in whole or in part, the requirements of subparagraph (A) with respect to an eligible applicant if, after considering the ability of the eligible applicant to provide non-Federal contributions, the Secretary determines that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the proposed business incubator will provide quality business incubation services; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the 1 or more reservation communities to be served are unlikely to receive similar services because of remoteness or other reasons that inhibit the provision of business and entrepreneurial development services.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Renewals</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary may renew a grant award under the program for a term not to exceed 3 years.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Considerations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In determining whether to renew a grant award, the Secretary shall consider with respect to the eligible applicant—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the results of the annual evaluations of the eligible applicant under subsection (f)(1);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the performance of the business incubator of the eligible applicant, as compared to the performance of other business incubators receiving assistance under the program;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> whether the eligible applicant continues to be eligible for the program; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the evaluation considerations for initial awards under subsection (c)(2).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Non-Federal contributions for renewals</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">An eligible applicant that receives a grant renewal under subparagraph (A) shall provide non-Federal contributions in an amount equal to not less than 33 percent of the total amount of the grant.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> No duplicative grants</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">An eligible applicant shall not be awarded a grant under the program that is duplicative of existing Federal funding from another source.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program requirements</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">An eligible applicant receiving a grant under the program may use grant amounts—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to provide physical workspace and facilities for Native businesses and Native entrepreneurs participating in the business incubator;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to establish partnerships with other institutions and entities to provide comprehensive business incubation services to Native businesses and Native entrepreneurs participating in the business incubator; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> for any other uses typically associated with business incubators that the Secretary determines to be appropriate and consistent with the purposes of the program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Minimum requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Each eligible applicant receiving a grant under the program shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> offer culturally tailored incubation services to Native businesses and Native entrepreneurs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> use a competitive process for selecting Native businesses and Native entrepreneurs to participate in the business incubator;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> provide physical workspace that permits Native businesses and Native entrepreneurs to conduct business and collaborate with other Native businesses and Native entrepreneurs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> provide entrepreneurship and business skills training and education to Native businesses and Native entrepreneurs including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> financial education, including training and counseling in—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> applying for and securing business credit and investment capital;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> preparing and presenting financial statements; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> managing cash flow and other financial operations of a business;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> management education, including training and counseling in planning, organization, staffing, directing, and controlling each major activity or function of a business or startup; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> marketing education, including training and counseling in—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> identifying and segmenting domestic and international market opportunities;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> preparing and executing marketing plans;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> locating contract opportunities;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> negotiating contracts; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(V)</num>
<content> using varying public relations and advertising techniques;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> provide direct mentorship or assistance finding mentors in the industry in which the Native business or Native entrepreneur operates or intends to operate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> provide access to networks of potential investors, professionals in the same or similar fields, and other business owners with similar businesses.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Technology</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Each eligible applicant shall leverage technology to the maximum extent practicable to provide Native businesses and Native entrepreneurs with access to the connectivity tools needed to compete and thrive in 21st-century markets.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Oversight</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual evaluations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 1 year after the date on which the Secretary awards a grant to an eligible applicant under the program, and annually thereafter for the duration of the grant, the Secretary shall conduct an evaluation of, and prepare a report on, the eligible applicant, which shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> describe the performance of the eligible applicant; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> be used in determining the ongoing eligibility of the eligible applicant.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual report</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Not later than 1 year after the date on which the Secretary awards a grant to an eligible applicant under the program, and annually thereafter for the duration of the grant, each eligible applicant receiving an award under the program shall submit to the Secretary a report describing the services the eligible applicant provided under the program during the preceding year.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report content</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The report described in subparagraph (A) shall include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> a detailed breakdown of the Native businesses and Native entrepreneurs receiving services from the business incubator, including, for the year covered by the report—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the number of Native businesses and Native entrepreneurs participating in or receiving services from the business incubator and the types of services provided to those Native businesses and Native entrepreneurs;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the number of Native businesses and Native entrepreneurs established and jobs created or maintained; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> the performance of Native businesses and Native entrepreneurs while participating in the business incubator and after graduation or departure from the business incubator; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any other information the Secretary may require to evaluate the performance of a business incubator to ensure appropriate implementation of the program.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">To the maximum extent practicable, the Secretary shall not require an eligible applicant to report under subparagraph (A) information provided to the Secretary by the eligible applicant under other programs.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary shall coordinate with the heads of other Federal agencies to ensure that, to the maximum extent practicable, the report content and form under subparagraphs (A) and (B) are consistent with other reporting requirements for Federal programs that provide business and entrepreneurial assistance.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report to Congress</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Not later than 2 years after the date on which the Secretary first awards funding under the program, and biennially thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Indian Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives a report on the performance and effectiveness of the program.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Each report submitted under subparagraph (A) shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> account for each program year; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> include with respect to each business incubator receiving grant funds under the program—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the number of Native businesses and Native entrepreneurs that received business incubation or other services;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the number of businesses established with the assistance of the business incubator;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> the number of jobs established or maintained by Native businesses and Native entrepreneurs receiving business incubation services, including a description of where the jobs are located with respect to reservation communities;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> to the maximum extent practicable, the amount of capital investment and loan financing accessed by Native businesses and Native entrepreneurs receiving business incubation services; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(V)</num>
<content> an evaluation of the overall performance of the business incubator.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–174, § 4</ref>, <date date="2020-10-20">Oct. 20, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 840</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5804.</num>
<heading> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2020-10-20">October 20, 2020</date>, the Secretary shall promulgate regulations to implement the program.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–174, § 5</ref>, <date date="2020-10-20">Oct. 20, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 847</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5805.</num>
<heading> Schools to business incubator pipeline</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall facilitate the establishment of relationships between eligible applicants receiving funds through the program and educational institutions serving Native American communities, including tribal colleges and universities.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–174, § 6</ref>, <date date="2020-10-20">Oct. 20, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 847</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5806.</num>
<heading> Agency partnerships</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall coordinate with the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of the Treasury, and the Administrator of the Small Business Administration to ensure, to the maximum extent practicable, that business incubators receiving grant funds under the program have the information and materials needed to provide Native businesses and Native entrepreneurs with the information and assistance necessary to apply for business and entrepreneurial development programs administered by the Department of Agriculture, the Department of Commerce, the Department of the Treasury, and the Small Business Administration.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–174, § 7</ref>, <date date="2020-10-20">Oct. 20, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 847</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5807.</num>
<heading> Authorizations of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out the program $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2020 through 2024.</p>
</content>
</section>
</chapter>