<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 15—</num>
<heading>CONSTITUTIONAL RIGHTS OF INDIANS</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>GENERALLY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1301.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this subchapter, the term—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “Indian tribe” means any tribe, band, or other group of Indians subject to the jurisdiction of the United States and recognized as possessing powers of self-government;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> “powers of self-government” means and includes all governmental powers possessed by an Indian tribe, executive, legislative, and judicial, and all offices, bodies, and tribunals by and through which they are executed, including courts of Indian offenses; and means the inherent power of Indian tribes, hereby recognized and affirmed, to exercise criminal jurisdiction over all Indians;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> “Indian court” means any Indian tribal court or court of Indian offense; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> “Indian” means any person who would be subject to the jurisdiction of the United States as an Indian under section 1153, title 18, if that person were to commit an offense listed in that section in Indian country to which that section applies.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–284, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1968-04-11">Apr. 11, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 77</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–511, title VIII, § 8077(b)</ref>, (c), <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1892</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1302.</num>
<heading> Constitutional rights</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">No Indian tribe in exercising powers of self-government shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> make or enforce any law prohibiting the free exercise of religion, or abridging the freedom of speech, or of the press, or the right of the people peaceably to assemble and to petition for a redress of grievances;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> violate the right of the people to be secure in their persons, houses, papers, and effects against unreasonable search and seizures, nor issue warrants, but upon probable cause, supported by oath or affirmation, and particularly describing the place to be searched and the person or thing to be seized;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> subject any person for the same offense to be twice put in jeopardy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> compel any person in any criminal case to be a witness against himself;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> take any private property for a public use without just compensation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> deny to any person in a criminal proceeding the right to a speedy and public trial, to be informed of the nature and cause of the accusation, to be confronted with the witnesses against him, to have compulsory process for obtaining witnesses in his favor, and at his own expense to have the assistance of counsel for his defense (except as provided in subsection (b));</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> require excessive bail, impose excessive fines, or inflict cruel and unusual punishments;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> except as provided in subparagraph (C), impose for conviction of any 1 offense any penalty or punishment greater than imprisonment for a term of 1 year or a fine of $5,000, or both;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> subject to subsection (b), impose for conviction of any 1 offense any penalty or punishment greater than imprisonment for a term of 3 years or a fine of $15,000, or both; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> impose on a person in a criminal proceeding a total penalty or punishment greater than imprisonment for a term of 9 years;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> deny to any person within its jurisdiction the equal protection of its laws or deprive any person of liberty or property without due process of law;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> pass any bill of attainder or ex post facto law; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> deny to any person accused of an offense punishable by imprisonment the right, upon request, to a trial by jury of not less than six persons.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Offenses subject to greater than 1-year imprisonment or a fine greater than $5,000</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A tribal court may subject a defendant to a term of imprisonment greater than 1 year but not to exceed 3 years for any 1 offense, or a fine greater than $5,000 but not to exceed $15,000, or both, if the defendant is a person accused of a criminal offense who—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> has been previously convicted of the same or a comparable offense by any jurisdiction in the United States; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> is being prosecuted for an offense comparable to an offense that would be punishable by more than 1 year of imprisonment if prosecuted by the United States or any of the States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rights of defendants</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In a criminal proceeding in which an Indian tribe, in exercising powers of self-government, imposes a total term of imprisonment of more than 1 year on a defendant, the Indian tribe shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provide to the defendant the right to effective assistance of counsel at least equal to that guaranteed by the United States Constitution; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> at the expense of the tribal government, provide an indigent defendant the assistance of a defense attorney licensed to practice law by any jurisdiction in the United States that applies appropriate professional licensing standards and effectively ensures the competence and professional responsibility of its licensed attorneys;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> require that the judge presiding over the criminal proceeding—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> has sufficient legal training to preside over criminal proceedings; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is licensed to practice law by any jurisdiction in the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> prior to charging the defendant, make publicly available the criminal laws (including regulations and interpretative documents), rules of evidence, and rules of criminal procedure (including rules governing the recusal of judges in appropriate circumstances) of the tribal government; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> maintain a record of the criminal proceeding, including an audio or other recording of the trial proceeding.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sentences</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In the case of a defendant sentenced in accordance with subsections (b) and (c), a tribal court may require the defendant—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> to serve the sentence—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in a tribal correctional center that has been approved by the Bureau of Indian Affairs for long-term incarceration, in accordance with guidelines to be developed by the Bureau of Indian Affairs (in consultation with Indian tribes) not later than 180 days after <date date="2010-07-29">July 29, 2010</date>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the nearest appropriate Federal facility, at the expense of the United States pursuant to the Bureau of Prisons tribal prisoner pilot program described in section 304(c) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002022">1</ref> of the Tribal Law and Order Act of 2010;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> in a State or local government-approved detention or correctional center pursuant to an agreement between the Indian tribe and the State or local government; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> in an alternative rehabilitation center of an Indian tribe; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to serve another alternative form of punishment, as determined by the tribal court judge pursuant to tribal law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition of offense</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this section, the term “offense” means a violation of a criminal law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect of section</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this section affects the obligation of the United States, or any State government that has been delegated authority by the United States, to investigate and prosecute any criminal violation in Indian country.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–284, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="1968-04-11">Apr. 11, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 77</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–570, title IV, § 4217</ref>, <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3207–146</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–211, title II, § 234(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-07-29">July 29, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2279</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1302a.</num>
<heading> Bureau of Prisons tribal prisoner program</heading>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 120 days after <date date="2022-03-15">March 15, 2022</date>, the Director of the Bureau of Prisons shall establish a program under which the Bureau of Prisons shall accept offenders convicted in tribal court pursuant to <ref>section 1302 of this title</ref> (as amended by this section), subject to the conditions described in paragraph (2).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conditions</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">As a condition of participation in the program described in paragraph (1), the tribal court shall submit to the Attorney General a request for confinement of the offender, for approval by the Attorney General (or a designee) by not later than 30 days after the date of submission.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Requests for confinement shall be limited to offenders convicted of a violent crime (comparable to the violent crimes described in <ref>section 1153(a) of title 18</ref>) for which the sentence includes a term of imprisonment of 1 or more years.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Custody conditions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The imprisonment by the Bureau of Prisons shall be subject to the conditions described in <ref>section 5003 of title 18</ref>, regarding the custody of State offenders, except that the offender shall be placed in the nearest available and appropriate Federal facility, and imprisoned at the expense of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cap</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Bureau of Prisons shall confine not more than 100 tribal offenders at any time.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rescinding requests</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The applicable tribal government shall retain the authority to rescind the request for confinement of a tribal offender by the Bureau of Prisons under this paragraph at any time during the sentence of the offender.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Return to tribal custody</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">On rescission of a request under subparagraph (A), a tribal offender shall be returned to tribal custody.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reassessment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If tribal court demand for participation in this program exceeds 100 tribal offenders, a representative of the Bureau of Prisons shall notify Congress.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–211, title II, § 234(c)</ref>, <date date="2010-07-29">July 29, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2281</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–103, div. W, title VIII, § 803</ref>, <date date="2022-03-15">Mar. 15, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 898</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1303.</num>
<heading> Habeas corpus</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The privilege of the writ of habeas corpus shall be available to any person, in a court of the United States, to test the legality of his detention by order of an Indian tribe.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–284, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="1968-04-11">Apr. 11, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 78</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1304.</num>
<heading> Tribal jurisdiction over covered crimes</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assault of Tribal justice personnel</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “assault of Tribal justice personnel” means any violation of the criminal law of the Indian tribe that has jurisdiction over the Indian country where the violation occurs that involves the use, attempted use, or threatened use of physical force against an individual authorized to act for, or on behalf of, that Indian tribe or serving that Indian tribe during, or because of, the performance or duties of that individual in—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> preventing, detecting, investigating, making arrests relating to, making apprehensions for, or prosecuting a covered crime;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> adjudicating, participating in the adjudication of, or supporting the adjudication of a covered crime;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> detaining, providing supervision for, or providing services for persons charged with a covered crime; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> incarcerating, supervising, providing treatment for, providing rehabilitation services for, or providing reentry services for persons convicted of a covered crime.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Child</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “child” means a person who has not attained the lesser of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the age of 18; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> except in the case of sexual abuse, the age specified by the criminal law of the Indian tribe that has jurisdiction over the Indian country where the violation occurs.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Child violence</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “child violence” means the use, threatened use, or attempted use of violence against a child proscribed by the criminal law of the Indian tribe that has jurisdiction over the Indian country where the violation occurs.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coercion; commercial sex act</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The terms “coercion” and “commercial sex act” have the meanings given the terms in <ref>section 1591(e) of title 18</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Covered crime</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “covered crime” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> assault of Tribal justice personnel;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> child violence;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> dating violence;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> domestic violence;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> obstruction of justice;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> sexual violence;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> sex trafficking;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> stalking; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> a violation of a protection order.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Dating violence</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “dating violence” means any violation of the criminal law of the Indian tribe that has jurisdiction over the Indian country where the violation occurs that is committed by a person who is or has been in a social relationship of a romantic or intimate nature with the victim, as determined by the length of the relationship, the type of relationship, and the frequency of interaction between the persons involved in the relationship.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Domestic violence</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “domestic violence” means any violation of the criminal law of the Indian tribe that has jurisdiction over the Indian country where the violation occurs that is committed by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a current or former spouse or intimate partner of the victim;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a person with whom the victim shares a child in common;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a person who is cohabitating with or who has cohabitated with the victim as a spouse or intimate partner; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a person similarly situated to a spouse of the victim under the domestic- or family-violence laws of the Indian tribe that has jurisdiction over the Indian country where the violation occurs.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Indian country</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Indian country” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 1151 of title 18</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Obstruction of justice</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “obstruction of justice” means any violation of the criminal law of the Indian tribe that has jurisdiction over the Indian country where the violation occurs that involves interfering with the administration or due process of the laws of the Indian tribe, including any Tribal criminal proceeding or investigation of a crime.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(10)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Participating tribe</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “participating tribe” means an Indian tribe that elects to exercise special Tribal criminal jurisdiction over the Indian country of that Indian tribe.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(11)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Protection order</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “protection order”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> means any injunction, restraining order, or other order issued by a civil or criminal court for the purpose of preventing violent or threatening acts or harassment against, sexual violence against, contact or communication with, or physical proximity to, another person; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> includes any temporary or final order issued by a civil or criminal court, whether obtained by filing an independent action or as a pendent lite order in another proceeding, if the civil or criminal order was issued in response to a complaint, petition, or motion filed by or on behalf of a person seeking protection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(12)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sex trafficking</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “sex trafficking” means conduct within the meaning of <ref>section 1591(a) of title 18</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(13)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sexual violence</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “sexual violence” means any nonconsensual sexual act or contact proscribed by the criminal law of the Indian tribe that has jurisdiction over the Indian country where the violation occurs, including in any case in which the victim lacks the capacity to consent to the act.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(14)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special Tribal criminal jurisdiction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “special Tribal criminal jurisdiction” means the criminal jurisdiction that a participating tribe may exercise under this section but could not otherwise exercise.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(15)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Spouse or intimate partner</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “spouse or intimate partner” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 2266 of title 18</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(16)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Stalking</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “stalking” means engaging in a course of conduct directed at a specific person proscribed by the criminal law of the Indian tribe that has jurisdiction over the Indian country where the violation occurs that would cause a reasonable person—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to fear for the person’s safety or the safety of others; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to suffer substantial emotional distress.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(17)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Violation of a protection order</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “violation of a protection order” means an act that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> occurs in the Indian country of a participating tribe; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> violates a provision of a protection order that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> prohibits or provides protection against violent or threatening acts or harassment against, sexual violence against, contact or communication with, or physical proximity to, another person;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> was issued against the defendant;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> is enforceable by the participating tribe; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> is consistent with <ref>section 2265(b) of title 18</ref>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nature of the criminal jurisdiction</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, in addition to all powers of self-government recognized and affirmed by sections 1301 and 1303 of this title, the powers of self-government of a participating tribe, including any participating tribes in the State of Maine, include the inherent power of that tribe, which is hereby recognized and affirmed, to exercise special Tribal criminal jurisdiction over all persons.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Concurrent jurisdiction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The exercise of special Tribal criminal jurisdiction by a participating tribe shall be concurrent with the jurisdiction of the United States, of a State, or of both.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Nothing in this section—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> creates or eliminates any Federal or State criminal jurisdiction over Indian country; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> affects the authority of the United States or any State government that has been delegated authority by the United States to investigate and prosecute a criminal violation in Indian country.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception if victim and defendant are both non-Indians</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A participating tribe may not exercise special Tribal criminal jurisdiction over an alleged offense, other than obstruction of justice or assault of Tribal justice personnel, if neither the defendant nor the alleged victim is an Indian.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition of victim</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In this paragraph and with respect to a criminal proceeding in which a participating tribe exercises special Tribal criminal jurisdiction based on a violation of a protection order, the term “victim” means a person specifically protected by a protection order that the defendant allegedly violated.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Criminal conduct</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A participating tribe may exercise special Tribal criminal jurisdiction over a defendant for a covered crime that occurs in the Indian country of the participating tribe.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rights of defendants</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In a criminal proceeding in which a participating tribe exercises special Tribal criminal jurisdiction, the participating tribe shall provide to the defendant—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> all applicable rights under this Act;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> if a term of imprisonment of any length may be imposed, all rights described in <ref>section 1302(c) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> the right to a trial by an impartial jury that is drawn from sources that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> reflect a fair cross section of the community; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> do not systematically exclude any distinctive group in the community, including non-Indians; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> all other rights whose protection is necessary under the Constitution of the United States in order for Congress to recognize and affirm the inherent power of the participating tribe to exercise special Tribal criminal jurisdiction over the defendant.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Petitions to stay detention</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A person who has filed a petition for a writ of habeas corpus in a court of the United States under <ref>section 1303 of this title</ref> may petition that court to stay further detention of that person by the participating tribe.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grant of stay</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A court shall grant a stay described in paragraph (1) if the court—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> finds that there is a substantial likelihood that the habeas corpus petition will be granted; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> after giving each alleged victim in the matter an opportunity to be heard, finds by clear and convincing evidence that under conditions imposed by the court, the petitioner is not likely to flee or pose a danger to any person or the community if released.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Petitions for writs of habeas corpus</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">After a defendant has been sentenced by a participating tribe, the defendant may file a petition for a writ of habeas corpus in a court of the United States under <ref>section 1303 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">An application for a writ of habeas corpus on behalf of a person in custody pursuant to an order of a Tribal court shall not be granted unless —</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the applicant has exhausted the remedies available in the Tribal court system;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> there is an absence of an available Tribal corrective process; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> circumstances exist that render the Tribal corrective process ineffective to protect the rights of the applicant.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice; habeas corpus petitions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A participating tribe that has ordered the detention of any person has a duty to timely notify in writing such person of their rights and privileges under this section and under <ref>section 1303 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reimbursement and grants to Tribal governments</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reimbursement</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Attorney General may reimburse Tribal government authorities (or an authorized designee of a Tribal government) for expenses incurred in exercising special Tribal criminal jurisdiction.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible expenses</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Eligible expenses for reimbursement under subparagraph (A) shall include expenses and costs incurred in, relating to, or associated with—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> investigating, making arrests relating to, making apprehensions for, or prosecuting covered crimes (including costs involving the purchasing, collecting, and processing of sexual assault forensic materials);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> detaining, providing supervision of, or providing services for persons charged with covered crimes (including costs associated with providing health care);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> providing indigent defense services for 1 or more persons charged with 1 or more covered crimes; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> incarcerating, supervising, or providing treatment, rehabilitation, or reentry services for 1 or more persons charged with 1 or more covered crimes.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Procedure</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Reimbursements authorized under subparagraph (A) shall be in accordance with rules promulgated by the Attorney General, after consultation with Indian tribes, and within 1 year after <date date="2022-03-15">March 15, 2022</date>.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Maximum reimbursement</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">The rules promulgated by the Attorney General under clause (i)—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> shall set a maximum allowable reimbursement to any Tribal government (or an authorized designee of any Tribal government) in a 1-year period; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<chapeau> may allow the Attorney General—</chapeau>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> to establish conditions under which a Tribal government (or an authorized designee of a Tribal government) may seek a waiver to the maximum allowable reimbursement requirement established under subclause (I); and</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> to waive the maximum allowable reimbursement requirements established under subclause (I) for a Tribal government (or an authorized designee of a Tribal government) if the conditions established by the Attorney General under item (aa) are met by that Tribal government (or authorized designee).</content>
</item>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Timeliness of reimbursements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">To the maximum extent practicable, the Attorney General shall—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<chapeau> not later than 90 days after the date on which the Attorney General receives a qualifying reimbursement request from a Tribal government (or an authorized designee of a Tribal government)—</chapeau>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> reimburse the Tribal government (or authorized designee); or</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> notify the Tribal government (or authorized designee) of the reason by which the Attorney General was unable to issue the reimbursement; and</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> not later than 30 days after the date on which a Tribal government (or an authorized designee of a Tribal government) reaches the annual maximum allowable reimbursement for the Tribal government (or an authorized designee) established by the Attorney General under clause (ii)(I), notify the Tribal government (or authorized designee) that the Tribal government has reached its annual maximum allowable reimbursement.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility for participating tribes in Alaska</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A Tribal government (or an authorized designee of a Tribal Government) of an Indian tribe designated as a participating Tribe under subtitle B of title VIII of the Violence Against Women Act Reauthorization Act of 2022 shall be eligible for reimbursement, in accordance with this paragraph, of expenses incurred in exercising special Tribal criminal jurisdiction under that subtitle.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grants</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Attorney General may award grants to Tribal governments (or authorized designees of Tribal governments), including a Tribal government (or an authorized designee of a Tribal government) of an Indian tribe designated as a participating Tribe under subtitle B of title VIII of the Violence Against Women Act Reauthorization Act of 2022—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> to strengthen Tribal criminal justice systems to assist Indian tribes in exercising special Tribal criminal jurisdiction, including for—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> law enforcement (including the capacity of law enforcement, court personnel, or other non-law enforcement entities that have no Federal or State arrest authority agencies but have been designated by an Indian tribe as responsible for maintaining public safety within the territorial jurisdiction of the Indian tribe, to enter information into and obtain information from national crime information databases);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> prosecution;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> trial and appellate courts (including facilities maintenance, renovation, and rehabilitation);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> supervision systems;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> detention and corrections (including facilities maintenance, renovation, and rehabilitation);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> treatment, rehabilitation, and reentry programs and services;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> culturally appropriate services and assistance for victims and their families; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> criminal codes and rules of criminal procedure, appellate procedure, and evidence;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to provide indigent criminal defendants with licensed defense counsel, at no cost to the defendant, in criminal proceedings in which a participating tribe prosecutes covered crimes;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to ensure that, in criminal proceedings in which a participating tribe exercises special Tribal criminal jurisdiction, jurors are summoned, selected, and instructed in a manner consistent with all applicable requirements; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> to accord victims of covered crimes rights that are similar to the rights of a crime victim described in <ref>section 3771(a) of title 18</ref> consistent with Tribal law and custom.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Supplement, not supplant</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Amounts made available under this section shall supplement and not supplant any other Federal, State, or local government amounts made available to carry out activities described in this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">There is authorized to be appropriated $25,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to carry out subsection (h); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to provide training, technical assistance, data collection, and evaluation of the criminal justice systems of participating tribes.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Of the total amount made available under paragraph (1) for each fiscal year, not more than 40 percent shall be used for reimbursements under subsection (h)(1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–284, title II, § 204</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 113–4, title IX, § 904</ref>, <date date="2013-03-07">Mar. 7, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 120</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 117–103, div. W, title VIII, § 804</ref>, <date date="2022-03-15">Mar. 15, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 898</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1305.</num>
<heading> Tribal jurisdiction in Alaska</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to title II of <ref>Public Law 90–284</ref> (<ref>25 U.S.C. 1301</ref> et seq.) (commonly known as the “Indian Civil Rights Act of 1968”), Congress recognizes and affirms the inherent authority of any Indian tribe occupying a Village in the State to exercise criminal and civil jurisdiction over all Indians present in the Village.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tribal civil jurisdiction to enforce protection orders</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A court of any Indian tribe in the State shall have full civil jurisdiction to issue and enforce protection orders involving any person in matters—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> arising within the Village of the Indian tribe; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> otherwise within the authority of the Indian tribe.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inclusions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The full civil jurisdiction to issue and enforce protection orders under paragraph (1) includes the authority to enforce protection orders through—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> civil contempt proceedings;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> exclusion of violators from the Village of the Indian tribe; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> other appropriate mechanisms.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special Tribal criminal jurisdiction</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, in addition to all powers of self-government recognized and affirmed under subsection (a), the powers of self-government of a participating Tribe include the inherent power of the participating Tribe, which is hereby recognized and affirmed, to exercise special Tribal criminal jurisdiction over a defendant for a covered crime that occurs in the Village of the participating Tribe.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Concurrent jurisdiction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The exercise of special Tribal criminal jurisdiction by a participating Tribe shall be concurrent with the jurisdiction of the United States, the State, or both.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception if victim and defendant are both non-Indians</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A participating Tribe may not exercise special Tribal criminal jurisdiction over an alleged offense of a covered crime, other than obstruction of justice or assault of Tribal justice personnel, if neither the defendant nor the alleged victim is an Indian.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition of victim</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In this paragraph and with respect to a criminal proceeding in which a participating Tribe exercises special Tribal criminal jurisdiction based on a violation of a protection order, the term “victim” means a person specifically protected by the protection order that the defendant allegedly violated.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Pilot program for special Tribal criminal jurisdiction over persons who are not Indians</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subject to title II of <ref>Public Law 90–284</ref> (<ref>25 U.S.C. 1301</ref> et seq.) (commonly known as the “Indian Civil Rights Act of 1968”), there is established a pilot program under which the Attorney General, subject to paragraph (5), shall designate not more than 5 Indian tribes per calendar year as participating Tribes to exercise the special Tribal criminal jurisdiction described in paragraph (6) over all persons present in the Village of the Indian tribe.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Procedure</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">At any time during the 1-year period beginning on <date date="2022-03-15">March 15, 2022</date>, and annually thereafter, an Indian tribe may request the Attorney General to designate the Indian tribe as a participating Tribe under paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Designation of participating tribes</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior and affected Indian tribes, shall establish a process to designate Indian tribes to participate in the pilot program, which process shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> require that preference shall be given to Indian tribes occupying Villages—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the populations of which are predominantly Indian; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> that lack a permanent State law enforcement physical presence;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> require that for each Indian tribe requesting to be designated as a participating Tribe, the Attorney General makes a determination that the criminal justice system of the Indian tribe has adequate safeguards in place to protect defendants’ rights, consistent with <ref>section 204(d) of Public Law 90–284</ref> (<ref>25 U.S.C. 1304(d)</ref>) (commonly known as the “Indian Civil Rights Act of 1968”); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> be subject to such other criteria as the Attorney General considers to be appropriate to achieve the purposes of this subtitle.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Designation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Attorney General shall designate Indian tribes to participate in the pilot program under paragraph (1) using the process established under subparagraph (A).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Intertribal participation</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">2 or more participating Tribes (or the Tribal organization (as defined in <ref>section 5304 of this title</ref>) of the participating Tribe, if the Tribal organization is exercising delegated authority from the participating Tribe)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> may elect to participate jointly in the pilot program by providing shared resources to carry out the purposes of the pilot program; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> on making an election pursuant to clause (i), shall be considered to be a single participating Tribe for purposes of the maximum number of participating Tribes under paragraphs (1) and (5).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional participating tribes</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Additional participating Tribes may elect to join an established intertribal partnership under subparagraph (A) at any time after the intertribal partnership is established.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">An intertribal partnership that additional participating Tribes elect to join pursuant to clause (i) shall be considered to be a single participating Tribe for purposes of the maximum number of participating Tribes under paragraphs (1) and (5).</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Maximum number of participating tribes</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the Attorney General may designate not more than 30 Indian tribes to participate in the pilot program.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The limitation under subparagraph (A) shall not apply if the Attorney General submits to the Committee on Indian Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives, and publishes in the Federal Register, a written notice of the intention to designate additional Indian tribes as participating Tribes, including the rationale for the designation, by not later than the date that is 180 days before the date of designation.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Description of jurisdiction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Congress recognizes and affirms that an Indian tribe selected to participate in the pilot program as a participating Tribe may exercise, subject to paragraph (7), special Tribal criminal jurisdiction with respect to covered crimes.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rights of defendants</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In exercising special Tribal criminal jurisdiction under the pilot program, a participating Tribe shall provide to each defendant all rights described in <ref>section 204(d) of Public Law 90–284</ref> (<ref>25 U.S.C. 1304(d)</ref>) (commonly known as the “Indian Civil Rights Act of 1968”).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sentences</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In a criminal proceeding in which an Indian court of a participating Tribe, in exercising special Tribal criminal jurisdiction with respect to a covered crime, imposes a sentence of imprisonment of more than 1 year on a defendant pursuant to <ref>section 202(b) of Public Law 90–284</ref> (<ref>25 U.S.C. 1302(b)</ref>) (commonly known as the “Indian Civil Rights Act of 1968”), the Indian court may require the defendant—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> to serve a sentence—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in a Tribal correctional center that has been approved by the Bureau of Indian Affairs for long-term incarceration, in accordance with guidelines set by the Bureau of Indian Affairs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> at the expense of the United States, in the nearest appropriate Federal facility pursuant to the Bureau of Prisons Tribal Prisoner Program established under <ref>section 1302a(c)(1) of this title</ref>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> at the expense of the participating Tribe and, subject to <ref>section 204(f)(1) of Public Law 90–284</ref> (<ref>25 U.S.C. 1304(f)(1)</ref>) (commonly known as the “Indian Civil Rights Act of 1968”), reimbursable by the Attorney General, in a detention or correctional center approved by the State or a local government of the State pursuant to a memorandum of agreement between the participating Tribe and the State or local government of the State; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to serve another alternative form of punishment, as determined by the Indian court pursuant to Tribal law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Memoranda of agreement</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Attorney General and the Secretary of the Interior may enter into such memoranda of agreement with participating Tribes and the State as are necessary and appropriate—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to coordinate respective law enforcement activities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to share equipment and other resources;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to establish cross-deputization arrangements;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to coordinate appropriate training activities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> to address any other matters that will facilitate the successful implementation of the pilot program, including intergovernmental agreements regarding—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the incarceration of convicted persons; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> cooperation in the investigation and prosecution of crimes.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Alaska Tribal Public Safety Advisory Committee</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 1 year <date date="2022-03-15">March 15, 2022</date>, the Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior, affected Indian tribes, and the State, shall establish a committee, to be known as the “Alaska Tribal Public Safety Advisory Committee” (referred to in this subsection as the “Committee”).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Membership</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Committee shall consist of 1 or more representatives from—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> participating Tribes and Indian tribes aspiring to participate in the pilot program;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Federal, Tribal, State, and local law enforcement; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Tribal nonprofit organizations providing victim services.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Committee shall focus on—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> improving the justice systems, crime prevention, and victim services of Indian tribes and the State; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> increasing coordination and communication among Federal, Tribal, State, and local law enforcement agencies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Travel expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A member of the Committee shall be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, at rates authorized for employees of agencies under subchapter I of chapter 57 of title 5, while away from their homes or regular places of business in the performance of services for the Committee.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonapplicability of FACA</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002023">1</ref> shall not apply to the Committee.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this subsection such sums as may be necessary for the period of fiscal years 2023 through 2027, to remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 5 years after <date date="2022-03-15">March 15, 2022</date>, the Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior and affected Indian tribes, shall submit to Congress a report describing the results of the pilot program, including an explanation of any modifications to law necessary to facilitate improved law enforcement in Villages.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Nothing in this subtitle—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> limits, alters, expands, or diminishes the civil or criminal jurisdiction of the United States, the State, any subdivision of the State, or any Indian tribe in the State;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> creates or eliminates any Federal or State criminal jurisdiction over a Village; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> affects the authority of the United States or any authority delegated by the United States to the State to investigate and prosecute a criminal violation in a Village.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–103, div. W, title VIII, § 813</ref>, <date date="2022-03-15">Mar. 15, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 906</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>MODEL CODE GOVERNING COURTS OF INDIAN OFFENSES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1311.</num>
<heading> Model code</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior is authorized and directed to recommend to the Congress, on or before <date date="1968-07-01">July 1, 1968</date>, a model code to govern the administration of justice by courts of Indian offenses on Indian reservations. Such code shall include provisions which will (1) assure that any individual being tried for an offense by a court of Indian offenses shall have the same rights, privileges, and immunities under the United States Constitution as would be guaranteed any citizen of the United States being tried in a Federal court for any similar offense, (2) assure that any individual being tried for an offense by a court of Indian offenses will be advised and made aware of his rights under the United States Constitution, and under any tribal constitution applicable to such individual, (3) establish proper qualifications for the office of judge of the court of Indian offenses, and (4) provide for the establishing of educational classes for the training of judges of courts of Indian offenses. In carrying out the provisions of this subchapter, the Secretary of the Interior shall consult with the Indians, Indian tribes, and interested agencies of the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–284, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="1968-04-11">Apr. 11, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 78</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1312.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is hereby authorized to be appropriated such sum as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–284, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="1968-04-11">Apr. 11, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 78</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>JURISDICTION OVER CRIMINAL AND CIVIL ACTIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1321.</num>
<heading> Assumption by State of criminal jurisdiction</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consent of United States</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The consent of the United States is hereby given to any State not having jurisdiction over criminal offenses committed by or against Indians in the areas of Indian country situated within such State to assume, with the consent of the Indian tribe occupying the particular Indian country or part thereof which could be affected by such assumption, such measure of jurisdiction over any or all of such offenses committed within such Indian country or any part thereof as may be determined by such State to the same extent that such State has jurisdiction over any such offense committed elsewhere within the State, and the criminal laws of such State shall have the same force and effect within such Indian country or part thereof as they have elsewhere within that State.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Concurrent jurisdiction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">At the request of an Indian tribe, and after consultation with and consent by the Attorney General, the United States shall accept concurrent jurisdiction to prosecute violations of sections 1152 and 1153 of title 18 within the Indian country of the Indian tribe.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Alienation, encumbrance, taxation, and use of property; hunting, trapping, or fishing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall authorize the alienation, encumbrance, or taxation of any real or personal property, including water rights, belonging to any Indian or any Indian tribe, band, or community that is held in trust by the United States or is subject to a restriction against alienation imposed by the United States; or shall authorize regulation of the use of such property in a manner inconsistent with any Federal treaty, agreement, or statute or with any regulation made pursuant thereto; or shall deprive any Indian or any Indian tribe, band, or community of any right, privilege, or immunity afforded under Federal treaty, agreement, or statute with respect to hunting, trapping, or fishing or the control, licensing, or regulation thereof.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–284, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="1968-04-11">Apr. 11, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 78</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–211, title II, § 221(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-07-29">July 29, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2271</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1322.</num>
<heading> Assumption by State of civil jurisdiction</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consent of United States; force and effect of civil laws</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The consent of the United States is hereby given to any State not having jurisdiction over civil causes of action between Indians or to which Indians are parties which arise in the areas of Indian country situated within such State to assume, with the consent of the tribe occupying the particular Indian country or part thereof which would be affected by such assumption, such measure of jurisdiction over any or all such civil causes of action arising within such Indian country or any part thereof as may be determined by such State to the same extent that such State has jurisdiction over other civil causes of action, and those civil laws of such State that are of general application to private persons or private property shall have the same force and effect within such Indian country or part thereof as they have elsewhere within that State.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Alienation, encumbrance, taxation, use, and probate of property</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall authorize the alienation, encumbrance, or taxation of any real or personal property, including water rights, belonging to any Indian or any Indian tribe, band, or community that is held in trust by the United States or is subject to a restriction against alienation imposed by the United States; or shall authorize regulation of the use of such property in a manner inconsistent with any Federal treaty, agreement, or statute, or with any regulation made pursuant thereto; or shall confer jurisdiction upon the State to adjudicate, in probate proceedings or otherwise, the ownership or right to possession of such property or any interest therein.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Force and effect of tribal ordinances or customs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any tribal ordinance or custom heretofore or hereafter adopted by an Indian tribe, band, or community in the exercise of any authority which it may possess shall, if not inconsistent with any applicable civil law of the State, be given full force and effect in the determination of civil causes of action pursuant to this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–284, title IV, § 402</ref>, <date date="1968-04-11">Apr. 11, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 79</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1323.</num>
<heading> Retrocession of jurisdiction by State</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Acceptance by United States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The United States is authorized to accept a retrocession by any State of all or any measure of the criminal or civil jurisdiction, or both, acquired by such State pursuant to the provisions of <ref>section 1162 of title 18</ref>, <ref>section 1360 of title 28</ref>, or <ref>section 7 of the Act of August 15, 1953</ref> (<ref>67 Stat. 588</ref>), as it was in effect prior to its repeal by subsection (b) of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Repeal of statutory provisions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0"><ref>Section 7 of the Act of August 15, 1953</ref> (<ref>67 Stat. 588</ref>), is hereby repealed, but such repeal shall not affect any cession of jurisdiction made pursuant to such section prior to its repeal.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–284, title IV, § 403</ref>, <date date="1968-04-11">Apr. 11, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 79</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1324.</num>
<heading> Amendment of State constitutions or statutes to remove legal impediment; effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding the provisions of any enabling Act for the admission of a State, the consent of the United States is hereby given to the people of any State to amend, where necessary, their State constitution or existing statutes, as the case may be, to remove any legal impediment to the assumption of civil or criminal jurisdiction in accordance with the provisions of this subchapter. The provisions of this subchapter shall not become effective with respect to such assumption of jurisdiction by any such State until the people thereof have appropriately amended their State constitution or statutes, as the case may be.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–284, title IV, § 404</ref>, <date date="1968-04-11">Apr. 11, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 79</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1325.</num>
<heading> Abatement of actions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Pending actions or proceedings; effect of cession</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No action or proceeding pending before any court or agency of the United States immediately prior to any cession of jurisdiction by the United States pursuant to this subchapter shall abate by reason of that cession. For the purposes of any such action or proceeding, such cession shall take effect on the day following the date of final determination of such action or proceeding.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Criminal actions; effect of cession</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No cession made by the United States under this subchapter shall deprive any court of the United States of jurisdiction to hear, determine, render judgment, or impose sentence in any criminal action instituted against any person for any offense committed before the effective date of such cession, if the offense charged in such action was cognizable under any law of the United States at the time of the commission of such offense. For the purposes of any such criminal action, such cession shall take effect on the day following the date of final determination of such action.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–284, title IV, § 405</ref>, <date date="1968-04-11">Apr. 11, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 80</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1326.</num>
<heading> Special election</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">State jurisdiction acquired pursuant to this subchapter with respect to criminal offenses or civil causes of action, or with respect to both, shall be applicable in Indian country only where the enrolled Indians within the affected area of such Indian country accept such jurisdiction by a majority vote of the adult Indians voting at a special election held for that purpose. The Secretary of the Interior shall call such special election under such rules and regulations as he may prescribe, when requested to do so by the tribal council or other governing body, or by 20 per centum of such enrolled adults.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–284, title IV, § 406</ref>, <date date="1968-04-11">Apr. 11, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 80</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>EMPLOYMENT OF LEGAL COUNSEL</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1331.</num>
<heading> Approval</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, if any application made by an Indian, Indian tribe, Indian council, or any band or group of Indians under any law requiring the approval of the Secretary of the Interior or the Commissioner of Indian Affairs of contracts or agreements relating to the employment of legal counsel (including the choice of counsel and the fixing of fees) by any such Indians, tribe, council, band, or group is neither granted nor denied within ninety days following the making of such application, such approval shall be deemed to have been granted.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–284, title VI, § 601</ref>, <date date="1968-04-11">Apr. 11, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 80</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER V—</num>
<heading>MATERIALS AND PUBLICATIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1341.</num>
<heading> Authorization of Secretary</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Revision of document on “Indian Affairs, Laws and Treaties” and treatise on “Federal Indian Laws”; compilation of official opinions; printing and republication</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In order that the constitutional rights of Indians might be fully protected, the Secretary of the Interior is authorized and directed to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> have the document entitled “Indian Affairs, Laws and Treaties” (Senate Document Numbered 319, volumes 1 and 2, Fifty-eighth Congress), revised and extended to include all treaties, laws, Executive orders, and regulations relating to Indian affairs in force on <date date="1967-09-01">September 1, 1967</date>, and to have such revised document printed at the Government Publishing Office;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> have revised and republished the treatise entitled “Federal Indian Law”; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> have prepared, to the extent determined by the Secretary of the Interior to be feasible, an accurate compilation of the official opinions, published and unpublished, of the Solicitor of the Department of the Interior relating to Indian affairs rendered by the Solicitor prior to <date date="1967-09-01">September 1, 1967</date>, and to have such compilation printed as a Government publication at the Government Publishing Office.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Current services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">With respect to the document entitled “Indian Affairs, Laws and Treaties” as revised and extended in accordance with paragraph (1) of subsection (a), and the compilation prepared in accordance with paragraph (3) of such subsection, the Secretary of the Interior shall take such action as may be necessary to keep such document and compilation current on an annual basis.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated for carrying out the provisions of this subchapter such sum as may be necessary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–284, title VII, § 701</ref>, <date date="1968-04-11">Apr. 11, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 80</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–265</ref>, <date date="1974-04-12">Apr. 12, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 84</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–235, div. H, title I, § 1301(b)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-16">Dec. 16, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 2537</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>