<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 40—</num>
<heading>INDIAN DAMS SAFETY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3801.</num>
<heading> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Secretary of the Interior has identified 53 dams on Indian lands that present a threat to human life in the event of a failure;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> because of inadequate attention in the past to problems stemming from structural deficiencies and regular maintenance requirements for dams operated by the Bureau of Indian Affairs, unsafe Bureau dams continue to pose an imminent threat to people and property;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> many Bureau dams have maintenance deficiencies regardless of their current safety condition classification and the deficiencies must be corrected to avoid future threats to human life and property;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> safe working dams on Indian lands are necessary to supply irrigation water, to provide flood control, to provide water for municipal, industrial, domestic, livestock, and recreation uses, and for fish and wildlife habitats; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> it is necessary to institute a regular dam maintenance and repair program, utilizing the expertise in the Bureau, Indian tribes, and other Federal agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–302, § 2</ref>, <date date="1994-08-23">Aug. 23, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1560</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3802.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “Bureau” means the Bureau of Indian Affairs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “dam” has the same meaning given such term by <ref>section 467 of title 33</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of the Interior.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “Indian tribe” means any Indian tribe, band, nation, pueblo, or other organized group or community, including any Alaska Native village or regional corporation as defined in or established pursuant to the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act [<ref>43 U.S.C. 1601</ref> et seq.], which is recognized as eligible for the special programs and services provided by the United States to Indian tribes because of their status as Indians.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–302, § 3</ref>, <date date="1994-08-23">Aug. 23, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1560</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–303, title II, § 215(d)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-12">Oct. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3694</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3803.</num>
<heading> Dam Safety Maintenance and Repair Program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish a dam safety maintenance and repair program within the Bureau to ensure maintenance and monitoring of the condition of each dam identified pursuant to subsection (e) necessary to maintain the dam in a satisfactory condition on a long-term basis.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer of existing functions and personnel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All functions performed before <date date="1994-08-23">August 23, 1994</date>, pursuant to the Dam Safety Program established by the Secretary of the Interior by order dated <date date="1980-02-28">February 28, 1980</date>, and all Bureau of Indian Affairs personnel assigned to such program as of <date date="1994-08-23">August 23, 1994</date>, are hereby transferred to the Dam Safety Maintenance and Repair Program. Any reference in any law, regulation, executive order, reorganization plan, or delegation of authority to the Dam Safety Program is deemed to be a reference to the Dam Safety Maintenance and Repair Program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rehabilitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Under the Dam Safety Maintenance and Repair Program, the Secretary shall perform such rehabilitation work as is necessary to bring the dams identified pursuant to subsection (e) to a satisfactory condition. In addition, each dam located on Indian lands shall be regularly maintained pursuant to the Dam Safety Maintenance and Repair Program established pursuant to subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Maintenance action plan</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall develop a maintenance action plan, which shall include a prioritization of actions to be taken, for those dams with a risk hazard rating of high or significant as identified pursuant to subsection (e).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Identification of dams</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Development of list</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall develop a comprehensive list of dams located on Indian lands that describes the dam safety condition classification of each dam, as specified in paragraph (2), the risk hazard classification of each dam, as specified in paragraph (3), and the conditions resulting from maintenance deficiencies.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Dam safety condition classifications</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The dam safety condition classification referred to in paragraph (1) is one of the following classifications:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Satisfactory</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">No existing or potential dam safety deficiencies are recognized. Safe performance is expected under all anticipated conditions.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fair</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">No existing dam safety deficiencies are recognized for normal loading conditions. Infrequent hydrologic or seismic events would probably result in a dam safety deficiency.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conditionally poor</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A potential dam safety deficiency is recognized for unusual loading conditions that may realistically occur during the expected life of the structure.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Poor</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A potential dam safety deficiency is clearly recognized for normal loading conditions. Immediate actions to resolve the deficiency are recommended; reservoir restrictions may be necessary until resolution of the problem.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(E)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Unsatisfactory</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A dam safety deficiency exists for normal loading conditions. Immediate remedial action is required for resolution of the problem.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Risk hazard classification</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The risk hazard classification referred to in paragraph (1) is one of the following classifications:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> High</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Six or more lives would be at risk or extensive property damage could occur if the dam failed.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Significant</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Between one and six lives would be at risk or significant property damage could occur if the dam failed.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Low</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">No lives would be at risk and limited property damage would occur if the dam failed.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on program authorization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Work authorized by this chapter shall be for the purpose of dam safety maintenance and structural repair. The Secretary may authorize, upon request of an Indian tribe, up to 20 percent of the cost of repairs to be used to provide additional conservation storage capacity or developing benefits beyond those provided by the original dams and reservoirs. This chapter is not intended to preclude development of increased storage or benefits under any other authority or to preclude measures to protect fish and wildlife.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Technical assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To carry out the purposes of this chapter, the Secretary may obtain technical assistance on a nonreimbursable basis from other departments and agencies. Notwithstanding any such technical assistance, the Dam Safety Maintenance and Repair Program established under subsection (a) shall be under the direction and control of the Bureau.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contract authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In addition to any other authority established by law, the Secretary is authorized to contract with Indian tribes under the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<ref>25 U.S.C. 450</ref> et seq.) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002224">1</ref> to carry out the Dam Safety Maintenance and Repair Program established under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall submit an annual report on the implementation of this chapter. The report shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the list of dams and their status on the maintenance action plan developed under this section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the projected total cost and a schedule of the projected annual cost of rehabilitation or repair for each dam under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">The report shall be submitted at the time the budget is required to be submitted under <ref>section 1105 of title 31</ref> to the Subcommittee on Native American Affairs of the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Indian Affairs of the Senate.</continuation>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–302, § 4</ref>, <date date="1994-08-23">Aug. 23, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1561</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–109, § 3</ref>, <date date="1996-02-12">Feb. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 764</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3804.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this chapter. Funds provided under this chapter are to be considered nonreimbursable.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–302, § 5</ref>, <date date="1994-08-23">Aug. 23, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1563</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3805.</num>
<heading> Indian dam safety</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Dam</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “dam” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 467 of title 33</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inclusions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “dam” includes any structure, facility, equipment, or vehicle used in connection with the operation of a dam.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fund</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “Fund” means, as applicable—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the High-Hazard Indian Dam Safety Deferred Maintenance Fund established by subsection (b)(1)(A); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Low-Hazard Indian Dam Safety Deferred Maintenance Fund established by subsection (b)(2)(A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> High hazard potential dam</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “high hazard potential dam” means a dam assigned to the significant or high hazard potential classification under the guidelines published by the Federal Emergency Management Agency entitled “Federal Guidelines for Dam Safety: Hazard Potential Classification System for Dams” (FEMA Publication Number 333).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Indian tribe</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Indian tribe” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 5304 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Low hazard potential dam</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “low hazard potential dam” means a dam assigned to the low hazard potential classification under the guidelines published by the Federal Emergency Management Agency entitled “Federal Guidelines for Dam Safety: Hazard Potential Classification System for Dams” (FEMA Publication Number 333).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Assistant Secretary for Indian Affairs, in consultation with the Secretary of the Army.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Indian Dam Safety Deferred Maintenance Funds</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> High-Hazard Fund</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">There is established in the Treasury of the United States a fund, to be known as the “High-Hazard Indian Dam Safety Deferred Maintenance Fund”, consisting of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> such amounts as are deposited in the Fund under subparagraph (B); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any interest earned on investment of amounts in the Fund under subparagraph (D).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deposits to Fund</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">For each of fiscal years 2017 through 2030, the Secretary of the Treasury shall deposit in the Fund $22,750,000 from the general fund of the Treasury.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability of amounts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Amounts deposited in the Fund under clause (i) shall be used, subject to appropriation, to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Expenditures from Fund</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">Subject to clause (ii), for each of fiscal years 2017 through 2030, the Secretary may, to the extent provided in advance in appropriations Acts, expend from the Fund, in accordance with this section, not more than the sum of—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> $22,750,000; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the amount of interest accrued in the Fund.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional expenditures</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The Secretary may expend more than $22,750,000 for any fiscal year referred to in clause (i) if the additional amounts are available in the Fund as a result of a failure of the Secretary to expend all of the amounts available under clause (i) in 1 or more prior fiscal years.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Investments of amounts</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The Secretary of the Treasury shall invest such portion of the Fund as is not, in the judgment of the Secretary, required to meet current withdrawals.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Credits to Fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The interest on, and the proceeds from the sale or redemption of, any obligations held in the Fund shall be credited to, and form a part of, the Fund.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(E)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfers of amounts</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The amounts required to be transferred to the Fund under this paragraph shall be transferred at least monthly.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adjustments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Proper adjustment shall be made in amounts subsequently transferred to the extent prior estimates are in excess of or less than the amounts required to be transferred.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(F)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">On <date date="2030-09-30">September 30, 2030</date>—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Fund shall terminate; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the unexpended and unobligated balance of the Fund shall be transferred to the general fund of the Treasury.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Low-Hazard Fund</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">There is established in the Treasury of the United States a fund, to be known as the “Low-Hazard Indian Dam Safety Deferred Maintenance Fund”, consisting of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> such amounts as are deposited in the Fund under subparagraph (B); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any interest earned on investment of amounts in the Fund under subparagraph (D).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deposits to Fund</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">For each of fiscal years 2017 through 2030, the Secretary of the Treasury shall deposit in the Fund $10,000,000 from the general fund of the Treasury.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability of amounts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Amounts deposited in the Fund under clause (i) shall be used, subject to appropriation, to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Expenditures from Fund</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">Subject to clause (ii), for each of fiscal years 2017 through 2030, the Secretary may, to the extent provided in advance in appropriations Acts, expend from the Fund, in accordance with this section, not more than the sum of—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> $10,000,000; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the amount of interest accrued in the Fund.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional expenditures</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The Secretary may expend more than $10,000,000 for any fiscal year referred to in clause (i) if the additional amounts are available in the Fund as a result of a failure of the Secretary to expend all of the amounts available under clause (i) in 1 or more prior fiscal years.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Investments of amounts</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The Secretary of the Treasury shall invest such portion of the Fund as is not, in the judgment of the Secretary, required to meet current withdrawals.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Credits to Fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The interest on, and the proceeds from the sale or redemption of, any obligations held in the Fund shall be credited to, and form a part of, the Fund.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(E)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfers of amounts</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The amounts required to be transferred to the Fund under this paragraph shall be transferred at least monthly.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adjustments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Proper adjustment shall be made in amounts subsequently transferred to the extent prior estimates are in excess of or less than the amounts required to be transferred.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(F)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">On <date date="2030-09-30">September 30, 2030</date>—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Fund shall terminate; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the unexpended and unobligated balance of the Fund shall be transferred to the general fund of the Treasury.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Repair, replacement, and maintenance of certain Indian dams</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program establishment</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Secretary shall establish a program to address the deferred maintenance needs of Indian dams that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> create flood risks or other risks to public or employee safety or natural or cultural resources; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> unduly impede the management and efficiency of Indian dams.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Funding</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> High-Hazard Fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Consistent with subsection (b)(1)(B), the Secretary shall use or transfer to the Bureau of Indian Affairs not less than $22,750,000 of amounts in the High-Hazard Indian Dam Safety Deferred Maintenance Fund, plus accrued interest, for each of fiscal years 2017 through 2030 to carry out maintenance, repair, and replacement activities for 1 or more of the Indian dams described in paragraph (2)(A).</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Low-Hazard Fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Consistent with subsection (b)(2)(B), the Secretary shall use or transfer to the Bureau of Indian Affairs not less than $10,000,000 of amounts in the Low-Hazard Indian Dam Safety Deferred Maintenance Fund, plus accrued interest, for each of fiscal years 2017 through 2030 to carry out maintenance, repair, and replacement activities for 1 or more of the Indian dams described in paragraph (2)(B).</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compliance with dam safety policies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Maintenance, repair, and replacement activities for Indian dams under this section shall be carried out in accordance with the dam safety policies of the Director of the Bureau of Indian Affairs established to carry out the Indian Dams Safety Act of 1994 (<ref>25 U.S.C. 3801</ref> et seq.).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible dams</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> High hazard potential dams</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The dams eligible for funding under paragraph (1)(B)(i) are Indian high hazard potential dams in the United States that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> are included in the safety of dams program established pursuant to the Indian Dams Safety Act of 1994 (<ref>25 U.S.C. 3801</ref> et seq.); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<item class="indent3">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002225">1</ref> are owned by the Federal Government, as listed in the Federal inventory required by Executive Order 13327 (<ref>40 U.S.C. 121</ref> note; relating to Federal real property asset management); and</content>
</item>
<item class="indent3">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> are managed by the Bureau of Indian Affairs (including dams managed under contracts or compacts pursuant to the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<ref>25 U.S.C. 5301</ref> et seq.)); or</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> have deferred maintenance documented by the Bureau of Indian Affairs.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Low hazard potential dams</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The dams eligible for funding under paragraph (1)(B)(ii) are Indian low hazard potential dams in the United States that, on <date date="2016-12-16">December 16, 2016</date>—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> are covered under the Indian Dams Safety Act of 1994 (<ref>25 U.S.C. 3801</ref> et seq.); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<item class="indent3">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> are owned by the Federal Government, as listed in the Federal inventory required by Executive Order 13327 (<ref>40 U.S.C. 121</ref> note; relating to Federal real property asset management); and</content>
</item>
<item class="indent3">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> are managed by the Bureau of Indian Affairs (including dams managed under contracts or compacts pursuant to the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<ref>25 U.S.C. 5301</ref> et seq.)); or</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> have deferred maintenance documented by the Bureau of Indian Affairs.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements and conditions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 120 days after <date date="2016-12-16">December 16, 2016</date>, and as a precondition to amounts being expended from the Fund to carry out this subsection, the Secretary, in consultation with representatives of affected Indian tribes, shall develop and submit to Congress—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> programmatic goals to carry out this subsection that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> would enable the completion of repairing, replacing, improving, or performing maintenance on Indian dams as expeditiously as practicable, subject to the dam safety policies of the Director of the Bureau of Indian Affairs established to carry out the Indian Dams Safety Act of 1994 (<ref>25 U.S.C. 3801</ref> et seq.);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> facilitate or improve the ability of the Bureau of Indian Affairs to carry out the mission of the Bureau of Indian Affairs in operating an Indian dam; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> ensure that the results of government-to-government consultation required under paragraph (4) be addressed; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> funding prioritization criteria to serve as a methodology for distributing funds under this subsection that take into account—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> the extent to which deferred maintenance of Indian dams poses a threat to—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> public or employee safety or health;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> natural or cultural resources; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> the ability of the Bureau of Indian Affairs to carry out the mission of the Bureau of Indian Affairs in operating an Indian dam;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> the extent to which repairing, replacing, improving, or performing maintenance on an Indian dam will—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> improve public or employee safety, health, or accessibility;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> assist in compliance with codes, standards, laws, or other requirements;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> address unmet needs; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> assist in protecting natural or cultural resources;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the methodology of the rehabilitation priority index of the Secretary, as in effect on <date date="2016-12-16">December 16, 2016</date>;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the potential economic benefits of the expenditures on job creation and general economic development in the affected tribal communities;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> the ability of an Indian dam to address tribal, regional, and watershed level flood prevention needs;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> the need to comply with the dam safety policies of the Director of the Bureau of Indian Affairs established to carry out the Indian Dams Safety Act of 1994 (<ref>25 U.S.C. 3801</ref> et seq.);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> the ability of the water storage capacity of an Indian dam to be increased to prevent flooding in downstream tribal and nontribal communities; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> such other factors as the Secretary determines to be appropriate to prioritize the use of available funds that are, to the fullest extent practicable, consistent with tribal and user recommendations received pursuant to the consultation and input process under paragraph (4).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tribal consultation and user input</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), before expending funds on an Indian dam pursuant to paragraph (1) and not later than 60 days after <date date="2016-12-16">December 16, 2016</date>, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> consult with the Director of the Bureau of Indian Affairs on the expenditure of funds;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> ensure that the Director of the Bureau of Indian Affairs advises the Indian tribe that has jurisdiction over the land on which a dam eligible to receive funding under paragraph (2) is located on the expenditure of funds; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> solicit and consider the input, comments, and recommendations of the landowners served by the Indian dam.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Emergencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">If the Secretary determines that an emergency circumstance exists with respect to an Indian dam, subparagraph (A) shall not apply with respect to that Indian dam.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Allocation among dams</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Subject to subparagraph (B), to the maximum extent practicable, the Secretary shall ensure that, for each of fiscal years 2017 through 2030, each Indian dam eligible for funding under paragraph (2) that has critical maintenance needs receives part of the funding under paragraph (1) to address critical maintenance needs.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Priority</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In allocating amounts under paragraph (1)(B), in addition to considering the funding priorities described in paragraph (3), the Secretary shall give priority to Indian dams eligible for funding under paragraph (2) that serve—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> more than 1 Indian tribe within an Indian reservation; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> highly populated Indian communities, as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cap on funding</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Subject to clause (ii), in allocating amounts under paragraph (1)(B), the Secretary shall allocate not more than $10,000,000 to any individual dam described in paragraph (2) during any consecutive 3-year period.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Notwithstanding the cap described in clause (i), if the full amount under paragraph (1)(B) cannot be fully allocated to eligible Indian dams because the costs of the remaining activities authorized in paragraph (1)(B) of an Indian dam would exceed the cap described in clause (i), the Secretary may allocate the remaining funds to eligible Indian dams in accordance with this subsection.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Basis of funding</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Any amounts made available under this paragraph shall be nonreimbursable.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(E)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability of ISDEAA</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<ref>25 U.S.C. 5301</ref> et seq.) shall apply to activities carried out under this paragraph.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tribal Safety of Dams Committee</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of Committee</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary of the Interior shall establish within the Bureau of Indian Affairs the Tribal Safety of Dams Committee (referred to in this paragraph as the “Committee”).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Membership</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Composition</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">The Committee shall be composed of 15 members, of whom—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<chapeau> 11 shall be appointed by the Secretary of the Interior from among individuals who, to the maximum extent practicable, have knowledge and expertise in dam safety issues and flood prevention and mitigation, of whom not less than 1 shall be a member of an Indian tribe in each of the Bureau of Indian Affairs regions of—</chapeau>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> the Northwest Region;</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> the Pacific Region;</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(cc)</num>
<content> the Western Region;</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(dd)</num>
<content> the Navajo Region;</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(ee)</num>
<content> the Southwest Region;</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(ff)</num>
<content> the Rocky Mountain Region;</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(gg)</num>
<content> the Great Plans <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002226">2</ref> Region; and</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(hh)</num>
<content> the Midwest Region;</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> 2 shall be appointed by the Secretary of the Interior from among employees of the Bureau of Indian Affairs who have knowledge and expertise in dam safety issues and flood prevention and mitigation;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> 1 shall be appointed by the Secretary of the Interior from among employees of the Bureau of Reclamation who have knowledge and expertise in dam safety issues and flood prevention and mitigation; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> 1 shall be appointed by the Secretary of the Army from among employees of the Corps of Engineers who have knowledge and expertise in dam safety issues and flood prevention and mitigation.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonvoting members</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The members of the Committee appointed under subclauses (II) and (III) of clause (i) shall be nonvoting members.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The appointments of the members of the Committee shall be made as soon as practicable after <date date="2016-12-16">December 16, 2016</date>.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Period of appointment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Members shall be appointed for the life of the Committee.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Vacancies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Any vacancy in the Committee shall not affect the powers of the Committee, but shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(E)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initial meeting</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Not later than 30 days after the date on which all members of the Committee have been appointed, the Committee shall hold the first meeting.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(F)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Meetings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Committee shall meet at the call of the Chairperson.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(G)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Quorum</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A majority of the members of the Committee shall constitute a quorum, but a lesser number of members may hold hearings.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(H)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Chairperson and Vice Chairperson</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Committee shall select a Chairperson and Vice Chairperson from among the members.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties of the committee</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Study</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Committee shall conduct a thorough study of all matters relating to the modernization of the Indian Dams Safety Act of 1994 (<ref>25 U.S.C. 3801</ref> et seq.).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recommendations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Committee shall develop recommendations for legislation to improve the Indian Dams Safety Act of 1994 (<ref>25 U.S.C. 3801</ref> et seq.).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Not later than 1 year after the date on which the Committee holds the first meeting, the Committee shall submit a report containing a detailed statement of the findings and conclusions of the Committee, together with recommendations for legislation that the Committee considers appropriate, to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Committee on Indian Affairs of the Senate; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Powers of the Committee</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Hearings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Committee may hold such hearings, sit and act at such times and places, take such testimony, and receive such evidence as the Committee considers appropriate to carry out this paragraph.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Information from Federal agencies</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The Committee may secure directly from any Federal department or agency such information as the Committee considers necessary to carry out this paragraph.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Request</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">On request of the Chairperson of the Committee, the head of any Federal department or agency shall furnish information described in clause (i) to the Committee.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Postal services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Committee may use the United States mails in the same manner and under the same conditions as other departments and agencies of the Federal Government.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Gifts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Committee may accept, use, and dispose of gifts or donations of services or property.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Committee personnel matters</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation of members</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Non-Federal members</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Each member of the Committee who is not an officer or employee of the Federal Government shall be compensated at a rate equal to the daily equivalent of the annual rate of basic pay prescribed for level IV of the Executive Schedule under <ref>section 5315 of title 5</ref> for each day (including travel time) during which the member is engaged in the performance of the duties of the Committee.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal members</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Each member of the Committee who is an officer or employee of the Federal Government shall serve without compensation in addition to that received for services as an officer or employee of the Federal Government.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Travel expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The members of the Committee shall be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, at rates authorized for employees of agencies under subchapter I of chapter 57 of title 5 while away from their homes or regular places of business in the performance of services for the Committee.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Staff</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(I)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent4">The Chairperson of the Committee may, without regard to the civil service laws and regulations, appoint and terminate an executive director and such other additional personnel as may be necessary to enable the Committee to perform the duties of the Committee.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(II)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Confirmation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent4">The employment of an executive director shall be subject to confirmation by the Committee.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The Chairperson of the Committee may fix the compensation of the executive director and other personnel without regard to chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5, relating to classification of positions and General Schedule pay rates, except that the rate of pay for the executive director and other personnel may not exceed the rate payable for level V of the Executive Schedule under section 5316 of that title.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Detail of Government employees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Any Federal Government employee may be detailed to the Committee without reimbursement, and such detail shall be without interruption or loss of civil service status or privilege.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(E)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Procurement of temporary and intermittent services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Chairperson of the Committee may procure temporary and intermittent services under <ref>section 3109(b) of title 5</ref> at rates for individuals that do not exceed the daily equivalent of the annual rate of basic pay prescribed for level V of the Executive Schedule under section 5316 of that title.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination of the Committee</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Committee shall terminate 90 days after the date on which the Committee submits the report under paragraph (2)(C).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Funding</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Of the amounts authorized to be expended from either Fund, $1,000,000 shall be made available from either Fund during fiscal year 2017 to carry out this subsection, to remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Indian dam surveys</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tribal reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall request that, not less frequently than once every 180 days, each Indian tribe submit to the Secretary a report providing an inventory of the dams located on the land of the Indian tribe.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> BIA reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not less frequently than once each year, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report describing the condition of each dam under the partial or total jurisdiction of the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Flood plain management pilot program</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary shall establish, within the Bureau of Indian Affairs, a flood plain management pilot program (referred to in this subsection as the “program”) to provide, at the request of an Indian tribe, guidance to the Indian tribe relating to best practices for the mitigation and prevention of floods, including consultation with the Indian tribe on—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> flood plain mapping; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> new construction planning.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The program shall terminate on the date that is 11 years after <date date="2016-12-16">December 16, 2016</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Funding</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Of the amounts authorized to be expended from either Fund, $250,000 shall be made available from either Fund during each of fiscal years 2017 through 2026 to carry out this subsection, to remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 114–322, title III, § 3101</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1740</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–270, title IV, § 4314</ref>, <date date="2018-10-23">Oct. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 3893</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>