<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 3—</num>
<heading>AGREEMENTS WITH INDIANS</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>TREATIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 71.</num>
<heading> Future treaties with Indian tribes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No Indian nation or tribe within the territory of the United States shall be acknowledged or recognized as an independent nation, tribe, or power with whom the United States may contract by treaty; but no obligation of any treaty lawfully made and ratified with any such Indian nation or tribe prior to <date date="1871-03-03">March 3, 1871</date>, shall be hereby invalidated or impaired. Such treaties, and any Executive orders and Acts of Congress under which the rights of any Indian tribe to fish are secured, shall be construed to prohibit (in addition to any other prohibition) the imposition under any law of a State or political subdivision thereof of any tax on any income derived from the exercise of rights to fish secured by such treaty, Executive order, or Act of Congress if <ref>section 7873 of title 26</ref> does not permit a like Federal tax to be imposed on such income.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(R.S. § 2079; <ref>Pub. L. 100–647, title III, § 3042</ref>, <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3641</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 72.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 117–317, § 2(1)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4419</ref></heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>CONTRACTS WITH INDIANS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 81.</num>
<heading> Contracts and agreements with Indian tribes</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “Indian lands” means lands the title to which is held by the United States in trust for an Indian tribe or lands the title to which is held by an Indian tribe subject to a restriction by the United States against alienation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “Indian tribe” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 5304(e) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of the Interior.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Approval</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No agreement or contract with an Indian tribe that encumbers Indian lands for a period of 7 or more years shall be valid unless that agreement or contract bears the approval of the Secretary of the Interior or a designee of the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subsection (b) shall not apply to any agreement or contract that the Secretary (or a designee of the Secretary) determines is not covered under that subsection.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Unapproved agreements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary (or a designee of the Secretary) shall refuse to approve an agreement or contract that is covered under subsection (b) if the Secretary (or a designee of the Secretary) determines that the agreement or contract—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> violates Federal law; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> does not include a provision that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> provides for remedies in the case of a breach of the agreement or contract;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> references a tribal code, ordinance, or ruling of a court of competent jurisdiction that discloses the right of the Indian tribe to assert sovereign immunity as a defense in an action brought against the Indian tribe; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> includes an express waiver of the right of the Indian tribe to assert sovereign immunity as a defense in an action brought against the Indian tribe (including a waiver that limits the nature of relief that may be provided or the jurisdiction of a court with respect to such an action).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2000-03-14">March 14, 2000</date>, the Secretary shall issue regulations for identifying types of agreements or contracts that are not covered under subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Construction</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall be construed to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> require the Secretary to approve a contract for legal services by an attorney;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> amend or repeal the authority of the National Indian Gaming Commission under the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act (<ref>25 U.S.C. 2701</ref> et seq.); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> alter or amend any ordinance, resolution, or charter of an Indian tribe that requires approval by the Secretary of any action by that Indian tribe.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(R.S. § 2103; <ref>Pub. L. 85–770</ref>, <date date="1958-08-27">Aug. 27, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 927</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–179, § 2</ref>, <date date="2000-03-14">Mar. 14, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 46</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 81a.</num>
<heading> Counsel for prosecution of claims against the United States; cancellation; revival</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any contracts or agreements approved prior to <date date="1936-06-26">June 26, 1936</date>, by the Secretary of the Interior between the authorities of any tribe, band, or group of Indians and their attorneys for the prosecution of claims against the United States, which provide that such contracts or agreements shall run for a period of years therein specified, and as long thereafter as may be required to complete the business therein provided for, or words of like import, or which provide that compensation for services rendered shall be on a quantum-meruit basis not to exceed a specified percentage, shall be deemed a sufficient compliance with <ref>section 81 of this title</ref>: <i>Provided, however</i>, That nothing herein contained shall limit the power of the Secretary of the Interior, after due notice and hearing and for proper cause shown, to cancel any such contract or agreement: <i>Provided further</i>, That the provisions of this section and <ref>section 81b of this title</ref> shall not be construed to revive any contract which has been terminated by lapse of time, operation of law, or by acts of the parties thereto.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 26, 1936, ch. 851, § 1</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 1984</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 81b.</num>
<heading> Continuation of contracts with attorneys containing limitation of time where suits have been filed</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any existing valid contract made and approved prior to <date date="1936-06-26">June 26, 1936</date>, pursuant to any Act of Congress by any tribe, band, or group of Indians with an attorney or attorneys for the rendition of services in the prosecution of claims against the United States under authority of which suit or suits have been filed, and which contains a limitation of time for the completion of the services to be performed may be continued in full force unless a subsequent contract dealing with the same subject matter has been made and approved.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 26, 1936, ch. 851, § 2</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 1984</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 82.</num>
<heading> Payments under contracts; aiding in making prohibited contracts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No money shall be paid to any agent or attorney by an officer of the United States under any such contract or agreement, other than the fees due him for services rendered thereunder; but the moneys due the tribe, Indian, or Indians, as the case may be, shall be paid by the United States, through its own officers or agents, to the party or parties entitled thereto; and no money or thing shall be paid to any person for services under such contract or agreement, until such person shall have first filed with the Commissioner of Indian Affairs a sworn statement, showing each particular act of service under the contract, giving date and fact in detail, and the Secretary of the Interior and Commissioner of Indian Affairs shall determine therefrom whether, in their judgment, such contract or agreement has been complied with or fulfilled; if so, the same may be paid, and, if not, it shall be paid in proportion to the services rendered under the contract.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(R.S. § 2104.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 82a.</num>
<heading> Contracts for payment of money permitted certain tribes; payment for legal services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Contracts involving the payment or expenditure of any money or affecting any property belonging to the Choctaw, Chickasaw, Cherokee, Creek, or Seminole Tribes of Indians, including contracts for professional legal services, may be made by said tribes, with the approval of the Secretary of the Interior, or his authorized representative, under such rules and regulations as the Secretary of the Interior may prescribe: <i>Provided</i>, That the provisions of this section shall not apply to contracts for professional legal services involving the prosecution of claims against the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 3, 1952, ch. 549, § 1</ref>, <ref>66 Stat. 323</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 83.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645, § 21</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 862</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 84.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 106–568, title VIII, § 812(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2000-12-27">Dec. 27, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2917</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 85.</num>
<heading> Contracts relating to tribal funds or property</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No contract made with any Indian, where such contract relates to the tribal funds or property in the hands of the United States, shall be valid, nor shall any payment for services rendered in relation thereto be made unless the consent of the United States has previously been given.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 30, 1913, ch. 4, § 18</ref>, <ref>38 Stat. 97</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 86.</num>
<heading> Encumbrances on lands allotted to applicants for enrollment in Five Civilized Tribes; use of interest on tribal funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Land allotted to any applicant for enrollment as a citizen in the Five Civilized Tribes whether an Indian or freedman, shall not be affected or encumbered by any deed, debt, or obligation of any character contracted prior to the time at which said land may be alienated under the laws of the United States: <i>Provided further</i>, That the interest accruing from tribal funds and deposited in banks in the State of Oklahoma may be used as authorized by the Act of March third, nineteen hundred and eleven, under the direction of the Secretary of the Interior, to defray the expense of per capita payments authorized by Congress.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 1, 1914, ch. 222, § 17</ref>, <ref>38 Stat. 601</ref>; <ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645, § 3</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 859</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 87.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645, § 21</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 862</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 87a.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 96–277, § 2</ref>, <date date="1980-06-17">June 17, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 545</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 88.</num>
<heading> False vouchers, accounts, or claims</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any disbursing or other officer of the United States, or other person, who shall knowingly present, or cause to be presented, any voucher, account, or claim to any officer of the United States, for approval or payment, or for the purpose of securing a credit in any account with the United States, relating to any matter pertaining to the Indian Service, which shall contain any material misrepresentation of fact in regard to the amount due or paid, the name or character of the article furnished or received; or of the service rendered, or to the date of purchase, delivery, or performance of service, or in any other particular, shall not be entitled to payment or credit for any part of said voucher, account, or claim; and if any such credit shall be given or received, or payment made, the United States may recharge the same to the officer or person receiving the credit or payment, and recover the amount from either or from both, in the same manner as other debts due the United States are collected: <i>Provided</i>, That where an account contains more than one voucher the foregoing shall apply only to such vouchers as contain the misrepresentation: <i>And provided further</i>, That the officers and persons by and between whom the business is transacted shall, in all civil actions in settlement of accounts, be presumed to know the facts in relation to the matter set forth in the voucher, account, or claim: <i>And provided further</i>, That the foregoing shall be in addition to the penalties prescribed by law, and in no way affect proceedings under existing law for like offenses. Where practicable this section shall be printed on the blank forms of vouchers provided for general use.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 4, 1884, ch. 180, § 8</ref>, <ref>23 Stat. 97</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>