<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 34—</num>
<heading>INDIAN CHILD PROTECTION AND FAMILY VIOLENCE PREVENTION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3201.</num>
<heading> Findings and purpose</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress, after careful review of the problem of child abuse on Indian reservations and the historical and special relationship of the Federal Government with Indian people,</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> finds that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> incidents of abuse of children on Indian reservations are grossly underreported;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> such underreporting is often a result of the lack of a mandatory Federal reporting law;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> multiple incidents of sexual abuse of children on Indian reservations have been perpetrated by persons employed or funded by the Federal Government;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Federal Government investigations of the background of Federal employees who care for, or teach, Indian children are often deficient;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> funds spent by the United States on Indian reservations or otherwise spent for the benefit of Indians who are victims of child abuse or family violence are inadequate to meet the growing needs for mental health treatment and counseling for victims of child abuse or family violence and their families; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> there is no resource that is more vital to the continued existence and integrity of Indian tribes than their children and the United States has a direct interest, as trustee, in protecting Indian children who are members of, or are eligible for membership in, an Indian tribe; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> declares that two major goals of the United States are to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> identify the scope of incidents of abuse of children and family violence in Indian country and to reduce such incidents; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provide funds for mental health treatment for Indian victims of child abuse and family violence on Indian reservations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purpose</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes of this chapter are to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> require that reports of abused Indian children are made to the appropriate authorities in an effort to prevent further abuse;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> establish a reliable data base for statistical purposes and to authorize a study to determine the need for a central registry for reported incidents of abuse;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> authorize such other actions as are necessary to ensure effective child protection in Indian country;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> establish the Indian Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment Grant Program to provide funds for the establishment on Indian reservations of treatment programs for victims of child sexual abuse;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> provide for technical assistance and training related to the investigation and treatment of cases of child abuse and neglect;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> establish Indian Child Resource and Family Services Centers in each Bureau of Indian Affairs Area Office which will consist of multi-disciplinary teams of personnel with experience and training in the prevention, identification, investigation, and treatment of child abuse and neglect;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> provide for the treatment and prevention of incidents of family violence;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> establish tribally operated programs to protect Indian children and reduce the incidents of family violence in Indian country; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> authorize other actions necessary to ensure effective child protection on Indian reservations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–630, title IV, § 402</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4544</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3202.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For the purposes of this chapter, the term—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “Bureau” means the Bureau of Indian Affairs of the Department of the Interior;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> “child” means an individual who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is not married, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> has not attained 18 years of age;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> “child abuse” includes but is not limited to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> in any case in which—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> a child is dead or exhibits evidence of skin bruising, bleeding, malnutrition, failure to thrive, burns, fracture of any bone, subdural hematoma, soft tissue swelling; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> such condition is not justifiably explained or may not be the product of an accidental occurrence; or</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a child is subjected to sexual assault, sexual molestation, sexual exploitation, sexual contact, or prostitution; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any case in which a child is subjected to sexual assault, sexual molestation, sexual exploitation, sexual contact, or prostitution;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> “child neglect” includes but is not limited to, negligent treatment or maltreatment of a child by a person, including a person responsible for the child’s welfare, under circumstances which indicate that the child’s health or welfare is harmed or threatened thereby;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> “family violence” means any act, or threatened act, of violence, including any forceful detention of an individual, which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> results, or threatens to result, in physical or mental injury, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> is committed by an individual against another individual—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> to whom such person is, or was, related by blood or marriage or otherwise legally related, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> with whom such person is, or was, residing;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> “Indian” means any individual who is a member of an Indian tribe;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> “Indian child” has the meaning given to such term by <ref>section 1903(4) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> “Indian country” has the meaning given to such term by <ref>section 1151 of title 18</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> “Indian reservation” means any Indian reservation, public domain Indian allotment, former Indian reservation in Oklahoma, or lands held by incorporated Native groups, regional corporations, or village corporations under the provisions of the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<ref>43 U.S.C. 1601</ref> et seq.);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> “Indian tribe” and “tribal organization” have the respective meanings given to each of such terms under <ref>section 5304 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<chapeau> “inter-tribal consortium” means a partnership between—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an Indian tribe or tribal organization of an Indian tribe, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> one or more Indian tribes or tribal organizations of one or more other Indian tribes;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> “local child protective services agency” means that agency of the Federal Government, of a State, or of an Indian tribe that has the primary responsibility for child protection on any Indian reservation or within any community in Indian country;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> “local law enforcement agency” means that Federal, tribal, or State law enforcement agency that has the primary responsibility for the investigation of an instance of alleged child abuse within the portion of Indian country involved;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<chapeau> “persons responsible for a child’s welfare” means any person who has legal or other recognized duty for the care and safety of a child, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any employee or volunteer of a children’s residential facility, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any person providing out-of-home care, education, or services to children;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<chapeau> “related assistance”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> includes counseling and self-help services to abusers, victims, and dependents in family violence situations (which shall include counseling of all family members to the extent feasible) and referrals for appropriate health-care services (including alcohol and drug abuse treatment), and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> may include food, clothing, child care, transportation, and emergency services for victims of family violence and their dependents;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(16)</num>
<content> “Secretary” means the Secretary of the Interior;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(17)</num>
<content> “shelter” means the provision of temporary refuge and related assistance in compliance with applicable Federal and tribal laws and regulations governing the provision, on a regular basis, of shelter, safe homes, meals, and related assistance to victims of family violence or their dependents; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(18)</num>
<content> “Service” means the Indian Health Service of the Department of Health and Human Services.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–630, title IV, § 403</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4545</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–160, § 2(1)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2567</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3203.</num>
<heading> Reporting procedures</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification of child abuse reports</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> When a local law enforcement agency or local child protective services agency receives an initial report from any person of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the abuse of a child in Indian country, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> actions which would reasonably be expected to result in abuse of a child in Indian country, the receiving agency shall immediately notify appropriate officials of the other agency of such report and shall also submit, when prepared, a copy of the written report required under subsection (c) to such agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Where a report of abuse involves an Indian child or where the alleged abuser is an Indian and where a preliminary inquiry indicates a criminal violation has occurred, the local law enforcement agency, if other than the Federal Bureau of Investigation, shall immediately report such occurrence to the Federal Bureau of Investigation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Written report of child abuse</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Within 36 hours after receiving an initial report described in subsection (b), the receiving agency shall prepare a written report which shall include, if available—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the name, address, age, and sex of the child that is the subject of the report;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the grade and the school in which the child is currently enrolled;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the name and address of the child’s parents or other person responsible for the child’s care;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the name and address of the alleged offender;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the name and address of the person who made the report to the agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> a brief narrative as to the nature and extent of the child’s injuries, including any previously known or suspected abuse of the child or the child’s siblings and the suspected date of the abuse; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> any other information the agency or the person who made the report to the agency believes to be important to the investigation and disposition of the alleged abuse.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Any local law enforcement agency or local child protective services agency that receives a report alleging abuse described in section 3202(3) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002209">1</ref> of this title shall immediately initiate an investigation of such allegation and shall take immediate, appropriate steps to secure the safety and well-being of the child or children involved.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Upon completion of the investigation of any report of alleged abuse that is made to a local law enforcement agency or local child protective services agency, such agency shall prepare a final written report on such allegation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Confidentiality of informant</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The identity of any person making a report described in subsection (b)(1) shall not be disclosed, without the consent of the individual, to any person other than a court of competent jurisdiction or an employee of an Indian tribe, a State or the Federal Government who needs to know the information in the performance of such employee’s duties.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–630, title IV, § 404</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4547</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3204.</num>
<heading> Central registry</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Preparation of study</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services and the Attorney General of the United States, is hereby authorized and directed to prepare a written study on the feasibility of, and need for, the establishment of a Central Register for reports or information on the abuse of children in Indian country.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Content of study</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The study conducted pursuant to subsection (a) shall include, but shall not be limited to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the need for, and purpose of, a Central Register;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the examination of due process implication of the maintenance of such a register;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the extension of access to information contained in the register;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the need and process for expunging information from the register;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the types, and duration of maintenance, of information in the register; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the classes of persons who should be covered by such register.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Submission to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall complete the study conducted pursuant to this section and shall submit such study, together with recommendations and draft legislation to implement such recommendations, to the Congress within 180 days after <date date="1990-11-28">November 28, 1990</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–630, title IV, § 405</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4549</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3205.</num>
<heading> Confidentiality</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Pursuant to <ref>section 552a of title 5</ref>, the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 (<ref>20 U.S.C. 1232g</ref>), or any other provision of law, agencies of any Indian tribe, of any State, or of the Federal Government that investigate and treat incidents of abuse of children may provide information and records to those agencies of any Indian tribe, any State, or the Federal Government that need to know the information in performance of their duties. For purposes of this section, Indian tribal governments shall be treated the same as other Federal Government entities.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–630, title IV, § 406</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4550</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3206.</num>
<heading> Waiver of parental consent</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Examinations and interviews</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Photographs, x-rays, medical examinations, psychological examinations, and interviews of an Indian child alleged to have been subject to abuse in Indian country shall be allowed without parental consent if local child protective services or local law enforcement officials have reason to believe the child has been subject to abuse.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interviews by law enforcement and child protective services officials</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In any case in which officials of the local law enforcement agency or local child protective services agency have reason to believe that an Indian child has been subject to abuse in Indian country, the officials of those agencies shall be allowed to interview the child without first obtaining the consent of the parent, guardian, or legal custodian.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Protection of child</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Examinations and interviews of a child who may have been the subject of abuse shall be conducted under such circumstances and with such safeguards as are designed to minimize additional trauma to the child and, where time permits, shall be conducted with the advise,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002210">1</ref> or under the guidance, of a local multidisciplinary team established pursuant to <ref>section 3210 of this title</ref> or, in the absence of a local team, a multidisciplinary team established pursuant to <ref>section 3209 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Court orders</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon a finding of reasonable suspicion that an Indian child has been the subject of abuse in Indian country, a Federal magistrate judge or United States District Court may issue an order enforcing any provision of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–630, title IV, § 407</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4550</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–650, title III, § 321</ref>, <date date="1990-12-01">Dec. 1, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 5117</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3207.</num>
<heading> Character investigations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> By Secretary of the Interior and Secretary of Health and Human Services</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary and the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> compile a list of all authorized positions within their respective departments the duties and responsibilities of which involve regular contact with, or control over, Indian children,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> conduct an investigation of the character of each individual who is employed, or is being considered for employment, by the respective Secretary in a position listed pursuant to paragraph (1), and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> prescribe by regulations minimum standards of character that each of such individuals must meet to be appointed to such positions.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Criminal records</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The minimum standards of character that are to be prescribed under this section shall ensure that none of the individuals appointed to positions described in subsection (a) have been found guilty of, or entered a plea of nolo contendere or guilty to, any felonious offense, or any of two or more misdemeanor offenses, under Federal, State, or tribal law involving crimes of violence; sexual assault, molestation, exploitation, contact or prostitution; crimes against persons; or offenses committed against children.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Investigations by Indian tribes and tribal organizations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each Indian tribe or tribal organization that receives funds under the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act [<ref>25 U.S.C. 5301</ref> et seq.] or the Tribally Controlled Schools Act of 1988 [<ref>25 U.S.C. 2501</ref> et seq.] shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> conduct an investigation of the character of each individual who is employed, or is being considered for employment, by such tribe or tribal organization in a position that involves regular contact with, or control over, Indian children, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> employ individuals in those positions only if the individuals meet standards of character, no less stringent than those prescribed under subsection (a), as the Indian tribe or tribal organization shall establish.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> By tribal social services agency for foster care placements in tribal court proceedings</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In this subsection:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Covered individual</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “covered individual” includes—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any individual 18 years of age or older; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any individual who the tribal social services agency determines is subject to a criminal records check under paragraph (2)(A).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Foster care placement</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “foster care placement” means any action removing an Indian child from a parent or Indian custodian for temporary placement in a foster home or institution or the home of a guardian or conservator if—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the parent or Indian custodian cannot have the child returned on demand; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> parental rights have not been terminated; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> parental rights have been terminated but the child has not been permanently placed.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Indian custodian</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “Indian custodian” means any Indian—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> who has legal custody of an Indian child under tribal law or custom or under State law; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> to whom temporary physical care, custody, and control has been transferred by the parent of the child.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Parent</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “parent” means—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any biological parent of an Indian child; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any Indian who has lawfully adopted an Indian child, including adoptions under tribal law or custom.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(E)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tribal court</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “tribal court” means a court—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> with jurisdiction over foster care placements; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> that is—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> a Court of Indian Offenses;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> a court established and operated under the code or custom of an Indian tribe; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> any other administrative body of an Indian tribe that is vested with authority over foster care placements.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(F)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tribal social services agency</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “tribal social services agency” means the agency of an Indian tribe that has the primary responsibility for carrying out foster care licensing or approval (as of the date on which the proceeding described in paragraph (2)(A) commences) for the Indian tribe.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Criminal records check before foster care placement</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Except as provided in paragraph (3), no foster care placement shall be finally approved and no foster care license shall be issued until the tribal social services agency—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> completes a criminal records check of each covered individual who resides in the household or is employed at the institution in which the foster care placement will be made; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> concludes that each covered individual described in clause (i) meets such standards as the Indian tribe shall establish in accordance with subparagraph (B).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Standards of placement</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The standards described in subparagraph (A)(ii) shall include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> requirements that each tribal social services agency described in subparagraph (A)—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> perform criminal records checks, including fingerprint-based checks of national crime information databases (as defined in <ref>section 534(f)(3) of title 28</ref>);</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> check any abuse registries maintained by the Indian tribe; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> check any child abuse and neglect registry maintained by the State in which the covered individual resides for information on the covered individual, and request any other State in which the covered individual resided in the preceding 5 years, to enable the tribal social services agency to check any child abuse and neglect registry maintained by that State for such information; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any other additional requirement that the Indian tribe determines is necessary and permissible within the existing authority of the Indian tribe, such as the creation of voluntary agreements with State entities in order to facilitate the sharing of information related to the performance of criminal records checks.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Results</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Except as provided in paragraph (3), no foster care placement shall be ordered in any proceeding described in subparagraph (A) if an investigation described in clause (i) of that subparagraph reveals that a covered individual described in that clause has been found by a Federal, State, or tribal court to have committed any crime listed in clause (i) or (ii) of <ref>section 671(a)(20)(A) of title 42</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Emergency placement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Paragraph (2) shall not apply to an emergency foster care placement, as determined by a tribal social services agency.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recertification of foster homes or institutions</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Not later than 2 years after <date date="2016-06-03">June 3, 2016</date>, each Indian tribe shall establish procedures to recertify homes or institutions in which foster care placements are made.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The procedures described in subparagraph (A) shall include, at a minimum, periodic intervals at which the home or institution shall be subject to recertification to ensure—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the safety of the home or institution for the Indian child; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> that each covered individual who resides in the home or is employed at the institution is subject to a criminal records check in accordance with this subsection, including any covered individual who—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> resides in the home or is employed at the institution on the date on which the procedures established under subparagraph (A) commences; <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002211">1</ref> and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> did not reside in the home or was not employed at the institution on the date on which the investigation described in paragraph (2)(A)(i) was completed.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Guidance issued by the Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The procedures established under subparagraph (A) shall be subject to any regulation or guidance issued by the Secretary that is in accordance with the purpose of this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Guidance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 2 years after <date date="2016-06-03">June 3, 2016</date>, and after consultation with Indian tribes, the Secretary shall issue guidance regarding—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> procedures for a criminal records check of any covered individual who—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> resides in the home or is employed at the institution in which the foster care placement is made after the date on which the investigation described in paragraph (2)(A)(i) is completed; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> was not the subject of an investigation described in paragraph (2)(A)(i) before the foster care placement was made;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> self-reporting requirements for foster care homes or institutions in which any covered individual described in subparagraph (A) resides if the head of the household or the operator of the institution has knowledge that the covered individual—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> has been found by a Federal, State, or tribal court to have committed any crime listed in clause (i) or (ii) of <ref>section 671(a)(20)(A) of title 42</ref>; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> is listed on a registry described in clause (II) or (III) of paragraph (2)(B)(i);</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> promising practices used by Indian tribes to address emergency foster care placement procedures under paragraph (3); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> procedures for certifying compliance with this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–630, title IV, § 408</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4551</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–568, title VIII, § 814</ref>, <date date="2000-12-27">Dec. 27, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2918</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–165, § 2</ref>, <date date="2016-06-03">June 3, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 415</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3208.</num>
<heading> Indian Child Abuse Treatment Grant Program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Service, in cooperation with the Bureau, shall establish an Indian Child Abuse Treatment Grant Program that provides grants to any Indian tribe or inter­tribal consortium for the establishment on Indian reservations of treatment programs for Indians who have been victims of child abuse or neglect.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grant applications</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Any Indian tribe or intertribal consortium, on its own or in partnership with an urban Indian organization, may submit to the Service an application for a grant under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Any application submitted under paragraph (1)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall be in such form as the Service may prescribe;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> shall be submitted to the Service on or before the date designated by the Service; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> shall specify—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the nature of the program proposed by the applicant,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the data and information on which the program is based,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the extent to which the program plans to use or incorporate existing services available on the reservation, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the specific treatment concepts to be used under the program.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Culturally appropriate treatment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In awarding grants under this section, the Service shall encourage the use of culturally appropriate treatment services and programs that respond to the unique cultural values, customs, and traditions of applicant Indian Tribes.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grant administration and final report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each recipient of a grant awarded under subsection (a) shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> furnish the Service with such information as the Service may require to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> evaluate the program for which the grant is made, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> ensure that the grant funds are expended for the purposes for which the grant was made, and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> submit to the Service at the close of the term of the grant a final report which shall include such information as the Service may require.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 2 years after <date date="2024-12-23">December 23, 2024</date>, the Service shall submit a report to Congress on the award of grants under this section. The report shall contain—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a description of treatment and services for which grantees have used funds awarded under this section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any other information that the Service requires.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">there <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002212">1</ref> is hereby authorized to be appropriated to carry out the provisions of this section $10,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 1992, 1993, 1994, 1995, 1996, and 1997.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–630, title IV, § 409</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4551</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–16, § 1</ref>, <date date="1995-06-21">June 21, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 190</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–160, § 2(2)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2567</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3209.</num>
<heading> National Indian Child Resource and Family Services Center</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2024-12-23">December 23, 2024</date>, the Secretary shall establish a National Indian Child Resource and Family Services Center.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 2 years after <date date="2024-12-23">December 23, 2024</date>, the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Bureau of Indian Affairs, shall submit a report to Congress on the status of the National Indian Child Resource and Family Services Center.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Center staffing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Center established under subsection (a) shall be staffed by a team of personnel with experience and training in prevention, identification, investigation, and treatment of incidents of family violence, child abuse, and child neglect.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Center responsibilities and functions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Center established under subsection (a) shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provide advice, technical assistance, and consultation to Indian tribes, tribal organizations, inter-tribal consortia, and urban Indian organizations upon request;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provide training to appropriate personnel of Indian tribes, tribal organizations, urban Indian organizations, the Bureau and the Service on the identification and investigation of cases of family violence, child abuse, and child neglect and, to the extent practicable, coordinate with institutions of higher education, including tribally controlled community colleges, to offer college-level credit to interested trainees;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> develop training and technical assistance materials on the prevention, identification, investigation, and treatment of incidents of family violence, child abuse, and child neglect for distribution to Indian tribes, Tribal organizations, and urban Indian organizations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> develop recommendations to assist Federal, State, Tribal, and urban Indian personnel to respond to cases of family violence, child abuse, and child neglect; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> develop model intergovernmental agreements between Tribes and States, and other materials that provide examples of how Federal, State, and Tribal governments can develop effective relationships and provide for maximum cooperation in the furtherance of prevention, investigation, treatment, and prosecution of incidents of family violence and child abuse and child neglect involving Indian children and families.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Team personnel</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The team established under this section shall include, but is not limited to, personnel with a background in—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> law enforcement,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> child protective services,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> juvenile counseling and adolescent mental health, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> domestic violence.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Center advisory board</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish an advisory board to advise and assist the National Indian Child Resource and Family Services Center in carrying out its activities under this section. The advisory board shall consist of 12 members appointed by the Secretary from Indian Tribes, Tribal organizations, and urban Indian organizations with expertise in child abuse and child neglect. Members shall serve without compensation, but may be reimbursed for travel and other expenses while carrying out the duties of the board. The advisory board shall assist the Center in coordinating programs, identifying training and technical assistance materials, and developing intergovernmental agreements relating to family violence, child abuse, and child neglect.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application of Indian Self-Determination Act to the Center</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The National Indian Child Resource and Family Services Center shall be subject to the provisions of the Indian Self-Determination Act [<ref>25 U.S.C. 5321</ref> et seq.]. The Secretary may also contract for the operation of the Center with a nonprofit Indian organization governed by an Indian-controlled board of directors that have substantial experience in child abuse, child neglect, and family violence involving Indian children and families.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out the provisions of this section $3,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 1992, 1993, 1994, 1995, 1996, and 1997.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–630, title IV, § 410</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4552</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–16, § 1</ref>, <date date="1995-06-21">June 21, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 190</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–160, § 2(3)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2568</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3210.</num>
<heading> Indian Child Protection and Family Violence Prevention Program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish within the Bureau an Indian Child Protection and Family Violence Prevention Program to provide financial assistance to any Indian tribe, tribal organization, or inter-tribal consortium for the development of an Indian Child Protection and Family Violence Prevention program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Indian Self-Determination Act agreements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to enter into agreements with Indian tribes, tribal organizations, or inter-tribal consortia pursuant to the Indian Self-Determination Act [<ref>25 U.S.C. 5321</ref> et seq.] for the establishment of Indian Child Protection and Family Violence Prevention programs on Indian reservations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Investigation and treatment and prevention of child abuse and family violence</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">An Indian tribe operating an Indian Child Protection and Family Violence Prevention program established under this section shall designate the agency or officials which shall be responsible—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> for the investigation of reported cases of child abuse and child neglect; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> for the treatment and prevention of incidents of family violence; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> for the provision of immediate shelter and related assistance for victims of family violence and their dependents.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program responsibilities and functions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Funds provided pursuant to this section may be used for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the establishment of a child protective services program which may include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the employment of child protective services staff to investigate cases of child abuse, neglect, or both,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> training programs for child protective services personnel, law enforcement personnel, and judicial personnel in the investigation, prevention, and treatment of cases of child abuse and child neglect,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> purchase of equipment to assist in the investigation of cases of child abuse and child neglect;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> development of agreements between Tribes, States, or private agencies on the coordination of child abuse and neglect prevention, investigation, and treatment services;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> child protective services operational costs including transportation, risk and protective factors assessments, family engagement and kinship navigator services, and relative searches, criminal background checks for prospective placements, and home studies; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> development of a Tribal child protection or multidisciplinary team to assist in the prevention and investigation of child abuse and neglect;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the establishment of a family violence prevention and treatment program which may include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the employment of family violence prevention and treatment staff to respond to incidents of family violence in culturally appropriate ways,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the provision of immediate shelter and related assistance for victims of family violence and their dependents,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> training programs that may include culturally appropriate programs for family violence prevention and treatment personnel, law enforcement personnel, and judicial personnel in the investigation, prevention, and treatment of cases of family violence; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> construction or renovation of facilities for the establishment of family violence shelters;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> the development and implementation of a multidisciplinary child abuse investigation and prosecution program which may—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> coordinate child abuse and neglect prevention, investigation, prosecution, treatment, and counseling services,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> develop protocols among related agencies to ensure that investigations of child abuse and neglect cases minimize the trauma to the child victim, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> provide for the coordination and cooperation of law enforcement agencies, courts of competent jurisdiction, and other tribal, Federal, and State agencies through intergovernmental or interagency agreements that define and specify each party’s responsibilities;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the development of tribal child protection codes and regulations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> the establishment of training programs for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> professional and paraprofessional personnel in the fields of medicine, law, education, social work, and other relevant fields who are engaged in, or intend to work in, the field of prevention, identification, investigation, and treatment of family violence, child abuse, and child neglect,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> instruction in methods of protecting children from abuse and neglect for persons responsible for the welfare of Indian children, including parents of, and persons who work with, Indian children, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> educational, identification, prevention and treatment services for child abuse and child neglect in cooperation with preschool, elementary and secondary schools, or tribally controlled college or university <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002213">1</ref> (within the meaning of <ref>section 1801 of this title</ref>);</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> other community education efforts for tribal members (including school children) regarding issues of family violence, child abuse, and child neglect; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<chapeau> such other innovative and culturally relevant programs and projects as the Secretary may approve, including programs and projects for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> parental awareness and self-help,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> prevention and treatment of alcohol and drug-related family violence, child abuse, and child neglect, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> home health visitor programs,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">that show promise of successfully preventing and treating cases of family violence, child abuse, and child neglect.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002214">2</ref> Secretarial regulations; base support funding</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary, with the participation of Indian tribes, shall establish, and promulgate by regulations, a formula which establishes base support funding for Indian Child Protection and Family Violence Prevention programs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In the development of regulations for base support funding for such programs, the Secretary shall develop, not later than one year after <date date="2024-12-23">December 23, 2024</date>, in consultation with Indian Tribes, appropriate caseload standards and staffing requirements. Each level of funding assistance shall correspond to the staffing requirements established by the Secretary pursuant to this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> Factors to be considered in the development of the base support funding formula shall include, but are not limited to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> projected service population of the program;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> projected service area of the program;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> projected number of cases per month; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> special circumstances warranting additional program resources, such as high incidence of child abuse and neglect, high incidence of family violence, high incidence of violent crimes against women, or the existence of a significant victim population within the community.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The formula established pursuant to this subsection shall provide funding necessary to support not less than one child protective services or family violence caseworker, including fringe benefits and support costs, for each Indian Tribe.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> In any fiscal year that appropriations are not sufficient to fully fund Indian Child Protection and Family Violence Prevention programs at each level of assistance under the formula required to be established in this subsection, available funds for each level of assistance shall be evenly divided among the Indian Tribes qualifying for that level of assistance.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 2 years after <date date="2024-12-23">December 23, 2024</date>, the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Bureau of Indian Affairs, shall submit a report to Congress on the award of grants under this section. The report shall contain—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a description of treatment and services for which grantees have used funds awarded under this section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any other information that the Secretary of the Interior requires.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contract evaluation and annual report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each recipient of funds awarded pursuant to subsection (a) shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> furnish the Secretary with such information as the Secretary may require to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> evaluate the program for which the award is made, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> ensure that funds are expended for the purposes for which the award was made; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> submit to the Secretary at the end of each fiscal year an annual report which shall include such information as the Secretary may require.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out the provisions of this section $30,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 1992, 1993, 1994, 1995, 1996, and 1997.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–630, title IV, § 411</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4553</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–16, § 1</ref>, <date date="1995-06-21">June 21, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 190</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–244, title IX, § 901(d)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-07">Oct. 7, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1828</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–315, title IX, § 941(k)(2)(J)</ref>, <date date="2008-08-14">Aug. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 3467</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–160, § 2(4)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2569</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3211.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 105–362, title VIII, § 801(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-10">Nov. 10, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3287</ref></heading>
</section>
</chapter>