<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 30—</num>
<heading>INDIAN LAW ENFORCEMENT REFORM</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2801.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “Branch of Criminal Investigations” means the entity the Secretary is required to establish within the Office of Justice Services under <ref>section 2802(d)(1) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “Bureau” means the Bureau of Indian Affairs of the Department of the Interior.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “employee of the Bureau” includes an officer of the Bureau.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “enforcement of a law” includes the prevention, detection, and investigation of an offense and the detention or confinement of an offender.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The term “Indian country” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 1151 of title 18</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The term “Indian tribe” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 1301 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The term “offense” means an offense against the United States and includes a violation of a Federal regulation relating to part or all of Indian country.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of the Interior.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<chapeau> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002186">1</ref> The term “tribal justice official” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a tribal prosecutor;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a tribal law enforcement officer; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any other person responsible for investigating or prosecuting an alleged criminal offense in tribal court.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–379, § 2</ref>, <date date="1990-08-18">Aug. 18, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 473</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–211, title II</ref>, §§ 203(b), 211(a), <date date="2010-07-29">July 29, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2263</ref>, 2264.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2802.</num>
<heading> Indian law enforcement responsibilities</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Responsibility of Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary, acting through the Bureau, shall be responsible for providing, or for assisting in the provision of, law enforcement services in Indian country as provided in this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Office of Justice Services</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There is established in the Bureau an office, to be known as the “Office of Justice Services”, that, under the supervision of the Secretary, or an individual designated by the Secretary, shall be responsible for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> carrying out the law enforcement functions of the Secretary in Indian country, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> implementing the provisions of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional responsibilities of Division</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subject to the provisions of this chapter and other applicable Federal or tribal laws, the responsibilities of the Office of Justice Services in Indian country shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the enforcement of Federal law and, with the consent of the Indian tribe, tribal law;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in cooperation with appropriate Federal and tribal law enforcement agencies, the investigation of offenses against criminal laws of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the protection of life and property;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the development of methods and expertise to resolve conflicts and solve crimes;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the provision of criminal justice remedial actions, correctional and detention services, and rehabilitation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the reduction of recidivism and adverse social effects;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the development of preventive and outreach programs which will enhance the public conception of law enforcement responsibilities through training and development of needed public service skills;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> the assessment and evaluation of program accomplishments in reducing crime;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> the development and provision of law enforcement training and technical assistance, including training to properly interview victims of domestic and sexual violence and to collect, preserve, and present evidence to Federal and tribal prosecutors to increase the conviction rate for domestic and sexual violence offenses for purposes of addressing and preventing domestic and sexual violent offenses;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> the development and provision of dispatch and emergency and E–911 services;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> communicating with tribal leaders, tribal community and victims’ advocates, tribal justice officials, indigent defense representatives, and residents of Indian country on a regular basis regarding public safety and justice concerns facing tribal communities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> conducting meaningful and timely consultation with tribal leaders and tribal justice officials in the development of regulatory policies and other actions that affect public safety and justice in Indian country;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> providing technical assistance and training to tribal law enforcement officials to gain access and input authority to utilize the National Criminal Information Center and other national crime information databases pursuant to <ref>section 534 of title 28</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> in coordination with the Attorney General pursuant to subsection (g) of <ref>section 10132 of title 34</ref>, collecting, analyzing, and reporting data regarding Indian country crimes on an annual basis;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<content> on an annual basis, sharing with the Department of Justice all relevant crime data, including Uniform Crime Reports, that the Office of Justice Services prepares and receives from tribal law enforcement agencies on a tribe-by-tribe basis to ensure that individual tribal governments providing data are eligible for programs offered by the Department of Justice;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(16)</num>
<chapeau> submitting to the appropriate committees of Congress, for each fiscal year, a detailed spending report regarding tribal public safety and justice programs that includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> the number of full-time employees of the Bureau and tribal governments who serve as—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> criminal investigators;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> uniform police;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> police and emergency dispatchers;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> detention officers;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(V)</num>
<content> executive personnel, including special agents in charge, and directors and deputies of various offices in the Office of Justice Services; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(VI)</num>
<content> tribal court judges, prosecutors, public defenders, appointed defense counsel, or related staff; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the amount of appropriations obligated for each category described in clause (i) for each fiscal year;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a list of amounts dedicated to law enforcement and corrections, vehicles, related transportation costs, equipment, inmate transportation costs, inmate transfer costs, replacement, improvement, and repair of facilities, personnel transfers, detailees and costs related to their details, emergency events, public safety and justice communications and technology costs, and tribal court personnel, facilities, indigent defense, and related program costs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a list of the unmet staffing needs of law enforcement, corrections, and court personnel (including indigent defense and prosecution staff) at tribal and Bureau of Indian Affairs justice agencies, the replacement and repair needs of tribal and Bureau corrections facilities, needs for tribal police and court facilities, and public safety and emergency communications and technology needs; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the formula, priority list or other methodology used to determine the method of disbursement of funds for the public safety and justice programs administered by the Office of Justice Services;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(17)</num>
<content> submitting to the appropriate committees of Congress, for each fiscal year, a report summarizing the technical assistance, training, and other support provided to tribal law enforcement and corrections agencies that operate relevant programs pursuant to self-determination contracts or self-governance compacts with the Secretary; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(18)</num>
<content> promulgating regulations to carry out this chapter, and routinely reviewing and updating, as necessary, the regulations contained in subchapter B of title 25,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002187">1</ref> Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Branch of Criminal Investigations; establishment, responsibilities, regulations, personnel, etc.</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall establish within the Office of Justice Services a separate Branch of Criminal Investigations which, under such inter-agency agreement as may be reached between the Secretary and appropriate agencies or officials of the Department of Justice and subject to such guidelines as may be adopted by relevant United States attorneys, shall be responsible for the investigation, and presentation for prosecution, of cases involving violations of sections 1152 and 1153 of title 18 within Indian country.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Branch of Criminal Investigations shall not be primarily responsible for the routine law enforcement and police operations of the Bureau in Indian country.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall prescribe regulations which shall establish a procedure for active cooperation and consultation of the criminal investigative employees of the Bureau assigned to an Indian reservation with the governmental and law enforcement officials of the Indian tribe located on such reservation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Criminal investigative personnel of the Branch shall be subject only to the supervision and direction of law enforcement personnel of the Branch or of the Office of Justice Services. Such personnel shall not be subject to the supervision of the Bureau of Indian Affairs Agency Superintendent or Bureau of Indian Affairs Area Office Director. Nothing in this paragraph is intended to prohibit cooperation, coordination, or consultation, as appropriate, with nonlaw enforcement Bureau of Indian Affairs personnel at the agency or area levels, or prohibit or restrict the right of a tribe to contract the investigative program under the authority of <ref>Public Law 93–638</ref> [<ref>25 U.S.C. 5301</ref> et seq.] or to maintain its own criminal investigative operations.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> At the end of one year following the date of establishment of the separate Branch of Criminal Investigations, any tribe may, by resolution of the governing body of the tribe, request the Secretary to reestablish line authority through the Agency Superintendent or Bureau of Indian Affairs Area Office Director. In the absence of good cause to the contrary, the Secretary, upon receipt of such resolution, shall reestablish the line authority as requested by the tribe.</content>
</clause>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Standards of education and experience and classification of positions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Standards of education and experience</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary shall establish appropriate standards of education, experience, training, and other relevant qualifications for law enforcement personnel of the Office of Justice Services who are charged with law enforcement responsibilities pursuant to <ref>section 2803 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements for training</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The training standards established under subparagraph (A)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> shall be consistent with standards accepted by the Federal Law Enforcement Training Accreditation commission for law enforcement officers attending similar programs; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> shall include, or be supplemented by, instruction regarding Federal sources of authority and jurisdiction, Federal crimes, Federal rules of criminal procedure, and constitutional law to bridge the gap between State training and Federal requirements.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Training at State, tribal, and local academies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Law enforcement personnel of the Office of Justice Services or an Indian tribe may satisfy the training standards established under subparagraph (A) through training at a State or tribal police academy, a State, regional, local, or tribal college or university, or other training academy (including any program at a State, regional, local, or tribal college or university) that meets the appropriate Peace Officer Standards of Training.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Maximum age requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Pursuant to <ref>section 3307(e) of title 5</ref>, the Secretary may employ as a law enforcement officer under <ref>section 2803 of this title</ref> any individual under the age of 47, if the individual meets all other applicable hiring requirements for the applicable law enforcement position.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall also provide for the classification of such positions within the Office of Justice Services at GS grades, as provided in <ref>section 5104 of title 5</ref>, consistent with the responsibilities and duties assigned to such positions and with the qualifications established for such positions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> In classifying positions in the Office of Justice Services under paragraph (2), the Secretary shall ensure that such positions are classified at GS grades comparable to those for other Federal law enforcement personnel in other Federal agencies in light of the responsibilities, duties, and qualifications required of such positions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Background checks for tribal justice officials</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Office of Justice Services shall develop standards and deadlines for the provision of background checks to tribal law enforcement and corrections officials.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Timing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">If a request for a background check is made by an Indian tribe that has contracted or entered into a compact for law enforcement or corrections services with the Bureau of Indian Affairs pursuant to the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<ref>25 U.S.C. 450</ref> et seq.),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002188">2</ref> the Office of Justice Services shall complete the check not later than 60 days after the date of receipt of the request, unless an adequate reason for failure to respond by that date is provided to the Indian tribe in writing.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Long-term plan for tribal detention programs</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2010-07-29">July 29, 2010</date>, the Secretary, acting through the Bureau, in coordination with the Department of Justice and in consultation with tribal leaders, tribal courts, tribal law enforcement officers, and tribal corrections officials, shall submit to Congress a long-term plan to address incarceration in Indian country, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> a description of proposed activities for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the construction, operation, and maintenance of juvenile (in accordance with <ref>section 2453(a)(3) of this title</ref> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002189">3</ref> and adult detention facilities (including regional facilities) in Indian country;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> contracting with State and local detention centers, upon approval of affected tribal governments; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> alternatives to incarceration, developed in cooperation with tribal court systems;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an assessment and consideration of the construction of Federal detention facilities in Indian country; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> any other alternatives as the Secretary, in coordination with the Attorney General and in consultation with Indian tribes, determines to be necessary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–379, § 3</ref>, <date date="1990-08-18">Aug. 18, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 473</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–211, title II</ref>, §§ 211(b), 231(a), 262, <date date="2010-07-29">July 29, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2264</ref>, 2272, 2299.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2803.</num>
<heading> Law enforcement authority</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary may charge employees of the Bureau with law enforcement responsibilities and may authorize those employees to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> carry firearms;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> execute or serve warrants, summonses, or other orders relating to a crime committed in Indian country and issued under the laws of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the United States (including those issued by a Court of Indian Offenses under regulations prescribed by the Secretary or offenses processed by the Central Violations Bureau); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an Indian tribe if authorized by the Indian tribe;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> make an arrest without a warrant for an offense committed in Indian country if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the offense is committed in the presence of the employee,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002190">1</ref></content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the offense is a felony and the employee has probable cause to believe that the person to be arrested has committed, or is committing, the felony;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the offense is a misdemeanor crime of domestic violence, dating violence, stalking, or violation of a protection order and has, as an element, the use or attempted use of physical force, or the threatened use of a deadly weapon, committed by a current or former spouse, parent, or guardian of the victim, by a person with whom the victim shares a child in common, by a person who is cohabitating with or has cohabited with the victim as a spouse, parent, or guardian, or by a person similarly situated to a spouse, parent or guardian of the victim, and the employee has probable cause to believe that the person to be arrested has committed, or is committing the crime; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> the offense involves—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<chapeau> a misdemeanor controlled substance offense in violation of—</chapeau>
<item class="indent4">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> the Controlled Substances Act (<ref>21 U.S.C. 801</ref> et seq.);</content>
</item>
<item class="indent4">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> title IX of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996 (<ref>21 U.S.C. 862a</ref> et seq.); <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002191">2</ref> or</content>
</item>
<item class="indent4">
<num>(cc)</num>
<content><ref>section 865 of title 21</ref>;</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> a misdemeanor firearms offense in violation of chapter 44 of title 18;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> a misdemeanor assault in violation of chapter 7 of title 18; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> a misdemeanor liquor trafficking offense in violation of chapter 59 of title 18; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the employee has probable cause to believe that the individual to be arrested has committed, or is committing, the crime;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> offer and pay a reward for services or information, or purchase evidence, assisting in the detection or investigation of the commission of an offense committed in Indian country or in the arrest of an offender against the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> make inquiries of any person, and administer to, or take from, any person an oath, affirmation, or affidavit, concerning any matter relevant to the enforcement or carrying out in Indian country of a law of either the United States or an Indian tribe that has authorized the employee to enforce or carry out tribal laws;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> wear a prescribed uniform and badge or carry prescribed credentials;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> perform any other law enforcement related duty; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> when requested, assist (with or without reimbursement) any Federal, tribal, State, or local law enforcement agency in the enforcement or carrying out of the laws or regulations the agency enforces or administers.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–379, § 4</ref>, <date date="1990-08-18">Aug. 18, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 475</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–162, title IX, § 908(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-05">Jan. 5, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3083</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–211, title II, § 211(c)</ref>, <date date="2010-07-29">July 29, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2266</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2804.</num>
<heading> Assistance by other agencies</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agreements</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2010-07-29">July 29, 2010</date>, the Secretary shall establish procedures to enter into memoranda of agreement for the use (with or without reimbursement) of the personnel or facilities of a Federal, tribal, State, or other government agency to aid in the enforcement or carrying out in Indian country of a law of either the United States or an Indian tribe that has authorized the Secretary to enforce tribal laws.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certain activities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may authorize a law enforcement officer of such an agency to perform any activity the Secretary may authorize under <ref>section 2803 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program enhancement</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Training sessions in Indian country</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The procedures described in paragraph (1) shall include the development of a plan to enhance the certification and provision of special law enforcement commissions to tribal law enforcement officials, and, subject to subsection (d), State and local law enforcement officials, pursuant to this section.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inclusions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The plan under clause (i) shall include the hosting of regional training sessions in Indian country, not less frequently than biannually, to educate and certify candidates for the special law enforcement commissions.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Memoranda of agreement</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2010-07-29">July 29, 2010</date>, the Secretary, in consultation with Indian tribes and tribal law enforcement agencies, shall develop minimum requirements to be included in special law enforcement commission agreements pursuant to this section.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Substance of agreements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Each agreement entered into pursuant to this section shall reflect the status of the applicable certified individual as a Federal law enforcement officer under subsection (f), acting within the scope of the duties described in <ref>section 2802(c) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agreement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Not later than 60 days after the date on which the Secretary determines that all applicable requirements under clause (i) are met, the Secretary shall offer to enter into a special law enforcement commission agreement with the Indian tribe.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agreement to be in accord with agreements between Secretary and Attorney General</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any agreement entered into under this section relating to the enforcement of the criminal laws of the United States shall be in accord with any agreement between the Secretary and the Attorney General of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations on use of personnel of non-Federal agency</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may not use the personnel of a non-Federal agency under this section in an area of Indian country if the Indian tribe having jurisdiction over such area of Indian country has adopted a resolution objecting to the use of the personnel of such agency. The Secretary shall consult with Indian tribes before entering into any agreement under subsection (a) with a non-Federal agency that will provide personnel for use in any area under the jurisdiction of such Indian tribes.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority of Federal agency head to enter into agreement with Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding the provisions of <ref>section 1535 of title 31</ref>, the head of a Federal agency with law enforcement personnel or facilities may enter into an agreement (with or without reimbursement) with the Secretary under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority of Federal agency head to enter into agreement with Indian tribe</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The head of a Federal agency with law enforcement personnel or facilities may enter into an agreement (with or without reimbursement) with an Indian tribe relating to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the law enforcement authority of the Indian tribe, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the carrying out of a law of either the United States or the Indian tribe.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Status of person as Federal employee</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">While acting under authority granted by the Secretary under subsection (a), a person who is not otherwise a Federal employee shall be considered to be—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> an employee of the Department of the Interior only for purposes of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the provisions of law described in <ref>section 3374(c)(2) of title 5</ref>, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> sections 111 and 1114 of title 18, and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an eligible officer under subchapter III of chapter 81 of title 5.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Acceptance of assistance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Bureau may accept reimbursement, resources, assistance, or funding from—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a Federal, tribal, State, or other government agency; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Indian Law Enforcement Foundation established under section 5412(a) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002192">1</ref> of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–379, § 5</ref>, <date date="1990-08-18">Aug. 18, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 476</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–211, title II, § 231(b)</ref>, (e), <date date="2010-07-29">July 29, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2273</ref>, 2278.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2805.</num>
<heading> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">After consultation with the Attorney General of the United States, the Secretary may prescribe under this chapter regulations relating to the enforcement of criminal laws of the United States and regulations relating to the consideration of applications for contracts awarded under the Indian Self-Determination Act [<ref>25 U.S.C. 5321</ref> et seq.] to perform the functions of the Branch of Criminal Investigations.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–379, § 6</ref>, <date date="1990-08-18">Aug. 18, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 476</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2806.</num>
<heading> Jurisdiction</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Investigative jurisdiction over offenses against criminal laws</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall have investigative jurisdiction over offenses against criminal laws of the United States in Indian country subject to an agreement between the Secretary and the Attorney General of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exercise of investigative authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In exercising the investigative authority conferred by this section, the employees of the Bureau shall cooperate with the law enforcement agency having primary investigative jurisdiction over the offense committed.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Law enforcement commission or other delegation of prior authority not invalidated or diminished</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This chapter does not invalidate or diminish any law enforcement commission or other delegation of authority issued under the authority of the Secretary before <date date="1990-08-18">August 18, 1990</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorities in addition to prior authority; civil or criminal jurisdiction, law enforcement, investigative, or judicial authority, of United States, Indian tribes, States, etc., unaffected</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The authority provided by this chapter is in addition to, and not in derogation of, any authority that existed before <date date="1990-08-18">August 18, 1990</date>. The provisions of this chapter alter neither the civil or criminal jurisdiction of the United States, Indian tribes, States, or other political subdivisions or agencies, nor the law enforcement, investigative, or judicial authority of any Indian tribe, State, or political subdivision or agency thereof, or of any department, agency, court, or official of the United States other than the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–379, § 7</ref>, <date date="1990-08-18">Aug. 18, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 476</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2807.</num>
<heading> Uniform allowance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding the limitation in <ref>section 5901(a) of title 5</ref>, the Secretary may provide a uniform allowance for uniformed law enforcement officers under <ref>section 2803 of this title</ref> of not more than $400 a year.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–379, § 8</ref>, <date date="1990-08-18">Aug. 18, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 477</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2808.</num>
<heading> Source of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any expenses incurred by the Secretary under this chapter shall be paid from funds appropriated under <ref>section 13 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–379, § 9</ref>, <date date="1990-08-18">Aug. 18, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 477</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2809.</num>
<heading> Reports to tribes</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination and data collection</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Investigative coordination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subject to subsection (c), if a law enforcement officer or employee of any Federal department or agency terminates an investigation of an alleged violation of Federal criminal law in Indian country without referral for prosecution, the officer or employee shall coordinate with the appropriate tribal law enforcement officials regarding the status of the investigation and the use of evidence relevant to the case in a tribal court with authority over the crime alleged.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Investigation data</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Federal Bureau of Investigation shall compile, on an annual basis and by Field Division, information regarding decisions not to refer to an appropriate prosecuting authority cases in which investigations had been opened into an alleged crime in Indian country, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the types of crimes alleged;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the statuses of the accused as Indians or non-Indians;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the statuses of the victims as Indians or non-Indians; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the reasons for deciding against referring the investigation for prosecution.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prosecutorial coordination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subject to subsection (c), if a United States Attorney declines to prosecute, or acts to terminate prosecution of, an alleged violation of Federal criminal law in Indian country, the United States Attorney shall coordinate with the appropriate tribal justice officials regarding the status of the investigation and the use of evidence relevant to the case in a tribal court with authority over the crime alleged.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prosecution data</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The United States Attorney shall submit to the Native American Issues Coordinator to compile, on an annual basis and by Federal judicial district, information regarding all declinations of alleged violations of Federal criminal law that occurred in Indian country that were referred for prosecution by law enforcement agencies, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the types of crimes alleged;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the statuses of the accused as Indians or non-Indians;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the statuses of the victims as Indians or non-Indians; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the reasons for deciding to decline or terminate the prosecutions.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual reports</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Attorney General shall submit to Congress annual reports containing, with respect to the applicable calendar year, the information compiled under paragraphs (2) and (4) of subsection (a)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> organized—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the aggregate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> for the Federal Bureau of Investigation, by Field Division; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> for United States Attorneys, by Federal judicial district; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> including any relevant explanatory statements.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect of section</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Nothing in this section requires any Federal agency or official to transfer or disclose any confidential, privileged, or statutorily protected communication, information, or source to an official of any Indian tribe.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Nothing in this section affects or limits the requirements of Rule 6 of the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Attorney General shall establish, by regulation, standards for the protection of the confidential or privileged communications, information, and sources described in this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–379, § 10</ref>, <date date="1990-08-18">Aug. 18, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 477</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–211, title II, § 212</ref>, <date date="2010-07-29">July 29, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2267</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2810.</num>
<heading> Assistant United States Attorney tribal liaisons</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The United States Attorney for each district that includes Indian country shall appoint not less than 1 assistant United States Attorney to serve as a tribal liaison for the district.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The duties of a tribal liaison shall include the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Coordinating the prosecution of Federal crimes that occur in Indian country.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Developing multidisciplinary teams to combat child abuse and domestic and sexual violence offenses against Indians.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Consulting and coordinating with tribal justice officials and victims’ advocates to address any backlog in the prosecution of major crimes in Indian country in the district.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Developing working relationships and maintaining communication with tribal leaders, tribal community and victims’ advocates, and tribal justice officials to gather information from, and share appropriate information with, tribal justice officials.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Coordinating with tribal prosecutors in cases in which a tribal government has concurrent jurisdiction over an alleged crime, in advance of the expiration of any applicable statute of limitation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Providing technical assistance and training regarding evidence gathering techniques and strategies to address victim and witness protection to tribal justice officials and other individuals and entities that are instrumental to responding to Indian country crimes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Conducting training sessions and seminars to certify special law enforcement commissions to tribal justice officials and other individuals and entities responsible for responding to Indian country crimes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Coordinating with the Office of Tribal Justice, as necessary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> Conducting such other activities to address and prevent violent crime in Indian country as the applicable United States Attorney determines to be appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect of section</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this section limits the authority of any United States Attorney to determine the duties of a tribal liaison officer to meet the needs of the Indian tribes located within the relevant Federal district.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Enhanced prosecution of minor crimes</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Each United States Attorney serving a district that includes Indian country is authorized and encouraged—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> to appoint Special Assistant United States Attorneys pursuant to <ref>section 543(a) of title 28</ref> to prosecute crimes in Indian country as necessary to improve the administration of justice, and particularly when—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the crime rate exceeds the national average crime rate; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the rate at which criminal offenses are declined to be prosecuted exceeds the national average declination rate;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to coordinate with applicable United States district courts regarding scheduling of Indian country matters and holding trials or other proceedings in Indian country, as appropriate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to provide to appointed Special Assistant United States Attorneys appropriate training, supervision, and staff support; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> to provide technical and other assistance to tribal governments and tribal court systems to ensure that the goals of this subsection are achieved.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sense of Congress regarding consultation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">It is the sense of Congress that, in appointing Special Assistant United States Attorneys under this subsection, a United States Attorney should consult with tribal justice officials of each Indian tribe that would be affected by the appointment.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–379, § 13</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 111–211, title II, § 213(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2010-07-29">July 29, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2268</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2811.</num>
<heading> Native American Issues Coordinator</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established in the Executive Office for United States Attorneys of the Department of Justice a position to be known as the “Native American Issues Coordinator”.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Native American Issues Coordinator shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> coordinate with the United States Attorneys that have authority to prosecute crimes in Indian country;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> coordinate prosecutions of crimes of national significance in Indian country, as determined by the Attorney General;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> coordinate as necessary with other components of the Department of Justice and any relevant advisory groups to the Attorney General or the Deputy Attorney General; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> carry out such other duties as the Attorney General may prescribe.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–379, § 14</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 111–211, title II, § 214(b)</ref>, <date date="2010-07-29">July 29, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2271</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2812.</num>
<heading> Indian Law and Order Commission</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established a commission to be known as the Indian Law and Order Commission (referred to in this section as the “Commission”).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Membership</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Commission shall be composed of 9 members, of whom—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> 3 shall be appointed by the President, in consultation with—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Attorney General; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the Secretary;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> 2 shall be appointed by the Majority Leader of the Senate, in consultation with the Chairpersons of the Committees on Indian Affairs and the Judiciary of the Senate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> 1 shall be appointed by the Minority Leader of the Senate, in consultation with the Vice Chairperson and Ranking Member of the Committees on Indian Affairs and the Judiciary of the Senate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> 2 shall be appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives, in consultation with the Chairpersons of the Committees on the Judiciary and Natural Resources of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> 1 shall be appointed by the Minority Leader of the House of Representatives, in consultation with the Ranking Members of the Committees on the Judiciary and Natural Resources of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements for eligibility</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Each member of the Commission shall have significant experience and expertise in—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Indian country criminal justice system; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> matters to be studied by the Commission.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The President, the Speaker and Minority Leader of the House of Representatives, and the Majority Leader and Minority Leader of the Senate shall consult before the appointment of members of the Commission under paragraph (1) to achieve, to the maximum extent practicable, fair and equitable representation of various points of view with respect to the matters to be studied by the Commission.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Term</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Each member shall be appointed for the life of the Commission.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Time for initial appointments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The appointment of the members of the Commission shall be made not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Vacancies</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A vacancy in the Commission shall be filled—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the same manner in which the original appointment was made; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> not later than 60 days after the date on which the vacancy occurred.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Operation</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Chairperson</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 15 days after the date on which all members of the Commission have been appointed, the Commission shall select 1 member to serve as Chairperson of the Commission.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Meetings</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Commission shall meet at the call of the Chairperson.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initial meeting</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The initial meeting shall take place not later than 30 days after the date described in paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Quorum</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A majority of the members of the Commission shall constitute a quorum, but a lesser number of members may hold hearings.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rules</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Commission may establish, by majority vote, any rules for the conduct of Commission business, in accordance with this chapter and other applicable law.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Comprehensive study of criminal justice system relating to Indian country</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Commission shall conduct a comprehensive study of law enforcement and criminal justice in tribal communities, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> jurisdiction over crimes committed in Indian country and the impact of that jurisdiction on—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the investigation and prosecution of Indian country crimes; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> residents of Indian land;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the tribal jail and Federal prisons systems and the effect of those systems with respect to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> reducing Indian country crime; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> rehabilitation of offenders;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> tribal juvenile justice systems and the Federal juvenile justice system as relating to Indian country; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the effect of those systems and related programs in preventing juvenile crime, rehabilitating Indian youth in custody, and reducing recidivism among Indian youth;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> the impact of the Indian Civil Rights Act of 1968 (<ref>25 U.S.C. 1301</ref> et seq.) on—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the authority of Indian tribes;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the rights of defendants subject to tribal government authority; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the fairness and effectiveness of tribal criminal systems; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> studies of such other subjects as the Commission determines relevant to achieve the purposes of the Tribal Law and Order Act of 2010.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recommendations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Taking into consideration the results of the study under paragraph (1),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002193">1</ref> the Commission shall develop recommendations on necessary modifications and improvements to justice systems at the tribal, Federal, and State levels, including consideration of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> simplifying jurisdiction in Indian country;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> improving services and programs—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to prevent juvenile crime on Indian land;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to rehabilitate Indian youth in custody; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to reduce recidivism among Indian youth;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> adjustments to the penal authority of tribal courts and exploring alternatives to incarceration;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the enhanced use of chapter 43 of title 28 (commonly known as “the Federal Magistrates Act”) in Indian country;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> effective means of protecting the rights of victims and defendants in tribal criminal justice systems (including defendants incarcerated for a period of less than 1 year);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> changes to the tribal jails and Federal prison systems; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> other issues that, as determined by the Commission, would reduce violent crime in Indian country.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission shall submit to the President and Congress a report that contains—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a detailed statement of the findings and conclusions of the Commission; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the recommendations of the Commission for such legislative and administrative actions as the Commission considers to be appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Powers</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Hearings</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Commission may hold such hearings, meet and act at such times and places, take such testimony, and receive such evidence as the Commission considers to be advisable to carry out the duties of the Commission under this section.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The hearings of the Commission under this paragraph shall be open to the public.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Witness expenses</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A witness requested to appear before the Commission shall be paid the same fees and allowances as are paid to witnesses under <ref>section 1821 of title 28</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Per diem and mileage</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The fees and allowances for a witness shall be paid from funds made available to the Commission.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Information from Federal, tribal, and State agencies</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Commission may secure directly from a Federal agency such information as the Commission considers to be necessary to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tribal and State agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Commission may request the head of any tribal or State agency to provide to the Commission such information as the Commission considers to be necessary to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Postal services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Commission may use the United States mails in the same manner and under the same conditions as other agencies of the Federal Government.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Gifts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Commission may accept, use, and dispose of gifts or donations of services or property.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Commission personnel matters</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Travel expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A member of the Commission shall be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, at rates authorized for an employee of an agency under subchapter I of chapter 57 of title 5, while away from the home or regular place of business of the member in the performance of the duties of the Commission.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Detail of Federal employees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">On the affirmative vote of ⅔ of the members of the Commission and the approval of the appropriate Federal agency head, an employee of the Federal Government may be detailed to the Commission without reimbursement, and such detail shall be without interruption or loss of civil service status, benefits, or privileges.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Procurement of temporary and intermittent services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">On request of the Commission, the Attorney General shall provide to the Commission, on a reimbursable basis, reasonable and appropriate office space, supplies, and administrative assistance.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contracts for research</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Researchers and experts</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">On an affirmative vote of ⅔ of the members of the Commission, the Commission may select nongovernmental researchers and experts to assist the Commission in carrying out the duties of the Commission under this section.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National Institute of Justice</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The National Institute of Justice may enter into a contract with the researchers and experts selected by the Commission under subparagraph (A) to provide funding in exchange for the services of the researchers and experts.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other organizations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Nothing in this subsection limits the ability of the Commission to enter into contracts with any other entity or organization to carry out research necessary to carry out the duties of the Commission under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tribal Advisory Committee</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Commission shall establish a committee, to be known as the “Tribal Advisory Committee”.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Membership</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Composition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Tribal Advisory Committee shall consist of 2 representatives of Indian tribes from each region of the Bureau of Indian Affairs.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Qualifications</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Each member of the Tribal Advisory Committee shall have experience relating to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> justice systems;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> crime prevention; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> victim services.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Tribal Advisory Committee shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> serve as an advisory body to the Commission; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provide to the Commission advice and recommendations, submit materials, documents, testimony, and such other information as the Commission determines to be necessary to carry out the duties of the Commission under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(k)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Funding</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the fiscal year after <date date="2010-07-29">July 29, 2010</date>, out of any unobligated amounts available to the Secretary of the Interior or the Attorney General, the Secretary or the Attorney General may use to carry out this section not more than $2,000,000.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(l)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination of Commission</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission shall terminate 90 days after the date on which the Commission submits the report of the Commission under subsection (f).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(m)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonapplicability of chapter 10 of title 5</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Chapter 10 of title 5 shall not apply to the Commission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–379, § 15</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 111–211, title II, § 235</ref>, <date date="2010-07-29">July 29, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2282</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 113–4, title IX, § 909(a)</ref>, <date date="2013-03-07">Mar. 7, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 126</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(a)(183)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4326</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2813.</num>
<heading> Testimony by Federal employees</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Approval of employee testimony or documents</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Director of the Office of Justice Services or the Director of the Indian Health Service, as appropriate (referred to in this section as the “Director concerned”), shall approve or disapprove, in writing, any request or subpoena from a tribal or State court for a law enforcement officer, sexual assault nurse examiner, or other employee under the supervision of the Director concerned to provide documents or testimony in a deposition, trial, or other similar criminal proceeding regarding information obtained in carrying out the official duties of the employee.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deadline</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The court issuing a subpoena under paragraph (1) shall provide to the appropriate Federal employee (or agency in the case of a document request) notice regarding the request to provide testimony (or release a document) by not less than 30 days before the date on which the testimony will be provided.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Approval</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Director concerned shall approve a request or subpoena under subsection (a) if the request or subpoena does not violate the policy of the Department to maintain impartiality.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Failure to approve</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the Director concerned fails to approve or disapprove a request or subpoena for testimony or release of a document by the date that is 30 days after the date of receipt of notice of the request or subpoena, the request or subpoena shall be considered to be approved for purposes of this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–379, § 16</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 111–211, title II, § 263</ref>, <date date="2010-07-29">July 29, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2300</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2814.</num>
<heading> Policies and protocol</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director of the Indian Health Service, in coordination with the Director of the Office of Justice Services and the Director of the Office on Violence Against Women of the Department of Justice, in consultation with Indian Tribes and Tribal Organizations, and in conference with Urban Indian Organizations, shall develop standardized sexual assault policies and protocol for the facilities of the Service, based on similar protocol that has been established by the Department of Justice.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–379, § 17</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 111–211, title II, § 265</ref>, <date date="2010-07-29">July 29, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2300</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2815.</num>
<heading> State, tribal, and local law enforcement cooperation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Attorney General may provide technical and other assistance to State, tribal, and local governments that enter into cooperative agreements, including agreements relating to mutual aid, hot pursuit of suspects, and cross-deputization for the purposes of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> improving law enforcement effectiveness;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> reducing crime in Indian country and nearby communities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> developing successful cooperative relationships that effectively combat crime in Indian country and nearby communities.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–211, title II, § 222</ref>, <date date="2010-07-29">July 29, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2272</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>