<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 29—</num>
<heading>INDIAN GAMING REGULATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2701.</num>
<heading> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> numerous Indian tribes have become engaged in or have licensed gaming activities on Indian lands as a means of generating tribal governmental revenue;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Federal courts have held that <ref>section 81 of this title</ref> requires Secretarial review of management contracts dealing with Indian gaming, but does not provide standards for approval of such contracts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> existing Federal law does not provide clear standards or regulations for the conduct of gaming on Indian lands;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> a principal goal of Federal Indian policy is to promote tribal economic development, tribal self-sufficiency, and strong tribal government; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Indian tribes have the exclusive right to regulate gaming activity on Indian lands if the gaming activity is not specifically prohibited by Federal law and is conducted within a State which does not, as a matter of criminal law and public policy, prohibit such gaming activity.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–497, § 2</ref>, <date date="1988-10-17">Oct. 17, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2467</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2702.</num>
<heading> Declaration of policy</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purpose of this chapter is—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to provide a statutory basis for the operation of gaming by Indian tribes as a means of promoting tribal economic development, self-sufficiency, and strong tribal governments;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to provide a statutory basis for the regulation of gaming by an Indian tribe adequate to shield it from organized crime and other corrupting influences, to ensure that the Indian tribe is the primary beneficiary of the gaming operation, and to assure that gaming is conducted fairly and honestly by both the operator and players; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to declare that the establishment of independent Federal regulatory authority for gaming on Indian lands, the establishment of Federal standards for gaming on Indian lands, and the establishment of a National Indian Gaming Commission are necessary to meet congressional concerns regarding gaming and to protect such gaming as a means of generating tribal revenue.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–497, § 3</ref>, <date date="1988-10-17">Oct. 17, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2467</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2703.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “Attorney General” means the Attorney General of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “Chairman” means the Chairman of the National Indian Gaming Commission.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “Commission” means the National Indian Gaming Commission established pursuant to <ref>section 2704 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> The term “Indian lands” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> all lands within the limits of any Indian reservation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any lands title to which is either held in trust by the United States for the benefit of any Indian tribe or individual or held by any Indian tribe or individual subject to restriction by the United States against alienation and over which an Indian tribe exercises governmental power.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> The term “Indian tribe” means any Indian tribe, band, nation, or other organized group or community of Indians which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is recognized as eligible by the Secretary for the special programs and services provided by the United States to Indians because of their status as Indians, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is recognized as possessing powers of self-government.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The term “class I gaming” means social games solely for prizes of minimal value or traditional forms of Indian gaming engaged in by individuals as a part of, or in connection with, tribal ceremonies or celebrations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> The term “class II gaming” means—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> the game of chance commonly known as bingo (whether or not electronic, computer, or other technologic aids are used in connection therewith)—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> which is played for prizes, including monetary prizes, with cards bearing numbers or other designations,</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> in which the holder of the card covers such numbers or designations when objects, similarly numbered or designated, are drawn or electronically determined, and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> in which the game is won by the first person covering a previously designated arrangement of numbers or designations on such cards,</content>
</subclause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">including (if played in the same location) pull-tabs, lotto, punch boards, tip jars, instant bingo, and other games similar to bingo, and</continuation>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> card games that—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> are explicitly authorized by the laws of the State, or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> are not explicitly prohibited by the laws of the State and are played at any location in the State,</content>
</subclause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">but only if such card games are played in conformity with those laws and regulations (if any) of the State regarding hours or periods of operation of such card games or limitations on wagers or pot sizes in such card games.</continuation>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> The term “class II gaming” does not include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any banking card games, including baccarat, chemin de fer, or blackjack (21), or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> electronic or electromechanical facsimiles of any game of chance or slot machines of any kind.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other provision of this paragraph, the term “class II gaming” includes those card games played in the State of Michigan, the State of North Dakota, the State of South Dakota, or the State of Washington, that were actually operated in such State by an Indian tribe on or before <date date="1988-05-01">May 1, 1988</date>, but only to the extent of the nature and scope of the card games that were actually operated by an Indian tribe in such State on or before such date, as determined by the Chairman.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other provision of this paragraph, the term “class II gaming” includes, during the 1-year period beginning on <date date="1988-10-17">October 17, 1988</date>, any gaming described in subparagraph (B)(ii) that was legally operated on Indian lands on or before <date date="1988-05-01">May 1, 1988</date>, if the Indian tribe having jurisdiction over the lands on which such gaming was operated requests the State, by no later than the date that is 30 days after <date date="1988-10-17">October 17, 1988</date>, to negotiate a Tribal-State compact under <ref>section 2710(d)(3) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other provision of this paragraph, the term “class II gaming” includes, during the 1-year period beginning on <date date="1991-12-17">December 17, 1991</date>, any gaming described in subparagraph (B)(ii) that was legally operated on Indian lands in the State of Wisconsin on or before <date date="1988-05-01">May 1, 1988</date>, if the Indian tribe having jurisdiction over the lands on which such gaming was operated requested the State, by no later than <date date="1988-11-16">November 16, 1988</date>, to negotiate a Tribal-State compact under <ref>section 2710(d)(3) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> If, during the 1-year period described in subparagraph (E), there is a final judicial determination that the gaming described in subparagraph (E) is not legal as a matter of State law, then such gaming on such Indian land shall cease to operate on the date next following the date of such judicial decision.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> The term “class III gaming” means all forms of gaming that are not class I gaming or class II gaming.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> The term “net revenues” means gross revenues of an Indian gaming activity less amounts paid out as, or paid for, prizes and total operating expenses, excluding management fees.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of the Interior.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–497, § 4</ref>, <date date="1988-10-17">Oct. 17, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2467</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–238, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-17">Dec. 17, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1908</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–497, § 16</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 3261</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2704.</num>
<heading> National Indian Gaming Commission</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established within the Department of the Interior a Commission to be known as the National Indian Gaming Commission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Composition; investigation; term of office; re­moval</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Commission shall be composed of three full-time members who shall be appointed as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a Chairman, who shall be appointed by the President with the advice and consent of the Senate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> two associate members who shall be appointed by the Secretary of the Interior.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Attorney General shall conduct a background investigation on any person considered for appointment to the Commission.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register the name and other information the Secretary deems pertinent regarding a nominee for membership on the Commission and shall allow a period of not less than thirty days for receipt of public comment.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Not more than two members of the Commission shall be of the same political party. At least two members of the Commission shall be enrolled members of any Indian tribe.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the term of office of the members of the Commission shall be three years.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> Of the initial members of the Commission—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> two members, including the Chairman, shall have a term of office of three years; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> one member shall have a term of office of one year.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> No individual shall be eligible for any appointment to, or to continue service on, the Commission, who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> has been convicted of a felony or gaming offense;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> has any financial interest in, or management responsibility for, any gaming activity; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> has a financial interest in, or management responsibility for, any management contract approved pursuant to <ref>section 2711 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> A Commissioner may only be removed from office before the expiration of the term of office of the member by the President (or, in the case of associate member, by the Secretary) for neglect of duty, or malfeasance in office, or for other good cause shown.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Vacancies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Vacancies occurring on the Commission shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment. A member may serve after the expiration of his term of office until his successor has been appointed, unless the member has been removed for cause under subsection (b)(6).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Quorum</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Two members of the Commission, at least one of which is the Chairman or Vice Chairman, shall constitute a quorum.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Vice Chairman</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission shall select, by majority vote, one of the members of the Commission to serve as Vice Chairman. The Vice Chairman shall serve as Chairman during meetings of the Commission in the absence of the Chairman.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Meetings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission shall meet at the call of the Chairman or a majority of its members, but shall meet at least once every 4 months.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Chairman of the Commission shall be paid at a rate equal to that of level IV of the Executive Schedule under <ref>section 5315 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The associate members of the Commission shall each be paid at a rate equal to that of level V of the Executive Schedule under <ref>section 5316 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> All members of the Commission shall be reimbursed in accordance with title 5 for travel, subsistence, and other necessary expenses incurred by them in the performance of their duties.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–497, § 5</ref>, <date date="1988-10-17">Oct. 17, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2469</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2705.</num>
<heading> Powers of Chairman</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Chairman, on behalf of the Commission, shall have power, subject to an appeal to the Commission, to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> issue orders of temporary closure of gaming activities as provided in <ref>section 2713(b) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> levy and collect civil fines as provided in <ref>section 2713(a) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> approve tribal ordinances or resolutions regulating class II gaming and class III gaming as provided in <ref>section 2710 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> approve management contracts for class II gaming and class III gaming as provided in sections 2710(d)(9) and 2711 of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Chairman shall have such other powers as may be delegated by the Commission.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–497, § 6</ref>, <date date="1988-10-17">Oct. 17, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2470</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2706.</num>
<heading> Powers of Commission</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Budget approval; civil fines; fees; subpoenas; permanent orders</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Commission shall have the power, not subject to delegation—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> upon the recommendation of the Chairman, to approve the annual budget of the Commission as provided in <ref>section 2717 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to adopt regulations for the assessment and collection of civil fines as provided in <ref>section 2713(a) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> by an affirmative vote of not less than 2 members, to establish the rate of fees as provided in <ref>section 2717 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> by an affirmative vote of not less than 2 members, to authorize the Chairman to issue subpoenas as provided in <ref>section 2715 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> by an affirmative vote of not less than 2 members and after a full hearing, to make permanent a temporary order of the Chairman closing a gaming activity as provided in <ref>section 2713(b)(2) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Monitoring; inspection of premises; investigations; access to records; mail; contracts; hearings; oaths; regulations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Commission—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall monitor class II gaming conducted on Indian lands on a continuing basis;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall inspect and examine all premises located on Indian lands on which class II gaming is conducted;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> shall conduct or cause to be conducted such background investigations as may be necessary;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> may demand access to and inspect, examine, photocopy, and audit all papers, books, and records respecting gross revenues of class II gaming conducted on Indian lands and any other matters necessary to carry out the duties of the Commission under this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> may use the United States mail in the same manner and under the same conditions as any department or agency of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> may procure supplies, services, and property by contract in accordance with applicable Federal laws and regulations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> may enter into contracts with Federal, State, tribal and private entities for activities necessary to the discharge of the duties of the Commission and, to the extent feasible, contract the enforcement of the Commission’s regulations with the Indian tribes;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> may hold such hearings, sit and act at such times and places, take such testimony, and receive such evidence as the Commission deems appropriate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> may administer oaths or affirmations to witnesses appearing before the Commission; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> shall promulgate such regulations and guidelines as it deems appropriate to implement the provisions of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application of Government Performance and Results Act</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In carrying out any action under this chapter, the Commission shall be subject to the Government Performance and Results Act of 1993 (<ref>Public Law 103–62</ref>; <ref>107 Stat. 285</ref>).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Plans</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In addition to any plan required under the Government Performance and Results Act of 1993 (<ref>Public Law 103–62</ref>; <ref>107 Stat. 285</ref>), the Commission shall submit a plan to provide technical assistance to tribal gaming operations in accordance with that Act.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–497, § 7</ref>, <date date="1988-10-17">Oct. 17, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2470</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–221, title III, § 301(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-05-12">May 12, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 341</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2707.</num>
<heading> Commission staffing</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General Counsel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Chairman shall appoint a General Counsel to the Commission who shall be paid at the annual rate of basic pay payable for GS–18 of the General Schedule under <ref>section 5332 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Staff</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Chairman shall appoint and supervise other staff of the Commission without regard to the provisions of title 5 governing appointments in the competitive service. Such staff shall be paid without regard to the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of such title relating to classification and General Schedule pay rates, except that no individual so appointed may receive pay in excess of the annual rate of basic pay payable for GS–17 of the General Schedule under section 5332 of that title.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Temporary services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Chairman may procure temporary and intermittent services under <ref>section 3109(b) of title 5</ref>, but at rates for individuals not to exceed the daily equivalent of the maximum annual rate of basic pay payable for GS–18 of the General Schedule.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal agency personnel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon the request of the Chairman, the head of any Federal agency is authorized to detail any of the personnel of such agency to the Commission to assist the Commission in carrying out its duties under this chapter, unless otherwise prohibited by law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrative support services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary or Administrator of General Services shall provide to the Commission on a reimbursable basis such administrative support services as the Commission may request.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–497, § 8</ref>, <date date="1988-10-17">Oct. 17, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2471</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2708.</num>
<heading> Commission; access to information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission may secure from any department or agency of the United States information necessary to enable it to carry out this chapter. Upon the request of the Chairman, the head of such department or agency shall furnish such information to the Commission, unless otherwise prohibited by law.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–497, § 9</ref>, <date date="1988-10-17">Oct. 17, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2472</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2709.</num>
<heading> Interim authority to regulate gaming</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, the Secretary shall continue to exercise those authorities vested in the Secretary on the day before <date date="1988-10-17">October 17, 1988</date>, relating to supervision of Indian gaming until such time as the Commission is organized and prescribes regulations. The Secretary shall provide staff and support assistance to facilitate an orderly transition to regulation of Indian gaming by the Commission.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–497, § 10</ref>, <date date="1988-10-17">Oct. 17, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2472</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2710.</num>
<heading> Tribal gaming ordinances</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Jurisdiction over class I and class II gaming activity</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Class I gaming on Indian lands is within the exclusive jurisdiction of the Indian tribes and shall not be subject to the provisions of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any class II gaming on Indian lands shall continue to be within the jurisdiction of the Indian tribes, but shall be subject to the provisions of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulation of class II gaming activity; net revenue allocation; audits; contracts</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> An Indian tribe may engage in, or license and regulate, class II gaming on Indian lands within such tribe’s jurisdiction, if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> such Indian gaming is located within a State that permits such gaming for any purpose by any person, organization or entity (and such gaming is not otherwise specifically prohibited on Indian lands by Federal law), and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the governing body of the Indian tribe adopts an ordinance or resolution which is approved by the Chairman.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">A separate license issued by the Indian tribe shall be required for each place, facility, or location on Indian lands at which class II gaming is conducted.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Chairman shall approve any tribal ordinance or resolution concerning the conduct, or regulation of class II gaming on the Indian lands within the tribe’s jurisdiction if such ordinance or resolution provides that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> except as provided in paragraph (4), the Indian tribe will have the sole proprietary interest and responsibility for the conduct of any gaming activity;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> net revenues from any tribal gaming are not to be used for purposes other than—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> to fund tribal government operations or programs;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> to provide for the general welfare of the Indian tribe and its members;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> to promote tribal economic development;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> to donate to charitable organizations; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> to help fund operations of local government agencies;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> annual outside audits of the gaming, which may be encompassed within existing independent tribal audit systems, will be provided by the Indian tribe to the Commission;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> all contracts for supplies, services, or concessions for a contract amount in excess of $25,000 annually (except contracts for professional legal or accounting services) relating to such gaming shall be subject to such independent audits;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the construction and maintenance of the gaming facility, and the operation of that gaming is conducted in a manner which adequately protects the environment and the public health and safety; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<chapeau> there is an adequate system which—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> ensures that background investigations are conducted on the primary management officials and key employees of the gaming enterprise and that oversight of such officials and their management is conducted on an ongoing basis; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> includes—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> tribal licenses for primary management officials and key employees of the gaming enterprise with prompt notification to the Commission of the issuance of such licenses;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> a standard whereby any person whose prior activities, criminal record, if any, or reputation, habits and associations pose a threat to the public interest or to the effective regulation of gaming, or create or enhance the dangers of unsuitable, unfair, or illegal practices and methods and activities in the conduct of gaming shall not be eligible for employment; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> notification by the Indian tribe to the Commission of the results of such background check before the issuance of any of such licenses.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> Net revenues from any class II gaming activities conducted or licensed by any Indian tribe may be used to make per capita payments to members of the Indian tribe only if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Indian tribe has prepared a plan to allocate revenues to uses authorized by paragraph (2)(B);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the plan is approved by the Secretary as adequate, particularly with respect to uses described in clause (i) or (iii) of paragraph (2)(B);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the interests of minors and other legally incompetent persons who are entitled to receive any of the per capita payments are protected and preserved and the per capita payments are disbursed to the parents or legal guardian of such minors or legal incompetents in such amounts as may be necessary for the health, education, or welfare, of the minor or other legally incompetent person under a plan approved by the Secretary and the governing body of the Indian tribe; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the per capita payments are subject to Federal taxation and tribes notify members of such tax liability when payments are made.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A tribal ordinance or resolution may provide for the licensing or regulation of class II gaming activities owned by any person or entity other than the Indian tribe and conducted on Indian lands, only if the tribal licensing requirements include the requirements described in the subclauses of subparagraph (B)(i) and are at least as restrictive as those established by State law governing similar gaming within the jurisdiction of the State within which such Indian lands are located. No person or entity, other than the Indian tribe, shall be eligible to receive a tribal license to own a class II gaming activity conducted on Indian lands within the jurisdiction of the Indian tribe if such person or entity would not be eligible to receive a State license to conduct the same activity within the jurisdiction of the State.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> The provisions of subparagraph (A) of this paragraph and the provisions of subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (2) shall not bar the continued operation of an individually owned class II gaming operation that was operating on <date date="1986-09-01">September 1, 1986</date>, if—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent1">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> such gaming operation is licensed and regulated by an Indian tribe pursuant to an ordinance reviewed and approved by the Commission in accordance with <ref>section 2712 of this title</ref>,</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent1">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> income to the Indian tribe from such gaming is used only for the purposes described in paragraph (2)(B) of this subsection,</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent1">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> not less than 60 percent of the net revenues is income to the Indian tribe, and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent1">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> the owner of such gaming operation pays an appropriate assessment to the National Indian Gaming Commission under <ref>section 2717(a)(1) of this title</ref> for regulation of such gaming.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The exemption from the application of this subsection provided under this subparagraph may not be transferred to any person or entity and shall remain in effect only so long as the gaming activity remains within the same nature and scope as operated on <date date="1988-10-17">October 17, 1988</date>.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Within sixty days of <date date="1988-10-17">October 17, 1988</date>, the Secretary shall prepare a list of each individually owned gaming operation to which clause (i) applies and shall publish such list in the Federal Register.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Issuance of gaming license; certificate of self-regulation</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Commission may consult with appropriate law enforcement officials concerning gaming licenses issued by an Indian tribe and shall have thirty days to notify the Indian tribe of any objections to issuance of such license.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If, after the issuance of a gaming license by an Indian tribe, reliable information is received from the Commission indicating that a primary management official or key employee does not meet the standard established under subsection (b)(2)(F)(ii)(II), the Indian tribe shall suspend such license and, after notice and hearing, may revoke such license.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> Any Indian tribe which operates a class II gaming activity and which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> has continuously conducted such activity for a period of not less than three years, including at least one year after <date date="1988-10-17">October 17, 1988</date>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> has otherwise complied with the provisions of this section <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002184">1</ref></content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">may petition the Commission for a certificate of self-regulation.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> The Commission shall issue a certificate of self-regulation if it determines from available information, and after a hearing if requested by the tribe, that the tribe has—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> conducted its gaming activity in a manner which—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> has resulted in an effective and honest accounting of all revenues;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> has resulted in a reputation for safe, fair, and honest operation of the activity; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> has been generally free of evidence of criminal or dishonest activity;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> adopted and is implementing adequate systems for—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> accounting for all revenues from the activity;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> investigation, licensing, and monitoring of all employees of the gaming activity; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> investigation, enforcement and prosecution of violations of its gaming ordinance and regulations; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> conducted the operation on a fiscally and economically sound basis.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> During any year in which a tribe has a certificate for self-regulation—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the tribe shall not be subject to the provisions of paragraphs (1), (2), (3), and (4) of <ref>section 2706(b) of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the tribe shall continue to submit an annual independent audit as required by subsection (b)(2)(C) and shall submit to the Commission a complete resume on all employees hired and licensed by the tribe subsequent to the issuance of a certificate of self-regulation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Commission may not assess a fee on such activity pursuant to <ref>section 2717 of this title</ref> in excess of one quarter of 1 per centum of the gross revenue.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The Commission may, for just cause and after an opportunity for a hearing, remove a certificate of self-regulation by majority vote of its members.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Class III gaming activities; authorization; revocation; Tribal-State compact</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Class III gaming activities shall be lawful on Indian lands only if such activities are—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> authorized by an ordinance or resolution that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is adopted by the governing body of the Indian tribe having jurisdiction over such lands,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> meets the requirements of subsection (b), and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> is approved by the Chairman,</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> located in a State that permits such gaming for any purpose by any person, organization, or entity, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> conducted in conformance with a Tribal-State compact entered into by the Indian tribe and the State under paragraph (3) that is in effect.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> If any Indian tribe proposes to engage in, or to authorize any person or entity to engage in, a class III gaming activity on Indian lands of the Indian tribe, the governing body of the Indian tribe shall adopt and submit to the Chairman an ordinance or resolution that meets the requirements of subsection (b).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> The Chairman shall approve any ordinance or resolution described in subparagraph (A), unless the Chairman specifically determines that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the ordinance or resolution was not adopted in compliance with the governing documents of the Indian tribe, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the tribal governing body was significantly and unduly influenced in the adoption of such ordinance or resolution by any person identified in <ref>section 2711(e)(1)(D) of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Upon the approval of such an ordinance or resolution, the Chairman shall publish in the Federal Register such ordinance or resolution and the order of approval.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Effective with the publication under subparagraph (B) of an ordinance or resolution adopted by the governing body of an Indian tribe that has been approved by the Chairman under subparagraph (B), class III gaming activity on the Indian lands of the Indian tribe shall be fully subject to the terms and conditions of the Tribal-State compact entered into under paragraph (3) by the Indian tribe that is in effect.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(D)</num>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The governing body of an Indian tribe, in its sole discretion and without the approval of the Chairman, may adopt an ordinance or resolution revoking any prior ordinance or resolution that authorized class III gaming on the Indian lands of the Indian tribe. Such revocation shall render class III gaming illegal on the Indian lands of such Indian tribe.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The Indian tribe shall submit any revocation ordinance or resolution described in clause (i) to the Chairman. The Chairman shall publish such ordinance or resolution in the Federal Register and the revocation provided by such ordinance or resolution shall take effect on the date of such publication.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> Notwithstanding any other provision of this subsection—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent1">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> any person or entity operating a class III gaming activity pursuant to this paragraph on the date on which an ordinance or resolution described in clause (i) that revokes authorization for such class III gaming activity is published in the Federal Register may, during the 1-year period beginning on the date on which such revocation ordinance or resolution is published under clause (ii), continue to operate such activity in conformance with the Tribal-State compact entered into under paragraph (3) that is in effect, and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent1">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> any civil action that arises before, and any crime that is committed before, the close of such 1-year period shall not be affected by such revocation ordinance or resolution.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Any Indian tribe having jurisdiction over the Indian lands upon which a class III gaming activity is being conducted, or is to be conducted, shall request the State in which such lands are located to enter into negotiations for the purpose of entering into a Tribal-State compact governing the conduct of gaming activities. Upon receiving such a request, the State shall negotiate with the Indian tribe in good faith to enter into such a compact.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Any State and any Indian tribe may enter into a Tribal-State compact governing gaming activities on the Indian lands of the Indian tribe, but such compact shall take effect only when notice of approval by the Secretary of such compact has been published by the Secretary in the Federal Register.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> Any Tribal-State compact negotiated under subparagraph (A) may include provisions relating to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the application of the criminal and civil laws and regulations of the Indian tribe or the State that are directly related to, and necessary for, the licensing and regulation of such activity;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the allocation of criminal and civil jurisdiction between the State and the Indian tribe necessary for the enforcement of such laws and regulations;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the assessment by the State of such activities in such amounts as are necessary to defray the costs of regulating such activity;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> taxation by the Indian tribe of such activity in amounts comparable to amounts assessed by the State for comparable activities;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> remedies for breach of contract;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> standards for the operation of such activity and maintenance of the gaming facility, including licensing; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> any other subjects that are directly related to the operation of gaming activities.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Except for any assessments that may be agreed to under paragraph (3)(C)(iii) of this subsection, nothing in this section shall be interpreted as conferring upon a State or any of its political subdivisions authority to impose any tax, fee, charge, or other assessment upon an Indian tribe or upon any other person or entity authorized by an Indian tribe to engage in a class III activity. No State may refuse to enter into the negotiations described in paragraph (3)(A) based upon the lack of authority in such State, or its political subdivisions, to impose such a tax, fee, charge, or other assessment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Nothing in this subsection shall impair the right of an Indian tribe to regulate class III gaming on its Indian lands concurrently with the State, except to the extent that such regulation is inconsistent with, or less stringent than, the State laws and regulations made applicable by any Tribal-State compact entered into by the Indian tribe under paragraph (3) that is in effect.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> The provisions of <ref>section 1175 of title 15</ref> shall not apply to any gaming conducted under a Tribal-State compact that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is entered into under paragraph (3) by a State in which gambling devices are legal, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is in effect.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(7)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> The United States district courts shall have jurisdiction over—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any cause of action initiated by an Indian tribe arising from the failure of a State to enter into negotiations with the Indian tribe for the purpose of entering into a Tribal-State compact under paragraph (3) or to conduct such negotiations in good faith,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any cause of action initiated by a State or Indian tribe to enjoin a class III gaming activity located on Indian lands and conducted in violation of any Tribal-State compact entered into under paragraph (3) that is in effect, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> any cause of action initiated by the Secretary to enforce the procedures prescribed under subparagraph (B)(vii).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> An Indian tribe may initiate a cause of action described in subparagraph (A)(i) only after the close of the 180-day period beginning on the date on which the Indian tribe requested the State to enter into negotiations under paragraph (3)(A).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> In any action described in subparagraph (A)(i), upon the introduction of evidence by an Indian tribe that—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent1">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> a Tribal-State compact has not been entered into under paragraph (3), and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent1">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the State did not respond to the request of the Indian tribe to negotiate such a compact or did not respond to such request in good faith,</content>
</subclause>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">the burden of proof shall be upon the State to prove that the State has negotiated with the Indian tribe in good faith to conclude a Tribal-State compact governing the conduct of gaming activities.</continuation>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> If, in any action described in subparagraph (A)(i), the court finds that the State has failed to negotiate in good faith with the Indian tribe to conclude a Tribal-State compact governing the conduct of gaming activities, the court shall order the State and the Indian Tribe <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002185">2</ref> to conclude such a compact within a 60-day period. In determining in such an action whether a State has negotiated in good faith, the court—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent1">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> may take into account the public interest, public safety, criminality, financial integrity, and adverse economic impacts on existing gaming activities, and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent1">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> shall consider any demand by the State for direct taxation of the Indian tribe or of any Indian lands as evidence that the State has not negotiated in good faith.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> If a State and an Indian tribe fail to conclude a Tribal-State compact governing the conduct of gaming activities on the Indian lands subject to the jurisdiction of such Indian tribe within the 60-day period provided in the order of a court issued under clause (iii), the Indian tribe and the State shall each submit to a mediator appointed by the court a proposed compact that represents their last best offer for a compact. The mediator shall select from the two proposed compacts the one which best comports with the terms of this chapter and any other applicable Federal law and with the findings and order of the court.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> The mediator appointed by the court under clause (iv) shall submit to the State and the Indian tribe the compact selected by the mediator under clause (iv).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> If a State consents to a proposed compact during the 60-day period beginning on the date on which the proposed compact is submitted by the mediator to the State under clause (v), the proposed compact shall be treated as a Tribal-State compact entered into under paragraph (3).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(vii)</num>
<chapeau> If the State does not consent during the 60-day period described in clause (vi) to a proposed compact submitted by a mediator under clause (v), the mediator shall notify the Secretary and the Secretary shall prescribe, in consultation with the Indian tribe, procedures—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent1">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> which are consistent with the proposed compact selected by the mediator under clause (iv), the provisions of this chapter, and the relevant provisions of the laws of the State, and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent1">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> under which class III gaming may be conducted on the Indian lands over which the Indian tribe has jurisdiction.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(8)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Secretary is authorized to approve any Tribal-State compact entered into between an Indian tribe and a State governing gaming on Indian lands of such Indian tribe.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary may disapprove a compact described in subparagraph (A) only if such compact violates—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any provision of this chapter,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any other provision of Federal law that does not relate to jurisdiction over gaming on Indian lands, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the trust obligations of the United States to Indians.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> If the Secretary does not approve or disapprove a compact described in subparagraph (A) before the date that is 45 days after the date on which the compact is submitted to the Secretary for approval, the compact shall be considered to have been approved by the Secretary, but only to the extent the compact is consistent with the provisions of this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register notice of any Tribal-State compact that is approved, or considered to have been approved, under this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> An Indian tribe may enter into a management contract for the operation of a class III gaming activity if such contract has been submitted to, and approved by, the Chairman. The Chairman’s review and approval of such contract shall be governed by the provisions of subsections (b), (c), (d), (f), (g), and (h) of <ref>section 2711 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Approval of ordinances</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this section, by not later than the date that is 90 days after the date on which any tribal gaming ordinance or resolution is submitted to the Chairman, the Chairman shall approve such ordinance or resolution if it meets the requirements of this section. Any such ordinance or resolution not acted upon at the end of that 90-day period shall be considered to have been approved by the Chairman, but only to the extent such ordinance or resolution is consistent with the provisions of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–497, § 11</ref>, <date date="1988-10-17">Oct. 17, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2472</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2711.</num>
<heading> Management contracts</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Class II gaming activity; information on operators</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Subject to the approval of the Chairman, an Indian tribe may enter into a management contract for the operation and management of a class II gaming activity that the Indian tribe may engage in under <ref>section 2710(b)(1) of this title</ref>, but, before approving such contract, the Chairman shall require and obtain the following information:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the name, address, and other additional pertinent background information on each person or entity (including individuals comprising such entity) having a direct financial interest in, or management responsibility for, such contract, and, in the case of a corporation, those individuals who serve on the board of directors of such corporation and each of its stockholders who hold (directly or indirectly) 10 percent or more of its issued and outstanding stock;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a description of any previous experience that each person listed pursuant to subparagraph (A) has had with other gaming contracts with Indian tribes or with the gaming industry generally, including specifically the name and address of any licensing or regulatory agency with which such person has had a contract relating to gaming; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a complete financial statement of each person listed pursuant to subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any person listed pursuant to paragraph (1)(A) shall be required to respond to such written or oral questions that the Chairman may propound in accordance with his responsibilities under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> For purposes of this chapter, any reference to the management contract described in paragraph (1) shall be considered to include all collateral agreements to such contract that relate to the gaming activity.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Approval</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Chairman may approve any management contract entered into pursuant to this section only if he determines that it provides at least—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> for adequate accounting procedures that are maintained, and for verifiable financial reports that are prepared, by or for the tribal governing body on a monthly basis;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> for access to the daily operations of the gaming to appropriate tribal officials who shall also have a right to verify the daily gross revenues and income made from any such tribal gaming activity;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> for a minimum guaranteed payment to the Indian tribe that has preference over the retirement of development and construction costs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> for an agreed ceiling for the repayment of development and construction costs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> for a contract term not to exceed five years, except that, upon the request of an Indian tribe, the Chairman may authorize a contract term that exceeds five years but does not exceed seven years if the Chairman is satisfied that the capital investment required, and the income projections, for the particular gaming activity require the additional time; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> for grounds and mechanisms for terminating such contract, but actual contract termination shall not require the approval of the Commission.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fee based on percentage of net revenues</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Chairman may approve a management contract providing for a fee based upon a percentage of the net revenues of a tribal gaming activity if the Chairman determines that such percentage fee is reasonable in light of surrounding circumstances. Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, such fee shall not exceed 30 percent of the net revenues.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Upon the request of an Indian tribe, the Chairman may approve a management contract providing for a fee based upon a percentage of the net revenues of a tribal gaming activity that exceeds 30 percent but not 40 percent of the net revenues if the Chairman is satisfied that the capital investment required, and income projections, for such tribal gaming activity require the additional fee requested by the Indian tribe.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Period for approval; extension</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">By no later than the date that is 180 days after the date on which a management contract is submitted to the Chairman for approval, the Chairman shall approve or disapprove such contract on its merits. The Chairman may extend the 180-day period by not more than 90 days if the Chairman notifies the Indian tribe in writing of the reason for the extension. The Indian tribe may bring an action in a United States district court to compel action by the Chairman if a contract has not been approved or disapproved within the period required by this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disapproval</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Chairman shall not approve any contract if the Chairman determines that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> any person listed pursuant to subsection (a)(1)(A) of this section—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is an elected member of the governing body of the Indian tribe which is the party to the management contract;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> has been or subsequently is convicted of any felony or gaming offense;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> has knowingly and willfully provided materially important false statements or information to the Commission or the Indian tribe pursuant to this chapter or has refused to respond to questions propounded pursuant to subsection (a)(2); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> has been determined to be a person whose prior activities, criminal record if any, or reputation, habits, and associations pose a threat to the public interest or to the effective regulation and control of gaming, or create or enhance the dangers of unsuitable, unfair, or illegal practices, methods, and activities in the conduct of gaming or the carrying on of the business and financial arrangements incidental thereto;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the management contractor has, or has attempted to, unduly interfere or influence for its gain or advantage any decision or process of tribal government relating to the gaming activity;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the management contractor has deliberately or substantially failed to comply with the terms of the management contract or the tribal gaming ordinance or resolution adopted and approved pursuant to this chapter; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> a trustee, exercising the skill and diligence that a trustee is commonly held to, would not approve the contract.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Modification or voiding</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Chairman, after notice and hearing, shall have the authority to require appropriate contract modifications or may void any contract if he subsequently determines that any of the provisions of this section have been violated.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interest in land</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No management contract for the operation and management of a gaming activity regulated by this chapter shall transfer or, in any other manner, convey any interest in land or other real property, unless specific statutory authority exists and unless clearly specified in writing in said contract.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The authority of the Secretary under <ref>section 81 of this title</ref>, relating to management contracts regulated pursuant to this chapter, is hereby transferred to the Commission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Investigation fee</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission shall require a potential contractor to pay a fee to cover the cost of the investigation necessary to reach a determination required in subsection (e) of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–497, § 12</ref>, <date date="1988-10-17">Oct. 17, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2479</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2712.</num>
<heading> Review of existing ordinances and contracts</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification to submit</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As soon as practicable after the organization of the Commission, the Chairman shall notify each Indian tribe or management contractor who, prior to <date date="1988-10-17">October 17, 1988</date>, adopted an ordinance or resolution authorizing class II gaming or class III gaming or entered into a management contract, that such ordinance, resolution, or contract, including all collateral agreements relating to the gaming activity, must be submitted for his review within 60 days of such notification. Any activity conducted under such ordinance, resolution, contract, or agreement shall be valid under this chapter, or any amendment made by this chapter, unless disapproved under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Approval or modification of ordinance or resolution</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> By no later than the date that is 90 days after the date on which an ordinance or resolution authorizing class II gaming or class III gaming is submitted to the Chairman pursuant to subsection (a), the Chairman shall review such ordinance or resolution to determine if it conforms to the requirements of <ref>section 2710(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If the Chairman determines that an ordinance or resolution submitted under subsection (a) conforms to the requirements of <ref>section 2710(b) of this title</ref>, the Chairman shall approve it.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> If the Chairman determines that an ordinance or resolution submitted under subsection (a) does not conform to the requirements of <ref>section 2710(b) of this title</ref>, the Chairman shall provide written notification of necessary modifications to the Indian tribe which shall have not more than 120 days to bring such ordinance or resolution into compliance.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Approval or modification of management contract</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Within 180 days after the submission of a management contract, including all collateral agreements, pursuant to subsection (a), the Chairman shall subject such contract to the requirements and process of <ref>section 2711 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If the Chairman determines that a management contract submitted under subsection (a), and the management contractor under such contract, meet the requirements of <ref>section 2711 of this title</ref>, the Chairman shall approve the management contract.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> If the Chairman determines that a contract submitted under subsection (a), or the management contractor under a contract submitted under subsection (a), does not meet the requirements of <ref>section 2711 of this title</ref>, the Chairman shall provide written notification to the parties to such contract of necessary modifications and the parties shall have not more than 120 days to come into compliance. If a management contract has been approved by the Secretary prior to <date date="1988-10-17">October 17, 1988</date>, the parties shall have not more than 180 days after notification of necessary modifications to come into compliance.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–497, § 13</ref>, <date date="1988-10-17">Oct. 17, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2481</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2713.</num>
<heading> Civil penalties</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority; amount; appeal; written complaint</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Subject to such regulations as may be prescribed by the Commission, the Chairman shall have authority to levy and collect appropriate civil fines, not to exceed $25,000 per violation, against the tribal operator of an Indian game or a management contractor engaged in gaming for any violation of any provision of this chapter, any regulation prescribed by the Commission pursuant to this chapter, or tribal regulations, ordinances, or resolutions approved under section 2710 or 2712 of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Commission shall, by regulation, provide an opportunity for an appeal and hearing before the Commission on fines levied and collected by the Chairman.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Whenever the Commission has reason to believe that the tribal operator of an Indian game or a management contractor is engaged in activities regulated by this chapter, by regulations prescribed under this chapter, or by tribal regulations, ordinances, or resolutions, approved under section 2710 or 2712 of this title, that may result in the imposition of a fine under subsection (a)(1), the permanent closure of such game, or the modification or termination of any management contract, the Commission shall provide such tribal operator or management contractor with a written complaint stating the acts or omissions which form the basis for such belief and the action or choice of action being considered by the Commission. The allegation shall be set forth in common and concise language and must specify the statutory or regulatory provisions alleged to have been violated, but may not consist merely of allegations stated in statutory or regulatory language.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Temporary closure; hearing</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Chairman shall have power to order temporary closure of an Indian game for substantial violation of the provisions of this chapter, of regulations prescribed by the Commission pursuant to this chapter, or of tribal regulations, ordinances, or resolutions approved under section 2710 or 2712 of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Not later than thirty days after the issuance by the Chairman of an order of temporary closure, the Indian tribe or management contractor involved shall have a right to a hearing before the Commission to determine whether such order should be made permanent or dissolved. Not later than sixty days following such hearing, the Commission shall, by a vote of not less than two of its members, decide whether to order a permanent closure of the gaming operation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appeal from final decision</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A decision of the Commission to give final approval of a fine levied by the Chairman or to order a permanent closure pursuant to this section shall be appealable to the appropriate Federal district court pursuant to chapter 7 of title 5.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulatory authority under tribal law</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter precludes an Indian tribe from exercising regulatory authority provided under tribal law over a gaming establishment within the Indian tribe’s jurisdiction if such regulation is not inconsistent with this chapter or with any rules or regulations adopted by the Commission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–497, § 14</ref>, <date date="1988-10-17">Oct. 17, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2482</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2714.</num>
<heading> Judicial review</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Decisions made by the Commission pursuant to sections 2710, 2711, 2712, and 2713 of this title shall be final agency decisions for purposes of appeal to the appropriate Federal district court pursuant to chapter 7 of title 5.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–497, § 15</ref>, <date date="1988-10-17">Oct. 17, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2483</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2715.</num>
<heading> Subpoena and deposition authority</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Attendance, testimony, production of papers, etc.</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">By a vote of not less than two members, the Commission shall have the power to require by subpoena the attendance and testimony of witnesses and the production of all books, papers, and documents relating to any matter under consideration or investigation. Witnesses so summoned shall be paid the same fees and mileage that are paid witnesses in the courts of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Geographical location</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The attendance of witnesses and the production of books, papers, and documents, may be required from any place in the United States at any designated place of hearing. The Commission may request the Secretary to request the Attorney General to bring an action to enforce any subpoena under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Refusal of subpoena; court order; contempt</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any court of the United States within the jurisdiction of which an inquiry is carried on may, in case of contumacy or refusal to obey a subpoena for any reason, issue an order requiring such person to appear before the Commission (and produce books, papers, or documents as so ordered) and give evidence concerning the matter in question and any failure to obey such order of the court may be punished by such court as a contempt thereof.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Depositions; notice</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A Commissioner may order testimony to be taken by deposition in any proceeding or investigation pending before the Commission at any stage of such proceeding or investigation. Such depositions may be taken before any person designated by the Commission and having power to administer oaths. Reasonable notice must first be given to the Commission in writing by the party or his attorney proposing to take such deposition, and, in cases in which a Commissioner proposes to take a deposition, reasonable notice must be given. The notice shall state the name of the witness and the time and place of the taking of his deposition. Any person may be compelled to appear and depose, and to produce books, papers, or documents, in the same manner as witnesses may be compelled to appear and testify and produce like documentary evidence before the Commission, as hereinbefore provided.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Oath or affirmation required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Every person deposing as herein provided shall be cautioned and shall be required to swear (or affirm, if he so requests) to testify to the whole truth, and shall be carefully examined. His testimony shall be reduced to writing by the person taking the deposition, or under his direction, and shall, after it has been reduced to writing, be subscribed by the deponent. All depositions shall be promptly filed with the Commission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Witness fees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Witnesses whose depositions are taken as authorized in this section, and the persons taking the same, shall severally be entitled to the same fees as are paid for like services in the courts of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–497, § 16</ref>, <date date="1988-10-17">Oct. 17, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2483</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2716.</num>
<heading> Investigative powers</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Confidential information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as provided in subsection (b), the Commission shall preserve any and all information received pursuant to this chapter as confidential pursuant to the provisions of paragraphs (4) and (7) of <ref>section 552(b) of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Provision to law enforcement officials</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission shall, when such information indicates a violation of Federal, State, or tribal statutes, ordinances, or resolutions, provide such information to the appropriate law enforcement officials.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Attorney General</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Attorney General shall investigate activities associated with gaming authorized by this chapter which may be a violation of Federal law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–497, § 17</ref>, <date date="1988-10-17">Oct. 17, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2484</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2717.</num>
<heading> Commission funding</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Commission shall establish a schedule of fees to be paid to the Commission annually by each gaming operation that conducts a class II or class III gaming activity that is regulated by this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> The rate of the fees imposed under the schedule established under paragraph (1) shall be—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> no more than 2.5 percent of the first $1,500,000, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> no more than 5 percent of amounts in excess of the first $1,500,000,</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">of the gross revenues from each activity regulated by this chapter.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The total amount of all fees imposed during any fiscal year under the schedule established under paragraph (1) shall not exceed 0.080 percent of the gross gaming revenues of all gaming operations subject to regulation under this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Commission, by a vote of not less than two of its members, shall annually adopt the rate of the fees authorized by this section which shall be payable to the Commission on a quarterly basis.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Failure to pay the fees imposed under the schedule established under paragraph (1) shall, subject to the regulations of the Commission, be grounds for revocation of the approval of the Chairman of any license, ordinance, or resolution required under this chapter for the operation of gaming.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> To the extent that revenue derived from fees imposed under the schedule established under paragraph (1) are not expended or committed at the close of any fiscal year, such surplus funds shall be credited to each gaming activity on a pro rata basis against such fees imposed for the succeeding year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> For purposes of this section, gross revenues shall constitute the annual total amount of money wagered, less any amounts paid out as prizes or paid for prizes awarded and less allowance for amortization of capital expenditures for structures.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Commission, in coordination with the Secretary and in conjunction with the fiscal year of the United States, shall adopt an annual budget for the expenses and operation of the Commission.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The budget of the Commission may include a request for appropriations, as authorized by <ref>section 2718 of this title</ref>, in an amount equal the amount of funds derived from assessments authorized by subsection (a) for the fiscal year preceding the fiscal year for which the appropriation request is made.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The request for appropriations pursuant to paragraph (2) shall be subject to the approval of the Secretary and shall be included as a part of the budget request of the Department of the Interior.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–497, § 18</ref>, <date date="1988-10-17">Oct. 17, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2484</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–83, title I, § 123(a)(1)</ref>–(2)(B), <date date="1997-11-14">Nov. 14, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1566</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–221, title III, § 301(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-05-12">May 12, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 341</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2717a.</num>
<heading> Availability of class II gaming activity fees to carry out duties of Commission</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In fiscal year 1990 and thereafter, fees collected pursuant to and as limited by <ref>section 2717 of this title</ref> shall be available to carry out the duties of the Commission, to remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–121, title I</ref>, <date date="1989-10-23">Oct. 23, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 718</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2718.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Subject to <ref>section 2717 of this title</ref>, there are authorized to be appropriated, for fiscal year 1998, and for each fiscal year thereafter, an amount equal to the amount of funds derived from the assessments authorized by <ref>section 2717(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding <ref>section 2717 of this title</ref>, there are authorized to be appropriated to fund the operation of the Commission, $2,000,000 for fiscal year 1998, and $2,000,000 for each fiscal year thereafter. The amounts authorized to be appropriated in the preceding sentence shall be in addition to the amounts authorized to be appropriated under subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–497, § 19</ref>, <date date="1988-10-17">Oct. 17, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2485</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–238, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-17">Dec. 17, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1908</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–83, title I, § 123(b)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-14">Nov. 14, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1566</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–119, title VI, § 627</ref>, <date date="1997-11-26">Nov. 26, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 2522</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2719.</num>
<heading> Gaming on lands acquired after <date date="1988-10-17">October 17, 1988</date></heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition on lands acquired in trust by Secretary</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except as provided in subsection (b), gaming regulated by this chapter shall not be conducted on lands acquired by the Secretary in trust for the benefit of an Indian tribe after <date date="1988-10-17">October 17, 1988</date>, unless—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> such lands are located within or contiguous to the boundaries of the reservation of the Indian tribe on <date date="1988-10-17">October 17, 1988</date>; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the Indian tribe has no reservation on <date date="1988-10-17">October 17, 1988</date>, and—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> such lands are located in Oklahoma and—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> are within the boundaries of the Indian tribe’s former reservation, as defined by the Secretary, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> are contiguous to other land held in trust or restricted status by the United States for the Indian tribe in Oklahoma; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> such lands are located in a State other than Oklahoma and are within the Indian tribe’s last recognized reservation within the State or States within which such Indian tribe is presently located.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Subsection (a) will not apply when—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Secretary, after consultation with the Indian tribe and appropriate State and local officials, including officials of other nearby Indian tribes, determines that a gaming establishment on newly acquired lands would be in the best interest of the Indian tribe and its members, and would not be detrimental to the surrounding community, but only if the Governor of the State in which the gaming activity is to be conducted concurs in the Secretary’s determination; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> lands are taken into trust as part of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a settlement of a land claim,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the initial reservation of an Indian tribe acknowledged by the Secretary under the Federal acknowledgment process, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the restoration of lands for an Indian tribe that is restored to Federal recognition.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Subsection (a) shall not apply to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any lands involved in the trust petition of the St. Croix Chippewa Indians of Wisconsin that is the subject of the action filed in the United States District Court for the District of Columbia entitled St. Croix Chippewa Indians of Wisconsin v. United States, Civ. No. 86–2278, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the interests of the Miccosukee Tribe of Indians of Florida in approximately 25 contiguous acres of land, more or less, in Dade County, Florida, located within one mile of the intersection of State Road Numbered 27 (also known as Krome Avenue) and the Tamiami Trail.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Upon request of the governing body of the Miccosukee Tribe of Indians of Florida, the Secretary shall, notwithstanding any other provision of law, accept the transfer by such Tribe to the Secretary of the interests of such Tribe in the lands described in paragraph (2)(B) and the Secretary shall declare that such interests are held in trust by the Secretary for the benefit of such Tribe and that such interests are part of the reservation of such Tribe under sections 5108 and 5110 of this title, subject to any encumbrances and rights that are held at the time of such transfer by any person or entity other than such Tribe. The Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register the legal description of any lands that are declared held in trust by the Secretary under this paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority of Secretary not affected</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall affect or diminish the authority and responsibility of the Secretary to take land into trust.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application of title 26</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The provisions of title 26 (including sections 1441, 3402(q), 6041, and 6050I, and chapter 35 of such title) concerning the reporting and withholding of taxes with respect to the winnings from gaming or wagering operations shall apply to Indian gaming operations conducted pursuant to this chapter, or under a Tribal-State compact entered into under <ref>section 2710(d)(3) of this title</ref> that is in effect, in the same manner as such provisions apply to State gaming and wagering operations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The provisions of this subsection shall apply notwithstanding any other provision of law enacted before, on, or after <date date="1988-10-17">October 17, 1988</date>, unless such other provision of law specifically cites this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–497, § 20</ref>, <date date="1988-10-17">Oct. 17, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2485</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2720.</num>
<heading> Dissemination of information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Consistent with the requirements of this chapter, sections 1301, 1302, 1303 and 1304 of title 18 shall not apply to any gaming conducted by an Indian tribe pursuant to this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–497, § 21</ref>, <date date="1988-10-17">Oct. 17, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2486</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2721.</num>
<heading> Severability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the event that any section or provision of this chapter, or amendment made by this chapter, is held invalid, it is the intent of Congress that the remaining sections or provisions of this chapter, and amendments made by this chapter, shall continue in full force and effect.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–497, § 22</ref>, <date date="1988-10-17">Oct. 17, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2486</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>