<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 47—</num>
<heading>CONVEYANCE OF SUBMARGINAL LAND</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5501.</num>
<heading> Submarginal lands of United States held in trust for specified Indian tribes</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Declaration; addition to reservations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as hereinafter provided, all of the right, title, and interest of the United States of America in all of the land, and the improvements now thereon, that was acquired under title II of the National Industrial Recovery Act of <date date="1933-06-16">June 16, 1933</date> (<ref>48 Stat. 200</ref>), the Emergency Relief Appropriation Act of <date date="1935-04-08">April 8, 1935</date> (<ref>49 Stat. 115</ref>), and <ref>section 55 of the Act of August 24, 1935</ref> (<ref>49 Stat. 750</ref>, 781), and that are now administered by the Secretary of the Interior for the use or benefit of the Indian tribes identified in <ref>section 5502(a) of this title</ref>, together with all minerals underlying any such land whether acquired pursuant to such Acts or otherwise owned by the United States, are hereby declared to be held by the United States in trust for each of said tribes, and (except in the case of the Cherokee Nation) shall be a part of the reservations heretofore established for each of said tribes.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Imposition of conditions on conveyed lands; lands excepted from conveying authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The property conveyed by this chapter shall be subject to the appropriation or disposition of any of the lands, or interests therein, within the Pine Ridge Indian Reservation, South Dakota, as authorized by sections 441j to 441<i>o</i> of title 16, and subject to a reservation in the United States of a right to prohibit or restrict improvements or structures on, and to continuously or intermittently inundate or otherwise use, lands in sections 25 and 26, township 48 north, range 3 west, at Odanah, Wisconsin, in connection with the Bad River flood control project as authorized by <ref>section 203 of the Act of July 3, 1958</ref> (<ref>72 Stat. 297</ref>, 311): <i>Provided</i>, That this chapter shall not convey the title to any part of the lands or any interest therein that prior to <date date="1975-10-17">October 17, 1975</date>, have been included in the authorized water resources development projects in the Missouri River Basin as authorized by <ref>section 203 of the Act of July 3, 1958</ref> (<ref>72 Stat. 297</ref>, 311), as amended and supplemented: <i>Provided further</i>, That such lands included in Missouri River Basin projects shall be treated as former trust lands are treated.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional lands held in trust for specified Indian tribes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The right, title, and interest of the United States of America in all of the lands, including the improvements now thereon (title to which is in the United States), acquired under title II of the National Industrial Recovery Act of <date date="1933-06-16">June 16, 1933</date> (<ref>48 Stat. 200</ref>), and any subsequent Emergency Relief Appropriation Acts, including but not limited to section 5 of the Emergency Relief Appropriation Act of 1939 (<ref>53 Stat. 927</ref>, 930) and section 4 of the Emergency Relief Appropriation Act, fiscal year 1941 (<ref>54 Stat. 611</ref>, 617), together with all minerals underlying any such land whether acquired pursuant to such Acts or otherwise owned by the United States, and which lands are now administered by the Secretary of the Interior for the use or benefit of (1) Ramah Navajo Indians, are hereby declared to be held in trust for the Ramah Band of the Navajo Tribe, and (2) Choctaw Indians of Mississippi, except lands subject to the Act of <date date="1939-06-21">June 21, 1939</date> (<ref>53 Stat. 851</ref>), are hereby declared to be held in trust for the Mississippi Band of Choctaw Indians; excepting valid rights-of-way of record.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 94–114, § 1</ref>, <date date="1975-10-17">Oct. 17, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 577</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–434, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1983-01-08">Jan. 8, 1983</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2280</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5502.</num>
<heading> Designation of tribes</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Description of lands</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The lands, declared by <ref>section 5501(a) of this title</ref> to be held in trust by the United States for the benefit of the Indian tribes named in this section, are generally described as follows:<table width="100%" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><colgroup><col/><col/><col/><col/></colgroup><thead><tr class="header"><th><p>Tribe</p></th><th><p>Reservation</p></th><th><p>Submarginal land project donated to said tribe or group</p></th><th><p>Approximate acreage</p></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><p> 1. Bad River Band of the Lake Superior Tribe of Chippewa     ­Indians of Wisconsin</p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>Bad River</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>Bad River LI–WI–8</span></p></td><td><p>13,148.81</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span> 2. Blackfeet Tribe</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>Blackfeet</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>Blackfeet LI–MT–9</span></p></td><td><p>9,036.73</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span> 3. Cherokee Nation of Oklahoma</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span> </span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>Delaware LI–OK–4</span></p></td><td><p>18,749.19</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p> </p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>Adair LI–OK–5</span></p></td><td><p>................</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span> 4. Cheyenne River Sioux Tribe</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>Cheyenne River</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>Cheyenne Indian LI–SD–13</span></p></td><td><p>3,738.47</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span> 5. Crow Creek Sioux Tribe</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>Crow Creek</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>Crow Creek LI–SD–10</span></p></td><td><p>19,169.89</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span> 6. Lower Brule Sioux Tribe</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>Lower Brule</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>Lower Brule LI–SD–10</span></p></td><td><p>13,209.22</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span> 7. Devils Lake Sioux Tribe</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>Fort Totten</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>Fort Totten LI–ND–11</span></p></td><td><p>1,424.45</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span> 8. Fort Belknap Indian Community</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>Fort Belknap</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>Fort Belknap LI–MT–8</span></p></td><td><p>25,530.10</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span> 9. Assiniboine and Sioux Tribes</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>Fort Peck</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>Fort Peck LI–MT–6</span></p></td><td><p>85,835.52</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>10. Lac Courte Oreilles Band of Lake Superior Chippewa Indians</p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>Lac Courte Oreilles</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>Lac Courte LI–WI–9</span></p></td><td><p>13,184.65</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>11. Keweenaw Bay Indian Community</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>L’Anse</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>L’Anse LI–MI–8</span></p></td><td><p>4,016.49</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>12. Minnesota Chippewa Tribe</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>White Earth</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>Twin Lakes LI–MN–6</span></p></td><td><p>28,544.80</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p> </p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>Flat Lake LI–MN–15</span></p></td><td><p>................</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>13. Navajo Tribe</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>Navajo</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>Gallup-Two Wells LI–NM–18</span></p></td><td><p>69,947.24</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>14. Oglala Sioux Tribe</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>Pine Ridge</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>Pine Ridge LI–SD–7</span></p></td><td><p>18,064.48</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>15. Rosebud Sioux Tribe</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>Rosebud</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>Cutmeat LI–SD–8</span></p></td><td><p>28,734.59</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p> </p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>Antelope LI–SD–9</span></p></td><td><p>................</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>16. Shoshone-Bannock Tribes</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>Fort Hall</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>Fort Hall LI–ID–2</span></p></td><td><p>8,711.00</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>17. Standing Rock Sioux Tribe</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>Standing Rock</span></p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>Standing Rock LI–ND–10</span></p></td><td><p>10,255.50</p></td></tr><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p> </p></td><td><p class="leaders"><span>Standing Rock LI–SD–10</span></p></td><td><p>................</p></td></tr></tbody></table>
</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Publication in Federal Register of boundaries, etc.; estimation of acreages</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior shall cause to be published in the Federal Register the boundaries and descriptions of the lands conveyed by this chapter. The acreages set out in the preceding subsection are estimates and shall not be construed as expanding or limiting the grant of the United States as defined in <ref>section 5501 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 94–114, § 2</ref>, <date date="1975-10-17">Oct. 17, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 578</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–434, § 1(b)</ref>, <date date="1983-01-08">Jan. 8, 1983</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2280</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5503.</num>
<heading> Submarginal lands of United States held in trust for Stockbridge Munsee Indian Community</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All of the right, title, and interest of the United States in all the minerals including gas and oil underlying the submarginal lands declared to be held in trust for the Stockbridge Munsee Indian Community by the Act of <date date="1972-10-09">October 9, 1972</date> (<ref>86 Stat. 795</ref>), are hereby declared to be held by the United States in trust for the Stockbridge Munsee Indian Community.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 94–114, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="1975-10-17">Oct. 17, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 578</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5504.</num>
<heading> Existing rights of possession, contract, interest, etc.</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Preservation; force and effect of mineral leases; rejection of pending applications for leases and return of advance rental payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall deprive any person of any existing valid right of possession, contract right, interest, or title he may have in the land involved, or of any existing right of access to public domain lands over and across the land involved, as determined by the Secretary of the Interior. All existing mineral leases, including oil and gas leases, which may have been issued or approved pursuant to section 5 of the Mineral Leasing Act for Acquired Lands of <date date="1947-08-07">August 7, 1947</date> (<ref>61 Stat. 913</ref>, 915) [<ref>30 U.S.C. 354</ref>], or the Mineral Leasing Act of 1920 (<ref>41 Stat. 437</ref>) [<ref>30 U.S.C. 181</ref> et seq.], as amended prior to <date date="1975-10-17">October 17, 1975</date>, shall remain in force and effect in accordance with the provisions thereof. All applications for mineral leases, including oil and gas leases, pursuant to such Acts, pending on <date date="1975-10-17">October 17, 1975</date>, and covering any of the minerals conveyed by sections 5501 and 5503 of this title shall be rejected and the advance rental payments returned to the applicants.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administration of lands</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to the provisions of subsection (a) of this section, the property conveyed by this chapter shall hereafter be administered in accordance with the laws and regulations applicable to property held in trust by the United States for Indian tribes, including but not limited to sections 396a to 396g of this title.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 94–114, § 4</ref>, <date date="1975-10-17">Oct. 17, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 578</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5505.</num>
<heading> Gross receipts from conveyed lands</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deposit to credit of tribe; nonapplicability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any and all gross receipts derived from, or which relate to, the property conveyed by this chapter, the Act of <date date="1956-07-20">July 20, 1956</date> (<ref>70 Stat. 581</ref>), the Act of <date date="1956-08-02">August 2, 1956</date> (<ref>70 Stat. 941</ref>), the Act of <date date="1972-10-09">October 9, 1972</date> (<ref>86 Stat. 795</ref>), and <ref>section 1 of the Act of October 13, 1972</ref> (<ref>86 Stat. 806</ref>) which were received by the United States subsequent to its acquisition by the United States under the statutes cited in <ref>section 5501 of this title</ref> and prior to such conveyance, from whatever source and for whatever purpose, including but not limited to the receipts in the special fund of the Treasury as required by section 6 of the Mineral Leasing Act for Acquired Lands of <date date="1947-08-07">August 7, 1947</date> (<ref>61 Stat. 913</ref>, 915) [<ref>30 U.S.C. 355</ref>], shall as of <date date="1975-10-17">October 17, 1975</date>, be deposited to the credit of the Indian tribe receiving such land and may be expended by the tribe for such beneficial programs as the tribal governing body may determine: <i>Provided</i>, That this section shall not apply to any such receipts received prior to <date date="1975-10-17">October 17, 1975</date>, from the leasing of public domain minerals which were subject to the Mineral Leasing Act of 1920 (<ref>41 Stat. 437</ref>) [<ref>30 U.S.C. 181</ref> et seq.], as amended and supplemented.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administration of gross receipts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All gross receipts (including but not limited to bonuses, rents, and royalties) hereafter derived by the United States from any contract, permit or lease referred to in <ref>section 5504(a) of this title</ref>, or otherwise, shall be administered in accordance with the laws and regulations applicable to receipts from property held in trust by the United States for Indian tribes.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 94–114, § 5</ref>, <date date="1975-10-17">Oct. 17, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 579</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5506.</num>
<heading> Tax exemption for conveyed lands and gross receipts; distribution of gross receipts to tribal members</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All property conveyed to tribes pursuant to this chapter and all the receipts therefrom referred to in <ref>section 5505 of this title</ref>, shall be exempt from Federal, State, and local taxation so long as such property is held in trust by the United States. Any distribution of such receipts to tribal members shall neither be considered as income or resources of such members for purposes of any such taxation nor as income, resources, or otherwise utilized as the basis for denying or reducing the financial assistance or other benefits to which such member or his household would otherwise be entitled to under the Social Security Act [<ref>42 U.S.C. 301</ref> et seq.] or any other Federal or federally assisted program.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 94–114, § 6</ref>, <date date="1975-10-17">Oct. 17, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 579</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>