<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 16—</num>
<heading>DISTRIBUTION OF JUDGMENT FUNDS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1401.</num>
<heading> Funds appropriated in satisfaction of judgments of Indian Claims Commission or United States Court of Federal Claims</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use and distribution</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other law, all use or distribution of funds appropriated in satisfaction of a judgment of the Indian Claims Commission or the United States Court of Federal Claims in favor of any Indian tribe, band, group, pueblo, or community (hereinafter referred to as “Indian tribe”), together with any investment income earned thereon, after payment of attorney fees and litigation expenses, shall be made pursuant to the provisions of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amounts remaining to be held in trust unless otherwise provided</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as provided in sections 164 and 165 of this title, amounts which the Secretary of the Interior has remaining after execution of either a plan under this chapter, or another Act enacted heretofore or hereafter providing for the use or distribution of amounts awarded in satisfaction of a judgment in favor of an Indian tribe or tribes, together with any investment income earned thereon and after payment of attorney fees and litigation expenses, shall be held in trust by the Secretary for the tribe or tribes involved if the plan or Act does not otherwise provide for the use of such amounts.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Short title</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This chapter may be cited as the “Indian Tribal Judgment Funds Use or Distribution Act”.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–134, § 1</ref>, <date date="1973-10-19">Oct. 19, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 466</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–164, title I, § 160(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1982-04-02">Apr. 2, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 48</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–153, § 4</ref>, <date date="1987-11-05">Nov. 5, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 886</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–572, title IX, § 902(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4516</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1402.</num>
<heading> Plan for use or distribution of funds</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Preparation and submission to Congress by Secretary of the Interior; contents; copy to affected Indian tribe</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Within one year after appropriation of funds to pay a judgment of the Indian Claims Commission or the United States Court of Federal Claims to any Indian tribe, the Secretary of the Interior shall prepare and submit to Congress a plan for the use and distribution of the funds. Such plan shall include identification of the present-day beneficiaries, a formula for the division of the funds among two or more beneficiary entities if such is warranted, and a proposal for the use and distribution of the funds. The Secretary shall simultaneously submit a copy of such plan to each affected tribe or group.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Time for preparation and submission of plan</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">With respect to judgments, for which funds have been appropriated prior to <date date="1983-01-12">January 12, 1983</date>, but for which use or distribution has not been authorized by enactment of legislation or by an effective plan under this chapter, the Secretary shall prepare and submit such plans within one year of <date date="1983-01-12">January 12, 1983</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Submission of proposed legislation and report to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In any case where the Secretary determines that the circumstances do not permit the preparation and submission of a plan as provided in this chapter, he shall submit to the Congress within the one-year period proposed legislation to authorize use or distribution of such funds, together with a report thereon.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Submission of proposed legislation and report to Congress in absence of consent of tribal governments to division of judgment funds between two or more beneficiary entities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In cases where the Secretary has to submit a plan dividing judgment funds between two or more beneficiary entities, he shall obtain the consent of the tribal governments involved to the proposed division. If the Secretary cannot obtain such consent within one hundred and eighty days after appropriation of the funds for the award or within one hundred and eighty days of <date date="1983-01-12">January 12, 1983</date>, he shall submit proposed legislation to the Congress as provided in subsection (c).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Extension of time for preparation and submission of plan</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An extension of the one-year period, not to exceed one hundred and eighty days, may be requested by the Secretary or by the affected Indian tribe, submitting such request to the committees through the Secretary, and any such request will be subject to the approval of both the Senate Committee on Indian Affairs and the United States House of Representatives Committee on Natural Resources.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–134, § 2</ref>, <date date="1973-10-19">Oct. 19, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 466</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–164, title I, § 160(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1982-04-02">Apr. 2, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 48</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–458, § 1</ref>, <date date="1983-01-12">Jan. 12, 1983</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2512</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–572, title IX, § 902(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4516</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–437, § 10(e)(1)</ref>, (2)(A), <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4589</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1403.</num>
<heading> Preparation of plan</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prerequisites for final preparation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall prepare a plan which shall best serve the interests of all those entities and individuals entitled to receive funds of each Indian judgment. Prior to the final preparation of the plan, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> receive and consider any resolution or communication, together with any suggested use or distribution plan, which any affected Indian tribe may wish to submit to him; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> hold a hearing of record, after appropriate public notice, to obtain the testimony of leaders and members of the Indian tribe which may receive any portion, or be affected by the use or distribution, of such funds, in the area in which such Indian tribe is located and at a time which shall best serve the convenience of the eligible members thereof.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Guidelines</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In preparing a plan for the use or distribution of the funds of each Indian judgment, the Secretary shall, among other things, be assured that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> legal, financial, and other expertise of the Department of the Interior has been made fully available in an advisory capacity to the Indian tribe which is entitled to such funds to assist it to develop and communicate to the Secretary pursuant to clause (1) of subsection (a) of this section its own suggested plan for the distribution and use of such funds;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the needs and desires of any groups or individuals who are in a minority position, but who are also entitled to receive such funds, have been fully ascertained and considered;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the interests of minors and other legally incompetent persons who are entitled to receive any portion of such funds as are subsequently distributed to them are and will be protected and preserved; <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002024">1</ref> <i>Provided</i>, That such funds may be disbursed to the parents or legal guardian of such minors or legal incompetents in such amounts as may be necessary for the minor or legal incompetent’s health, education, welfare, or emergencies under a plan or plans approved by the Secretary and the tribal governing body of the Indian tribe involved.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002025">2</ref></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> any provision, including enrollment provisions, of the constitution, bylaws, rules, and procedures of such tribe which may affect the distribution or other use of such funds are in full accord with the principles of fairness and equity;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> a significant portion of such funds shall be set aside and programed to serve common tribal needs, educational requirements, and such other purposes as the circumstances of the affected Indian tribe may justify, except not less than 20 per centum of such funds shall be so set aside and programed unless the Secretary determines that the particular circumstances of the pertinent Indian tribe clearly warrant otherwise: <i>Provided</i>, That in the development of such plan the Secretary shall survey past and present plans of the tribe for economic development, shall consider long range benefits which might accrue to the tribe from such plans, and shall encourage programing of funds for economic development purposes where appropriate; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> methods exist and will be employed to insure the proper performance of the plan once it becomes effective under <ref>section 1405 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–134, § 3</ref>, <date date="1973-10-19">Oct. 19, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 467</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–458, § 2</ref>, <date date="1983-01-12">Jan. 12, 1983</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2512</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1404.</num>
<heading> Hearing transcripts and tribal support statements; submission to Congress with plan</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">When submitting the plan as provided in <ref>section 1402 of this title</ref>, the Secretary shall also submit to the Congress with such plan—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> copies of the transcripts of hearings held by him concerning the Indian judgment pursuant to clause (2) of <ref>section 1403(a) of this title</ref> and all other papers and documents considered by him in the preparation of such plan, including any resolution, communication, or suggested use or distribution plan of the pertinent Indian tribe submitted pursuant to clause (1) of <ref>section 1403(a) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a statement of the extent to which such plan reflects the desires of the Indian tribe or individuals who are entitled to such funds, which statement shall specify the alternatives, if any, proposed by such Indian tribe or individuals in lieu of such plan, together with an indication of the degree of support among the interested parties for each such alternative.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–134, § 4</ref>, <date date="1973-10-19">Oct. 19, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 467</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1405.</num>
<heading> Effective date of plan; joint resolution of disapproval</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Original plan</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The plan prepared by the Secretary shall become effective, and he shall take immediate action to implement the plan for the use or distribution of such judgment funds, at the end of the sixty-day period (excluding days on which either the House of Representatives or the Senate is not in session because of an adjournment of more than three calendar days to a day certain) beginning on the day such plan is submitted to the Congress, unless during such sixty-day period a joint resolution is enacted disapproving such plans.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Proposed legislation and report to Congress following Congressional disapproval</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Within thirty calendar days after the date of enactment of a joint resolution disapproving a plan, the Secretary shall submit to the Congress proposed legislation, together with a report thereon, authorizing use or distribution of such funds.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Successor plan previously withdrawn or amended prior to Congressional action; consent to amendments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Within the sixty-day period and before the adoption of any resolution disapproving a plan, the Secretary may withdraw or amend such plan: <i>Provided</i>, That any amendments affecting the division of an award between two or more beneficiary entities shall be subject to the consent of these entities as provided in <ref>section 1402(d) of this title</ref>. Any such amended plan shall become valid at the end of a sixty-day period beginning on the day such amendment is submitted to the Congress, unless during such sixty-day period, a joint resolution is enacted disapproving such plan as amended.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Resubmission of successor plan within prescribed period following withdrawal of plan</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Once a plan is withdrawn before the end of a sixty-day period, the Secretary has until the expiration of the original one-year deadline to resubmit a plan to Congress. Such a plan shall become valid at the end of a sixty-day period beginning on the day such new plan is submitted to the Congress, unless during such sixty-day period, a joint resolution is enacted disapproving such plan.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recomputation of sixty-day period from date of introduction of joint resolution of disapproval; reextension restriction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon the introduction of the first such resolution of disapproval in either the House of Representatives or the Senate, the sixty-day period shall be recomputed from the date of such introduction and shall not again be extended.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–134, § 5</ref>, <date date="1973-10-19">Oct. 19, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 468</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–458, § 3</ref>, <date date="1983-01-12">Jan. 12, 1983</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2513</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1406.</num>
<heading> Rules and regulations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Promulgation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall promulgate rules and regulations to implement this chapter no later than the end of the one hundred and eighty-day period beginning on <date date="1973-10-19">October 19, 1973</date>. Among other things, such rules and regulations shall provide for adequate notice to all entities and persons who may receive funds under any Indian judgment of all relevant procedures pursuant to this chapter concerning any such judgment.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Publication in Federal Register</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No later than sixty days prior to the promulgation of such rules and regulations the Secretary shall publish the proposed rules and regulations in the Federal Register.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Hearings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No later than thirty days prior to the promulgation of such rules and regulations, the Secretary shall provide, with adequate public notice, the opportunity for hearings on the proposed rules and regulations, once published, to all interested parties.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–134, § 6</ref>, <date date="1973-10-19">Oct. 19, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 468</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1407.</num>
<heading> Tax exemption; resources exemption limitation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">None of the funds which—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> are distributed per capita or held in trust pursuant to a plan approved under the provisions of this chapter, or <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002026">1</ref></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> on <date date="1983-01-12">January 12, 1983</date>, are to be distributed per capita or are held in trust pursuant to a plan approved by the Congress prior to <date date="1983-01-12">January 12, 1983</date>,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> were distributed pursuant to a plan approved by Congress after <date date="1981-12-31">December 31, 1981</date> but prior to <date date="1983-01-12">January 12, 1983</date>, and any purchases made with such funds, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> are paid by the State of Minnesota to the Bois Forte Band of Chippewa Indians or the Grand Portage Band of Lake Superior Chippewa Indians, or both, pursuant to the agreements of each Band to voluntarily restrict tribal rights to hunt and fish in territory cede <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002027">2</ref> under the Treaty of <date date="1854-09-30">September 30, 1854</date> (<ref>10 Stat. 1109</ref>), including all interest accrued on such funds during any period in which such funds are held in a minor’s trust,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">including all interest and investment income accrued thereon while such funds are so held in trust, shall be subject to Federal or State income taxes, nor shall such funds nor their availability be considered as income or resources nor otherwise utilized as the basis for denying or reducing the financial assistance or other benefits to which such household or member would otherwise be entitled under the Social Security Act [<ref>42 U.S.C. 301</ref> et seq.] or, except for per capita shares in excess of $2,000, any Federal or federally assisted program.</continuation>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–134, § 7</ref>, <date date="1973-10-19">Oct. 19, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 468</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–458, § 4</ref>, <date date="1983-01-12">Jan. 12, 1983</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2513</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–568, title VIII, § 818</ref>, <date date="2000-12-27">Dec. 27, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2918</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–290, § 2</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3291</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1408.</num>
<heading> Resources exemption</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Interests of individual Indians in trust or restricted lands shall not be considered a resource, and up to $2,000 per year of income received by individual Indians that is derived from such interests shall not be considered income, in determining eligibility for assistance under the Social Security Act [<ref>42 U.S.C. 301</ref> et seq.] or any other Federal or federally assisted program.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–134, § 8</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 97–458, § 4</ref>, <date date="1983-01-12">Jan. 12, 1983</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2514</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–66, title XIII, § 13736(a)</ref>, <date date="1993-08-10">Aug. 10, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 663</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>