<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 44—</num>
<heading>NATIVE AMERICAN BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT, TRADE PROMOTION, AND TOURISM</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4301.</num>
<heading> Findings; purposes</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Congress finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> clause 3 of section 8 of article I of the United States Constitution recognizes the special relationship between the United States and Indian Tribes;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> beginning in 1970, with the inauguration by the Nixon Administration of the Indian self-determination era, each President has reaffirmed the special government-to-government relationship between Indian Tribes and the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> in 1994, President Clinton issued an Executive memorandum to the heads of departments and agencies that obligated all Federal departments and agencies, particularly those that have an impact on economic development, to evaluate the potential impacts of their actions on Indian Tribes;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> consistent with the principles of inherent Tribal sovereignty and the special relationship between Indian Tribes and the United States, Indian Tribes retain the right to enter into contracts and agreements to trade freely, and seek enforcement of treaty and trade rights;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Congress has carried out the responsibility of the United States for the protection and preservation of Indian Tribes and the resources of Indian Tribes through the endorsement of treaties, and the enactment of other laws, including laws that provide for the exercise of administrative authorities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the United States has an obligation to guard and preserve the sovereignty of Indian Tribes in order to foster strong Tribal governments, Indian self-determination, and economic self-sufficiency among Indian Tribes;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the capacity of Indian Tribes to build strong Tribal governments and vigorous economies is hindered by the inability of Indian Tribes to engage communities that surround Indian lands and outside investors in economic activities on Indian lands;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> despite the availability of abundant natural resources on Indian lands and a rich cultural legacy that accords great value to self-determination, self-reliance, and independence, Native Americans suffer higher rates of unemployment, poverty, poor health, substandard housing, and associated social ills than those of any other group in the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<chapeau> the United States has an obligation to assist Indian Tribes with the creation of appropriate economic and political conditions with respect to Indian lands to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> encourage investment from outside sources that do not originate with the Tribes; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> facilitate economic ventures with outside entities that are not Tribal entities;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> the economic success and material well-being of Native American communities depends on the combined efforts of the Federal Government, Tribal governments, the private sector, and individuals;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<chapeau> the lack of employment and entrepreneurial opportunities in the communities referred to in paragraph (7) has resulted in a multigenerational dependence on Federal assistance that is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> insufficient to address the magnitude of needs; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> unreliable in availability; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<chapeau> the twin goals of economic self-sufficiency and political self-determination for Native Americans can best be served by making available to address the challenges faced by those groups—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the resources of the private market;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> adequate capital; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> technical expertise.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes of this chapter are as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> To revitalize economically and physically distressed Native American economies by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> encouraging the formation of new businesses by eligible entities, and the expansion of existing businesses; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> facilitating the movement of goods to and from Indian lands and the provision of services by Indians.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> To promote private investment in the economies of Indian Tribes and to encourage the sustainable development of resources of Indian Tribes and Indian-owned businesses.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> To promote the long-range sustained growth of the economies of Indian Tribes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> To raise incomes of Indians in order to reduce the number of Indians at poverty levels and provide the means for achieving a higher standard of living on Indian reservations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> To encourage intertribal, regional, and international trade and business development in order to assist in increasing productivity and the standard of living of members of Indian Tribes and improving the economic self-sufficiency of the governing bodies of Indian Tribes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> To promote economic self-sufficiency and political self-determination for Indian Tribes and members of Indian Tribes.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability to Indian-Owned Businesses</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The findings and purposes in subsections (a) and (b) shall apply to any Indian-owned business governed—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> by Tribal laws regulating trade or commerce on Indian lands; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> pursuant to <ref>section 261 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–464, § 2</ref>, <date date="2000-11-07">Nov. 7, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2012</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–261, § 3(a)</ref>, (e)(2), (3), <date date="2020-12-30">Dec. 30, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3307</ref>, 3311.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4302.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Director</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Director” means the Director of Native American Business Development appointed pursuant to <ref>section 4303(a)(2) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible entity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “eligible entity” means an Indian Tribe or Tribal organization, an Indian arts and crafts organization, as that term is defined in <ref>section 305a of this title</ref>, a Tribal enterprise, a Tribal marketing cooperative (as that term is defined by the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior), or any other Indian-owned business.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Indian</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Indian” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 5304(d) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Indian goods and services</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “Indian goods and services” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Indian goods, within the meaning of <ref>section 305a of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> goods produced or originated by an eligible entity; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> services provided by eligible entities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Indian lands</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “Indian lands” includes lands under the definition of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the term “Indian country” under <ref>section 1151 of title 18</ref>; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> the term “reservation” under—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content><ref>section 1452(d) of this title</ref>; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content><ref>section 1903(10) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Former Indian reservations in Oklahoma</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">For purposes of applying <ref>section 1452(d) of this title</ref> under subparagraph (A)(ii), the term “former Indian reservations in Oklahoma” shall be construed to include lands that are—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> within the jurisdictional areas of an Oklahoma Indian Tribe (as determined by the Secretary of the Interior); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> recognized by the Secretary of the Interior as eligible for trust land status under part 151 of title 25, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on <date date="2000-11-07">November 7, 2000</date>).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Indian-owned business</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Indian-owned business” means an entity organized for the conduct of trade or commerce with respect to which at least 50 percent of the property interests of the entity are owned by Indians or Indian Tribes (or a combination thereof).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Indian Tribe</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Indian Tribe” has the meaning given the term “Indian tribe” in <ref>section 5304(e) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Office</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Office” means the Office of Native American Business Development established by <ref>section 4303(a)(1) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Commerce.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(10)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tribal enterprise</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Tribal enterprise” means a commercial activity or business managed or controlled by an Indian Tribe.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(11)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tribal organization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Tribal organization” has the meaning given that term in section 5304(<i>l</i>) of this title.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–464, § 3</ref>, <date date="2000-11-07">Nov. 7, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2013</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–261, § 3(b)</ref>, (e), <date date="2020-12-30">Dec. 30, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3307</ref>, 3311.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4303.</num>
<heading> Office of Native American Business Development</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is established within the Office of the Secretary an office known as the Office of Native American Business Development.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Director</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Office shall be headed by a Director, appointed by the Secretary, whose title shall be the Director of Native American Business Development. The Director shall be compensated at a rate not to exceed level V of the Executive Schedule under <ref>section 5316 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties of the Secretary</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary, acting through the Director, shall ensure the coordination of Federal programs that provide assistance, including financial and technical assistance, to eligible entities for increased business, the expansion of trade by eligible entities, and economic development on Indian lands.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interagency coordination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary, acting through the Director, shall coordinate Federal programs relating to Indian economic development, including any such program of the Department of the Interior, the Small Business Administration, the Department of Labor, or any other Federal agency charged with Indian economic development responsibilities.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Activities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In carrying out the duties described in paragraph (1), the Secretary, acting through the Director, shall ensure the coordination of, or, as appropriate, carry out—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Federal programs designed to provide legal, accounting, or financial assistance to eligible entities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> market surveys;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the development of promotional materials;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the financing of business development seminars;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the facilitation of marketing;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the participation of appropriate Federal agencies or eligible entities in trade fairs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> any activity that is not described in subparagraphs (A) through (F) that is related to the development of appropriate markets; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> any other activity that the Secretary, in consultation with the Director, determines to be appropriate to carry out this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In conjunction with the activities described in paragraph (3), the Secretary, acting through the Director, shall provide—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> financial assistance, technical assistance, and administrative services to eligible entities to assist those entities with—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> identifying and taking advantage of business development opportunities; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> compliance with appropriate laws and regulatory practices; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> such other assistance as the Secretary, in consultation with the Director, determines to be necessary for the development of business opportunities for eligible entities to enhance the economies of Indian Tribes.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Priorities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In carrying out the duties and activities described in paragraphs (3) and (4), the Secretary, acting through the Director, shall give priority to activities that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> provide the greatest degree of economic benefits to Indians; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> foster long-term stable economies of Indian Tribes.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may not provide under this section assistance for any activity related to the operation of a gaming activity on Indian lands pursuant to the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act [<ref>25 U.S.C. 2701</ref> et seq.].</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties of Director</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Director shall serve as—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the program and policy advisor to the Secretary with respect to the trust and governmental relationship between the United States and Indian Tribes; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> the point of contact for Indian Tribes, Tribal organizations, and Indians regarding—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> policies and programs of the Department of Commerce; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> other matters relating to economic development and doing business in Indian lands.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Departmental coordination</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Director shall coordinate with all offices and agencies within the Department of Commerce to ensure that each office and agency has an accountable process to ensure—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> meaningful and timely coordination and assistance, as required by this chapter; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> consultation with Indian Tribes regarding the policies, programs, assistance, and activities of the offices and agencies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Office operations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section not more than $2,000,000 for each fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–464, § 4</ref>, <date date="2000-11-07">Nov. 7, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2015</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–261, § 3(c)</ref>, (e)(2), <date date="2020-12-30">Dec. 30, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3308</ref>, 3311.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4304.</num>
<heading> Native American trade and export promotion</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary, acting through the Director, shall carry out a Native American export and trade promotion program (referred to in this section as the “program”).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination of Federal programs and services</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In carrying out the program, the Secretary, acting through the Director, and in cooperation with the heads of appropriate Federal agencies, shall ensure the coordination of Federal programs and services designed to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> develop the economies of Indian Tribes; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> stimulate the demand for Indian goods and services that are available from eligible entities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Activities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In carrying out the duties described in subsection (b), the Secretary, acting through the Director, shall ensure the coordination of, or, as appropriate, carry out—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Federal programs designed to provide technical or financial assistance to eligible entities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the development of promotional materials;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the financing of appropriate trade missions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the marketing of Indian goods and services;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the participation of appropriate Federal agencies or eligible entities in international trade fairs; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> any other activity related to the development of markets for Indian goods and services.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Technical assistance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In conjunction with the activities described in subsection (c), the Secretary, acting through the Director, shall provide technical assistance and administrative services to eligible entities to assist those entities with—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the identification of appropriate markets for Indian goods and services;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> entering the markets referred to in paragraph (1);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> compliance with foreign or domestic laws and practices with respect to financial institutions with respect to the export and import of Indian goods and services; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> entering into financial arrangements to provide for the export and import of Indian goods and services.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Priorities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In carrying out the duties and activities described in subsections (b) and (c), the Secretary, acting through the Director, shall give priority to activities that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provide the greatest degree of economic benefits to Indians; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> foster long-term stable international markets for Indian goods and services.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–464, § 5</ref>, <date date="2000-11-07">Nov. 7, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2016</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–261, § 3(e)(2)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-30">Dec. 30, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3311</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4305.</num>
<heading> Intertribal tourism demonstration projects</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program to conduct tourism projects</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary, acting through the Director, shall conduct a Native American tourism program to facilitate the development and conduct of tourism demonstration projects by Indian Tribes, on a Tribal, intertribal, or regional basis.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Demonstration projects</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Under the program established under this section, in order to assist in the development and promotion of tourism on and in the vicinity of Indian lands, the Secretary, acting through the Director, shall, in coordination with the Under Secretary of Agriculture for Rural Development, assist eligible entities in the planning, development, and implementation of tourism development demonstration projects that meet the criteria described in subparagraph (B).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Projects described</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In selecting tourism development demonstration projects under this section, the Secretary, acting through the Director, shall select projects that have the potential to increase travel and tourism revenues by attracting visitors to Indian lands and lands in the vicinity of Indian lands, including projects that provide for—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the development and distribution of educational and promotional materials pertaining to attractions located on and near Indian lands;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the development of educational resources to assist in private and public tourism development on and in the vicinity of Indian lands; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the coordination of tourism-related joint ventures and cooperative efforts between eligible entities and appropriate State and local governments that have jurisdiction over areas in the vicinity of Indian lands.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grants</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To carry out the program under this section, the Secretary, acting through the Director, may award grants or enter into other appropriate arrangements with Indian Tribes, Tribal organizations, intertribal consortia, or other Tribal entities that the Secretary, in consultation with the Director, determines to be appropriate.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Locations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In providing for tourism development demonstration projects under the program under this section, the Secretary, acting through the Director, shall provide for a demonstration project to be conducted—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> for Indians of the Four Corners area located in the area adjacent to the border between Arizona, Utah, Colorado, and New Mexico;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for Indians of the northwestern area that is commonly known as the Great Northwest (as determined by the Secretary);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> for the Oklahoma Indians in Oklahoma;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> for the Indians of the Great Plains area (as determined by the Secretary); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> for Alaska Natives in Alaska.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary, acting through the Director, shall provide financial assistance, technical assistance, and administrative services to participants that the Secretary, acting through the Director, selects to carry out a tourism development project under this section, with respect to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> feasibility studies conducted as part of that project;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> market analyses;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> participation in tourism and trade missions; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> any other activity that the Secretary, in consultation with the Director, determines to be appropriate to carry out this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Infrastructure development</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The demonstration projects conducted under this section shall include provisions to facilitate the development and financing of infrastructure, including the development of Indian reservation roads in a manner consistent with title 23.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–464, § 6</ref>, <date date="2000-11-07">Nov. 7, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2016</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–261, § 3(e)(2)</ref>, (3), <date date="2020-12-30">Dec. 30, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3311</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4306.</num>
<heading> Report to Congress</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2000-11-07">November 7, 2000</date>, and annually thereafter, the Secretary, in consultation with the Director, shall prepare and submit to the Committee on Indian Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Resources of the House of Representatives a report on the operation of the Office.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents of report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each report prepared under subsection (a) shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> for the period covered by the report, a summary of the activities conducted by the Secretary, acting through the Director, in carrying out sections 4303 through 4305 of this title; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any recommendations for legislation that the Secretary, in consultation with the Director, determines to be necessary to carry out sections 4303 through 4305 of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–464, § 7</ref>, <date date="2000-11-07">Nov. 7, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2018</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4306a.</num>
<heading> Indian community development initiatives</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interagency coordination</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2020-12-30">December 30, 2020</date>, the Secretary, the Secretary of the Interior, and the Secretary of the Treasury shall coordinate—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> to develop initiatives that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> encourage, promote, and provide education regarding investments in Indian communities through—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the loan guarantee program of Bureau of Indian Affairs under <ref>section 1481 of this title</ref>;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> programs carried out using amounts in the Community Development Financial Institutions Fund established under <ref>section 4703(a) of title 12</ref>; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> other capital development programs;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> examine and develop alternatives that would qualify as collateral for financing in Indian communities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> provide entrepreneur and other training relating to economic development through tribally controlled colleges and universities and other Indian organizations with experience in providing such training;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to consult with Indian Tribes and with the Securities and Exchange Commission to study, and collaborate to establish, regulatory changes necessary to qualify an Indian Tribe as an accredited investor for the purposes of sections 230.500 through 230.508 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations), consistent with the goals of promoting capital formation and ensuring qualifying Indian Tribes have the ability to withstand investment loss, on a basis comparable to other legal entities that qualify as accredited investors who are not natural persons;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to identify regulatory, legal, or other barriers to increasing investment, business, and economic development, including qualifying or approving collateral structures, measurements of economic strength, and contributions of Indian economies in Indian communities through the Authority established under section 4 of the Indian Tribal Regulatory Reform and Business Development Act of 2000 (<ref>25 U.S.C. 4301</ref> note);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to ensure consultation with Indian Tribes regarding increasing investment in Indian communities and the development of the report required in paragraph (5); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> not less than once every 2 years, to provide a report to Congress regarding—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> improvements to Indian communities resulting from such initiatives and recommendations for promoting sustained growth of the Tribal economies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> results of the study and collaboration regarding the necessary changes referenced in paragraph (2) and the impact of allowing Indian Tribes to qualify as an accredited investor; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the identified regulatory, legal, and other barriers referenced in paragraph (3).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Waiver</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For assistance provided pursuant to <ref>section 4707 of title 12</ref> to benefit Native Community Development Financial Institutions, as defined by the Secretary of the Treasury, section 4707(e) of such title shall not apply.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Indian Economic Development Feasibility Study</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Government Accountability Office shall conduct a study and, not later than 18 months after <date date="2020-12-30">December 30, 2020</date>, submit to the Committee on Indian Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives a report on the findings of the study and recommendations.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The study shall include an assessment of each of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The study shall assess current Federal capitalization and related programs and services that are available to assist Indian communities with business and economic development, including manufacturing, physical infrastructure (such as telecommunications and broadband), community development, and facilities construction for such purposes. For each of the Federal programs and services identified, the study shall assess the current use and demand by Indian Tribes, individuals, businesses, and communities of the programs, the capital needs of Indian Tribes, businesses, and communities related to economic development, the extent to which the programs and services overlap or are duplicative, and the extent that similar programs have been used to assist non-Indian communities compared to the extent used for Indian communities.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Financing assistance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The study shall assess and quantify the extent of assistance provided to non-Indian borrowers and to Indian (both Tribal and individual) borrowers (including information about such assistance as a percentage of need for Indian borrowers and for non-Indian borrowers, assistance to Indian borrowers and to non-Indian borrowers as a percentage of total applicants, and such assistance to Indian borrowers as individuals as compared to such assistance to Indian Tribes) through the loan programs, the loan guarantee programs, or bond guarantee programs of the—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Department of the Interior;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Department of Agriculture;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Department of Housing and Urban Development;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> Department of Energy;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> Small Business Administration; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> Community Development Financial Institutions Fund of the Department of the Treasury.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tax incentives</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The study shall assess and quantify the extent of the assistance and allocations afforded for non-Indian projects and for Indian projects pursuant to each of the following tax incentive programs:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> New market tax credit.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Low income housing tax credit.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Investment tax credit.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> Renewable energy tax incentives.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> Accelerated depreciation.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tribal investment incentive</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The study shall assess various alternative incentives that could be provided to enable and encourage Tribal governments to invest in an Indian community development investment fund or bank.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–464, § 8</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 116–261, § 3(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-30">Dec. 30, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3308</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4307.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as are necessary to carry out this chapter, to remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–464, § 10</ref>, formerly § 8, <date date="2000-11-07">Nov. 7, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2018</ref>; renumbered § 10, <ref>Pub. L. 116–261, § 3(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-30">Dec. 30, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3308</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>