<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 49—</num>
<heading>SAVANNA’S ACT</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5701.</num>
<heading> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes of this chapter are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to clarify the responsibilities of Federal, State, Tribal, and local law enforcement agencies with respect to responding to cases of missing or murdered Indians;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to increase coordination and communication among Federal, State, Tribal, and local law enforcement agencies, including medical examiner and coroner offices;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to empower Tribal governments with the resources and information necessary to effectively respond to cases of missing or murdered Indians; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to increase the collection of data related to missing or murdered Indian men, women, and children, regardless of where they reside, and the sharing of information among Federal, State, and Tribal officials responsible for responding to and investigating cases of missing or murdered Indians.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–165, § 2</ref>, <date date="2020-10-10">Oct. 10, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 760</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5702.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Confer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “confer” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 1660d of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Databases</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “databases” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the National Crime Information Center database;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Combined DNA Index System;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Next Generation Identification System; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> any other database relevant to responding to cases of missing or murdered Indians, including that under the Violent Criminal Apprehension Program and the National Missing and Unidentified Persons System.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Indian</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Indian” means a member of an Indian Tribe.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Indian country</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Indian country” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 1151 of title 18</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Indian land</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Indian land” means Indian lands, as defined in <ref>section 4302 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Indian Tribe</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Indian Tribe” has the meaning given the term “Indian tribe” in <ref>section 5304 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Law enforcement agency</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “law enforcement agency” means a Tribal, Federal, State, or local law enforcement agency.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–165, § 3</ref>, <date date="2020-10-10">Oct. 10, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 760</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5703.</num>
<heading> Improving Tribal access to databases</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tribal Enrollment Information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Attorney General shall provide training to law enforcement agencies regarding how to record the Tribal enrollment information or affiliation, as appropriate, of a victim in Federal databases.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2020-10-10">October 10, 2020</date>, the Attorney General, in cooperation with the Secretary of the Interior, shall complete a formal consultation with Indian Tribes on how to further improve Tribal data relevance and access to databases.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initial confer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2020-10-10">October 10, 2020</date>, the Attorney General, in coordination with the Secretary of the Interior, shall confer with Tribal organizations and urban Indian organizations on how to further improve American Indian and Alaska Native data relevance and access to databases.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2020-10-10">October 10, 2020</date>, the Attorney General shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> develop and implement a dissemination strategy to educate the public of the National Missing and Unidentified Persons System; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> conduct specific outreach to Indian Tribes, Tribal organizations, and urban Indian organizations regarding the ability to publicly enter information, through the National Missing and Unidentified Persons System or other non-law enforcement sensitive portal, regarding missing persons, which may include family members and other known acquaintances.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–165, § 4</ref>, <date date="2020-10-10">Oct. 10, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 761</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5704.</num>
<heading> Guidelines for responding to cases of missing or murdered Indians</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 60 days after the date on which the consultation described in <ref>section 5703(b)(1) of this title</ref> is completed, the Attorney General shall direct United States attorneys to develop regionally appropriate guidelines to respond to cases of missing or murdered Indians that shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> guidelines on inter-jurisdictional cooperation among law enforcement agencies at the Tribal, Federal, State, and local levels, including inter-jurisdictional enforcement of protection orders and detailing specific responsibilities of each law enforcement agency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> best practices in conducting searches for missing persons on and off Indian land;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> standards on the collection, reporting, and analysis of data and information on missing persons and unidentified human remains, and information on culturally appropriate identification and handling of human remains identified as Indian, including guidance stating that all appropriate information related to missing or murdered Indians be entered in a timely manner into applicable databases;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> guidance on which law enforcement agency is responsible for inputting information into appropriate databases under paragraph (3) if the Tribal law enforcement agency does not have access to those appropriate databases;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> guidelines on improving law enforcement agency response rates and follow-up responses to cases of missing or murdered Indians; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> guidelines on ensuring access to culturally appropriate victim services for victims and their families.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">United States attorneys shall develop the guidelines required under subsection (a) in consultation with Indian Tribes and other relevant partners, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Department of Justice;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Federal Bureau of Investigation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the Department of the Interior;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the Bureau of Indian Affairs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Tribal, State, and local law enforcement agencies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> medical examiners;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> coroners;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Tribal, State, and local organizations that provide victim services; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> national, regional, or urban Indian organizations with relevant expertise.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compliance</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2020-10-10">October 10, 2020</date>, the United States attorneys shall implement, by incorporating into office policies and procedures, the guidelines developed under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Modification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Each Federal law enforcement agency shall modify the guidelines, policies, and protocols of the agency to incorporate the guidelines developed under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than the end of each fiscal year beginning after the date the guidelines are established under this section and incorporated under this subsection, upon the request of a Tribal, State, or local law enforcement agency, the Attorney General shall determine whether the Tribal, State, or local law enforcement agency seeking recognition of compliance has incorporated guidelines into their respective guidelines, policies, and protocols.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Accountability</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 30 days after compliance determinations are made each fiscal year in accordance with subsection (c)(3), the Attorney General shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> disclose and publish, including on the website of the Department of Justice, the name of each Tribal, State, or local law enforcement agency that the Attorney General has determined has incorporated guidelines in accordance with subsection (c)(3);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> disclose and publish, including on the website of the Department of Justice, the name of each Tribal, State, or local law enforcement agency that has requested a determination in accordance with subsection (c)(3) that is pending;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> collect the guidelines into a resource of examples and best practices that can be used by other law enforcement agencies seeking to create and implement such guidelines.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Training and technical assistance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Attorney General shall use the National Indian Country Training Initiative to provide training and technical assistance to Indian Tribes and law enforcement agencies on—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> implementing the guidelines developed under subsection (a) or developing and implementing locally specific guidelines or protocols for responding to cases of missing or murdered Indians; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> using the National Missing and Unidentified Persons System and accessing program services that will assist Indian Tribes with responding to cases of missing or murdered Indians.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Guidelines from Indian Tribes</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Indian Tribes may submit their own guidelines to respond to cases of missing or murdered Indians to the Attorney General.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Publication</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Upon receipt of any guidelines from an Indian Tribe, the Attorney General shall publish the guidelines on the website of the Department of Justice in 1 centralized location to make the guidelines available as a resource to any Federal agency, State, or Tribal government.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–165, § 5</ref>, <date date="2020-10-10">Oct. 10, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 762</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5705.</num>
<heading> Annual reporting requirements</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual reporting</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Beginning in the first fiscal year after <date date="2020-10-10">October 10, 2020</date>, the Attorney General shall include in its annual Indian Country Investigations and Prosecutions report to Congress information that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> includes known statistics on missing Indians in the United States, available to the Department of Justice, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> age;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> gender;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Tribal enrollment information or affiliation, if available;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the current number of open cases per State;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the total number of closed cases per State each calendar year, from the most recent 10 calendar years; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> other relevant information the Attorney General determines is appropriate;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> includes known statistics on murdered Indians in the United States, available to the Department of Justice, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> age;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> gender;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Tribal enrollment information or affiliation, if available;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the current number of open cases per State;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the total number of closed cases per State each calendar year, from the most recent 10 calendar years; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> other relevant information the Attorney General determines is appropriate;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> maintains victim privacy to the greatest extent possible by excluding information that can be used on its own or with other information to identify, contact, or locate a single person, or to identify an individual in context; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an explanation of why the statistics described in paragraph (1) may not be comprehensive; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> recommendations on how data collection on missing or murdered Indians may be improved.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compliance</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Beginning in the first fiscal year after <date date="2020-10-10">October 10, 2020</date>, and annually thereafter, for the purpose of compiling accurate data for the annual report required under subsection (a), the Attorney General shall request all Tribal, State, and local law enforcement agencies to submit to the Department of Justice, to the fullest extent possible, all relevant information pertaining to missing or murdered Indians collected by the Tribal, State, and local law enforcement agency, and in a format provided by the Department of Justice that ensures the streamlining of data reporting.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disclosure</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Attorney General shall disclose and publish annually, including on the website of the Department of Justice, the name of each Tribal, State, or local law enforcement agency that the Attorney General has determined has submitted the information requested under paragraph (1) for the fiscal year in which the report was published.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inclusion of gender in missing and unidentified persons statistics</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Beginning in the first calendar year after <date date="2020-10-10">October 10, 2020</date>, and annually thereafter, the Federal Bureau of Investigation shall include gender in its annual statistics on missing and unidentified persons published on its public website.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–165, § 6</ref>, <date date="2020-10-10">Oct. 10, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 763</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>