<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 13—</num>
<heading>APPROPRIATIONS</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>GENERAL</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1301.</num>
<heading> Application</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Appropriations shall be applied only to the objects for which the appropriations were made except as otherwise provided by law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The reappropriation and diversion of the unexpended balance of an appropriation for a purpose other than that for which the appropriation originally was made shall be construed and accounted for as a new appropriation. The unexpended balance shall be reduced by the amount to be diverted.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> An appropriation in a regular, annual appropriation law may be construed to be permanent or available continuously only if the appropriation—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> is for rivers and harbors, lighthouses, public buildings, or the pay of the Navy and Marine Corps; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> expressly provides that it is available after the fiscal year covered by the law in which it appears.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> A law may be construed to make an appropriation out of the Treasury or to authorize making a contract for the payment of money in excess of an appropriation only if the law specifically states that an appropriation is made or that such a contract may be made.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 917</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1302.</num>
<heading> Determining amounts appropriated</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as specifically provided by law, the total amount appropriated in an appropriation law is determined by adding up the specific amounts or rates appropriated in each paragraph of the law.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 917</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1303.</num>
<heading> Effect of changes in titles of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Expenditures for a particular object or purpose authorized by a law (and referred to in that law by the specific title previously used for the appropriation item in the appropriation law concerned) may be made from a corresponding appropriation item when the specific title is changed or eliminated from a later appropriation law.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 917</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1304.</num>
<heading> Judgments, awards, and compromise settlements</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Necessary amounts are appropriated to pay final judgments, awards, compromise settlements, and interest and costs specified in the judgments or otherwise authorized by law when—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> payment is not otherwise provided for;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> payment is certified by the Secretary of the Treasury; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> the judgment, award, or settlement is payable—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> under section 2414, 2517, 2672, or 2677 of title 28;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> under <ref>section 3723 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> under a decision of a board of contract appeals; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> in excess of an amount payable from the appropriations of an agency for a meritorious claim under section 2733, 2733a, or 2734 of title 10, <ref>section 715 of title 32</ref>, or <ref>section 20113 of title 51</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Interest may be paid from the appropriation made by this section—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> on a judgment of a district court, only when the judgment becomes final after review on appeal or petition by the United States Government, and then only from the date of filing of the transcript of the judgment with the Secretary of the Treasury through the day before the date of the mandate of affirmance; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> on a judgment of the Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit or the United States Court of Federal Claims under <ref>section 2516(b) of title 28</ref>, only from the date of filing of the transcript of the judgment with the Secretary of the Treasury through the day before the date of the mandate of affirmance.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Interest payable under this subsection in a proceeding reviewed by the Supreme Court is not allowed after the end of the term in which the judgment is affirmed.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> A judgment or compromise settlement against the Government shall be paid under this section and sections 2414, 2517, and 2518 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002032">1</ref> of title 28 when the judgment or settlement arises out of an express or implied contract made by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Army and Air Force Exchange Service;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Navy Exchanges;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Marine Corps Exchanges;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Coast Guard Exchanges; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the Exchange Councils of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Exchange making the contract shall reimburse the Government for the amount paid by the Government.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> Beginning not later than the date that is 60 days after the date of enactment of the John D. Dingell, Jr. Conservation, Management, and Recreation Act, and unless the disclosure of such information is otherwise prohibited by law or a court order, the Secretary of the Treasury shall make available to the public on a website, as soon as practicable, but not later than 30 days after the date on which a payment under this section is tendered, the following information with regard to that payment:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The name of the specific agency or entity whose actions gave rise to the claim or judgment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The name of the plaintiff or claimant.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The name of counsel for the plaintiff or claimant.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The amount paid representing principal liability, and any amounts paid representing any ancillary liability, including attorney fees, costs, and interest.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> A brief description of the facts that gave rise to the claim.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The name of the agency that submitted the claim.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, §§ 1, 2(m)(2), <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 917</ref>, 1062; <ref>Pub. L. 102–572, title IX, § 902(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4516</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–316, title II, § 202(m)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3843</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 4(b)</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3440</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–9, title IV, § 4201(b)</ref>, <date date="2019-03-12">Mar. 12, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 764</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title VII, § 731(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1460</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1305.</num>
<heading> Miscellaneous permanent appropriations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Necessary amounts are appropriated for the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to pay the proceeds of the personal estate of a United States citizen dying abroad to the legal representative of the deceased on proper demand and proof.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to pay interest on the public debt under laws authorizing payment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to pay proceeds from derelict and salvage cases adjudged by the courts of the United States to salvors.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to make payments required under contracts made under section 108 of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 5308</ref>) for the payment of interest on obligations guaranteed by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development under section 108.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to make payments required under contracts made under section 103(b) of the Housing Act of 1949 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 1453(b)</ref>) for projects or programs for which amounts had been committed before <date date="1975-01-01">January 1, 1975</date>, and for which amounts have not been appropriated.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> to pay the interest on the fund derived from the bequest of James Smithson, for the construction of buildings and expenses of the Smithsonian Institution, at the rates determined under section 5590 of the Revised Statutes (<ref>20 U.S.C. 54</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="centered">
<inline class="small-caps">annual contributions for assisted housing</inline>
</continuation>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> to make payments required under contracts made under section 5 of the United States Housing Act of 1937, as amended (<ref>42 U.S.C. 1437c</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="centered">
<inline class="small-caps">college housing grants</inline>
</continuation>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> to make payments required under contracts made under title IV of the Housing Act of 1950, as amended (<ref>12 U.S.C. 1749</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="centered">
<inline class="small-caps">rent supplement program</inline>
</continuation>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> to make payments required under contracts under section 101 of the Housing and Urban Development Act of 1965, as amended (<ref>12 U.S.C. 1701s</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="centered">
<inline class="small-caps">homeownership and rental housing assistance</inline>
</continuation>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> to make payments required under contracts under sections 235 and 236, respectively, of the National Housing Act, as amended (<ref>12 U.S.C. 1715z</ref>, 1715z–1).</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 918</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–452, § 1(4)</ref>, <date date="1983-01-12">Jan. 12, 1983</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2467</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–371, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1220</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1306.</num>
<heading> Use of foreign credits</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Foreign credits (including currencies) owed to or owned by the United States may be used by any agency for any purpose for which appropriations are made for the agency for the current fiscal year (including the carrying out of Acts requiring or authorizing the use of such credits), but only when reimbursement therefor is made to the Treasury from applicable appropriations of the agency.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception to Reimbursement Requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Credits described in subsection (a) that are received as exchanged allowances, or as the proceeds of the sale of personal property, may be used in whole or partial payment for the acquisition of similar items, to the extent and in the manner authorized by law, without reimbursement to the Treasury.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 918</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–208, div. A, title I, § 101(f) [title VI, § 612(a)]</ref>, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3009–314</ref>, 3009–355.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1307.</num>
<heading> Public building construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Amounts appropriated to construct public buildings remain available until completion of the work. When a building is completed and outstanding liabilities for the construction are paid, balances remaining shall revert immediately to the Treasury.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 918</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1308.</num>
<heading> Telephone and metered services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Charges for telephone and metered services (such as gas, electricity, water, and steam) for a time period beginning in one fiscal year or allotment period and ending in another fiscal year or allotment period may be charged against the appropriation or allotment current at the end of the time period covered by the service.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 919</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1309.</num>
<heading> Social security tax</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Amounts made available for the compensation of officers and employees of the United States Government may be used to pay taxes imposed on an agency as an employer under chapter 21 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (<ref>26 U.S.C. 3101</ref> et seq.).</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 919</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 2095</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1310.</num>
<heading> Appropriations for private organizations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of the Treasury shall credit an appropriation for a private organization to the appropriate fiscal official of the organization. The credit shall be carried on the accounts of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Treasury; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a designated depositary of the United States Government (except a national bank).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> The fiscal official may pay an amount out of the appropriation only on a check of the fiscal official—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> payable to the order of the person to whom payment is to be made; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> that states the specific purpose for which the amount is to be applied.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The fiscal official may pay an amount of less than $20 out of the appropriation on a check—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> payable to the order of the fiscal official; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> that states the amount is to be applied to small claims.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The fiscal official shall provide the Secretary or the designated depositary on which the check is drawn with a certified list of the claims. The list shall state the kind and amount of each claim and the name of each claimant.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 919</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>TRUST FUNDS AND REFUNDS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1321.</num>
<heading> Trust funds</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The following are classified as trust funds:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Philippine special fund (customs duties).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Philippine special fund (internal revenue).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Unclaimed condemnation awards, Department of the Treasury.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Naval reservation, Olangapo civil fund.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Armed Forces Retirement Home Trust Fund.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Return to deported aliens of passage money collected from steamship companies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Vocational rehabilitation, special fund.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Library of Congress gift fund.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> Library of Congress trust fund, investment account.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> Library of Congress trust fund, income from investment account.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> Library of Congress trust fund, permanent loan.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> Relief and rehabilitation, Longshore and Harbor Workers’ Compensation Act.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> Cooperative work, Forest Service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> Wages and effects of American seamen, Department of Commerce.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<content> Pension money, Saint Elizabeths Hospital.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(16)</num>
<content> Personal funds of patients, Saint Elizabeths Hospital.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(17)</num>
<content> National Park Service, donations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(18)</num>
<content> Purchase of lands, national parks, donations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(19)</num>
<content> Extension of winter-feed facilities of game animals of Yellowstone National Park, donations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(20)</num>
<content> Indian moneys, proceeds of labor, agencies, schools, and so forth.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(21)</num>
<content> Funds of Federal prisoners.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(22)</num>
<content> Commissary funds, Federal prisons.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(23)</num>
<content> Pay of the Navy, deposit funds.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(24)</num>
<content> Pay of Marine Corps, deposit funds.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(25)</num>
<content> Pay of the Army, deposit fund.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(26)</num>
<content> Preservation birthplace of Abraham Lincoln.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(27)</num>
<content> Funds contributed for flood control, Mississippi River, its outlets and tributaries.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(28)</num>
<content> Funds contributed for flood control, Sacramento River, California.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(29)</num>
<content> Effects of deceased employees, Department of the Treasury.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(30)</num>
<content> Money and effects of deceased patients, Public Health Service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(31)</num>
<content> Effects of deceased employees, Department of Commerce.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(32)</num>
<content> Topographic survey of the United States, contributions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(33)</num>
<content> National Institutes of Health, gift fund.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(34)</num>
<content> National Institutes of Health, conditional gift fund.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(35)</num>
<content> Patients’ deposits, United States Marine Hospital, Carville, Louisiana.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(36)</num>
<content> Estates of deceased personnel, Department of the Army.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(37)</num>
<content> Effects of deceased employees, Department of the Interior.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(38)</num>
<content> Fredericksburg and Spotsylvania County Battlefields memorial fund.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(39)</num>
<content> Petersburg National Military Park fund.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(40)</num>
<content> Gorgas memorial laboratory quotas.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(41)</num>
<content> Contributions to International Boundary Commission, United States and Mexico.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(42)</num>
<content> Salvage proceeds, American vessels.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(43)</num>
<content> Wages due American seamen.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(44)</num>
<content> Federal Industrial Institution for Women, contributions for chapel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(45)</num>
<content> General post fund, National Homes, Department of Veterans Affairs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(46)</num>
<content> Repatriation of American seamen.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(47)</num>
<content> Expenses, public survey work, general.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(48)</num>
<content> Expenses, public survey work, Alaska.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(49)</num>
<content> Funds contributed for improvement of roads, bridges, and trails, Alaska.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(50)</num>
<content> Protective works and measures, Lake of the Woods and Rainy River, Minnesota.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(51)</num>
<content> Washington redemption fund.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(52)</num>
<content> Permit fund, District of Columbia.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(53)</num>
<content> Unclaimed condemnation awards, National Capital Park and Planning Commission, District of Columbia.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(54)</num>
<content> Unclaimed condemnation awards, Rock Creek and Potomac Parkway Commission, District of Columbia.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(55)</num>
<content> Miscellaneous trust fund deposits, District of Columbia.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(56)</num>
<content> Surplus fund, District of Columbia.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(57)</num>
<content> Relief and rehabilitation, District of Columbia Workmen’s Compensation Act.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(58)</num>
<content> Inmates’ fund, workhouse and reformatory, District of Columbia.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(59)</num>
<content> International Center for Middle Eastern-Western Dialogue Trust Fund.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(60)</num>
<content> Chamber Music Auditorium, Library of Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(61)</num>
<content> Bequest of Gertrude Hubbard.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(62)</num>
<content> Puerto Rico special fund (Internal Revenue).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(63)</num>
<content> Miscellaneous trust funds, Department of State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(64)</num>
<content> Funds contributed for improvement of (name of river or harbor).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(65)</num>
<content> Funds advanced for improvement of (name of river or harbor).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(66)</num>
<content> Funds contributed for Indian projects.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(67)</num>
<content> Miscellaneous trust funds of Indian tribes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(68)</num>
<content> Ship’s stores profits, Navy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(69)</num>
<content> Completing Surveys within Railroad Land Grants.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(70)</num>
<content> Memorial to Women of World War, contributions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(71)</num>
<content> Funds contributed for Memorial to John Ericsson.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(72)</num>
<content> American National Red Cross Building, contributions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(73)</num>
<content> Estate of decedents, Department of State, Trust Fund.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(74)</num>
<content> Funds due Incompetent Beneficiaries, Department of Veterans Affairs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(75)</num>
<content> To promote the Education of the Blind (principal).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(76)</num>
<content> Paving Government Road across Fort Sill Military Reservation, Okla.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(77)</num>
<content> Bequest of William F. Edgar, Museum and Library, office of Surgeon General of the Army.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(78)</num>
<content> Funds Contributed for Flood Control (name of river, harbor, or project).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(79)</num>
<content> Matured obligations of the District of Columbia.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(80)</num>
<content> To promote the education of the blind (interest).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>[(81)</num>
<content> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XV, § 1533(c)(1)(A)(ii)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1735</ref>.]</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(82)</num>
<content> Post-Vietnam Era Veterans Education Account, Department of Veterans Affairs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(83)</num>
<content> United States Government life insurance fund, Department of Veterans Affairs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(84)</num>
<content> Estates of deceased soldiers, United States Army.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(85)</num>
<content> Teachers Retirement Fund Deductions, District of Columbia.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(86)</num>
<content> Teachers Retirement Fund, Government Reserves, District of Columbia.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(87)</num>
<content> Expenses of Smithsonian Institution Trust Fund (principal).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(88)</num>
<content> Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(89)</num>
<content> Canal Zone Retirement and Disability Fund.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(90)</num>
<content> Foreign Service Retirement and Disability Fund.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(91)</num>
<content> Violent Crime Reduction Trust Fund.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Amounts (except amounts received by the Comptroller of the Currency and the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation) that are analogous to the funds named in subsection (a) of this section and are received by the United States Government as trustee shall be deposited in an appropriate trust fund account in the Treasury. Except as provided in paragraph (2), amounts accruing to these funds are appropriated to be disbursed in compliance with the terms of the trust.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Expenditures from the following trust funds may be made only under annual appropriations and only if the appropriations are specifically authorized by law:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Armed Forces Retirement Home Trust Fund.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Fisher House Trust Fund, Department of the Army.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Fisher House Trust Fund, Department of the Air Force.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Fisher House Trust Fund, Department of the Navy.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 919</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–426, § 27(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="1984-09-28">Sept. 28, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1654</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title III, § 341(a)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1419</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XV, § 1533(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1735</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–54, § 13</ref>(<i>l</i>)(1), <date date="1991-06-13">June 13, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 277</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXI, § 310001(d)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2103</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title IX, § 914(c)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 413</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title X, § 1008(c)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2633</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title IX, § 906(f)(2)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2096</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–199, div. B, title VI, § 633(f)</ref>, <date date="2004-01-23">Jan. 23, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 101</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1322.</num>
<heading> Payments of unclaimed trust fund amounts and refund of amounts erroneously deposited</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> On September 30 of each year, the Secretary of the Treasury shall transfer to the Treasury trust fund receipt account “Unclaimed Moneys of Individuals Whose Whereabouts are Unknown” that part of the balance of a trust fund account named in section 1321(a)(1)–(82) of this title or an analogous trust fund established under <ref>section 1321(b) of this title</ref> that has been in the fund for more than one year and represents money belonging to individuals whose whereabouts are unknown. Subsequent claims to the transferred funds shall be paid from the account “Unclaimed Moneys of Individuals Whose Whereabouts are Unknown”.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, necessary amounts are appropriated to the Secretary of the Treasury to make payments from—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Treasury trust fund receipt account “Unclaimed Moneys of Individuals Whose Whereabouts are Unknown”; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the United States Government account “Refund of Moneys Erroneously Received and Covered” and other collections erroneously deposited that are not properly chargeable to another appropriation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Treasury shall hold in the Treasury trust fund receipt account “Unclaimed Moneys of Individuals Whose Whereabouts Are Unknown” the balance remaining after the final distribution of unclaimed Postal Savings System deposits under subsection (a) of the first section of the Act of <date date="1971-08-13">August 13, 1971</date> (<ref>Public Law 92–117</ref>; <ref>85 Stat. 337</ref>). The Secretary shall use the balance to pay claims for Postal Savings System deposits without regard to the State law or the law of other jurisdictions of deposit concerning the disposition of unclaimed or abandoned property.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Necessary amounts may be appropriated without fiscal year limitation to the trust fund receipt account to pay claims for deposits when the balance in the account is not sufficient to pay the claims made within the time limitation set forth in paragraph (3) of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> No claim for any Postal Savings System deposit may be brought more than one year from the date of the enactment of the Postal Savings System Statute of Limitations Act.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The United States Postal Service shall assist the Secretary of the Treasury in providing public notice of the time limitation set forth in paragraph (3) of this subsection by posting notices thereof in all post offices as soon as practicable after the date of the enactment of the Postal Savings System Statute of Limitations Act.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 922</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–359, § 2</ref>, <date date="1984-07-13">July 13, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 402</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1323.</num>
<heading> Trust funds for certain fees, donations, quasi-public amounts, and unearned amounts</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Amounts from the following sources held in checking accounts of disbursing officials shall be deposited in the Treasury to the appropriate trust fund receipt accounts:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> unearned money, lands (Department of the Interior).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> reentry permit fees (Department of Justice).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> naturalization fees (Department of Justice).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> registry fees (Department of Justice).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Amounts deposited under subsection (a) of this section are appropriated for refunds. Earned parts of those amounts shall be transferred and credited to the appropriate receipt fund accounts.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> Donations, quasi-public amounts, and unearned amounts shall be deposited in the Treasury as trust funds and are appropriated for disbursement under the terms of the trusts when the donation or amount is—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> administered by officers and employees of the United States Government; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> carried in checking accounts of disbursing officials or others required to account to the Comptroller General (except clerks and marshals of the United States district courts).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 922</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1324.</num>
<heading> Refund of internal revenue collections</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Necessary amounts are appropriated to the Secretary of the Treasury for refunding internal revenue collections as provided by law, including payment of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> claims for prior fiscal years; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> accounts arising under—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> “Allowance or drawback (Internal Revenue)”;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> “Redemption of stamps (Internal Revenue)”;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> “Refunding legacy taxes, Act of <date date="1928-03-30">March 30, 1928</date>”;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> “Repayment of taxes on distilled spirits destroyed by casualty”; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> “Refunds and payments of processing and related taxes”.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Disbursements may be made from the appropriation made by this section only for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> refunds to the limit of liability of an individual tax account; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> refunds due from credit provisions of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (<ref>26 U.S.C. 1</ref> et seq.) enacted before <date date="1978-01-01">January 1, 1978</date>, or enacted by the Taxpayer Relief Act of 1997, or from section 21, 24, 25A, 35, 36, 36A,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002033">1</ref> 36B, 168(k)(4)(F), 53(e),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002033">1</ref> 54B(h),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002033">1</ref> 3131, 3132, 3134, 6428, 6428A, 6428B, 6431,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002033">1</ref> or 7527A of such Code, or due under section 3081(b)(2) of the Housing Assistance Tax Act of 2008.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 923</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 2095</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–34, title I, § 101(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 799</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–210, div. A, title II, § 201(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-08-06">Aug. 6, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 960</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–432, div. A, title IV, § 402(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2954</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–185, title I, § 101(f)(1)</ref>, <date date="2008-02-13">Feb. 13, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 617</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title XV, § 15316(c)(6)</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1511</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title XV, § 15316(c)(6), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2273; <ref>Pub. L. 110–289, div. C, title I, § 3011(b)(3)</ref>, title III, § 3081(c), <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2891</ref>, 2906; <ref>Pub. L. 111–5, div. B, title I</ref>, §§ 1001(e)(2), 1004(b)(8), 1531(c)(1), <date date="2009-02-17">Feb. 17, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 312</ref>, 314, 360; <ref>Pub. L. 111–148, title I, § 1401(d)(1)</ref>, title X, § 10909(b)(2)(P), (c), <date date="2010-03-23">Mar. 23, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 220</ref>, 1023; <ref>Pub. L. 111–312, title I, § 101(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2010-12-17">Dec. 17, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3298</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–295, div. A, title II, § 221(a)(112)(D)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 4054</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–136, div. A, title II, § 2201(g)(1)</ref>, <date date="2020-03-27">Mar. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 339</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–260, div. N, title II, § 272(g)(1)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 1976</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–2, title IX</ref>, §§ 9601(c)(3)(A), 9611(b)(4)(C), 9631(c)(2), 9641(b), 9651(b), <date date="2021-03-11">Mar. 11, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 143</ref>, 150, 160, 171, 182; <ref>Pub. L. 117–328, div. T, title I, § 103(d)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 5285</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>LIMITATIONS, EXCEPTIONS, AND PENALTIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1341.</num>
<heading> Limitations on expending and obligating amounts</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Except as specified in this subchapter or any other provision of law, an officer or employee of the United States Government or of the District of Columbia government may not—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> make or authorize an expenditure or obligation exceeding an amount available in an appropriation or fund for the expenditure or obligation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> involve either government in a contract or obligation for the payment of money before an appropriation is made unless authorized by law;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> make or authorize an expenditure or obligation of funds required to be sequestered under section 252 of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> involve either government in a contract or obligation for the payment of money required to be sequestered under section 252 of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> This subsection does not apply to a corporation getting amounts to make loans (except paid in capital amounts) without legal liability of the United States Government.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> An article to be used by an executive department in the District of Columbia that could be bought out of an appropriation made to a regular contingent fund of the department may not be bought out of another amount available for obligation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> In this subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the term “covered lapse in appropriations” means any lapse in appropriations that begins on or after <date date="2018-12-22">December 22, 2018</date>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> the term “District of Columbia public employer” means—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the District of Columbia Courts;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the Public Defender Service for the District of Columbia; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the District of Columbia government;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the term “employee” includes an officer; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the term “excepted employee” means an excepted employee or an employee performing emergency work, as such terms are defined by the Office of Personnel Management or the appropriate District of Columbia public employer, as applicable.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Each employee of the United States Government or of a District of Columbia public employer furloughed as a result of a covered lapse in appropriations shall be paid for the period of the lapse in appropriations, and each excepted employee who is required to perform work during a covered lapse in appropriations shall be paid for such work, at the employee’s standard rate of pay, at the earliest date possible after the lapse in appropriations ends, regardless of scheduled pay dates, and subject to the enactment of appropriations Acts ending the lapse.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> During a covered lapse in appropriations, each excepted employee who is required to perform work shall be entitled to use leave under chapter 63 of title 5, or any other applicable law governing the use of leave by the excepted employee, for which compensation shall be paid at the earliest date possible after the lapse in appropriations ends, regardless of scheduled pay dates.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 923</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–508, title XIII, § 13213(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1388–621</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–1, § 2</ref>, <date date="2019-01-16">Jan. 16, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 3</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–5, § 103</ref>, <date date="2019-01-25">Jan. 25, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 11</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1342.</num>
<heading> Limitation on voluntary services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An officer or employee of the United States Government or of the District of Columbia government may not accept voluntary services for either government or employ personal services exceeding that authorized by law except for emergencies involving the safety of human life or the protection of property. This section does not apply to a corporation getting amounts to make loans (except paid in capital amounts) without legal liability of the United States Government. As used in this section, the term “emergencies involving the safety of human life or the protection of property” does not include ongoing, regular functions of government the suspension of which would not imminently threaten the safety of human life or the protection of property.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 923</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–508, title XIII, § 13213(b)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1388–621</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–92, title III, § 310(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-01-06">Jan. 6, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 20</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1343.</num>
<heading> Buying and leasing passenger motor vehicles and aircraft</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> In this section, buying a passenger motor vehicle or aircraft includes a transfer of the vehicle or aircraft between agencies.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> An appropriation may be expended to buy or lease passenger motor vehicles only—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> for the use of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the President;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the secretaries to the President; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the heads of executive departments listed in <ref>section 101 of title 5</ref>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> as specifically provided by law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Except as specifically provided by law, an agency may use an appropriation to buy a passenger motor vehicle (except a bus or ambulance) only at a total cost (except costs required only for transportation) that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> includes the price of systems and equipment the Administrator of General Services decides is incorporated customarily in standard passenger motor vehicles completely equipped for ordinary operation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> includes the value of a vehicle used in exchange;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> is not more than the maximum price established by the agency having authority under law to establish a maximum price; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> is not more than the amount specified in a law.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Additional systems and equipment may be bought for a passenger motor vehicle if the Administrator decides the purchase is appropriate. The price of additional systems or equipment is not included in deciding whether the cost of the vehicle is within a maximum price specified in a law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> An appropriation (except an appropriation for the armed forces) is available to buy, maintain, or operate an aircraft only if the appropriation specifically authorizes the purchase, maintenance, or operation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<chapeau> This section does not apply to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> buying, maintaining, and repairing passenger motor vehicles by the United States Capitol Police;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> buying, maintaining, and repairing vehicles necessary to carry out projects to improve, preserve, and protect rivers and harbors; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> leasing, maintaining, repairing, or operating motor passenger vehicles necessary in the field work of the Department of Agriculture.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 924</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1344.</num>
<heading> Passenger carrier use</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Funds available to a Federal agency, by appropriation or otherwise, may be expended by the Federal agency for the maintenance, operation, or repair of any passenger carrier only to the extent that such carrier is used to provide transportation for official purposes. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, transporting any individual other than the individuals listed in subsections (b) and (c) of this section between such individual’s residence and such individual’s place of employment is not transportation for an official purpose.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of paragraph (1), transportation between the residence of an officer or employee and various locations that is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> required for the performance of field work, in accordance with regulations prescribed pursuant to subsection (e) of this section, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> essential for the safe and efficient performance of intelligence, counterintelligence, protective services, or criminal law enforcement duties, or transportation of federally owned canines associated with force protection duties of any part of the intelligence community (as defined in section 3 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3003</ref>)),</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">is transportation for an official purpose, when approved in writing by the head of the Federal agency.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> For purposes of paragraph (1), the transportation of an individual between such individual’s place of employment and a mass transit facility pursuant to subsection (g) is transportation for an official purpose.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> A passenger carrier may be used to transport between residence and place of employment the following officers and employees of Federal agencies:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the President and the Vice President;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> no more than 6 officers or employees in the Executive Office of the President, as designated by the President; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> no more than 10 additional officers or employees of Federal agencies, as designated by the President;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Chief Justice and the Associate Justices of the Supreme Court;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> officers compensated at Level I of the Executive Schedule pursuant to <ref>section 5312 of title 5</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a single principal deputy to an officer described in subclause (A) of this clause, when a determination is made by such officer that such transportation is appropriate;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> principal diplomatic and consular officials abroad, and the United States Ambassador to the United Nations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the Deputy Secretary of Defense and Under Secretaries of Defense, the Secretary of the Air Force, the Secretary of the Army, the Secretary of the Navy, the members and Vice Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, and the Commandant of the Coast Guard;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency, the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, Director of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002034">1</ref> the Administrator of the Drug Enforcement Administration, and the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the Chairman of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> the Comptroller General of the United States and the Postmaster General of the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> an officer or employee with regard to whom the head of a Federal agency makes a determination, in accordance with subsection (d) of this section and with regulations prescribed pursuant to paragraph (1) of subsection (e), that highly unusual circumstances present a clear and present danger, that an emergency exists, or that other compelling operational considerations make such transportation essential to the conduct of official business.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of subsection (d), any authorization made pursuant to clause (9) of this subsection to permit the use of a passenger carrier to transport an officer or employee between residence and place of employment shall be effective for not more than 15 calendar days.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> A passenger carrier may be used to transport between residence and place of employment any person for whom protection is specifically authorized pursuant to <ref>section 3056(a) of title 18</ref> or for whom transportation is authorized pursuant to section 28 of the State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956, <ref>section 2637 of title 10</ref>, or section 8(a)(1) of the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Any determination made under subsection (b)(9) of this section shall be in writing and shall include the name and title of the officer or employee affected, the reason for such determination, and the duration of the authorization for such officer or employee to use a passenger carrier for transportation between residence and place of employment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If a clear and present danger, an emergency, or a compelling operational consideration described in subsection (b)(9) of this section extends or may extend for a period in excess of 15 calendar days, the head of the Federal agency shall determine whether an authorization under such paragraph shall be extended in excess of 15 calendar days for a period of not more than 90 additional calendar days. Determinations made under this paragraph may be reviewed by the head of such agency at the end of each such period, and, where appropriate, a subsequent determination may be made whether such danger, emergency, or consideration continues to exist and whether an additional extension, not to exceed 90 calendar days, may be authorized. Determinations made under this paragraph shall be in accordance with regulations prescribed pursuant to paragraph (1) of subsection (e).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The authority to make designations under subsection (b)(1) of this section and to make determinations pursuant to subsections (a)(2) and (b)(3)(B) and (9) of this section and pursuant to paragraph (2) of this subsection may not be delegated, except that, with respect to the Executive Office of the President, the President may delegate the authority of the President under subsection (b)(9) of this section to an officer in the Executive Office of the President. No designation or determination under this section may be made solely or principally for the comfort or convenience of the officer or employee.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Notification of each designation or determination made under subsection (b)(1), (3)(B), and (9) of this section and under paragraph (2) of this subsection, including the name and title of the officer or employee affected, the reason for any determination under subsection (b)(9), and the expected duration of any authorization under subsection (b)(9), shall be transmitted promptly to the Committee on Government Operations of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Governmental Affairs of the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Not later than <date date="1987-03-15">March 15, 1987</date>, the Administrator of General Services, after consultation with the Comptroller General, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, and the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts, shall promulgate regulations governing the heads of all Federal agencies in making the determinations authorized by subsections (a)(2)(A), (b)(9), and (d)(2) of this section. Such regulations shall specify that the comfort and convenience of an officer or employee is not sufficient justification for authorizations of transportation under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In promulgating regulations under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Administrator of General Services shall provide criteria defining the term “field work” for purposes of subsection (a)(2)(A) of this section. Such criteria shall ensure that transportation between an employee’s residence and the location of the field work will be authorized only to the extent that such transportation will substantially increase the efficiency and economy of the Government.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> Each Federal agency shall maintain logs or other records necessary to establish the official purpose for Government transportation provided between an individual’s residence and such individual’s place of employment pursuant to this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> If and to the extent that the head of a Federal agency, in his or her sole discretion, deems it appropriate, a passenger carrier may be used to transport an officer or employee of a Federal agency between the officer’s or employee’s place of employment and a mass transit facility (whether or not publicly owned) in accordance with succeeding provisions of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding section 1343, a Federal agency that provides transportation services under this subsection (including by passenger carrier) may absorb the costs of such services using any funds available to such agency, whether by appropriation or otherwise.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> In carrying out this subsection, a Federal agency, to the maximum extent practicable and consistent with sound budget policy, should—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> use alternative fuel vehicles for the provision of transportation services;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to the extent consistent with the purposes of this subsection, provide transportation services in a manner that does not result in additional gross income for Federal income tax purposes; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> coordinate with other Federal agencies to share, and otherwise avoid duplication of, transportation services provided under this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> For purposes of any determination under chapter 81 of title 5 or chapter 171 of title 28, an individual shall not be considered to be in the “performance of duty” or “acting within the scope of his or her office or employment” by virtue of the fact that such individual is receiving transportation services under this subsection. Nor shall any time during which an individual uses such services be considered when calculating the hours of work or employment for that individual for purposes of title 5 of the United States Code, including chapter 55 of that title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Administrator of General Services, after consultation with the appropriate agencies, shall prescribe any regulations necessary to carry out this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Transportation services under this subsection shall be subject neither to the last sentence of subsection (d)(3) nor to any regulations under the last sentence of subsection (e)(1).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> In this subsection, the term “passenger carrier” means a passenger motor vehicle or similar means of transportation that is owned, leased, or provided pursuant to contract by the United States Government.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<chapeau> As used in this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “passenger carrier” means a passenger motor vehicle, aircraft, boat, ship, or other similar means of transportation that is owned or leased by the United States Government; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the term “Federal agency” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> a department—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> including independent establishments, other agencies, and wholly owned Government corporations; but</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> not including the Senate, House of Representatives, or Architect of the Capitol, or the officers or employees thereof;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an Executive department (as such term is defined in <ref>section 101 of title 5</ref>);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a military department (as such term is defined in <ref>section 102 of title 5</ref>);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a Government corporation (as such term is defined in <ref>section 103(1) of title 5</ref>);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> a Government controlled corporation (as such term is defined in <ref>section 103(2) of title 5</ref>);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> a mixed-ownership Government corporation (as such term is defined in <ref>section 9101(2) of this title</ref>);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> any establishment in the executive branch of the Government (including the Executive Office of the President);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> any independent regulatory agency (including an independent regulatory agency specified in section 3502(10) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002035">2</ref> of title 44);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the Smithsonian Institution; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> any nonappropriated fund instrumentality of the United States,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">except that such term does not include the government of the District of Columbia.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding <ref>section 410(a) of title 39</ref>, this section applies to the United States Postal Service.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 924</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–550, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3067</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–180, div. A, title XIII, § 1314(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1176</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–202, § 101(a) [title IV, § 407]</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1329</ref>, 1329–26; <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title III, § 326(b)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1531</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 4(f)(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1363</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–91, title I, § 101(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-01-06">Jan. 6, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 11</ref>, amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–99, title II, § 211</ref>, <date date="1996-01-26">Jan. 26, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 37</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–7, div. K, title IV, § 423</ref>, <date date="2003-02-20">Feb. 20, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 526</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–447, div. B, title I, § 117</ref>, <date date="2004-12-08">Dec. 8, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2870</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–59, title III, § 3049(b)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="2005-08-10">Aug. 10, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 1712</ref>, 1713; <ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 5(h)(4)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3849</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–103, div. X, title III, § 306</ref>, <date date="2022-03-15">Mar. 15, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 966</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1345.</num>
<heading> Expenses of meetings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except as specifically provided by law, an appropriation may not be used for travel, transportation, and subsistence expenses for a meeting. This section does not prohibit—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an agency from paying the expenses of an officer or employee of the United States Government carrying out an official duty; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Agriculture from paying necessary expenses for a meeting called by the Secretary for 4–H Boys and Girls Clubs as part of the cooperative extension work of the Department of Agriculture.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 925</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1346.</num>
<heading> Commissions, councils, boards, and inter­agency and similar groups</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Except as provided in this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> public money and appropriations are not available to pay—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the pay or expenses of a commission, council, board, or similar group, or a member of that group;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> expenses related to the work or the results of work or action of that group; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> for the detail or cost of personal services of an officer or employee from an executive agency in connection with that group; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an accounting or disbursing official, absent a special appropriation to pay the account or charge, may not allow or pay an account or charge related to that group.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Appropriations of an executive agency are available for the expenses of an interagency group conducting activities of interest common to executive agencies when the group includes a representative of the agency. The representatives receive no additional pay because of membership in the group. An officer or employee of an executive agency not a representative of the group may not receive additional pay for providing services for the group.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> Subject to <ref>section 1347 of this title</ref>, this section does not apply to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> commissions, councils, boards, or similar groups authorized by law;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> courts-martial or courts of inquiry of the armed forces; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the contingent fund related to foreign relations at the disposal of the President.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 925</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1347.</num>
<heading> Appropriations or authorizations required for agencies in existence for more than one year</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> An agency in existence for more than one year may not use amounts otherwise available for obligation to pay its expenses without a specific appropriation or specific authorization by law. If the principal duties and powers of the agency are substantially the same as or similar to the duties and powers of an agency established by executive order, the agency established later is deemed to have been in existence from the date the agency established by the order came into existence.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Except as specifically authorized by law, another agency may not use amounts available for obligation to pay expenses to carry out duties and powers substantially the same as or similar to the principal duties and powers of an agency that is prohibited from using amounts under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 925</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1348.</num>
<heading> Telephone installation and charges</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in this section, appropriations are not available to install telephones in private residences or for tolls or other charges for telephone service from private residences.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Under regulations of the Secretary of State, appropriations may be used to install and pay for the use of telephones in residences owned or leased by the United States Government in foreign countries for the use of the Foreign Service.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of the Army on recommendation of the Chief of Engineers, not more than $30,000 may be expended each fiscal year to install and use in private residences telephones required for official business in constructing and operating locks and dams for navigation, flood control, and related water uses.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, funds appropriated to the Department of Defense are available to install, repair, and maintain telephone wiring in residences owned or leased by the United States Government and, if necessary for national defense purposes, in other private residences.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 926</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–407, title VIII, § 811(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-08-28">Aug. 28, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1523</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XVII, § 1721</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2758</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1349.</num>
<heading> Adverse personnel actions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> An officer or employee of the United States Government or of the District of Columbia government violating section 1341(a) or 1342 of this title shall be subject to appropriate administrative discipline including, when circumstances warrant, suspension from duty without pay or removal from office.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> An officer or employee who willfully uses or authorizes the use of a passenger motor vehicle or aircraft owned or leased by the United States Government (except for an official purpose authorized by <ref>section 1344 of this title</ref>) or otherwise violates section 1344 shall be suspended without pay by the head of the agency. The officer or employee shall be suspended for at least one month, and when circumstances warrant, for a longer period or summarily removed from office.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 926</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1350.</num>
<heading> Criminal penalty</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An officer or employee of the United States Government or of the District of Columbia government knowingly and willfully violating section 1341(a) or 1342 of this title shall be fined not more than $5,000, imprisoned for not more than 2 years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 926</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1351.</num>
<heading> Reports on violations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If an officer or employee of an executive agency or an officer or employee of the District of Columbia government violates section 1341(a) or 1342 of this title, the head of the agency or the Mayor of the District of Columbia, as the case may be, shall report immediately to the President and Congress all relevant facts and a statement of actions taken. A copy of each report shall also be transmitted to the Comptroller General on the same date the report is transmitted to the President and Congress.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 926</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–447, div. G, title I, § 1401(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-12-08">Dec. 8, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3192</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1352.</num>
<heading> Limitation on use of appropriated funds to influence certain Federal contracting and financial transactions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> None of the funds appropriated by any Act may be expended by the recipient of a Federal contract, grant, loan, or cooperative agreement to pay any person for influencing or attempting to influence an officer or employee of any agency, a Member of Congress, an officer or employee of Congress, or an employee of a Member of Congress in connection with any Federal action described in paragraph (2) of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The prohibition in paragraph (1) of this subsection applies with respect to the following Federal actions:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The awarding of any Federal contract.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The making of any Federal grant.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The making of any Federal loan.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The entering into of any cooperative agreement.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The extension, continuation, renewal, amendment, or modification of any Federal contract, grant, loan, or cooperative agreement.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Each person who requests or receives a Federal contract, grant, loan, or cooperative agreement from an agency or requests or receives from an agency a commitment providing for the United States to insure or guarantee a loan shall file with that agency, in accordance with paragraph (4) of this subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a written declaration described in paragraph (2) or (3) of this subsection, as the case may be; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> copies of all declarations received by such person under paragraph (5).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> A declaration filed by a person pursuant to paragraph (1)(A) of this subsection in connection with a Federal contract, grant, loan, or cooperative agreement shall contain—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the name of any registrant under the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 who has made lobbying contacts on behalf of the person with respect to that Federal contract, grant, loan, or cooperative agreement; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a certification that the person making the declaration has not made, and will not make, any payment prohibited by subsection (a).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A declaration filed by a person pursuant to paragraph (1)(A) of this subsection in connection with a commitment providing for the United States to insure or guarantee a loan shall contain the name of any registrant under the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 who has made lobbying contacts on behalf of the person in connection with that loan insurance or guarantee.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> A person referred to in paragraph (1)(A) of this subsection shall file a declaration referred to in that paragraph—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> with each submission by such person that initiates agency consideration of such person for award of a Federal contract, grant, loan, or cooperative agreement, or for grant of a commitment providing for the United States to insure or guarantee a loan;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> upon receipt by such person of a Federal contract, grant, loan, or cooperative agreement or of a commitment providing for the United States to insure or guarantee a loan, unless such person previously filed a declaration with respect to such contract, grant, loan, cooperative agreement or commitment pursuant to clause (A); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> at the end of each calendar quarter in which there occurs any event that materially affects the accuracy of the information contained in any declaration previously filed by such person in connection with such Federal contract, grant, loan, cooperative agreement, loan insurance commitment, or loan guaranty commitment.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Any person who requests or receives from a person referred to in paragraph (1) of this subsection a subcontract under a Federal contract, a subgrant or contract under a Federal grant, a contract or subcontract to carry out any purpose for which a particular Federal loan is made, or a contract under a Federal cooperative agreement shall be required to file with the person referred to in such paragraph a written declaration referred to in clause (A) of such paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The Director of the Office of Management and Budget, after consulting with the Secretary of the Senate and the Clerk of the House of Representatives, shall issue guidance for agency implementation of, and compliance with, the requirements of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Any person who makes an expenditure prohibited by subsection (a) of this section shall be subject to a civil penalty of not less than $10,000 and not more than $100,000 for each such expenditure.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Any person who fails to file or amend a declaration required to be filed or amended under subsection (b) of this section shall be subject to a civil penalty of not less than $10,000 and not more than $100,000 for each such failure.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A filing of a declaration of a declaration amendment on or after the date on which an administrative action for the imposition of a civil penalty under this subsection is commenced does not prevent the imposition of such civil penalty for a failure occurring before that date. For the purposes of this subparagraph, an administrative action is commenced with respect to a failure when an investigating official determines in writing to commence an investigation of an allegation of such failure.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Sections 3803 (except for subsection (c)), 3804, 3805, 3806, 3807, 3808, and 3812 of this title shall be applied, consistent with the requirements of this section, to the imposition and collection of civil penalties under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> An imposition of a civil penalty under this subsection does not prevent the United States from seeking any other remedy that the United States may have for the same conduct that is the basis for the imposition of such civil penalty.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Subsection (a)(1) of this section does not apply in the case of a payment of reasonable compensation made to an officer or employee of a person requesting or receiving a Federal contract, grant, loan, or cooperative agreement to the extent that the payment is for agency and legislative liaison activities not directly related to a Federal action referred to in subsection (a)(2) of this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Subsection (a)(1) of this section does not prohibit any reasonable payment to a person in connection with, or any payment of reasonable compensation to an officer or employee of a person requesting or receiving, a Federal contract, grant, loan, or cooperative agreement or an extension, continuation, renewal, amendment, or modification of a Federal contract, grant, loan, or cooperative agreement if the payment is for professional or technical services rendered directly in the preparation, submission, or negotiation of any bid, proposal, or application for that Federal contract, grant, loan, or cooperative agreement or for meeting requirements imposed by or pursuant to law as a condition for receiving that Federal contract, grant, loan, or cooperative agreement.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed as permitting the use of appropriated funds for making any payment prohibited in or pursuant to any other provision of law.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The reporting requirement in subsection (b) of this section shall not apply to any person with respect to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> payments of reasonable compensation made to regularly employed officers or employees of a person requesting or receiving a Federal contract, grant, loan, or cooperative agreement or a commitment providing for the United States to insure or guarantee a loan;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a request for or receipt of a contract (other than a contract referred to in clause (C)), grant, cooperative agreement, subcontract (other than a subcontract referred to in clause (C)), or subgrant that does not exceed $100,000; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a request for or receipt of a loan, or a commitment providing for the United States to insure or guarantee a loan, that does not exceed $150,000, or the single family maximum mortgage limit for affected programs, whichever is greater, including a contract or subcontract to carry out any purpose for which such a loan is made.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may exempt a Federal action described in subsection (a)(2) from the prohibition in subsection (a)(1) whenever the Secretary determines, in writing, that such an exemption is in the national interest. The Secretary shall transmit a copy of each such written exemption to Congress immediately after making such determination.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> The head of each Federal agency shall take such actions as are necessary to ensure that the provisions of this section are vigorously implemented and enforced in such agency.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<chapeau> As used in this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The term “recipient”, with respect to funds received in connection with a Federal contract, grant, loan, or cooperative agreement—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> includes the contractors, subcontractors, or subgrantees (as the case may be) of the recipient; but</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> does not include an Indian tribe, tribal organization, or any other Indian organization eligible to receive Federal contracts, grants, cooperative agreements, or loans from an agency but only with respect to expenditures that are by such tribe or organization for purposes specified in subsection (a) and are permitted by other Federal law.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “agency” has the same meaning provided for such term in <ref>section 552(f) of title 5</ref>, and includes a Government corporation, as defined in <ref>section 9101(1) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The term “person”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> includes an individual, corporation, company, association, authority, firm, partnership, society, State, and local government, regardless of whether such entity is operated for profit or not for profit; but</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> does not include an Indian tribe, tribal organization, or any other Indian organization eligible to receive Federal contracts, grants, cooperative agreements, or loans from an agency but only with respect to expenditures by such tribe or organization that are made for purposes specified in subsection (a) and are permitted by other Federal law.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “State” means a State of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, a territory or possession of the United States, an agency or instrumentality of a State, and a multi-State, regional, or interstate entity having governmental duties and powers.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> The term “local government” means a unit of government in a State and, if chartered, established, or otherwise recognized by a State for the performance of a governmental duty, the following entities:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A local public authority.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A special district.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> An intrastate district.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> A council of governments.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> A sponsor group representative organization.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Any other instrumentality of a local government.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> The terms “Federal contract”, “Federal grant”, “Federal cooperative agreement” mean, respectively—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a contract awarded by an agency;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a grant made by an agency or a direct appropriation made by law to any person; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a cooperative agreement entered into by an agency.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> Such terms do not include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> direct United States cash assistance to an individual;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a loan;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> loan insurance; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> a loan guaranty.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The term “Federal loan” means a loan made by an agency. Such term does not include loan insurance or a loan guaranty.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> The term “reasonable payment” means, with respect to professional and other technical services, a payment in an amount that is consistent with the amount normally paid for such services in the private sector.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> The term “reasonable compensation” means, with respect to a regularly employed officer or employee of any person, compensation that is consistent with the normal compensation for such officer or employee for work that is not furnished to, not funded by, or not furnished in cooperation with the Federal Government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> The term “regularly employed”, with respect to an officer or employee of a person requesting or receiving a Federal contract, grant, loan, or cooperative agreement or a commitment providing for the United States to insure or guarantee a loan, means an officer or employee who is employed by such person for at least 130 working days within one year immediately preceding the date of the submission that initiates agency consideration of such person for receipt of such contract, grant, loan, cooperative agreement, loan insurance commitment, or loan guaranty commitment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> The terms “Indian tribe” and “tribal organization” have the meaning provided in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<ref>25 U.S.C. 450b</ref>).<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002036">1</ref></content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–121, title III, § 319(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1989-10-23">Oct. 23, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 750</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–512, title III, § 320</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1977</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 4(f)(1)(F)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1362</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–65, § 10</ref>, <date date="1995-12-19">Dec. 19, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 700</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–66, title III, § 3001(b)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-21">Dec. 21, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 734</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title X, § 1064(c)</ref>, div. D, title XLIII, § 4301(a)(2), <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 445</ref>, 656.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1353.</num>
<heading> Acceptance of travel and related expenses from non-Federal sources</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Administrator of General Services, in consultation with the Director of the Office of Government Ethics, shall prescribe by regulation the conditions under which an agency in the executive branch (including an independent agency) may accept payment, or authorize an employee of such agency to accept payment on the agency’s behalf, from non-Federal sources for travel, subsistence, and related expenses with respect to attendance of the employee (or the spouse of such employee) at any meeting or similar function relating to the official duties of the employee. Any cash payment so accepted shall be credited to the appropriation applicable to such expenses. In the case of a payment in kind so accepted, a pro rata reduction shall be made in any entitlement of the employee to payment from the Government for such expenses.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Except as provided in this section or section 4111 or 7342 of title 5, an agency or employee may not accept payment for expenses referred to in subsection (a). An employee who accepts any payment in violation of the preceding sentence—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> may be required, in addition to any penalty provided by law, to repay, for deposit in the general fund of the Treasury, an amount equal to the amount of the payment so accepted; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in the case of a repayment under paragraph (1), shall not be entitled to any payment from the Government for such expenses.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> As used in this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “executive branch” means all executive agencies (as such term is defined in <ref>section 105 of title 5</ref>); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the term “employee in the executive branch” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an appointed officer or employee in the executive branch; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an expert or consultant in the executive branch, under <ref>section 3109 of title 5</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “payment” means a payment or reimbursement, in cash or in kind.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The head of each agency of the executive branch shall, in the manner provided in paragraph (2), submit to the Director of the Office of Government Ethics reports of payments of more than $250 accepted under this section with respect to employees of the agency. The Director shall make such reports available for public inspection and copying.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The reports required by paragraph (1) shall, with respect to each payment—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> specify the amount and method of payment, the name of the person making the payment, the name of the employee, the nature of the meeting or similar function, the time and place of travel, the nature of the expenses, and such other information as the Administrator of General Services may prescribe by regulation under subsection (a);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> be submitted not later than May 31 of each year with respect to payments in the preceding period beginning on October 1 and ending on March 31; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> be submitted not later than November 30 of each year with respect to payments in the preceding period beginning on April 1 and ending on September 30.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–194, title III, § 302(a)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-30">Nov. 30, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1745</ref>, § 1352; renumbered § 1353 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–280, § 4(b)(1)</ref>, (c), <date date="1990-05-04">May 4, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 157</ref>, 158.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1354.</num>
<heading> Limitation on use of appropriated funds for contracts with entities not meeting veterans’ employment reporting requirements</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Subject to paragraph (2), no agency may obligate or expend funds appropriated for the agency for a fiscal year to enter into a contract described in <ref>section 4212(a) of title 38</ref> with a contractor from which a report was required under section 4212(d) of that title with respect to the preceding fiscal year if such contractor did not submit such report.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Paragraph (1) shall cease to apply with respect to a contractor otherwise covered by that paragraph on the date on which the contractor submits the report required by such section 4212(d) for the fiscal year concerned.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Labor shall make available in a database a list of the contractors that have complied with the provisions of such section 4212(d).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 105–339, § 7(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-31">Oct. 31, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3189</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1355.</num>
<heading> Prohibition on use of funds for portraits</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> No funds appropriated or otherwise made available to the Federal Government may be used to pay for the painting of a portrait of an officer or employee of the Federal Government, including the President, the Vice President, a Member of Congress, the head of an executive agency, or the head of an office of the legislative branch.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> In this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “executive agency” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 133 of title 41</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “Member of Congress” includes a Delegate or Resident Commissioner to Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–158, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-03-27">Mar. 27, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1242</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>