<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 51—</num>
<heading>COINS AND CURRENCY</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>MONETARY SYSTEM</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5101.</num>
<heading> Decimal system</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">United States money is expressed in dollars, dimes or tenths, cents or hundreths,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002076">1</ref> and mills or thousandths. A dime is a tenth of a dollar, a cent is a hundredth of a dollar, and a mill is a thousandth of a dollar.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 980</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5102.</num>
<heading> Standard weight</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The standard troy pound of the National Institute of Standards and Technology of the Department of Commerce shall be the standard used to ensure that the weight of United States coins conforms to specifications in <ref>section 5112 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 980</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title V, § 5115(c)</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1433</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5103.</num>
<heading> Legal tender</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">United States coins and currency (including Federal reserve notes and circulating notes of Federal reserve banks and national banks) are legal tender for all debts, public charges, taxes, and dues. Foreign gold or silver coins are not legal tender for debts.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 980</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–452, § 1(19)</ref>, <date date="1983-01-12">Jan. 12, 1983</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2477</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>GENERAL AUTHORITY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5111.</num>
<heading> Minting and issuing coins, medals, and numismatic items</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of the Treasury—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall mint and issue coins described in <ref>section 5112 of this title</ref> in amounts the Secretary decides are necessary to meet the needs of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> may prepare national medal dies and strike national and other medals if it does not interfere with regular minting operations but may not prepare private medal dies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> may prepare and distribute numismatic items; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> may mint coins for a foreign country if the minting does not interfere with regular minting operations, and shall prescribe a charge for minting the foreign coins equal to the cost of the minting (including labor, materials, and the use of machinery).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Department of the Treasury has a coinage metal fund and a coinage profit fund. The Secretary may use the coinage metal fund to buy metal to mint coins. The Secretary shall credit the coinage profit fund with the amount by which the nominal value of the coins minted from the metal exceeds the cost of the metal. The Secretary shall charge the coinage profit fund with waste incurred in minting coins and the cost of distributing the coins, including the cost of coin bags and pallets. The Secretary shall deposit in the Treasury as miscellaneous receipts excess amounts in the coinage profit fund.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Procurements Relating to Coin Production.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may make contracts, on conditions the Secretary decides are appropriate and are in the public interest, to acquire articles, materials, supplies, and services (including equipment, manufacturing facilities, patents, patent rights, technical knowledge, and assistance) necessary to produce the coins referred to in this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Domestic control of coinage</inline>.—</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Subject to subparagraph (B), in order to protect the national security through domestic control of the coinage process, the Secretary shall acquire only such articles, materials, supplies, and services (including equipment, manufacturing facilities, patents, patent rights, technical knowledge, and assistance) for the production of coins as have been produced or manufactured in the United States unless the Secretary determines it to be inconsistent with the public interest, or the cost to be unreasonable, and publishes in the Federal Register a written finding stating the basis for the determination.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Subparagraph (A) shall apply only in the case of a bid or offer from a supplier the principal place of business of which is in a foreign country which does not accord to United States companies the same competitive opportunities for procurements in connection with the production of coins as it accords to domestic companies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Determination.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any determination of the Secretary referred to in paragraph (2) shall not be reviewable in any administrative proceeding or court of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Other rights unaffected</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This paragraph does not alter or annul any right of review that arises under any provision of any law or regulation of the United States other than paragraph (2).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Nothing in paragraph (2) of this subsection in any way affects the procurement by the Secretary of gold and silver for the production of coins by the United States Mint.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary may prohibit or limit the exportation, melting, or treatment of United States coins when the Secretary decides the prohibition or limitation is necessary to protect the coinage of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A person knowingly violating an order or license issued or regulation prescribed under paragraph (1) of this subsection, shall be fined not more than $10,000, imprisoned not more than 5 years, or both.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Coins exported, melted, or treated in violation of an order or license issued or regulation prescribed, and metal resulting from the melting or treatment, shall be forfeited to the United States Government. The powers of the Secretary and the remedies available to enforce forfeitures are those provided in part II of subchapter C of chapter 75 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1954 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002077">1</ref> (<ref>26 U.S.C. 7321</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 980</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–274, § 3</ref>, <date date="1988-03-31">Mar. 31, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 49</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–390, title II, § 222</ref>, <date date="1992-10-06">Oct. 6, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 1629</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5112.</num>
<heading> Denominations, specifications, and design of coins</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of the Treasury may mint and issue only the following coins:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a dollar coin that is 1.043 inches in diameter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a half dollar coin that is 1.205 inches in diameter and weighs 11.34 grams.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a quarter dollar coin that is 0.955 inch in diameter and weighs 5.67 grams.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> a dime coin that is 0.705 inch in diameter and weighs 2.268 grams.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> a 5-cent coin that is 0.835 inch in diameter and weighs 5 grams.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> except as provided under subsection (c) of this section, a one-cent coin that is 0.75 inch in diameter and weighs 3.11 grams.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> A fifty dollar gold coin that is 32.7 millimeters in diameter, weighs 33.931 grams, and contains one troy ounce of fine gold.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> A twenty-five dollar gold coin that is 27.0 millimeters in diameter, weighs 16.966 grams, and contains one-half troy ounce of fine gold.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> A ten dollar gold coin that is 22.0 millimeters in diameter, weighs 8.483 grams, and contains one-fourth troy ounce of fine gold.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> A five dollar gold coin that is 16.5 millimeters in diameter, weighs 3.393 grams, and contains one-tenth troy ounce of fine gold.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> A $50 gold coin that is of an appropriate size and thickness, as determined by the Secretary, weighs 1 ounce, and contains 99.99 percent pure gold.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> A $25 coin of an appropriate size and thickness, as determined by the Secretary, that weighs 1 troy ounce and contains .9995 fine palladium.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The half dollar, quarter dollar, and dime coins are clad coins with 3 layers of metal. The 2 identical outer layers are an alloy of 75 percent copper and 25 percent nickel. The inner layer is copper. The outer layers are metallurgically bonded to the inner layer and weigh at least 30 percent of the weight of the coin. The dollar coin shall be golden in color, have a distinctive edge, have tactile and visual features that make the denomination of the coin readily discernible, be minted and fabricated in the United States, and have similar metallic, anti-counterfeiting properties as United States coinage in circulation on the date of enactment of the United States $1 Coin Act of 1997. The 5-cent coin is an alloy of 75 percent copper and 25 percent nickel. In minting 5-cent coins, the Secretary shall use bars that vary not more than 2.5 percent from the percent of nickel required. Except as provided under subsection (c) of this section, the one-cent coin is an alloy of 95 percent copper and 5 percent zinc. In minting gold coins, the Secretary shall use alloys that vary not more than 0.1 percent from the percent of gold required. The specifications for alloys are by weight.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Secretary may prescribe the weight and the composition of copper and zinc in the alloy of the one-cent coin that the Secretary decides are appropriate when the Secretary decides that a different weight and alloy of copper and zinc are necessary to ensure an adequate supply of one-cent coins to meet the needs of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> United States coins shall have the inscription “In God We Trust”. The obverse side of each coin shall have the inscription “Liberty”. The reverse side of each coin shall have the inscriptions “United States of America” and “E Pluribus Unum” and a designation of the value of the coin. The design on the reverse side of the dollar, half dollar, and quarter dollar is an eagle. Subject to other provisions of this subsection, the obverse of any 5-cent coin issued after <date date="2005-12-31">December 31, 2005</date>, shall bear the likeness of Thomas Jefferson and the reverse of any such 5-cent coin shall bear an image of the home of Thomas Jefferson at Monticello. The Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Congress, shall select appropriate designs for the obverse and reverse sides of the dollar coin. The coins have an inscription of the year of minting or issuance. However, to prevent or alleviate a shortage of a denomination, the Secretary may inscribe coins of the denomination with the year that was last inscribed on coins of the denomination.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall prepare the devices, models, hubs, and dies for coins, emblems, devices, inscriptions, and designs authorized under this chapter. The Secretary may, after consulting with the Citizens Coinage Advisory Committee and the Commission of Fine Arts, adopt and prepare new designs or models of emblems or devices that are authorized in the same way as when new coins or devices are authorized. The Secretary may change the design or die of a coin only once within 25 years of the first adoption of the design, model, hub, or die for that coin. The Secretary may procure services under <ref>section 3109 of title 5</ref> in carrying out this paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<chapeau> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary shall mint and issue, in qualities and quantities that the Secretary determines are sufficient to meet public demand, coins which—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> are 40.6 millimeters in diameter and weigh 31.103 grams;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> contain .999 fine silver;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> have a design—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> symbolic of Liberty on the obverse side; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> of an eagle on the reverse side;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> have inscriptions of the year of minting or issuance, and the words “Liberty”, “In God We Trust”, “United States of America”, “1 Oz. Fine Silver”, “E Pluribus Unum”, and “One Dollar”; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> have reeded edges.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Silver Coins.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Sale price</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall sell the coins minted under subsection (e) to the public at a price equal to the market value of the bullion at the time of sale, plus the cost of minting, marketing, and distributing such coins (including labor, materials, dies, use of machinery, and promotional and overhead expenses).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Bulk sales</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall make bulk sales of the coins minted under subsection (e) at a reasonable discount.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Numismatic items</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of <ref>section 5132(a)(1) of this title</ref>, all coins minted under subsection (e) shall be considered to be numismatic items.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> For purposes of <ref>section 5132(a)(1) of this title</ref>, all coins minted under subsection (e) of this section shall be considered to be numismatic items.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<content> The coins issued under this title shall be legal tender as provided in <ref>section 5103 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Notwithstanding <ref>section 5111(a)(1) of this title</ref>, the Secretary shall mint and issue the gold coins described in paragraphs (7), (8), (9), and (10) of subsection (a) of this section, in qualities and quantities that the Secretary determines are sufficient to meet public demand, and such gold coins shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> have a design determined by the Secretary, except that the fifty dollar gold coin shall have—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> on the obverse side, a design symbolic of Liberty; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> on the reverse side, a design representing a family of eagles, with the male carrying an olive branch and flying above a nest containing a female eagle and hatchlings;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> have inscriptions of the denomination, the weight of the fine gold content, the year of minting or issuance, and the words “Liberty”, “In God We Trust”, “United States of America”, and “E Pluribus Unum”; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> have reeded edges.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall sell the coins minted under this subsection to the public at a price equal to the market value of the bullion at the time of sale, plus the cost of minting, marketing, and distributing such coins (including labor, materials, dies, use of machinery, and promotional and overhead expenses).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall make bulk sales of the coins minted under this subsection at a reasonable discount.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> For purposes of <ref>section 5132(a)(1) of this title</ref>, all coins minted under this subsection shall be considered to be numismatic items.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law and subject to subparagraph (B), the Secretary of the Treasury may change the diameter, weight, or design of any coin minted under this subsection or the fineness of the gold in the alloy of any such coin if the Secretary determines that the specific diameter, weight, design, or fineness of gold which differs from that otherwise required by law is appropriate for such coin.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Secretary may not mint any coin with respect to which a determination has been made by the Secretary under subparagraph (A) before the end of the 30-day period beginning on the date a notice of such determination is published in the Federal Register.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The Secretary may continue to mint and issue coins in accordance with the specifications contained in paragraphs (7), (8), (9), and (10) of subsection (a) and paragraph (1)(A) of this subsection at the same time the Secretary in minting and issuing other bullion and proof gold coins under this subsection in accordance with such program procedures and coin specifications, designs, varieties, quantities, denominations, and inscriptions as the Secretary, in the Secretary’s discretion, may prescribe from time to time.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">General Waiver of Procurement Regulations.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in paragraph (2), no provision of law governing procurement or public contracts shall be applicable to the procurement of goods or services necessary for minting, marketing, or issuing any coin authorized under paragraph (7), (8), (9), or (10) of subsection (a) or subsection (e), including any proof version of any such coin.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Equal employment opportunity</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Paragraph (1) shall not relieve any person entering into a contract with respect to any coin referred to in such paragraph from complying with any law relating to equal employment opportunity.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(k)</num>
<content> The Secretary may mint and issue platinum bullion coins and proof platinum coins in accordance with such specifications, designs, varieties, quantities, denominations, and inscriptions as the Secretary, in the Secretary’s discretion, may prescribe from time to time.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(l)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Redesign and Issuance of Quarter Dollar in Commemoration of Each of the</inline> 50 <inline class="small-caps">States.—</inline></heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Redesign beginning in 1999.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding the fourth sentence of subsection (d)(1) and subsection (d)(2), quarter dollar coins issued during the 10-year period beginning in 1999, shall have designs on the reverse side selected in accordance with this subsection which are emblematic of the 50 States.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transition provision</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding subparagraph (A), the Secretary may continue to mint and issue quarter dollars in 1999 which bear the design in effect before the redesign required under this subsection and an inscription of the year “1998” as required to ensure a smooth transition into the 10-year program under this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Flexibility with regard to placement of inscriptions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Notwithstanding subsection (d)(1), the Secretary may select a design for quarter dollars issued during the 10-year period referred to in subparagraph (A) in which—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the inscription described in the second sentence of subsection (d)(1) appears on the reverse side of any such quarter dollars; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any inscription described in the third sentence of subsection (d)(1) or the designation of the value of the coin appears on the obverse side of any such quarter dollars.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Single state designs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The design on the reverse side of each quarter dollar issued during the 10-year period referred to in paragraph (1) shall be emblematic of 1 of the 50 States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Issuance of coins commemorating 5 states during each of the 10 years.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The designs for the quarter dollar coins issued during each year of the 10-year period referred to in paragraph (1) shall be emblematic of 5 States selected in the order in which such States ratified the Constitution of the United States or were admitted into the Union, as the case may be.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Number of each of 5 coin designs in each year</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Of the quarter dollar coins issued during each year of the 10-year period referred to in paragraph (1), the Secretary of the Treasury shall prescribe, on the basis of such factors as the Secretary determines to be appropriate, the number of quarter dollars which shall be issued with each of the 5 designs selected for such year.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Selection of design.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each of the 50 designs required under this subsection for quarter dollars shall be—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> selected by the Secretary after consultation with—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the Governor of the State being commemorated, or such other State officials or group as the State may designate for such purpose; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the Commission of Fine Arts; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> reviewed by the Citizens Coinage Advisory Committee.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Selection and approval process</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Designs for quarter dollars may be submitted in accordance with the design selection and approval process developed by the Secretary in the sole discretion of the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Participation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may include participation by State officials, artists from the States, engravers of the United States Mint, and members of the general public.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Standards</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Because it is important that the Nation’s coinage and currency bear dignified designs of which the citizens of the United States can be proud, the Secretary shall not select any frivolous or inappropriate design for any quarter dollar minted under this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition on certain representations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No head and shoulders portrait or bust of any person, living or dead, and no portrait of a living person may be included in the design of any quarter dollar under this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Treatment as numismatic items</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of sections 5134 and 5136, all coins minted under this subsection shall be considered to be numismatic items.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Issuance.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Quality of coins</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may mint and issue such number of quarter dollars of each design selected under paragraph (4) in uncirculated and proof qualities as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Silver coins</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding subsection (b), the Secretary may mint and issue such number of quarter dollars of each design selected under paragraph (4) as the Secretary determines to be appropriate, with a content of 90 percent silver and 10 percent copper.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Sources of bullion</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall obtain silver for minting coins under subparagraph (B) from available resources, including stockpiles established under the Strategic and Critical Materials Stock Piling Act.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Application in event of the admission of additional states</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If any additional State is admitted into the Union before the end of the 10-year period referred to in paragraph (1), the Secretary of the Treasury may issue quarter dollar coins, in accordance with this subsection, with a design which is emblematic of such State during any 1 year of such 10-year period, in addition to the quarter dollar coins issued during such year in accordance with paragraph (3)(A).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(m)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Commemorative Coin Program Restrictions.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Maximum number</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Beginning <date date="1999-01-01">January 1, 1999</date>, the Secretary may mint and issue commemorative coins under this section during any calendar year with respect to not more than 2 commemorative coin programs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Mintage levels.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), in carrying out any commemorative coin program, the Secretary shall mint—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> not more than 750,000 clad half-dollar coins;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> not more than 500,000 silver one-dollar coins; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> not more than 100,000 gold five-dollar or ten-dollar coins.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the Secretary determines, based on independent, market-based research conducted by a designated recipient organization of a commemorative coin program, that the mintage levels described in subparagraph (A) are not adequate to meet public demand for that commemorative coin, the Secretary may waive one or more of the requirements of subparagraph (A) with respect to that commemorative coin program.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designated recipient organization defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of this paragraph, the term “designated recipient organization” means any organization designated, under any provision of law, as the recipient of any surcharge imposed on the sale of any numismatic item.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(n)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Redesign and Issuance of Circulating</inline> $1 <inline class="small-caps">Coins Honoring Each of the Presidents of the United States.—</inline></heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Redesign beginning in 2007</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Notwithstanding subsection (d) and in accordance with the provisions of this subsection, $1 coins issued during the period beginning <date date="2007-01-01">January 1, 2007</date>, and ending upon the termination of the program under paragraph (8), shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> have designs on the obverse selected in accordance with paragraph (2)(B) which are emblematic of the Presidents of the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> have a design on the reverse selected in accordance with paragraph (2)(A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Design requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The $1 coins issued in accordance with paragraph (1)(A) shall meet the following design requirements:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Coin reverse</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The design on the reverse shall bear—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a likeness of the Statue of Liberty extending to the rim of the coin and large enough to provide a dramatic representation of Liberty while not being large enough to create the impression of a “2-headed” coin;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the inscription “$1”; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the inscription “United States of America”.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Coin obverse</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The design on the obverse shall contain—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the name and likeness of a President of the United States; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> basic information about the President, including—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the dates or years of the term of office of such President; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> a number indicating the order of the period of service in which the President served.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Edge-incused inscriptions.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The inscription of the year of minting or issuance of the coin and the inscription “E Pluribus Unum” shall be edge-incused into the coin.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Preservation of distinctive edge</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The edge-incusing of the inscriptions under clause (i) on coins issued under this subsection shall be done in a manner that preserves the distinctive edge of the coin so that the denomination of the coin is readily discernible, including by individuals who are blind or visually impaired.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inscriptions of “liberty”</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding the second sentence of subsection (d)(1), because the use of a design bearing the likeness of the Statue of Liberty on the reverse of the coins issued under this subsection adequately conveys the concept of Liberty, the inscription of “Liberty” shall not appear on the coins.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation in series to deceased presidents</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No coin issued under this subsection may bear the image of a living former or current President, or of any deceased former President during the 2-year period following the date of the death of that President.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inscription of “in god we trust”</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The design on the obverse or the reverse shall bear the inscription “In God We Trust”.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Issuance of coins commemorating presidents.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Order of issuance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The coins issued under this subsection commemorating Presidents of the United States shall be issued in the order of the period of service of each President, beginning with President George Washington.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Treatment of period of service.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to clause (ii), only 1 coin design shall be issued for a period of service for any President, no matter how many consecutive terms of office the President served.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Nonconsecutive terms</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If a President has served during 2 or more nonconsecutive periods of service, a coin shall be issued under this subsection for each such nonconsecutive period of service.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Issuance of coins commemorating 4 presidents during each year of the period.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The designs for the $1 coins issued during each year of the period referred to in paragraph (1) shall be emblematic of 4 Presidents until each President has been so honored, subject to paragraph (2)(E).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Number of 4 circulating coin designs in each year</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall prescribe, on the basis of such factors as the Secretary determines to be appropriate, the number of $1 coins that shall be issued with each of the designs selected for each year of the period referred to in paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Legal tender</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The coins minted under this title shall be legal tender, as provided in section 5103.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Treatment as numismatic items</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of section <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002078">1</ref> 5134 and 5136, all coins minted under this subsection shall be considered to be numismatic items.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Issuance of numismatic coins</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may mint and issue such number of $1 coins of each design selected under this subsection in uncirculated and proof qualities as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Termination of program</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The issuance of coins under this subsection shall terminate when each President has been so honored, subject to paragraph (2)(E), and may not be resumed except by an Act of Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reversion to preceding design</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Upon the termination of the issuance of coins under this subsection, the design of all $1 coins shall revert to the so-called “Sacagawea-design” $1 coins.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(o)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">First Spouse Bullion Coin Program.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>During the same period described in subsection (n), the Secretary shall issue bullion coins under this subsection that are emblematic of the spouse of each such President.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Specifications</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The coins issued under this subsection shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> have the same diameter as the $1 coins described in subsection (n);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> weigh 0.5 ounce; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> contain 99.99 percent pure gold.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Design requirements.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Coin obverse</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The design on the obverse of each coin issued under this subsection shall contain—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the name and likeness of a person who was a spouse of a President during the President’s period of service;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> an inscription of the years during which such person was the spouse of a President during the President’s period of service; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a number indicating the order of the period of service in which such President served.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Coin reverse</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The design on the reverse of each coin issued under this subsection shall bear—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> images emblematic of the life and work of the First Spouse whose image is borne on the obverse; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the inscription “United States of America”.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designated denomination</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each coin issued under this subsection shall bear, on the reverse, an inscription of the nominal denomination of the coin which shall be “$10”.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Design in case of no first spouse</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In the case of any President who served without a spouse—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> the image on the obverse of the bullion coin corresponding to the $1 coin relating to such President shall be an image emblematic of the concept of “Liberty”—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> as represented on a United States coin issued during the period of service of such President; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> as represented, in the case of President Chester Alan Arthur, by a design incorporating the name and likeness of Alice Paul, a leading strategist in the suffrage movement, who was instrumental in gaining women the right to vote upon the adoption of the 19th amendment and thus the ability to participate in the election of future Presidents, and who was born on <date date="1885-01-11">January 11, 1885</date>, during the term of President Arthur; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the reverse of such bullion coin shall be of a design representative of themes of such President, except that in the case of the bullion coin referred to in clause (i)(II) the reverse of such coin shall be representative of the suffrage movement.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Design and coin for each spouse</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A separate coin shall be designed and issued under this section for each person who was the spouse of a President during any portion of a term of office of such President.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inscriptions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each bullion coin issued under this subsection shall bear the inscription of the year of minting or issuance of the coin and such other inscriptions as the Secretary may determine to be appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Sale of bullion coins</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each bullion coin issued under this subsection shall be sold by the Secretary at a price that is equal to or greater than the sum of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the face value of the coins; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the cost of designing and issuing the coins (including labor, materials, dies, use of machinery, overhead expenses, marketing, and shipping).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Issuance of coins commemorating first spouses.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The bullion coins issued under this subsection with respect to any spouse of a President shall be issued on the same schedule as the $1 coin issued under subsection (n) with respect to each such President.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Maximum number of bullion coins for each design</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> prescribe, on the basis of such factors as the Secretary determines to be appropriate, the maximum number of bullion coins that shall be issued with each of the designs selected under this subsection; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> announce, before the issuance of the bullion coins of each such design, the maximum number of bullion coins of that design that will be issued.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Termination of program</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No bullion coin may be issued under this subsection after the termination, in accordance with subsection (n)(8), of the $1 coin program established under subsection (n).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Quality of coins</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The bullion coins minted under this Act shall be issued in both proof and uncirculated qualities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Source of gold bullion.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall acquire gold for the coins issued under this subsection by purchase of gold mined from natural deposits in the United States, or in a territory or possession of the United States, within 1 year after the month in which the ore from which it is derived was mined.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Price of gold</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall pay not more than the average world price for the gold mined under subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Bronze medals</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may strike and sell bronze medals that bear the likeness of the bullion coins authorized under this subsection, at a price, size, and weight, and with such inscriptions, as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Legal tender</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The coins minted under this title shall be legal tender, as provided in section 5103.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Treatment as numismatic items</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of section <sup>1</sup> 5134 and 5136, all coins minted under this subsection shall be considered to be numismatic items.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(p)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Removal of Barriers to Circulation of</inline> $1 <inline class="small-caps">Coin.—</inline></heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Acceptance by agencies and instrumentalities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Beginning <date date="2006-01-01">January 1, 2006</date>, all agencies and instrumentalities of the United States, the United States Postal Service, all nonappropriated fund instrumentalities established under title 10, and all transit systems that receive operational subsidies or any disbursement of funds from the Federal Government, such as funds from the Federal Highway Trust Fund, including the Mass Transit Account, shall take such action as may be appropriate to ensure that by the end of the 2-year period beginning on such date—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> any business operations conducted by any such agency, instrumentality, system, or entity that involve coins or currency will be fully capable of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> accepting $1 coins in connection with such operations; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> other than vending machines that do not receive currency denominations higher than $1, dispensing $1 coins in connection with such operations; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> display signs and notices denoting such capability on the premises where coins or currency are accepted or dispensed, including on each vending machine.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">This paragraph does not apply with respect to business operations conducted by any entity under a contract with an agency or instrumentality of the United States, including with any nonappropriated fund instrumentality established under title 10.</continuation>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Publicity</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Director of the United States Mint,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002079">2</ref> shall work closely with consumer groups, media outlets, and schools to ensure an adequate amount of news coverage, and other means of increasing public awareness, of the inauguration of the Presidential $1 Coin Program established in subsection (n) to ensure that consumers know of the availability of the coin.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Coordination</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System and the Secretary shall take steps to ensure that an adequate supply of $1 coins is available for commerce and collectors at such places and in such quantities as are appropriate by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> consulting, to accurately gauge demand for coins and to anticipate and eliminate obstacles to the easy and efficient distribution and circulation of $1 coins as well as all other circulating coins, from time to time but no less frequently than annually, with a coin users group, which may include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> representatives of merchants who would benefit from the increased usage of $1 coins;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> vending machine and other coin acceptor manufacturers;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> vending machine owners and operators;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> transit officials;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> municipal parking officials;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> depository institutions;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> coin and currency handlers;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> armored-car operators;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ix)</num>
<content> car wash operators; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(x)</num>
<content> coin collectors and dealers;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> submitting an annual report to the Congress containing—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an assessment of the remaining obstacles to the efficient and timely circulation of coins, particularly $1 coins;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> an assessment of the extent to which the goals of subparagraph (C) are being met; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> such recommendations for legislative action the Board and the Secretary may determine to be appropriate;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> consulting with industry representatives to encourage operators of vending machines and other automated coin-accepting devices in the United States to accept coins issued under the Presidential $1 Coin Program established under subsection (n) and any coins bearing any design in effect before the issuance of coins required under subsection (n) (including the so-called “Sacagawea-design” $1 coins), and to include notices on the machines and devices of such acceptability;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> ensuring that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> during an introductory period, all institutions that want unmixed supplies of each newly-issued design of $1 coins minted under subsections (n) and (<i>o</i>) are able to obtain such unmixed supplies; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> circulating coins will be available for ordinary commerce in packaging of sizes and types appropriate for and useful to ordinary commerce, including rolled coins;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> working closely with any agency, instrumentality, system, or entity referred to in paragraph (1) to facilitate compliance with the requirements of such paragraph; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> identifying, analyzing, and overcoming barriers to the robust circulation of $1 coins minted under subsections (n) and (<i>o</i>), including the use of demand prediction, improved methods of distribution and circulation, and improved public education and awareness campaigns.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Bullion dealers</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Director of the United States Mint shall take all steps necessary to ensure that a maximum number of reputable, reliable, and responsible dealers are qualified to offer for sale all bullion coins struck and issued by the United States Mint.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Review of co-circulation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>At such time as the Secretary determines to be appropriate, and after consultation with the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Secretary shall notify the Congress of its assessment of issues related to the co-circulation of any circulating $1 coin bearing any design, other than the so-called “Sacagawea-design” $1 coin, in effect before the issuance of coins required under subsection (n), including the effect of co-circulation on the acceptance and use of $1 coins, and make recommendations to the Congress for improving the circulation of $1 coins.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(q)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Gold Bullion Coins.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of the Presidential $1 Coin Act of 2005, the Secretary shall commence striking and issuing for sale such number of $50 gold bullion and proof coins as the Secretary may determine to be appropriate, in such quantities, as the Secretary, in the Secretary’s discretion, may prescribe.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Initial design.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided under subparagraph (B), the obverse and reverse of the gold bullion coins struck under this subsection during the first year of issuance shall bear the original designs by James Earle Fraser, which appear on the 5-cent coin commonly referred to as the “Buffalo nickel” or the “1913 Type 1”.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Variations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The coins referred to in subparagraph (A) shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> have inscriptions of the weight of the coin and the nominal denomination of the coin incused in that portion of the design on the reverse of the coin commonly known as the “grassy mound”; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> bear such other inscriptions as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Source of gold bullion.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall acquire gold for the coins issued under this subsection by purchase of gold mined from natural deposits in the United States, or in a territory or possession of the United States, within 1 year after the month in which the ore from which it is derived was mined.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Price of gold</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall pay not more than the average world price for the gold mined under subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Sale of coins</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each gold bullion coin issued under this subsection shall be sold for an amount the Secretary determines to be appropriate, but not less than the sum of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the market value of the bullion at the time of sale; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the cost of designing and issuing the coins, including labor, materials, dies, use of machinery, overhead expenses, marketing, and shipping.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Legal tender</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The coins minted under this title shall be legal tender, as provided in section 5103.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Treatment as numismatic items</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of section <sup>1</sup> 5134 and 5136, all coins minted under this subsection shall be considered to be numismatic items.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(r)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Redesign and Issuance of Circulating</inline> $1 <inline class="small-caps">Coins Honoring Native Americans and the Important Contributions Made by Indian Tribes and Individual Native Americans in United States History.—</inline></heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Redesign beginning in 2008.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Effective beginning <date date="2008-01-01">January 1, 2008</date>, notwithstanding subsection (d), in addition to the coins to be issued pursuant to subsection (n), and in accordance with this subsection, the Secretary shall mint and issue $1 coins that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> have as the designs on the obverse the so-called “Sacagawea design”; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> have a design on the reverse selected in accordance with paragraph (2)(A), subject to paragraph (3)(A).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Delayed date</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the date of the enactment of the Native American $1 Coin Act is after <date date="2007-08-25">August 25, 2007</date>, subparagraph (A) shall be applied by substituting “2009” for “2008”.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Design requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The $1 coins issued in accordance with paragraph (1) shall meet the following design requirements:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Coin reverse</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The design on the reverse shall bear—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> images celebrating the important contributions made by Indian tribes and individual Native Americans to the development of the United States and the history of the United States;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the inscription “$1”; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the inscription “United States of America”.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Coin obverse</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The design on the obverse shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> be chosen by the Secretary, after consultation with the Commission of Fine Arts and review by the Citizens Coinage Advisory Committee; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> contain the so-called “Sacagawea design” and the inscription “Liberty”.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Edge-incused inscriptions.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The inscription of the year of minting and issuance of the coin and the inscription “E Pluribus Unum” shall be edge-incused into the coin.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Preservation of distinctive edge</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The edge-incusing of the inscriptions under clause (i) on coins issued under this subsection shall be done in a manner that preserves the distinctive edge of the coin so that the denomination of the coin is readily discernible, including by individuals who are blind or visually impaired.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reverse design selection</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The designs selected for the reverse of the coins described under this subsection—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> shall be chosen by the Secretary after consultation with the Committee on Indian Affairs of the Senate, the Congressional Native American Caucus of the House of Representatives, the Commission of Fine Arts, and the National Congress of American Indians;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> shall be reviewed by the Citizens Coinage Advisory Committee;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> may depict individuals and events such as—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the creation of Cherokee written language;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the Iroquois Confederacy;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> Wampanoag Chief Massasoit;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> the “Pueblo Revolt”;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(V)</num>
<content> Olympian Jim Thorpe;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(VI)</num>
<content> Ely S. Parker, a general on the staff of General Ulysses S. Grant and later head of the Bureau of Indian Affairs; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(VII)</num>
<content> code talkers who served the United States Armed Forces during World War I and World War II; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> in the case of a design depicting the contribution of an individual Native American to the development of the United States and the history of the United States, shall not depict the individual in a size such that the coin could be considered to be a “2-headed” coin.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inscription of “in god we trust”</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The design on the obverse or the reverse shall bear the inscription “In God We Trust”.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Issuance of coins commemorating 1 native american event during each year.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each design for the reverse of the $1 coins issued during each year shall be emblematic of 1 important Native American or Native American contribution each year.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Issuance period</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each $1 coin minted with a design on the reverse in accordance with this subsection for any year shall be issued during the 1-year period beginning on January 1 of that year and shall be available throughout the entire 1-year period.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Order of issuance of designs</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each coin issued under this subsection commemorating Native Americans and their contributions—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> shall be issued, to the maximum extent practicable, in the chronological order in which the Native Americans lived or the events occurred, until the termination of the coin program described in subsection (n); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> thereafter shall be issued in any order determined to be appropriate by the Secretary, after consultation with the Committee on Indian Affairs of the Senate, the Congressional Native American Caucus of the House of Representatives, and the National Congress of American Indians.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Issuance of numismatic coins</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may mint and issue such number of $1 coins of each design selected under this subsection in uncirculated and proof qualities as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Quantity</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The number of $1 coins minted and issued in a year with the Sacagawea-design on the obverse shall be not less than 20 percent of the total number of $1 coins minted and issued in such year.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(s)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Redesign and Issuance of Circulating Quarter Dollar Honoring the District of Columbia and Each of the Territories.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Redesign in 2009.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding the fourth sentence of subsection (d)(1) and subsection (d)(2) and subject to paragraph (6)(B), quarter dollar coins issued during 2009, shall have designs on the reverse side selected in accordance with this subsection which are emblematic of the District of Columbia and the territories.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Flexibility with regard to placement of inscriptions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Notwithstanding subsection (d)(1), the Secretary may select a design for quarter dollars issued during 2009 in which—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the inscription described in the second sentence of subsection (d)(1) appears on the reverse side of any such quarter dollars; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any inscription described in the third sentence of subsection (d)(1) or the designation of the value of the coin appears on the obverse side of any such quarter dollars.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Single district or territory design</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The design on the reverse side of each quarter dollar issued during 2009 shall be emblematic of one of the following: The District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the United States Virgin Islands, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Selection of design.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each of the 6 designs required under this subsection for quarter dollars shall be—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> selected by the Secretary after consultation with—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the chief executive of the District of Columbia or the territory being honored, or such other officials or group as the chief executive officer of the District of Columbia or the territory may designate for such purpose; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the Commission of Fine Arts; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> reviewed by the Citizens Coinage Advisory Committee.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Selection and approval process</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Designs for quarter dollars may be submitted in accordance with the design selection and approval process developed by the Secretary in the sole discretion of the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Participation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may include participation by District or territorial officials, artists from the District of Columbia or the territory, engravers of the United States Mint, and members of the general public.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Standards</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Because it is important that the Nation’s coinage and currency bear dignified designs of which the citizens of the United States can be proud, the Secretary shall not select any frivolous or inappropriate design for any quarter dollar minted under this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition on certain representations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No head and shoulders portrait or bust of any person, living or dead, and no portrait of a living person may be included in the design of any quarter dollar under this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Treatment as numismatic items</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of sections 5134 and 5136, all coins minted under this subsection shall be considered to be numismatic items.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Issuance.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Quality of coins</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may mint and issue such number of quarter dollars of each design selected under paragraph (3) in uncirculated and proof qualities as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Silver coins</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding subsection (b), the Secretary may mint and issue such number of quarter dollars of each design selected under paragraph (3) as the Secretary determines to be appropriate, with a content of 90 percent silver and 10 percent copper.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Timing and order of issuance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Coins minted under this subsection honoring the District of Columbia and each of the territories shall be issued in equal sequential intervals during 2009 in the following order: the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the United States Virgin Islands, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Other provisions.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Application in event of admission as a state</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the District of Columbia or any territory becomes a State before the end of the 10-year period referred to in subsection (<i>l</i>)(1), subsection (<i>l</i>)(7) shall apply, and this subsection shall not apply, with respect to such State.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Application in event of independence</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If any territory becomes independent or otherwise ceases to be a territory or possession of the United States before quarter dollars bearing designs which are emblematic of such territory are minted pursuant to this subsection, this subsection shall cease to apply with respect to such territory.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Territory defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of this subsection, the term “territory” means the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the United States Virgin Islands, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(t)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Redesign and Issuance of Quarter Dollars Emblematic of National Sites in Each State, the District of Columbia, and Each Territory.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Redesign beginning upon completion of prior program.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding the fourth sentence of subsection (d)(1) and subsection (d)(2), quarter dollars issued beginning in 2010 shall have designs on the reverse selected in accordance with this subsection which are emblematic of the national sites in the States, the District of Columbia and the territories of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Flexibility with regard to placement of inscriptions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Notwithstanding subsection (d)(1), the Secretary may select a design for quarter dollars referred to in subparagraph (A) in which—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the inscription described in the second sentence of subsection (d)(1) appears on the reverse side of any such quarter dollars; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any inscription described in the third sentence of subsection (d)(1) or the designation of the value of the coin appears on the obverse side of any such quarter dollars.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inclusion of district of columbia, and territories</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of this subsection, the term “State” has the same meaning as in section 3(a)(3) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Single site in each state</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The design on the reverse side of each quarter dollar issued during the period of issuance under this subsection shall be emblematic of 1 national site in each State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Selection of site and design.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Site.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The selection of a national park or other national site in each State to be honored with a coin under this subsection shall be made by the Secretary of the Treasury, after consultation with the Secretary of the Interior and the governor or other chief executive of each State with respect to which a coin is to be issued under this subsection, and after giving full and thoughtful consideration to national sites that are not under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Interior so that the national site chosen for each State shall be the most appropriate in terms of natural or historic significance.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Timing</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The selection process under clause (i) shall be completed before the end of the 270-day period beginning on the date of the enactment of the America’s Beautiful National Parks Quarter Dollar Coin Act of 2008.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Design</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each of the designs required under this subsection for quarter dollars shall be—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> selected by the Secretary after consultation with—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the Secretary of the Interior; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the Commission of Fine Arts; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> reviewed by the Citizens Coinage Advisory Committee.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Selection and approval process</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Recommendations for site selections and designs for quarter dollars may be submitted in accordance with the site and design selection and approval process developed by the Secretary in the sole discretion of the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Participation in design</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may include participation by officials of the State, artists from the State, engravers of the United States Mint, and members of the general public.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Standards</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Because it is important that the Nation’s coinage and currency bear dignified designs of which the citizens of the United States can be proud, the Secretary shall not select any frivolous or inappropriate design for any quarter dollar minted under this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition on certain representations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No head and shoulders portrait or bust of any person, living or dead, no portrait of a living person, and no outline or map of a State may be included in the design on the reverse of any quarter dollar under this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Issuance of coins.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Order of issuance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The quarter dollar coins issued under this subsection bearing designs of national sites shall be issued in the order in which the sites selected under paragraph (3) were first established as a national site.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rate of issuance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The quarter dollar coins bearing designs of national sites under this subsection shall be issued at the rate of 5 new designs during each year of the period of issuance under this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Number of each of 5 coin designs in each year</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Of the quarter dollar coins issued during each year of the period of issuance, the Secretary of the Treasury shall prescribe, on the basis of such factors as the Secretary determines to be appropriate, the number of quarter dollars which shall be issued with each of the designs selected for such year.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Treatment as numismatic items</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of sections 5134 and 5136, all coins minted under this subsection shall be considered to be numismatic items.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Issuance.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Quality of coins</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may mint and issue such number of quarter dollars of each design selected under paragraph (3) in uncirculated and proof qualities as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Silver coins</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding subsection (b), the Secretary may mint and issue such number of quarter dollars of each design selected under paragraph (3) as the Secretary determines to be appropriate, with a content of not less than 90 percent silver.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Period of issuance.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to paragraph (2), the program established under this subsection shall continue in effect until a national site in each State has been honored.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Second round at discretion of secretary.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Determination</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may make a determination before the end of the 9-year period beginning when the first quarter dollar is issued under this subsection to continue the period of issuance until a second national site in each State, the District of Columbia, and each territory referred to in this subsection has been honored with a design on a quarter dollar.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice and report</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Within 30 days after making a determination under clause (i), the Secretary shall submit a written report on such determination to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Applicability of provisions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the Secretary makes a determination under clause (i), the provisions of this subsection applicable to site and design selection and approval, the order, timing, and conditions of issuance shall apply in like manner as the initial issuance of quarter dollars under this subsection, except that the issuance of quarter dollars pursuant to such determination bearing the first design shall commence in order immediately following the last issuance of quarter dollars under the first round.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Continuation until all states are honored</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the Secretary makes a determination under clause (i), the program under this subsection shall continue until a second site in each State has been so honored.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designs after end of program</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Upon the completion of the coin program under this subsection, the design on—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the obverse of the quarter dollar shall revert to the same design containing an image of President Washington in effect for the quarter dollar before the institution of the 50-State quarter dollar program; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> notwithstanding the fourth sentence of subsection (d)(1), the reverse of the quarter dollar shall contain an image of General Washington crossing the Delaware River prior to the Battle of Trenton.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">National site</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of this subsection, the term “national site” means any site under the supervision, management, or conservancy of the National Park Service, the United States Forest Service, the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, or any similar department or agency of the Federal Government, including any national park, national monument, national battlefield, national military park, national historical park, national historic site, national lakeshore, seashore, recreation area, parkway, scenic river, or trail and any site in the National Wildlife Refuge System.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Application in event of independence</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If any territory becomes independent or otherwise ceases to be a territory or possession of the United States before quarter dollars bearing designs which are emblematic of such territory are minted pursuant to this subsection, this subsection shall cease to apply with respect to such territory.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(u)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Silver Bullion Investment Product.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary is authorized to strike and make available for sale such number of bullion coins as the Secretary determines to be appropriate that feature the designs of the quarter dollars and half dollars issued under subsections (x), (y), and (z), that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> have a diameter of 3.0 inches and weigh 5.0 ounces;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> contain .999 fine silver;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> have incused into the edge the fineness and weight of the bullion coin; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> bear an inscription of the denomination of such coins, such denominations to be determined by the Secretary as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Fractionals</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary is authorized to mint and issue so-called “fractional” silver bullion coins bearing the designs of the quarter dollars and half dollars issued under subsections (x), (y), and (z) in sizes, weights, fineness, and denominations, and with inscriptions, that the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Availability for sale</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Should the Secretary exercise the Secretary’s discretion to strike bullion coins under this subsection, the bullion coins minted under paragraph (1) shall become available for sale no sooner than the first day of the calendar year in which the corresponding circulating quarter dollar or half dollar is issued.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Continuity</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Until the conclusion of the quarter dollar program authorized under subsection (t), the Secretary shall strike and make available for sale such number of bullion coins as the Secretary determines to be appropriate that are likenesses of the quarter dollars issued under subsection (t).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(v)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Palladium Bullion Investment Coins.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall mint and issue the palladium coins described in paragraph (12) of subsection (a) in such quantities as the Secretary may determine to be appropriate to meet demand.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Source of bullion.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>To the greatest extent possible, the Secretary shall acquire bullion for the palladium coins issued under this subsection by purchase of palladium mined from natural deposits in the United States, or in a territory or possession of the United States, within 1 year after the month in which the ore from which it is derived was mined. If no such palladium is available or if it is not economically feasible to obtain such palladium, the Secretary may obtain palladium for the palladium coins described in paragraph (12) of subsection (a) from other available sources.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Price of bullion</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall pay not more than the average world price for the palladium under subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Sale of coins</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each coin issued under this subsection shall be sold for an amount the Secretary determines to be appropriate, but not less than the sum of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the market value of the bullion at the time of sale; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the cost of designing and issuing the coins, including labor, materials, dies, use of machinery, overhead expenses, marketing, distribution, and shipping.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Treatment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of section 5134 and 5136, all coins minted under this subsection shall be considered to be numismatic items.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Quality</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may issue collectible versions of the coins described in paragraph (1) in both proof and uncirculated versions, except that, should the Secretary determine that it is appropriate to issue proof or uncirculated versions of such coin, the Secretary shall, to the greatest extent possible, ensure that the surface treatment of each year’s proof or uncirculated version differs in some material way from that of the preceding year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Design</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Coins minted and issued under this subsection shall bear designs on the obverse and reverse that are close likenesses of the work of famed American coin designer and medallic artist Adolph Alexander Weinman—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the obverse shall bear a high-relief likeness of the “Winged Liberty” design used on the obverse of the so-called “Mercury dime”;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the reverse shall bear a high-relief version of the reverse design of the 1907 American Institute of Architects medal; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the coin shall bear such other inscriptions, including “Liberty”, “In God We Trust”, “United States of America”, the denomination and weight of the coin and the fineness of the metal, as the Secretary determines to be appropriate and in keeping with the original design.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Mint facility</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any United States mint, other than the United States Mint at West Point, New York, may be used to strike coins minted under this subsection other than any proof version of any such coin. If the Secretary determines that it is appropriate to issue any proof version of such coin, coins of such version shall be struck only at the United States Mint at West Point, New York.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(w)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Redesign and Issuance of </inline>$1<inline class="small-caps"> Coins Honoring Innovation and Innovators From Each State, the District of Columbia, and Each Territory.—</inline></heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Redesign beginning in 2019.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Notwithstanding subsection (d)(1) and subsection (d)(2) and in accordance with the provisions of this subsection, during the 14-year period beginning on <date date="2019-01-01">January 1, 2019</date> (or such later date as provided under subparagraph (B)(ii)), the Secretary of the Treasury shall mint and issue $1 coins to be known as “American Innovation $1 coins”, that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> have designs on the obverse selected in accordance with paragraph (2)(A); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> have a design on the reverse selected in accordance with paragraph (2)(B).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Continuity provisions.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall continue to mint and issue $1 coins honoring Native Americans and their contributions in accordance with subsection (r).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">First coin</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Notwithstanding subparagraph (A), if the Secretary finds that it is feasible and cost-effective, the Secretary may mint and issue a $1 coin in 2018 to introduce the series of coins described in this subsection, that—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> has the obverse described under paragraph (2)(A);</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> has a reverse that bears the inscription “United States of America” and “American Innovators” and a representation of the signature of President George Washington on the first United States patent issued;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> has the edge-incusing described under paragraph (2)(C); and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> the design for which has reviewed by <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002080">3</ref> the Citizens Coinage Advisory Committee.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition of territory</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of this subsection, the term “territory” means the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the United States Virgin Islands, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Design requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Notwithstanding subsection (d)(1) and subsection (d)(2), the $1 coins issued in accordance with paragraph (1)(A) shall meet the following design requirements:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Coin obverse</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The common design on the obverse of each coin issued under this subsection shall contain—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a likeness of the Statue of Liberty extending to the rim of the coin and large enough to provide a dramatic representation of Liberty;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the inscription “$1”; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the inscription “In God We Trust”.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Coin reverse</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The design on the reverse of each coin issued under this subsection shall bear the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> An image or images emblematic of one of the following from one of the 50 States, the District of Columbia, or the territories of the United States:</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> A significant innovation.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> An innovator.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> A group of innovators.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The name of the State, the District of Columbia, or territory, as applicable.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> The inscription “United States of America”.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Edge-incused inscriptions.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The inscription of the year of minting or issuance of the coin, the mint mark, and the inscription “E Pluribus Unum” shall be edge-incused into the coin.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Preservation of distinctive edge</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The edge-incusing of the inscriptions under clause (i) on coins issued under this subsection shall be done in a manner that preserves the distinctive edge of the coin so that the denomination of the coin is readily discernible, including by individuals who are blind or visually impaired.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Issuance of coins commemorating innovation or innovators.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Order of issuance.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The coins issued under this subsection commemorating either an innovation, an individual innovator, or a group of innovators, from each State, the District of Columbia, or a territory shall be issued in the following order:</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">State</inline>.—</heading>
<content>With respect to each State, the coins shall be issued in the order in which the States ratified the Constitution of the United States or were admitted into the Union, as the case may be.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">District of columbia and territories</inline>.—</heading>
<content>After all coins are issued under subclause (I), the coins shall be issued for the District of Columbia and the territories in the following order: the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the United States Virgin Islands, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Application in event of the admission of additional states</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding clause (i), if any additional State is admitted into the Union before the end of the 14-year period referred to in paragraph (1), the Secretary of the Treasury may issue a $1 coin with respect to the additional State in accordance with clause (i)(I).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Application in the event of independence or adding of a territory</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Notwithstanding clause (i)—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> if any territory becomes independent or otherwise ceases to be a territory of the United States before $1 coins are minted pursuant to this subsection, the subsection shall cease to apply with respect to such territory; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> if any new territory is added to the United States, $1 coins shall be issued for such territories in the order in which the new the territories are added, beginning after the $1 coin is issued for the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Issuance of coins commemorating four innovations or innovators during each of 14 years.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Four $1 coin designs as described in this subsection shall be issued during each year of the period referred to in paragraph (1) until 1 coin featuring 1 innovation, an individual innovator, or a group of innovators, from each of the States, the District of Columbia, and territories has been issued.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Number of coins of each design</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall prescribe, on the basis of such factors as the Secretary determines to be appropriate, the number of $1 coins that shall be issued with each of the designs selected for each year of the period referred to in paragraph (1).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Selection of concept and design.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Concept</inline>.—</heading>
<content>With respect to each State, the District of Columbia, and each territory to be honored with a coin under this subsection, the selection of the significant innovation, innovator, or group of innovators to be borne on the reverse of such coin shall be made by the Secretary of the Treasury, after consultation with the Governor or other chief executive of the State, the District of Columbia, or territory with respect to which a coin is to be issued under this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Design</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each of the designs required under this subsection shall be selected by the Secretary after—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> consultation with—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the Governor or other chief executive of the State, the District of Columbia, or territory with respect to which a coin is to be issued under this subsection; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the Commission of Fine Arts; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> review by the Citizens Coinage Advisory Committee.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Selection and approval process</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Proposals for designs for $1 coins under this subsection may be submitted in accordance with the design selection and approval process developed by the Secretary in the sole discretion of the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Standards</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Because it is important that the Nation’s coinage and currency bear dignified designs of which the citizens of the United States can be proud, the Secretary shall not select any frivolous or inappropriate design for any $1 coin minted under this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition on certain representations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No head and shoulders portrait or bust of any person and no portrait of a living person may be included in the design of any coin issued under this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Treatment as numismatic items</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of sections 5134 and 5136, all $1 coins minted under this subsection shall be considered to be numismatic items.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Issuance of numismatic coins</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may mint and issue such number of $1 coins of each design selected under this subsection in uncirculated and proof qualities as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Termination of program</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The issuance of coins under this subsection shall terminate when one innovation, an individual innovator, or a group of innovators, from each State, the District of Columbia, and each territory has been honored and may not be resumed except by an Act of Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(x)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Redesign and Issuance of Quarter Dollars Emblematic of Prominent American Women and Commemorating the </inline>19<inline class="small-caps">th Amendment.—</inline></heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Redesign of quarter dollars beginning in 2022.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Effective beginning <date date="2022-01-01">January 1, 2022</date>, notwithstanding the fourth sentence of subsection (d)(1) and subsection (d)(2), the Secretary of the Treasury shall issue quarter dollars that have designs on the reverse selected in accordance with this subsection which are emblematic of the accomplishment of a prominent American woman.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Flexibility with regard to placement of inscriptions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Notwithstanding subsection (d)(1), the Secretary may select a design for quarter dollars referred to in subparagraph (A) in which—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the inscription described in the second sentence of subsection (d)(1) appears on the reverse side of any such quarter dollar; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any of the inscriptions described in the third sentence of subsection (d)(1) or the designation of the value of the coin appear on the obverse side of any such quarter dollar.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Single prominent american woman on each quarter dollar</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The design on the reverse side of each quarter dollar issued under this subsection shall be emblematic of the accomplishments and contributions of one prominent woman of the United States, and may include contributions to the United States in a wide spectrum of accomplishments and fields, including but not limited to suffrage, civil rights, abolition, government, humanities, science, space, and arts, and should honor women from ethnically, racially, and geographically diverse backgrounds.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Issuance of quarter dollars emblematic of up to five prominent american women each year</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The designs for the quarter dollars issued during each year of the period of issuance described under paragraph (4) shall be emblematic of up to five prominent American women.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Selection of prominent american women generally</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The selection of a prominent American woman to be featured under this subsection shall be made by the Secretary—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> in accordance with a selection process developed by the Secretary;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> after soliciting recommendations from the general public for prominent women designs for quarter dollars; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> in consultation with the Smithsonian Institution American Women’s History Initiative, National Women’s History Museum, and the Bipartisan Women’s Caucus.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Design generally</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The coins issued in accordance with this subsection shall meet the following design requirements—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>All designs under this subsection shall be selected by the Secretary, after consultation with the Commission of Fine Arts and review by the Citizens Coinage Advisory Committee.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Obverse</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The design on the obverse of the quarter dollars shall maintain a likeness of George Washington, and be designed in a manner, such as with incused inscriptions, so as to distinguish it from the obverse design used during the previous quarters program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Issuance of coins</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall prescribe, on the basis of such factors as the Secretary determines to be appropriate, the number of new designs during each year of the period of issuance, and the number of coins which shall be issued with each of the designs selected for such year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Period of issuance.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The program established under this subsection shall continue in effect until the end of 2025.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Continuity</inline>.—</heading>
<content>After 2025, the Secretary may continue to issue coins minted during the program but not yet issued.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(y)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Redesign and Issuance of Coins Emblematic of the United States Semiquincentennial.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Redesign beginning in 2026.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">In general.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding the 4th, 5th, and 6th sentences of subsection (d)(1), the Secretary may change the design on any of the coins authorized under this section and minted for issuance during the one-year period beginning <date date="2026-01-01">January 1, 2026</date>, in celebration of the United States semiquincentennial.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding the 2nd and 3rd sentences of subsection (d)(1), the Secretary may place the required inscriptions on either the obverse or reverse sides of the coins authorized for redesign under this subsection.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Quarter dollars</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may issue quarter dollars in 2026 with up to five different designs emblematic of the United States semiquincentennial. One of the quarter dollar designs must be emblematic of a woman’s or women’s contribution to the birth of the Nation or the Declaration of Independence or any other monumental moments in American History.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Dollars</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may, in addition to the coins produced under subsections (r) and (w), mint for issuance during the one-year period beginning <date date="2026-01-01">January 1, 2026</date>, $1 dollar [sic] coins with designs emblematic of the United States semiquincentennial.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designs after end of the program</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Beginning in 2027, any coin redesigned under this subsection shall revert to the immediately previous designs, with the exception of the quarter dollar and the half dollar, which shall bear designs in accordance with subsection (z).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Redesign definition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A redesign authorized under this subsection shall not constitute a “change” for purposes of subsection (d)(2).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Selection of designs.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each of the designs authorized under this subsection shall be selected by the Secretary after consultation with Commission of Fine Arts and review by the Citizens Coinage Advisory Committee.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Design selection process</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Designs shall be developed and selected in accordance with the design selection process developed by the Secretary in consultation with the United States Semiquincentennial Commission and with recommendations from the general public.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(z)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Redesign and Issuance of Quarter Dollars and Half Dollars Emblematic of Sports Played by American Youth.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Redesign of quarter dollars beginning in 2027.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Effective beginning <date date="2027-01-01">January 1, 2027</date>, notwithstanding the fourth sentence of subsection (d)(1) and subsection (d)(2), the Secretary shall issue quarter dollars that have designs on the reverse selected in accordance with this subsection which are emblematic of sports played by American youth.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Flexibility with regard to placement of inscriptions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Notwithstanding subsection (d)(1), the Secretary may select a design for quarter dollars referred to in subparagraph (A) in which—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the inscription described in the second sentence of subsection (d)(1) appears on the reverse side of any such quarter dollars; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any of the inscriptions described in the third sentence of subsection (d)(1) or the designation of the value of the coin appear on the obverse side of any such quarter dollars.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Single sport on each quarter dollar</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The design on the reverse side of each quarter dollar issued under this subsection shall be emblematic of one sport played by American youth.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Issuance of quarter dollars emblematic of up to five sports each year</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The designs for the quarter dollars issued during each year of the period referred to in paragraph (5) shall be emblematic of up to five sports.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Selection of sports generally</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall select the sports to be honored during each year of the period referred to in paragraph (5) after appropriate outreach and consultation with the public.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Redesign of half dollars beginning in 2027.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Effective <date date="2027-01-01">January 1, 2027</date>, notwithstanding the fourth sentence of subsection (d)(1) and subsection (d)(2), the Secretary shall issue half dollars that have designs on the reverse selected in accordance with this subsection which are emblematic of a sport tailored to athletes with a range of disabilities, including physical impairment, vision impairment and intellectual impairment (referred to in this Act <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002081">4</ref> as a “Paralympic” sport).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Flexibility with regard to placement of inscriptions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Notwithstanding subsection (d)(1), the Secretary may select a design for half dollars referred to in subparagraph (A) in which—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the inscription described in the second sentence of subsection (d)(1) appears on the reverse side of any such half dollars; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any of the inscriptions described in the third sentence of subsection (d)(1) or the designation of the value of the coin appear on the obverse side of any such half dollars.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Single paralympic sport on each half dollar</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The design on the reverse side of each half dollar issued under this subsection shall be emblematic of one Paralympic sport.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Selection of sports</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The selection of a Paralympic sport to be honored with a half dollar under this subsection shall be made by the Secretary after consultation with U.S. Paralympics.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Design generally</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The coins issued in accordance with this subsection shall meet the following design requirements:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>All designs under this subsection shall be selected by the Secretary, after consultation with the Commission of Fine Arts and review by the Citizens Coinage Advisory Committee.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Quarter dollar obverse</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The design on the obverse of the quarter dollars shall maintain a likeness of George Washington, and be designed in a manner so as to distinguish it from the obverse design used during the previous quarter dollars program.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Half dollar obverse</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The design on the obverse of the half dollar shall maintain a likeness of John Kennedy, and be designed in a manner so as to distinguish it from the obverse design used on the current half dollar.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Issuance of coins.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Quarter dollar</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The quarter dollar coins bearing designs under this subsection shall be issued at the rate of up to 5 new designs during each year of the period of issuance described under paragraph (5).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Half dollar</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The half dollar coins bearing designs under this subsection shall be issued at the rate of 1 new design during each year of the period of issuance described under paragraph (5).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Period of issuance.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The program established under this subsection shall continue in effect until the end of 2030.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Continuity</inline>.—</heading>
<content>After the date specified in subparagraph (A), the Secretary may continue to issue coins minted during the program but not yet issued.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Accompanying sports medals</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For every design of a coin honoring a sport issued under this subsection, the Secretary is authorized to design and issue one or more accompanying medals with designs emblematic of the sport honored with the issuance of the coin, and include a surcharge on the sale the medals sold in accordance with this paragraph, in an amount determined by the Secretary, in the Secretary’s sole discretion, that may be used for the design and manufacture of the medals described in paragraph (7).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Olympic medals.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary is authorized to design and manufacture medals for award at the 2028 Olympic Games in Los Angeles, California.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Working stock</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may use Treasury working gold and silver stock in the manufacture of the award medals produced under this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Olympic &amp; paralympic committees</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may provide the medals described in this paragraph to the United States Olympic &amp; Paralympic Committee under terms and conditions established by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Cooperative marketing and promotion opportunities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary is encouraged to seek out cooperative marketing and promotion opportunities, including with the United States Olympic &amp; Paralympic Committee, LA28, and United States Olympic and Paralympic Properties to promote the coins and medals produced under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designs after end of program</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Upon the completion or termination of the coin program under this subsection, the designs on the quarter dollar and half dollar shall be as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Quarter dollar.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Obverse</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The obverse of the quarter dollar shall bear a design containing a likeness of George Washington.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reverse</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The reverse of the quarter dollar shall be of a design selected by the Secretary after consultation with the Commission of Fine Arts and review by the Citizens Coinage Advisory Committee.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Half dollar.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Obverse</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The obverse of the half dollar shall bear a design containing a likeness of John Kennedy.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reverse</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The reverse of the half dollar shall be of a design selected by the Secretary after consultation with the Commission of Fine Arts and review by the Citizens Coinage Advisory Committee.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(aa)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Standards and General Provisions for Circulating Collectible Coins Under Subsections (x), (y), and (z).—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition on certain representations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No head and shoulders portrait or bust of any person, living or dead, and no portrait of a living person may be included in the design on the reverse of any coin under subsections (x), (y), and (z).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Treatment as numismatic items</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of sections 5134 and 5136, all coins and medals minted under subsections (x), (y), and (z) shall be considered to be numismatic items.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Issuance.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Quality of coins</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may mint and issue such number of coins of each design selected under subsections (x), (y), and (z) in uncirculated and proof qualities as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Coordination</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System and the Secretary shall take steps to ensure that an adequate supply of coins produced under subsections (x), (y), and (z) are available for commerce and collectors at such places and in such quantities as are appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Number of each coin designs in each year</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Of the coins issued during each year of the period of issuance under subsections (x), (y), and (z), the Secretary shall prescribe, on the basis of such factors as the Secretary determines to be appropriate, the number of coins which shall be issued with each of the designs selected for such year.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Special inscriptions or symbol across the coins</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary is encouraged to develop and include on any coin issued in accordance with subsections (x), (y), or (z), a unifying inscription, privy mark, or other symbol for that particular coin program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Legal tender</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The coins minted under subsections (x), (y), and (z) shall be legal tender, as provided in section 5103.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Marketing and educational campaign</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In an effort to advance the collecting of the coins and medals authorized under subsections (x), (y), and (z), and numismatics in general, the Secretary may develop and execute a marketing, advertising, promotional, and educational program to promote the collecting of the coins and medals authorized under subsections (x), (y), and (z). As part of this program, the Secretary is encouraged to seek out appropriate cooperative marketing opportunities, and to develop ancillary derivative products beyond traditional numismatic products such as sports, women, and youth oriented products appropriate to the particular coin and medal program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Quality of medals</inline>.—</heading>
<content>It is the sense of Congress that the medals authorized under subsection (z) be produced in high relief and, if feasible and cost effective, with surface treatments such as frosting and colorization.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 981</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–452, § 1(20)</ref>, <date date="1983-01-12">Jan. 12, 1983</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2477</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–61, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="1985-07-09">July 9, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 115</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–185, § 2(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1985-12-17">Dec. 17, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 1177</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–274</ref>, §§ 4(a), 6, <date date="1988-03-31">Mar. 31, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 50</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–390, title II</ref>, §§ 226(a), 227, 228, <date date="1992-10-06">Oct. 6, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 1630</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 4(f)(1)(R)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1362</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–208, div. A, title I, § 101(f) [title V, §§ 523, 524, 529(a)]</ref>, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3009–314</ref>, 3009–347 to 3009–349; <ref>Pub. L. 105–124</ref>, §§ 3, 4(b)–(d), <date date="1997-12-01">Dec. 1, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 2534</ref>, 2536; <ref>Pub. L. 105–176</ref>, <date date="1998-05-29">May 29, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 104</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–445, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="2000-11-06">Nov. 6, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1931</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–15, title I</ref>, §§ 102, 103(d)(1), <date date="2003-04-23">Apr. 23, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 615</ref>, 619; <ref>Pub. L. 109–145, title I</ref>, §§ 102–104, title II, § 201, <date date="2005-12-22">Dec. 22, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 2665–2669</ref>, 2672; <ref>Pub. L. 110–82</ref>, §§ 2, 3, <date date="2007-09-20">Sept. 20, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 777</ref>, 779; <ref>Pub. L. 110–147</ref>, <date date="2007-12-21">Dec. 21, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 1817</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–161, div. D, title VI</ref>, §§ 622–623(b), <date date="2007-12-26">Dec. 26, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2016</ref>, 2018; <ref>Pub. L. 110–456, title I, § 102</ref>, title II, § 201, <date date="2008-12-23">Dec. 23, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 5039</ref>, 5042; <ref>Pub. L. 111–8, div. D, title VI, § 616</ref>, <date date="2009-03-11">Mar. 11, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 677</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–302</ref>, §§ 4, 5, <date date="2010-12-14">Dec. 14, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3273</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–303, § 2</ref>, <date date="2010-12-14">Dec. 14, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3275</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–94, div. G, title LXXIII, § 73001(1)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 1785</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title VIII, § 885</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1505</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–197, § 2</ref>, <date date="2018-07-20">July 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1515</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title X, § 1081(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1986</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–330</ref>, §§ 2–6, <date date="2021-01-13">Jan. 13, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 5101–5106</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5113.</num>
<heading> Tolerances and testing of coins</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Treasury may prescribe reasonable manufacturing tolerances for specifications in <ref>section 5112 of this title</ref> (except for specifications that are limits) for the dollar, half dollar, quarter dollar, and dime coins. The weight of the 5-cent coin may vary not more than 0.194 gram. The weight of the one-cent coin may vary not more than 0.13 gram. Any gold coin issued under <ref>section 5112 of this title</ref> shall contain the full weight of gold stated on the coin.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary shall keep a record of the kind, number, and weight of each group of coins minted and test a number of the coins separately to determine if the coins conform to the weight specified in <ref>section 5112(a) of this title</ref>. If the coins tested do not conform, the Secretary—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall weigh each coin of the group separately and deface the coins that do not conform and cast them into bars for reminting; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> may remelt the group of coins.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 983</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–274, § 4(b)</ref>, <date date="1988-03-31">Mar. 31, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 50</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5114.</num>
<heading> Engraving and printing currency and security documents</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Authority To Engrave and Print.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the Treasury shall engrave and print United States currency and bonds of the United States Government and currency and bonds of United States territories and possessions from intaglio plates on plate printing presses the Secretary selects. However, other security documents and checks may be printed by any process the Secretary selects. Engraving and printing shall be carried out within the Department of the Treasury if the Secretary decides the engraving and printing can be carried out as cheaply, perfectly, and safely as outside the Department.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Engraving and printing for other governments</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of the Treasury may produce currency, postage stamps, and other security documents for foreign governments if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Secretary of the Treasury determines that such production will not interfere with engraving and printing needs of the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Secretary of State determines that such production would be consistent with the foreign policy of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Procurement guidelines</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Articles, material, and supplies procured for use in the production of currency, postage stamps, and other security documents for foreign governments pursuant to paragraph (2) shall be treated in the same manner as articles, material, and supplies procured for public use within the United States for purposes of title III of the Act of <date date="1933-03-03">March 3, 1933</date> (<ref>41 U.S.C. 10a</ref> et seq.; commonly referred to as the Buy American Act).<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002082">1</ref></content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> United States currency has the inscription “In God We Trust” in a place the Secretary decides is appropriate. Only the portrait of a deceased individual may appear on United States currency and securities. The name of the individual shall be inscribed below the portrait.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary may make a contract to manufacture distinctive paper for United States currency and securities. To promote competition among manufacturers of the distinctive paper, the Secretary may split the award for the manufacture of the paper between the 2 bidders with the lowest prices a pound. When the Secretary decides that it is necessary to operate more than one mill to manufacture distinctive paper, the Secretary may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> employ individuals temporarily at rates of pay equivalent to the rates of pay of regular employees; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> charge the pay of the temporary employees to the appropriation available for manufacturing distinctive paper.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 983</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–458, title VI, § 6301(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-12-17">Dec. 17, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3748</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–74, div. C, title I, § 116</ref>, <date date="2011-12-23">Dec. 23, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 891</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5115.</num>
<heading> United States currency notes</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of the Treasury may issue United States currency notes. The notes—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> are payable to bearer; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall be in a form and in denominations of at least one dollar that the Secretary prescribes.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> The amount of United States currency notes outstanding and in circulation—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> may not be more than $300,000,000; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> may not be held or used for a reserve.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 983</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5116.</num>
<heading> Buying and selling gold and silver</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> With the approval of the President, the Secretary of the Treasury may—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> buy and sell gold in the way, in amounts, at rates, and on conditions the Secretary considers most advantageous to the public interest; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> buy the gold with any direct obligations of the United States Government or United States coins and currency authorized by law, or with amounts in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Amounts received from the purchase of gold are an asset of the general fund of the Treasury. Amounts received from the sale of gold shall be deposited by the Secretary in the general fund of the Treasury and shall be used for the sole purpose of reducing the national debt.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall acquire gold for the coins issued under <ref>section 5112(i) of this title</ref> by purchase of gold mined from natural deposits in the United States, or in a territory or possession of the United States, within one year after the month in which the ore from which it is derived was mined. The Secretary shall pay not more than the average world price for the gold. In the absence of available supplies of such gold at the average world price, the Secretary may use gold from reserves held by the United States to mint the coins issued under <ref>section 5112(i) of this title</ref>. The Secretary shall issue such regulations as may be necessary to carry out this paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary may buy silver mined from natural deposits in the United States, or in a territory or possession of the United States, that is brought to a United States mint or assay office within one year after the month in which the ore from which it is derived was mined. The Secretary may use the coinage metal fund under <ref>section 5111(b) of this title</ref> to buy silver under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary may sell or use Government silver to mint coins, except silver transferred to stockpiles established under the Strategic and Critical Materials Stock Piling Act (<ref>50 U.S.C. 98</ref> et seq.). The Secretary shall obtain the silver for the coins authorized under <ref>section 5112(e) of this title</ref> by purchase from stockpiles established under the Strategic and Critical Materials Stock Piling Act (<ref>50 U.S.C. 98</ref> et seq.). At such time as the silver stockpile is depleted, the Secretary shall obtain silver as described in paragraph (1) to mint coins authorized under section 5112(e). If it is not economically feasible to obtain such silver, the Secretary may obtain silver for coins authorized under section 5112(e) from other available sources. The Secretary shall not pay more than the average world price for silver under any circumstances. As used in this paragraph, the term “average world price” means the price determined by a widely recognized commodity exchange at the time the silver is obtained by the Secretary. The Secretary shall sell silver under conditions the Secretary considers appropriate for at least $1.292929292 a fine troy ounce.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 984</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–61, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="1985-07-09">July 9, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 116</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–185, § 2(c)</ref>, <date date="1985-12-17">Dec. 17, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 1178</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–274, § 5</ref>, <date date="1988-03-31">Mar. 31, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 50</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–201, § 3(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-07-23">July 23, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 737</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5117.</num>
<heading> Transferring gold and gold certificates</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> All right, title, and interest, and every claim of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, a Federal reserve bank, and a Federal reserve agent, in and to gold is transferred to and vests in the United States Government to be held in the Treasury. Payment for the transferred gold is made by crediting equivalent amounts in dollars in accounts established in the Treasury under the 15th paragraph of section 16 of the Federal Reserve Act (<ref>12 U.S.C. 467</ref>). Gold not in the possession of the Government shall be held in custody for the Government and delivered on the order of the Secretary of the Treasury. The Board of Governors, Federal reserve banks, and Federal reserve agents shall give instructions and take action necessary to ensure that the gold is so held and delivered.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall issue gold certificates against gold transferred under subsection (a) of this section. The Secretary may issue gold certificates against other gold held in the Treasury. The Secretary may prescribe the form and denominations of the certificates. The amount of outstanding certificates may be not more than the value (for the purpose of issuing those certificates, of 42 and two-ninths dollars a fine troy ounce) of the gold held against gold certificates. The Secretary shall hold gold in the Treasury equal to the required dollar amount as security for gold certificates issued after <date date="1934-01-29">January 29, 1934</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> With the approval of the President, the Secretary may prescribe regulations the Secretary considers necessary to carry out this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 984</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5118.</num>
<heading> Gold clauses and consent to sue</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> In this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> “gold clause” means a provision in or related to an obligation alleging to give the obligee a right to require payment in—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> gold;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a particular United States coin or currency; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> United States money measured in gold or a particular United States coin or currency.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> “public debt obligation” means a domestic obligation issued or guaranteed by the United States Government to repay money or interest.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The United States Government may not pay out any gold coin. A person lawfully holding United States coins and currency may present the coins and currency to the Secretary of the Treasury for exchange (dollar for dollar) for other United States coins and currency (other than gold and silver coins) that may be lawfully held. The Secretary shall make the exchange under regulations prescribed by the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Government withdraws its consent given to anyone to assert against the Government, its agencies, or its officers, employees, or agents, a claim—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> on a gold clause public debt obligation or interest on the obligation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for United States coins or currency; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> arising out of the surrender, requisition, seizure, or acquisition of United States coins or currency, gold, or silver involving the effect or validity of a change in the metallic content of the dollar or in a regulation about the value of money.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Paragraph (1) of this subsection does not apply to a proceeding in which no claim is made for payment or credit in an amount greater than the face or nominal value in dollars of public debt obligations or United States coins or currency involved in the proceeding.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Except when consent is not withdrawn under this subsection, an amount appropriated for payment on public debt obligations and for United States coins and currency may be expended only dollar for dollar.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In this subsection, “obligation” means any obligation (except United States currency) payable in United States money.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> An obligation issued containing a gold clause or governed by a gold clause is discharged on payment (dollar for dollar) in United States coin or currency that is legal tender at the time of payment. This paragraph does not apply to an obligation issued after <date date="1977-10-27">October 27, 1977</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 985</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–185, § 2(d)</ref>, <date date="1985-12-17">Dec. 17, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 1178</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–208, div. A, title II, § 2609</ref>, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3009–475</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–61, title VI, § 641</ref>, <date date="1997-10-10">Oct. 10, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1318</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5119.</num>
<heading> Redemption and cancellation of currency</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Except to the extent authorized in regulations the Secretary of the Treasury prescribes with the approval of the President, the Secretary may not redeem United States currency (including Federal reserve notes and circulating notes of Federal reserve banks and national banks) in gold. However, the Secretary shall redeem gold certificates owned by the Federal reserve banks at times and in amounts the Secretary decides are necessary to maintain the equal purchasing power of each kind of United States currency. When redemption in gold is authorized, the redemption may be made only in gold bullion bearing the stamp of a United States mint or assay office in an amount equal at the time of redemption to the currency presented for redemption.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Except as provided in subsection (c)(1) of this section, the following are public debts bearing no interest:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> gold certificates issued before <date date="1934-01-30">January 30, 1934</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> silver certificates.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> notes issued under the Act of <date date="1890-07-14">July 14, 1890</date> (ch. 708, <ref>26 Stat. 289</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Federal Reserve notes for which payment was made under section 4 of the Old Series Currency Adjustment Act.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> United States currency notes, including those issued under <ref>section 1 of the Act of February 25, 1862</ref> (ch. 33, <ref>12 Stat. 345</ref>), the Act of <date date="1862-07-11">July 11, 1862</date> (ch. 142, <ref>12 Stat. 532</ref>), the resolution of <date date="1863-01-17">January 17, 1863</date> (P.R. 9; <ref>12 Stat. 822</ref>), <ref>section 2 of the Act of March 3, 1863</ref> (ch. 73, <ref>12 Stat. 710</ref>), or <ref>section 5115 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Redemption, cancellation, and destruction of currency</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> redeem any currency described in paragraph (1) from the general fund of the Treasury upon presentment to the Secretary; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> cancel and destroy such currency upon redemption.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">The Secretary shall not be required to reissue United States currency notes upon redemption.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary may determine the amount of the following United States currency that will not be presented for redemption because the currency has been destroyed or irretrievably lost:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> circulating notes of Federal reserve banks and national banks issued before <date date="1929-07-01">July 1, 1929</date>, for which the United States Government has assumed liability.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> outstanding currency referred to in subsection (b)(1) of this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> When the Secretary makes a determination under this subsection, the Secretary shall reduce the amount of that currency outstanding by the amount the Secretary determines will not be redeemed and credit the appropriate receipt account.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> To provide a historical collection of United States currency, the Secretary may withhold from cancellation and destruction and transfer to a special account one piece of each design, issue, or series of each denomination of each kind of currency (including circulating notes of Federal reserve banks and national banks) after redemption. The Secretary may make appropriate entries in Treasury accounts because of the transfers.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 985</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–390, title II, § 226(b)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-06">Oct. 6, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 1630</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–325, title VI, § 602(g)(14)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-23">Sept. 23, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2294</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5120.</num>
<heading> Obsolete, mutilated, and worn coins and currency</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of the Treasury shall melt obsolete and worn United States coins withdrawn from circulation. The Secretary may use the metal from melting the coins for reminting or may sell the metal. The Secretary shall account for the following in the coinage metal fund under <ref>section 5111(b) of this title</ref>:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> obsolete and worn coins and the metal from melting the coins.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> proceeds from the sale of the metal.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> losses incurred in the sale of the metal.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> losses incurred because of the difference between the face value of the coins melted and the coins minted from the metal.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall reimburse the coinage metal fund for losses under paragraph (1)(C) and (D) of this subsection out of amounts in the coinage profit fund under <ref>section 5111(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> cancel and destroy (by a secure process) obsolete, mutilated, and worn United States currency withdrawn from circulation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> dispose of the residue of the currency and notes.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Comptroller General shall audit the cancellation and destruction of United States currency and the accounting of the cancellation and destruction. Records the Comptroller General considers necessary to make an effective audit easier shall be made available to the Comptroller General.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 986</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5121.</num>
<heading> Refining, assaying, and valuation of bullion</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of the Treasury shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> melt and refine bullion;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> as required, assay coins, metal, and bullion;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> cast gold and silver bullion deposits into bars; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> cast alloys into bars for minting coins.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> A person owning gold or silver bullion may deposit the bullion with the Secretary to be cast into fine, standard fineness, or unrefined bars weighing at least 5 troy ounces. When practicable, the Secretary shall weigh the bullion in front of the depositor. The Secretary shall give the depositor a receipt for the bullion stating the description and weight of the bullion. When the Secretary has to melt the bullion or remove base metals before the value of the bullion can be determined, the weight is the weight after the melting or removal of the metals. The Secretary may refuse a deposit of gold bullion if the deposit is less than $100 in value or the bullion is so base that it is unsuitable for the operations of the Bureau of the Mint.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> When the gold and silver are combined in bullion that is deposited and either the gold or silver is so little that it cannot be separated economically, the Secretary may not pay the depositor for the gold or silver that cannot be separated.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Under conditions prescribed by the Secretary, a person may exchange unrefined bullion for fine bars when—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> gold and silver are combined in the bullion in proportions that cannot be economically refined; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> necessary supplies of acids cannot be procured at reasonable rates.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The charge for refining in an exchange under this subsection may be not more than the charge imposed in an exchange of unrefined bullion for refined bullion.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall prepare bars for payment of deposits. The Secretary shall stamp each bar with a designation of the weight and fineness of the bar and a symbol the Secretary considers suitable to prevent fraudulent imitation of the bar.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 987</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5122.</num>
<heading> Payment to depositors</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Treasury shall determine the fineness, weight, and value of each deposit and bar under <ref>section 5121 of this title</ref>. The value and the amount of charges under subsection (b) of this section shall be based on the fineness and weight of the bullion. The Secretary shall give the depositor a statement of the charges and the net amount of the deposit to be paid in money or bars of the same species of bullion as that deposited.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary shall impose a charge equal to the average cost of material, labor, waste, and use of machinery of a United States mint or assay office for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> melting and refining bullion;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> using copper as an alloy when bullion deposited is above standard;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> separating gold and silver combined in the bullion; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> preparing bars.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall pay to the depositor or to a person designated by the depositor money or bars equivalent to the bullion deposited as soon as practicable after the value of the deposit is determined. If demanded, the Secretary shall pay depositors in the order in which the bullion is deposited with the Secretary. However, when there is an unavoidable delay in determining the value of a deposit, the Secretary shall pay subsequent depositors. When practicable and convenient, the Secretary shall pay depositors in the denominations requested by the depositor. After the depositor is paid, the bullion is the property of the United States Government.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> To allow the Secretary to pay depositors with as little delay as possible, the Secretary shall keep in the mints and assay offices, when possible, money and bullion the Secretary decides are convenient and necessary.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 987</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>UNITED STATES MINT</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5131.</num>
<heading> Organization</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The United States Mint has—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a United States mint at Philadelphia, Pennsylvania.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a United States mint at Denver, Colorado.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a United States mint at West Point, New York.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> a United States mint at San Francisco, California.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Treasury shall carry out duties and powers related to refining and assaying bullion, minting coins, striking medals, and numismatic items at the mints. However, until the Secretary decides that the mints are adequate for minting and striking an ample supply of coins and medals, the Secretary may use any facility of the United States Mint to mint coins and strike medals and to store coins and medals.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Laws on mints, officers and employees of mints, and punishment of offenses related to mints and minting coins apply to assay offices, as applicable.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 988</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–274, § 2(a)</ref>–(c)(2), <date date="1988-03-31">Mar. 31, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 48</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–390, title II</ref>, §§ 224, 225(b)(3), (4), <date date="1992-10-06">Oct. 6, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 1629</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–208, div. A, title I, § 101(f) [title V, §§ 503, 522]</ref>, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3009–314</ref>, 3009–344, 3009–347; <ref>Pub. L. 104–329, title III, § 304</ref>, <date date="1996-10-20">Oct. 20, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 4015</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5132.</num>
<heading> Administrative</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in this chapter, the Secretary of the Treasury shall deposit in the Treasury as miscellaneous receipts amounts the Secretary receives from the operations of the United States Mint. Expenditures made from appropriated funds which are subsequently determined to be properly chargeable to the Numismatic Public Enterprise Fund established by section 5134 shall be reimbursed by such Fund to the appropriation. The Secretary shall annually sell to the public, directly and by mail, sets of uncirculated and proof coins minted under paragraphs (1) through (6) of <ref>section 5112(a) of this title</ref>, and shall solicit such sales through the use of the customer list of the United States Mint. Except with respect to amounts deposited in the Numismatic Public Enterprise Fund in accordance with section 5134, the Secretary may not use amounts the Secretary receives from profits on minting coins or from charges on gold or silver bullion under section 5122 to pay officers and employees.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> In addition to the coins described in paragraph (1), the Secretary shall sell annually to the public directly and by mail, sets of proof coins minted under paragraphs (1) through (6) of section 5112(a).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, for purposes of this paragraph—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the coins described in paragraphs (2) through (4) of section 5112(a) shall be made of an alloy of not less than 90 percent silver; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> all coins minted under this paragraph shall have a mint mark indicating the place of manufacture.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> All coins minted under this paragraph shall be considered to be—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> numismatic items for purposes of paragraph (1) and section 5111(a)(3); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> legal tender, as provided in section 5103.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall obtain silver for coins minted under this paragraph by purchase from stockpiles established under the Strategic and Critical Materials Stock Piling Act (<ref>50 U.S.C. 98</ref> et seq.). At such time as the silver stockpile is depleted, the Secretary shall obtain silver for such coins by purchase of silver mined from natural deposits in the United States or in a territory or possession of the United States not more than 1 year following the month in which the ore from which it is derived was mined. The Secretary shall pay not more than the average world price for such silver. The Secretary may issue such regulations as may be necessary to carry out this subparagraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Not more than $54,208,000 may be appropriated to the Secretary for the fiscal year ending on <date date="1993-09-30">September 30, 1993</date>, to pay costs of the mints. Not more than $965,000 of amounts appropriated pursuant to the preceding sentence shall remain available until expended for research and development.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> To the extent the Secretary decides is necessary, the Secretary may use amounts received from depositors for refining bullion and the proceeds from the sale of byproducts (including spent acids from surplus bullion recovered in refining processes) to pay the costs of refining the bullion (including labor, material, waste, and loss on the sale of sweeps). The Secretary may not use amounts appropriated for the mints to pay those costs.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall make an annual report at the end of each fiscal year on the operation of the United States Mint.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 988</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–452, § 1(21)</ref>, <date date="1983-01-12">Jan. 12, 1983</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2477</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–151, § 123</ref>, <date date="1983-11-14">Nov. 14, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 979</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–216, § 1(7)</ref>, <date date="1984-02-14">Feb. 14, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 4</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–61, title II, § 204</ref>, <date date="1985-07-09">July 9, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 116</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–185, § 2(e)</ref>, <date date="1985-12-17">Dec. 17, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 1178</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–274</ref>, §§ 1, 2(c)(3), <date date="1988-03-31">Mar. 31, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 48</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–585, § 2</ref>, <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 2874</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–390, title II</ref>, §§ 211, 221(c)(1), 225(b)(3), (4), <date date="1992-10-06">Oct. 6, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 1624</ref>, 1628, 1629; <ref>Pub. L. 106–445, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2000-11-06">Nov. 6, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1931</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–94, div. G, title LXXIII, § 73001(2)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 1786</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5133.</num>
<heading> Settlement of accounts</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of the Treasury shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> charge the superintendent of each mint with the amount in weight of standard metal of bullion the superintendent receives from the Secretary;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> credit each superintendent with the amount in weight of coins, clippings, and other bullion the superintendent returns to the Secretary; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> charge separately to each superintendent, who shall account for, copper to be used in the alloy of gold and silver bullion.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Settlement of Accounts.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>At least once each year, the Secretary of the Treasury shall settle the accounts of the superintendents of the mints.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Procedure</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>At any settlement under this subsection, the superintendent shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> return to the Secretary any coin, clipping, or other bullion in the possession of the superintendent; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> present the Secretary with a statement of bullion received and returned since the last settlement (including any bullion returned for settlement).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Audit</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> audit the accounts of each superintendent; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> allow each superintendent the waste of precious metals that the Secretary determines is necessary—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> for refining and minting (within the limitations which the Secretary shall prescribe); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> for casting fine gold and silver bars (within the limit prescribed for refining), except that any waste allowance under this clause may not apply to deposit operations.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> After settlement, the Secretary shall compare the amount of gold and silver bullion and coins on hand with the total liabilities of the mints. The Secretary also shall make a statement of the ordinary expense account.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall procure for each mint a series of standard weights corresponding to the standard troy pound of the National Institute of Standards and Technology of the Department of Commerce. The series shall include a one pound weight and multiples and subdivisions of one pound from .01 grain to 25 pounds. At least once a year, the Secretary shall test the weights normally used in transactions at the mints against the standard weights.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 989</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–274, § 2(c)(4)</ref>–(7), (9), (10), <date date="1988-03-31">Mar. 31, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 49</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title V, § 5115(c)</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1433</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5134.</num>
<heading> Numismatic Public Enterprise Fund</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Fund</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “Fund” means the Numismatic Public Enterprise Fund.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Mint</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “Mint” means the United States Mint.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Numismatic item</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “numismatic item” means any medal, proof coin, uncirculated coin, bullion coin, or other coin specifically designated by statute as a numismatic item, including products and accessories related to any such medal, coin, or item.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Numismatic operations and programs</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “numismatic operations and programs”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> means the activities concerning, and assets utilized in, the production, administration, sale, and management of numismatic items and the Numismatic Public Enterprise Fund; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> includes capital, personnel salaries, functions relating to operations, marketing, distribution, promotion, advertising, and official reception and representation, the acquisition or replacement of equipment, and the renovation or modernization of facilities (other than the construction or acquisition of new buildings).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Secretary</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of the Treasury.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment of Fund</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is hereby established in the Treasury of the United States a revolving Numismatic Public Enterprise Fund consisting of amounts deposited in the fund <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002083">1</ref> under subsection (c)(2) of this section or section 221(b) of the United States Mint Reauthorization and Reform Act of 1992 which shall be available to the Secretary for numismatic operations and programs of the United States Mint without fiscal year limitation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Operations of the Fund.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Payment of expenses</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any expense incurred by the Secretary for numismatic operations and programs which the Secretary determines, in the Secretary’s sole discretion, to be ordinary and reasonable incidents of the numismatic business shall be paid out of the Fund, including any expense incurred pursuant to any obligation or other commitment of Mint numismatic operations and programs which was entered into before the beginning of fiscal year 1993.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Deposit of receipts</inline>.—</heading>
<content>All receipts from numismatic operations and programs shall be deposited into the Fund, including amounts attributable to any surcharge imposed with respect to the sale of any numismatic item.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transfer of seigniorage</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall transfer monthly from the Fund to the general fund of the Treasury an amount equal to the total amount on the seigniorage of numismatic items sold since the date of any preceding transfer.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Transfer of excess amounts to the treasury.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>At such times as the Secretary determines to be appropriate, the Secretary shall transfer any amount in the Fund which the Secretary determines to be in excess of the amount required by the Fund to the Treasury for deposit as miscellaneous receipts.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report to congress</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall submit an annual report to the Congress containing—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a statement of the total amount transferred to the Treasury pursuant to subparagraph (A) during the period covered by the report;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a statement of the amount by which the amount on deposit in the Fund at the end of the period covered by the report exceeds the estimated operating costs of the Fund for the 1-year period beginning at the end of such period; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> an explanation of the specific purposes for which such excess amounts are being retained in the Fund.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Budget Treatment.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall prepare budgets for the Fund, and estimates and statements of financial condition of the Fund in accordance with the requirements of section 9103 which shall be submitted to the President for inclusion in the budget submitted under section 1105.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inclusion in annual report</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Statements of the financial condition of the Fund shall be included in the Secretary’s annual report on the operation of the Mint.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Treatment as wholly owned government corporation for certain purposes</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Section 9104 shall apply to the Fund to the same extent such section applies to wholly owned Government corporations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Financial Statements, Audits, and Reports.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual financial statement required</inline>.—</heading>
<content>By the end of each calendar year, the Secretary shall prepare an annual financial statement of the Fund for the fiscal year which ends during such calendar year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contents of financial statement</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each statement prepared pursuant to paragraph (1) shall, at a minimum, contain—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the overall financial position (including assets and liabilities) of the Fund as of the end of the fiscal year;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the results of the numismatic operations and programs of the Fund during the fiscal year;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the cash flows or the changes in financial position of the Fund;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a reconciliation of the financial statement to the budget reports of the Fund; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<chapeau> a supplemental schedule detailing—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the costs and expenses for the production, for the marketing, and for the distribution of each denomination of circulating coins produced by the Mint during the fiscal year and the per-unit cost of producing, of marketing, and of distributing each denomination of such coins; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the gross revenue derived from the sales of each such denomination of coins.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Annual audits.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each annual financial statement prepared under paragraph (1) shall be audited—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> by—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> an independent external auditor; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the Inspector General of the Department of the Treasury,</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent3 firstIndent-1"> as designated by the Secretary; and</continuation>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in accordance with the generally accepted Government auditing standards issued by the Comptroller General of the United States.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Auditor’s report required</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The auditor designated to audit any financial statement of the Fund pursuant to subparagraph (A) shall submit a report—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> to the Secretary by March 31 of the year beginning after the end of the fiscal year covered by such financial statement; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> containing the auditor’s opinion on—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the financial statement of the Fund;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the internal accounting and administrative controls and accounting systems of the Fund; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> the Fund’s compliance with applicable laws and regulations.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Annual report on fund.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report required</inline>.—</heading>
<content>By April 30 of each year, the Secretary shall submit a report on the Fund for the most recently completed fiscal year to the President, the Congress, and the Director of the Office of Management and Budget.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contents of annual report</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The annual report required under subparagraph (A) for any fiscal year shall include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the financial statement prepared under paragraph (1) for such fiscal year;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the audit report submitted to the Secretary pursuant to paragraph (3)(B) for such fiscal year;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a description of activities carried out during such fiscal year;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> a summary of information relating to numismatic operations and programs contained in the reports on systems on internal accounting and administrative controls and accounting systems submitted to the President and the Congress under section 3512(c);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> a summary of the corrective actions taken with respect to material weaknesses relating to numismatic operations and programs identified in the reports prepared under section 3512(c);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> any other information the Secretary considers appropriate to fully inform the Congress concerning the financial management of the Fund; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> a statement of the total amount of excess funds transferred to the Treasury.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Marketing report.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report required for 10 years</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For each fiscal year beginning before fiscal year 2003, the Secretary shall submit an annual report on all marketing activities and expenses of the Fund to the Congress before the end of the 3-month period beginning at the end of such fiscal year.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contents of report</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The report submitted pursuant to subparagraph (A) shall contain a detailed description of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the sources of income including surcharges; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> expenses incurred for manufacturing, materials, overhead, packaging, marketing, and shipping.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Conditions on Payment of Surcharges to Recipient Organizations.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Payment of surcharges.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no amount derived from the proceeds of any surcharge imposed on the sale of any numismatic item shall be paid from the fund <sup>1</sup> to any designated recipient organization unless—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> all numismatic operation and program costs allocable to the program under which such numismatic item is produced and sold have been recovered; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the designated recipient organization submits an audited financial statement that demonstrates, to the satisfaction of the Secretary, that, with respect to all projects or purposes for which the proceeds of such surcharge may be used, the organization has raised funds from private sources for such projects and purposes in an amount that is equal to or greater than the total amount of the proceeds of such surcharge derived from the sale of such numismatic item.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Unpaid amounts</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>If any amount derived from the proceeds of any surcharge imposed on the sale of any numismatic item that may otherwise be paid from the fund,<sup>1</sup> under any provision of law relating to such numismatic item, to any designated recipient organization remains unpaid to such organization solely by reason of the matching fund requirement contained in subparagraph (A)(ii) after the end of the 2-year period beginning on the later of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the last day any such numismatic item is issued by the Secretary; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the date of the enactment of the American 5-Cent Coin Design Continuity Act of 2003,</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">such unpaid amount shall be deposited in the Treasury as miscellaneous receipts.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Annual audits.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual audits of recipients required</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each designated recipient organization that receives any payment from the fund <sup>1</sup> of any amount derived from the proceeds of any surcharge imposed on the sale of any numismatic item shall provide, as a condition for receiving any such amount, for an annual audit, in accordance with generally accepted government auditing standards by an independent public accountant selected by the organization, of all such payments to the organization beginning in the first fiscal year of the organization in which any such amount is received and continuing until all amounts received by such organization from the fund <sup>1</sup> with respect to such surcharges are fully expended or placed in trust.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Minimum requirements for annual audits</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>At a minimum, each audit of a designated recipient organization pursuant to subparagraph (A) shall report—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the amount of payments received by the designated recipient organization from the fund <sup>1</sup> during the fiscal year of the organization for which the audit is conducted that are derived from the proceeds of any surcharge imposed on the sale of any numismatic item;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the amount expended by the designated recipient organization from the proceeds of such surcharges during the fiscal year of the organization for which the audit is conducted; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> whether all expenditures by the designated recipient organization during the fiscal year of the organization for which the audit is conducted from the proceeds of such surcharges were for authorized purposes.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Responsibility of organization to account for expenditures of surcharges</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each designated recipient organization that receives any payment from the fund <sup>1</sup> of any amount derived from the proceeds of any surcharge imposed on the sale of any numismatic item shall take appropriate steps, as a condition for receiving any such payment, to ensure that the receipt of the payment and the expenditure of the proceeds of such surcharge by the organization in each fiscal year of the organization can be accounted for separately from all other revenues and expenditures of the organization.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Submission of audit report</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not later than 90 days after the end of any fiscal year of a designated recipient organization for which an audit is required under subparagraph (A), the organization shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> submit a copy of the report to the Secretary of the Treasury; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> make a copy of the report available to the public.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of surcharges for audits</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any designated recipient organization that receives any payment from the fund <sup>1</sup> of any amount derived from the proceeds of any surcharge imposed on the sale of any numismatic item may use the amount received to pay the cost of an audit required under subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Waiver of paragraph</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the Treasury may waive the application of any subparagraph of this paragraph to any designated recipient organization for any fiscal year after taking into account the amount of surcharges that such organization received or expended during such year.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Nonapplicability to federal entities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This paragraph shall not apply to any Federal agency or department or any independent establishment in the executive branch that receives any payment from the fund <sup>1</sup> of any amount derived from the proceeds of any surcharge imposed on the sale of any numismatic item.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Availability of books and records</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An organization that receives any payment from the fund <sup>1</sup> of any amount derived from the proceeds of any surcharge imposed on the sale of any numismatic item shall provide, as a condition for receiving any such payment, to the Inspector General of the Department of the Treasury or the Comptroller General of the United States, upon the request of such Inspector General or the Comptroller General, all books, records, and work papers belonging to or used by the organization, or by any independent public accountant who audited the organization in accordance with subparagraph (A), which may relate to the receipt or expenditure of any such amount by the organization.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of agents or attorneys to influence commemorative coin legislation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No portion of any payment from the fund <sup>1</sup> to any designated recipient organization of any amount derived from the proceeds of any surcharge imposed on the sale of any numismatic item may be used, directly or indirectly, by the organization to compensate any agent or attorney for services rendered to support or influence in any way legislative action of the Congress relating to such numismatic item.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designated recipient organization defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of this subsection, the term “designated recipient organization” means any organization designated, under any provision of law, as the recipient of any surcharge imposed on the sale of any numismatic item.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Quarterly Financial Reports.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than the 30th day of each month following each calendar quarter through and including the final period of sales with respect to any commemorative coin program authorized on or after the date of enactment of the Treasury, Postal Service, and General Government Appropriations Act, 1997, the Mint shall submit to the Congress a quarterly financial report in accordance with this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each report submitted under paragraph (1) shall include, with respect to the calendar quarter at issue—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a detailed financial statement, prepared in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles, that includes financial information specific to that quarter, as well as cumulative financial information relating to the entire program;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> a detailed accounting of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> all costs relating to marketing efforts;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> all funds projected for marketing use;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> all costs for employee travel relating to the promotion of commemorative coin programs;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> all numismatic items minted, sold, not sold, and rejected during the production process; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> the costs of melting down all rejected and unsold products;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> adequate market-based research for all commemorative coin programs; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a description of the efforts of the Mint in keeping the sale price of numismatic items as low as practicable.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–390, title II, § 221(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-06">Oct. 6, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 1624</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–208, div. A, title I, § 101(f) [title V, § 529(b)(1), (2), (c)]</ref>, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3009–314</ref>, 3009–349, 3009–350, 3009–352; <ref>Pub. L. 106–445, § 3</ref>, <date date="2000-11-06">Nov. 6, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1931</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–15, title I, § 103(d)(2)</ref>, title II, § 201(a), <date date="2003-04-23">Apr. 23, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 619</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5135.</num>
<heading> Citizens Coinage Advisory Committee</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Establishment.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is hereby established the Citizens Coinage Advisory Committee (in this section referred to as the “Advisory Committee”) to advise the Secretary of the Treasury on the selection of themes and designs for coins.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Oversight of advisory committee</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Advisory Committee shall be subject to the authority of the Secretary of the Treasury (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Secretary”).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Membership.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appointment</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Advisory Committee shall consist of 11 members appointed by the Secretary as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> Seven persons appointed by the Secretary—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> one of whom shall be appointed from among individuals who are specially qualified to serve on the Advisory Committee by virtue of their education, training, or experience as a nationally or internationally recognized curator in the United States of a numismatic collection;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> one of whom shall be appointed from among individuals who are specially qualified to serve on the Advisory Committee by virtue of their experience in the medallic arts or sculpture;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> one of whom shall be appointed from among individuals who are specially qualified to serve on the Advisory Committee by virtue of their education, training, or experience in American history;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> one of whom shall be appointed from among individuals who are specially qualified to serve on the Advisory Committee by virtue of their education, training, or experience in numismatics; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> three of whom shall be appointed from among individuals who can represent the interests of the general public in the coinage of the United States.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> Four persons appointed by the Secretary on the basis of the recommendations of the following officials who shall make the selection for such recommendation from among citizens who are specially qualified to serve on the Advisory Committee by virtue of their education, training, or experience:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> One person recommended by the Speaker of the House of Representatives.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> One person recommended by the minority leader of the House of Representatives.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> One person recommended by the majority leader of the Senate.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> One person recommended by the minority leader of the Senate.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Terms.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), members of the Advisory Committee shall be appointed for a term of 4 years.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Terms of initial appointees</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>As designated by the Secretary at the time of appointment, of the members first appointed—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> four of the members appointed under paragraph (1)(A) shall be appointed for a term of 4 years;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the four members appointed under paragraph (1)(B) shall be appointed for a term of 3 years; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> three of the members appointed under paragraph (1)(A) shall be appointed for a term of 2 years.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Preservation of public advisory status</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No individual may be appointed to the Advisory Committee while serving as an officer or employee of the Federal Government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Continuation of service</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each appointed member may continue to serve for up to 6 months after the expiration of the term of office to which such member was appointed until a successor has been appointed.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Vacancy and removal.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any vacancy on the Advisory Committee shall be filled in the manner in which the original appointment was made.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Removal</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Advisory Committee members shall serve at the discretion of the Secretary and may be removed at any time for good cause.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Chairperson</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Chairperson of the Advisory Committee shall be appointed for a term of 1 year by the Secretary from among the members of the Advisory Committee.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Pay and expenses</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Members of the Advisory Committee shall serve without pay for such service but each member of the Advisory Committee shall be reimbursed from the United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund for travel, lodging, meals, and incidental expenses incurred in connection with attendance of such members at meetings of the Advisory Committee in the same amounts and under the same conditions as employees of the United States Mint who engage in official travel, as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Meetings.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Advisory Committee shall meet at the call of the Secretary, the chairperson, or a majority of the members, but not less frequently than twice annually.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Open meetings</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each meeting of the Advisory Committee shall be open to the public.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prior notice of meetings</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Timely notice of each meeting of the Advisory Committee shall be published in the Federal Register, and timely notice of each meeting shall be made to trade publications and publications of general circulation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Quorum</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Seven members of the Advisory Committee shall constitute a quorum.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duties of the Advisory Committee</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The duties of the Advisory Committee are as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Advising the Secretary of the Treasury on any theme or design proposals relating to circulating coinage, bullion coinage, congressional gold medals and national and other medals produced by the Secretary of the Treasury in accordance with <ref>section 5111 of title 31</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Advising the Secretary of the Treasury with regard to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the events, persons, or places that the Advisory Committee recommends be commemorated by the issuance of commemorative coins in each of the 5 calendar years succeeding the year in which a commemorative coin designation is made;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the mintage level for any commemorative coin recommended under subparagraph (A); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the proposed designs for commemorative coins.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Expenses</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The expenses of the Advisory Committee that the Secretary of the Treasury determines to be reasonable and appropriate shall be paid by the Secretary from the United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Administrative Support, Technical Services, and Advice</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Upon the request of the Advisory Committee, or as necessary for the Advisory Committee to carry out the responsibilities of the Advisory Committee under this section, the Director of the United States Mint shall provide to the Advisory Committee the administrative support, technical services, and advice that the Secretary of the Treasury determines to be reasonable and appropriate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consultation Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In carrying out the duties of the Advisory Committee under this section, the Advisory Committee may consult with the Commission of Fine Arts.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Annual Report.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Required</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than September 30 of each year, the Advisory Committee shall submit a report to the Secretary, the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate. Should circumstances arise in which the Advisory Committee cannot meet the September 30 deadline in any year, the Secretary shall advise the Chairpersons of the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate of the reasons for such delay and the date on which the submission of the report is anticipated.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contents</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The report required by paragraph (1) shall describe the activities of the Advisory Committee during the preceding year and the reports and recommendations made by the Advisory Committee to the Secretary of the Treasury.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Chapter </inline>10<inline class="small-caps"> of Title </inline>5<inline class="small-caps"> Does Not Apply</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to the requirements of subsection (b)(8), chapter 10 of title 5 shall not apply with respect to the Committee.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–390, title II, § 229(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-06">Oct. 6, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 1631</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–208, div. A, title I, § 101(f) [title V, § 529(d)]</ref>, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3009–314</ref>, 3009–352; <ref>Pub. L. 104–329, title III, § 303(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-20">Oct. 20, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 4014</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–15, title I, § 103(a)</ref>, <date date="2003-04-23">Apr. 23, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 616</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(a)(196)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4327</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5136.</num>
<heading> United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There shall be established in the Treasury of the United States, a United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund (the “Fund”) for fiscal year 1996 and hereafter: <i>Provided</i>, That all receipts from Mint operations and programs, including the production and sale of numismatic items, the production and sale of circulating coinage, the protection of Government assets, and gifts and bequests of property, real or personal shall be deposited into the Fund and shall be available without fiscal year limitations: <i>Provided further</i>, That all expenses incurred by the Secretary of the Treasury for operations and programs of the United States Mint that the Secretary of the Treasury determines, in the Secretary’s sole discretion, to be ordinary and reasonable incidents of Mint operations and programs, and any expense incurred pursuant to any obligation or other commitment of Mint operations and programs that was entered into before the establishment of the Fund, shall be paid out of the Fund: <i>Provided further</i>, That not to exceed 6.2415 percent of the nominal value of the coins minted, shall be paid out of the Fund for the circulating coin operations and programs in fiscal year 1996 for those operations and programs previously provided for by appropriation: <i>Provided further</i>, That the Secretary of the Treasury may borrow such funds from the General Fund as may be necessary to meet existing liabilities and obligations incurred prior to the receipt of revenues into the Fund: <i>Provided further</i>, That the General Fund shall be reimbursed for such funds by the Fund within one year of the date of the loan: <i>Provided further</i>, That the Fund may retain receipts from the Federal Reserve System from the sale of circulating coins at face value for deposit into the Fund (retention of receipts is for the circulating operations and programs): <i>Provided further</i>, That the Secretary of the Treasury shall transfer to the Fund all assets and liabilities of the Mint operations and programs, including all Numismatic Public Enterprise Fund assets and liabilities, all receivables, unpaid obligations and unobligated balances from the Mint’s appropriation, the Coinage Profit Fund, and the Coinage Metal Fund, and the land and buildings of the Philadelphia Mint, Denver Mint, and the Fort Knox Bullion Depository: <i>Provided further</i>, That the Numismatic Public Enterprise Fund, the Coinage Profit Fund and the Coinage Metal Fund shall cease to exist as separate funds as their activites <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002084">1</ref> and functions are subsumed under and subject to the Fund, and the requirements of 31 USC <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002085">2</ref> 5134(c)(4), (c)(5)(B), and (d) and (e) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002086">3</ref> of the Numismatic Public Enterprise Fund shall apply to the Fund: <i>Provided further</i>, That at such times as the Secretary of the Treasury determines appropriate, but not less than annually, any amount in the Fund that is determined to be in excess of the amount required by the Fund shall be transferred to the Treasury for deposit as miscellaneous receipts: <i>Provided further</i>, That the term “Mint operations and programs” means (1) the activities concerning, and assets utilized in, the production, administration, distribution, marketing, purchase, sale, and management of coinage, numismatic items, the protection and safeguarding of Mint assets and those non-Mint assets in the custody of the Mint, and the Fund; and (2) includes capital, personnel salaries and compensation, functions relating to operations, marketing, distribution, promotion, advertising, official reception and representation, the acquisition or replacement of equipment, the renovation or modernization of facilities, and the construction or acquisition of new buildings: <i>Provided further</i>, That the term “numismatic item” includes any medal, proof coin, uncirculated coin, bullion coin, numismatic collectible, other monetary issuances and products and accessories related to any such medal or coin: <i>Provided further</i>, That provisions of law governing procurement or public contracts shall not be applicable to the procurement of goods or services necessary for carrying out Mint programs and operations.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–52, title V, § 522</ref>, <date date="1995-11-19">Nov. 19, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 494</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>BUREAU OF ENGRAVING AND PRINTING</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5141.</num>
<heading> Operation of the Bureau</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Treasury shall prepare and submit to the President an annual business-type budget for the Bureau of Engraving and Printing.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary shall maintain in the Bureau an integrated accounting system with internal controls that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> ensures adequate control over assets and liabilities of the Bureau of Engraving and Printing Fund described in <ref>section 5142 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> develops accurate production costs to enable the Bureau to recover those costs on the basis of the work requisitioned;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> provides for replacement of capitalized equipment and other fixed assets by maintaining adequate depreciation reserves based on original cost or appraised values;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> discloses the financial condition and operations of the Fund on an accrual basis of accounting; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> provides information for the prior fiscal year on the annual budget of the Bureau.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The accounting system shall conform to principles and standards prescribed by the Comptroller General to carry out this subsection. The Comptroller General may review the system to ensure conformity to the principles and standards and its effectiveness of operation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> An officer or employee in the clerical-mech­anical service of the Bureau assigned to an established shift or tour of duty at least half of which occurs between 6 p.m. and 6 a.m. is entitled to pay for the regular 40-hour week (except when on leave) at a rate of pay 15 percent higher than the day rate for the same work.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 990</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5142.</num>
<heading> Bureau of Engraving and Printing Fund</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Department of the Treasury has a Bureau of Engraving and Printing Fund. Amounts—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in the Fund are available to operate the Bureau of Engraving and Printing;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in the Fund remain available until expended; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> may be appropriated to the Fund.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> The Fund consists of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> property and physical assets (except buildings and land) acquired by the Bureau;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> all amounts received by the Bureau; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> proceeds from the disposition of property and assets acquired by the Fund.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> The capital of the Fund consists of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> amounts appropriated to the Fund;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> physical assets of the Bureau (except buildings and land) as of the close of business <date date="1951-06-30">June 30, 1951</date>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> all payments made after <date date="1974-06-30">June 30, 1974</date>, under <ref>section 5143 of this title</ref> at prices adjusted to permit buying capital equipment and to provide future working capital.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall deposit each fiscal year, in the Treasury as miscellaneous receipts, amounts accruing to the Fund in the prior fiscal year that the Secretary decides are in excess of the needs of the Fund. However, the Secretary may use the excess amounts to restore capital of the Fund reduced by the difference between the charges for services of the Bureau and the cost of providing those services.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall maintain a special deposit account in the Treasury for the Fund. The Secretary shall credit the account with amounts appropriated to the Fund and receipts of the Bureau without depositing the receipts in the Treasury as miscellaneous receipts.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 990</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5143.</num>
<heading> Payment for services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Treasury shall impose charges for Bureau of Engraving and Printing services the Secretary provides to an agency or to a foreign government under section 5114. The charges shall be in amounts the Secretary considers adequate to cover the costs of the services (including administrative and other costs related to providing the services). The agency shall pay promptly bills submitted by the Secretary, and the Secretary shall take such action, in coordination with the Secretary of State, as may be appropriate to ensure prompt payment by a foreign government of any invoice or statement of account submitted by the Secretary with respect to services rendered under section 5114.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 991</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–458, title VI, § 6301(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-12-17">Dec. 17, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3748</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5144.</num>
<heading> Providing impressions of portraits and vignettes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of the Treasury may provide impressions from an engraved portrait or vignette in the possession of the Bureau of Engraving and Printing. An impression shall be provided—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> at the request of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a member of Congress;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a head of an agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> an art association; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a library; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> for a charge and under conditions the Secretary decides are necessary to protect the public interest.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 991</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER V—</num>
<heading>MISCELLANEOUS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5151.</num>
<heading> Conversion of currency of foreign countries</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> In this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “buying rate” means the buying rate in the market in New York, New York, for cable transfers payable in the currency of a foreign country to be converted.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> when merchandise is exported on a day that banks are generally closed in New York, the buying rate at noon on the last prior business day is deemed to be the buying rate at noon on the day the merchandise is exported.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The value of coins of a foreign country expressed in United States money is the value of the pure metal of the standard coin of the foreign country. The Secretary of the Treasury shall estimate the values of standard coins of the country quarterly and publish the values on the first day of January, April, July, and October of each year.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Except as provided in this section, conversion of currency of a foreign country into United States currency for assessment and collection of duties on merchandise imported into the United States shall be made at values published by the Secretary under subsection (b) of this section for the quarter in which the merchandise is exported.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> If the Secretary has not published a value for the quarter in which the merchandise is exported, or if the value published by the Secretary varies by at least 5 percent from a value measured by the buying rate at noon on the day the merchandise is exported, the conversion of the currency of the foreign country shall be made at a value—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> equal to the buying rate at noon on the day the merchandise is exported; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> prescribed by regulation of the Secretary for the currency that is equal to the first buying rate certified for that currency by the Federal Reserve Bank of New York under subsection (e) of this section in the quarter in which the merchandise is exported, but only if the buying rate at noon on the day the merchandise is exported varies less than 5 percent from the buying rate first certified.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<chapeau> The Federal Reserve Bank of New York shall decide the buying rate and certify the rate to the Secretary. The Secretary shall publish the rate at times and to the extent the Secretary considers necessary. In deciding the buying rate, the Bank may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> consider the last ascertainable transactions and quotations (direct or through exchange of other currencies); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> if there is no buying rate, calculate the rate from—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> actual transactions and quotations in demand or time bills of exchange; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the last ascertainable transactions and quotations outside the United States in or for exchange payable in United States currency or foreign currency.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 991</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5152.</num>
<heading> Value of United States money holdings in international institutions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Treasury shall maintain the value in terms of gold of the holdings of United States money of the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development, the Inter-American Development Bank, the International Development Association, and the Asian Development Bank to the extent provided in the articles of agreement of those institutions. Amounts necessary to maintain the value may be appropriated. Amounts appropriated under this section remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 992</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5153.</num>
<heading> Counterfeit currency</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Disbursing officials of the United States Government and officers of national banks shall stamp or mark the word “counterfeit”, “altered”, or “worthless” on counterfeit notes intended to circulate as currency that are presented to them. An official or officer wrongfully stamping or marking an item of genuine United States currency (including a Federal reserve note or a circulating note of Federal reserve banks and national banks) shall redeem the currency at face value when presented.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 992</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5154.</num>
<heading> State taxation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A State or a territory or possession of the United States may tax United States coins and currency (including Federal reserve notes and circulating notes of Federal reserve banks and national banks) as money on hand or on deposit in the same way and at the same rate that the State, territory, or possession taxes other forms of money. This section does not affect a law taxing national banks.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 992</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–452, § 1(22)</ref>, <date date="1983-01-12">Jan. 12, 1983</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2477</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5155.</num>
<heading> Providing engraved plates of portraits of deceased members of Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On conditions the Secretary of the Treasury decides, the Secretary may send an engraved plate of a portrait of a deceased Senator or Representative to an heir or legal representative of such a Senator or Representative.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 993</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>