<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 63—</num>
<heading>USING PROCUREMENT CONTRACTS AND GRANT AND COOPERATIVE AGREEMENTS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6301.</num>
<heading> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes of this chapter are to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> promote a better understanding of United States Government expenditures and help eliminate unnecessary administrative requirements on recipients of Government awards by characterizing the relationship between executive agencies and contractors, States, local governments, and other recipients in acquiring property and services and in providing United States Government assistance;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> prescribe criteria for executive agencies in selecting appropriate legal instruments to achieve—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> uniformity in their use by executive agencies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a clear definition of the relationships they reflect; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a better understanding of the responsibilities of the parties to them; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> promote increased discipline in selecting and using procurement contracts, grant agreements, and cooperative agreements, maximize competition in making procurement contracts, and encourage competition in making grants and cooperative agreements.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1003</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6302.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “executive agency” does not include a mixed-ownership Government corporation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> “grant agreement” and “cooperative agreement” do not include an agreement under which is provided only—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> direct United States Government cash assistance to an individual;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a subsidy;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a loan;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a loan guarantee; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> insurance.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> “local government” means a unit of government in a State, a local public authority, a special district, an intrastate district, a council of governments, a sponsor group representative organization, an interstate entity, or another instrumentality of a local government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> “other recipient” means a person or recipient (except a State or local government) authorized to receive United States Government assistance or procurement contracts and includes a charitable or educational institution.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> “State” means a State of the United States, the District of Columbia, a territory or possession of the United States, an agency or instrumentality of a State, and a multi-State, regional, or interstate entity having governmental duties and powers.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1003</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6303.</num>
<heading> Using procurement contracts</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">An executive agency shall use a procurement contract as the legal instrument reflecting a relationship between the United States Government and a State, a local government, or other recipient when—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the principal purpose of the instrument is to acquire (by purchase, lease, or barter) property or services for the direct benefit or use of the United States Government; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the agency decides in a specific instance that the use of a procurement contract is appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1004</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6304.</num>
<heading> Using grant agreements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">An executive agency shall use a grant agreement as the legal instrument reflecting a relationship between the United States Government and a State, a local government, or other recipient when—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the principal purpose of the relationship is to transfer a thing of value to the State or local government or other recipient to carry out a public purpose of support or stimulation authorized by a law of the United States instead of acquiring (by purchase, lease, or barter) property or services for the direct benefit or use of the United States Government; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> substantial involvement is not expected between the executive agency and the State, local government, or other recipient when carrying out the activity contemplated in the agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1004</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6305.</num>
<heading> Using cooperative agreements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">An executive agency shall use a cooperative agreement as the legal instrument reflecting a relationship between the United States Government and a State, a local government, or other recipient when—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the principal purpose of the relationship is to transfer a thing of value to the State, local government, or other recipient to carry out a public purpose of support or stimulation authorized by a law of the United States instead of acquiring (by purchase, lease, or barter) property or services for the direct benefit or use of the United States Government; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> substantial involvement is expected between the executive agency and the State, local government, or other recipient when carrying out the activity contemplated in the agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1004</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6306.</num>
<heading> Authority to vest title in tangible personal property for research</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The head of an executive agency may vest title in tangible personal property in a nonprofit institution of higher education or in a nonprofit organization whose primary purpose is conducting scientific research—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> when the property is bought with amounts provided under a procurement contract, grant agreement, or cooperative agreement with the institution or organization to conduct basic or applied scientific research;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> when the head of the agency decides the vesting furthers the objectives of the agency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> without further obligation to the United States Government; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> under conditions the head of the agency considers appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1004</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6307.</num>
<heading> Interpretative guidelines and exemptions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Director of the Office of Management and Budget may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> issue supplementary interpretative guidelines to promote consistent and efficient use of procurement contracts, grant agreements, and cooperative agreements; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> exempt a transaction or program of an executive agency from this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1005</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6308.</num>
<heading> Use of multiple relationships for different parts of jointly financed projects</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This chapter does not require an executive agency to establish only one relationship between the United States Government and a State, a local government, or other recipient on a jointly financed project involving amounts from more than one program or appropriation when different relationships would otherwise be appropriate for different parts of the project.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1005</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6309.</num>
<heading> Non-propagation of core-based statistical area delineations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Beginning on the date of enactment of the MAPS Act of 2021, and notwithstanding any other provision of law, any change to the standards of core-based statistical area delineations pursuant to <ref>section 3504(e) of title 44</ref>—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> shall not propagate automatically for any non-statistical use by any domestic assistance program, including any such use as required through—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> statutory reference to any core-based statistical area delineation; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> administrative or regulatory reference to any core-based statistical area delineation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> shall propagate for any non-statistical use by any domestic assistance program only—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> if a relevant agency determines that such a propagation—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> supports the purposes of the program; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> is in the public interest; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> through affirmative adoption through notice-and-comment rulemaking pursuant to <ref>section 553 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The definitions in section 4 of the MAPS Act of 2021 shall apply to this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–219, § 5(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-05">Dec. 5, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2272</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>