<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 71—</num>
<heading>JOINT FUNDING SIMPLIFICATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7101.</num>
<heading> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes of this chapter are to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> enable States, local governments, and private nonprofit organizations to use assistance of the United States Government more effectively and efficiently;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> adapt the assistance more readily to particular needs through wider use of projects that are supported by more than one executive agency, assistance program, or appropriation of the United States Government; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> encourage Federal-State arrangements under which local governments and private nonprofit organizations may more effectively and efficiently combine Federal and State resources to support projects of common interest to those local governments and those organizations.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1035</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7102.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “applicant” means a State, local government, or private nonprofit organization applying for assistance for one project.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> “assistance program” means a program of the United States Government providing assistance through a grant or contract but does not include revenue sharing, a loan, a loan guarantee, or insurance.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> “local government” means a county, city, political subdivision of a county or city, or other general purpose political subdivision of a State, a school district, a council of governments, or other instrumentality of a local government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> “project” means an undertaking that includes components that contribute materially to carrying out one purpose or closely related purposes and are proposed or approved for assistance under—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> more than one United States Government program; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> at least one Government program and at least one State program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> “State” means a State of the United States, the District of Columbia, a territory or possession of the United States, an agency or instrumentality of a State, and a tribe as defined in section 3(c) of the Indian Financing Act of 1974 (<ref>25 U.S.C. 1452(c)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1035</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 4(f)(1)(V)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1363</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7103.</num>
<heading> Authority of the President and heads of executive agencies</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The President shall prescribe necessary regulations to carry out <ref>section 7101 of this title</ref> and to ensure that this chapter is applied by all executive agencies consistently. The regulations may require executive agencies to adopt or prescribe procedures requiring applicants for assistance for a project to be jointly financed under this chapter to take steps to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> get the views and recommendations of States and local governments that may be significantly affected by the project; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> resolve questions of common interest to those States and local governments before making application.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Subject to regulations prescribed under subsection (a) of this section and other law, the head of an executive agency may do the following by an order of the agency head or by agreement with another executive agency:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> identify related programs likely to be particularly suitable in providing joint financing for specific kinds of projects.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> to assist in planning and developing a project financed from different programs, develop and prescribe—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> guidelines;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> model or illustrative projects;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> joint or common application forms; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> other materials or guidance.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> review administrative program requirements to identify requirements that may impede joint financing of a project and modify the requirements when appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> establish common technical or administrative regulations for related programs to assist in providing joint financing to support a specific project or class of projects.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> establish joint or common application processing and project supervision procedures, including procedures for designating—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a lead agency responsible for processing applications; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a managing agency responsible for project supervision.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> The head of an executive agency shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> take maximum action to carry out <ref>section 7101 of this title</ref> in conducting an assistance program of the agency; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> consult and cooperate with the heads of other executive agencies to carry out <ref>section 7101 of this title</ref> in conducting assistance programs of different executive agencies that may be used jointly to finance projects undertaken by States, local governments, or private nonprofit organizations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1036</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7104.</num>
<heading> Processing project requests to be financed by at least 2 assistance programs</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In processing an application or request for assistance for a project to be financed by at least 2 assistance programs, the head of an executive agency shall take action that will ensure that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> required reviews and approvals are handled expeditiously;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> complete account is taken of special considerations of timing that are made known by the applicant that would affect the feasibility of a jointly financed project;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> an applicant is required to deal with a minimum number of representatives of the United States Government;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> an applicant is promptly informed of a decision or special problem that could affect the feasibility of providing joint assistance under the application; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> an applicant is not required to get information or assurances from one executive agency for a requesting executive agency when the requesting agency may get the information or assurances directly.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1037</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7105.</num>
<heading> Prescribing uniform technical and administrative provisions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> To make participation in a project easier than would be possible because of varying or conflicting technical or administrative regulations and procedures not required by law, the head of an executive agency may prescribe uniform provisions about inconsistent or conflicting requirements on—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> financial administration of the project (including accounting, reporting and auditing, and maintaining a separate bank account), to the extent consistent with <ref>section 7108 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the timing of payments by the United States Government for the project when one schedule or a combined schedule is to be established for the project;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> providing assistance by grant rather than procurement contract or by procurement contract rather than by grant; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> accountability for, or the disposition of, records, property, or structures acquired or constructed with assistance from the Government when common regulations are established for the project.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> To make easier the processing of applications for assistance, the head of an executive agency may provide for review of proposals for a project by one panel, board, or committee where reviews by separate panels, boards, or committees are not specifically required by law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> Notwithstanding a requirement that one public agency or a specific public agency be established or designated to carry out or supervise that part of the assistance from the Government under an assistance program for a jointly financed project, the head of the executive agency carrying out the program may waive the requirement when—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> administration by another public agency is consistent with State or local law and the objectives of the assistance program; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the waiver is requested by the head of a unit of general government certifying jurisdiction over the public agencies concerned; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the State or local public agencies concerned agree to the waiver.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1037</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7106.</num>
<heading> Delegation of supervision of assistance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">With the approval of the President, the head of an executive agency may delegate or otherwise arrange to have another executive agency carry out or supervise a project or class of projects jointly financed under this chapter. A delegation—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall be made under conditions ensuring that duties and powers delegated are exercised consistent with law; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> may not relieve the head of an executive agency of responsibility for the proper and efficient management of a project for which the agency provides assistance.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1038</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7107.</num>
<heading> Joint management funds</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> In supporting a project, a joint management fund may be established to administer more effectively amounts received from more than one assistance program or appropriation. A proportional share of the amount required to pay a grantee shall be transferred periodically to the fund from each program or appropriation. When a project is completed, the grantee shall return to the fund an amount not expended.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> An account in a joint management fund is subject to an agreement made by the heads of the executive agencies providing assistance for the project about the responsibilities of each agency. An agreement shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> ensure the availability of necessary information to the executive agencies and Congress;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provide that the agency administering a fund is responsible and accountable by program and appropriation for the amounts provided for the purposes of each account in the fund; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> include procedures for returning, subject to fiscal year limitations, an excess amount to participating executive agencies under the applicable appropriation. An excess amount of an expired appropriation lapses from the fund.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> For each project financed through an account in a joint management fund, a recipient of an amount from the fund shall keep records prescribed by the head of the executive agency responsible for administering the fund. The records shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the amount and disposition by the recipient of assistance received under each program and appropriation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the total cost of the project for which assistance was given or used;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> that part of the cost of the project provided from other sources; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> other records that will make it easier to carry out an audit.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Records of a recipient related to an amount received from a joint management fund shall be made available to the head of the executive agency responsible for administering the fund and the Comptroller General for inspection and audit.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<chapeau> For a project subject to a joint management fund, one non-Government share may be established conforming to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the proportional shares applicable to the assistance programs involved; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the proportional shares of an amount transferred to the project account from each of the programs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1038</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7108.</num>
<heading> Limitation on authority under sections 7105–7107</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Under regulations prescribed by the President, the head of an executive agency may act under sections 7105–7107 of this title for a project assisted under at least 2 assistance programs. The regulations shall ensure that the head of an executive agency acts under those sections only—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> when a problem cannot be adequately solved through other action under this chapter or other law;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> when necessary to promote expeditious processing of applications or effective and efficient administration of the project; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> in a way consistent with protecting the interest of the United States Government and with the program purposes and requirements of law.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1039</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7109.</num>
<heading> Appropriations available for joint financing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An appropriation available for technical assistance or personnel training under an assistance program is available for technical assistance and training for a project proposed or approved for joint financing involving the program and another assistance program.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1039</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7110.</num>
<heading> Use of joint financing provisions for Federal-State assisted projects</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Under regulations prescribed by the President, the head of an executive agency may make an agreement with a State to extend the benefits of this chapter to a project involving assistance from at least one executive agency and at least one State agency. The agreement may include arrangements to process requests or administer assistance on a joint basis.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1039</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7111.</num>
<heading> Report to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">By <date date="1984-02-03">February 3, 1984</date>, the President shall submit to Congress a report on actions taken under this chapter and make recommendations for its continuation, amendment, or termination. The report shall include a detailed evaluation of the operation of the chapter, including information on the benefits and costs of jointly financed projects that accrue to participating States, local governments, private nonprofit organizations, and the United States Government.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1039</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7112.</num>
<heading> Expiration date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This chapter expires on <date date="1985-02-03">February 3, 1985</date>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1039</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>