<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 9—</num>
<heading>AGENCY CHIEF FINANCIAL OFFICERS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 901.</num>
<heading> Establishment of agency Chief Financial Officers</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> There shall be within each agency described in subsection (b) an agency Chief Financial Officer. Each agency Chief Financial Officer shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> for those agencies described in subsection (b)(1)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> be designated by the President, in consultation with the head of the agency, from among officials of the agency who are required by law to be so appointed;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> for those agencies described in subsection (b)(2)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> be appointed by the head of the agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> be in the competitive service or the senior executive service; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> be career appointees; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> be appointed or designated, as applicable, from among individuals who possess demonstrated ability in general management of, and knowledge of and extensive practical experience in financial management practices in large governmental or business entities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The agencies referred to in subsection (a)(1) are the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Department of Agriculture.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Department of Commerce.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The Department of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The Department of Education.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The Department of Energy.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> The Department of Health and Human Services.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> The Department of Homeland Security.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> The Department of Housing and Urban Development.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> The Department of the Interior.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> The Department of Justice.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> The Department of Labor.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(L)</num>
<content> The Department of State.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(M)</num>
<content> The Department of Transportation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(N)</num>
<content> The Department of the Treasury.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(O)</num>
<content> The Department of Veterans Affairs.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(P)</num>
<content> The Environmental Protection Agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(Q)</num>
<content> The National Aeronautics and Space Administration.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The agencies referred to in subsection (a)(2) are the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Agency for International Development.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The General Services Administration.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The National Science Foundation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The Nuclear Regulatory Commission.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The Office of Personnel Management.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> The Small Business Administration.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> The Social Security Administration.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> There shall be within the Executive Office of the President a Chief Financial Officer, who shall be designated or appointed by the President from among individuals meeting the standards described in subsection (a)(3). The position of Chief Financial Officer established under this paragraph may be so established in any Office (including the Office of Administration) of the Executive Office of the President.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Chief Financial Officer designated or appointed under this subsection shall, to the extent that the President determines appropriate and in the interest of the United States, have the same authority and perform the same functions as apply in the case of a Chief Financial Officer of an agency described in subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The President shall submit to Congress notification with respect to any provision of section 902 that the President determines shall not apply to a Chief Financial Officer designated or appointed under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The President may designate an employee of the Executive Office of the President (other than the Chief Financial Officer), who shall be deemed “the head of the agency” for purposes of carrying out section 902, with respect to the Executive Office of the President.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–576, title II, § 205(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 2842</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–296, title I, § 108(j)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-08-15">Aug. 15, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1488</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–58, title VI, § 638(a)</ref>, <date date="1999-09-29">Sept. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 475</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–330, § 3(a)</ref>, (d)(2), <date date="2004-10-16">Oct. 16, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1276</ref>, 1277.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 902.</num>
<heading> Authority and functions of agency Chief Financial Officers</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> An agency Chief Financial Officer shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> report directly to the head of the agency regarding financial management matters;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> oversee all financial management activities relating to the programs and operations of the agency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> develop and maintain an integrated agency accounting and financial management system, including financial reporting and internal controls, which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> complies with applicable accounting principles, standards, and requirements, and internal control standards;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> complies with such policies and requirements as may be prescribed by the Director of the Office of Management and Budget;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> complies with any other requirements applicable to such systems; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> provides for—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> complete, reliable, consistent, and timely information which is prepared on a uniform basis and which is responsive to the financial information needs of agency management;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the development and reporting of cost information;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the integration of accounting and budgeting information; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the systematic measurement of performance;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> make recommendations to the head of the agency regarding the selection of the Deputy Chief Financial Officer of the agency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> direct, manage, and provide policy guidance and oversight of agency financial management personnel, activities, and operations, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> the preparation and annual revision of an agency plan to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> implement the 5-year financial management plan prepared by the Director of the Office of Management and Budget under <ref>section 3512(a)(3) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> comply with the requirements established under sections 3515 and subsections (e) and (f) of <ref>section 3521 of this title</ref>;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the development of agency financial management budgets;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the recruitment, selection, and training of personnel to carry out agency financial management functions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the approval and management of agency financial management systems design or enhancement projects;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the implementation of agency asset management systems, including systems for cash management, credit management, debt collection, and property and inventory management and control;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> prepare and transmit, by not later than 60 days after the submission of the audit report required by <ref>section 3521(f) of this title</ref>, an annual report to the agency head and the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, which shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a description and analysis of the status of financial management of the agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the annual financial statements prepared under <ref>section 3515 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the audit report transmitted to the head of the agency under <ref>section 3521(f) of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a summary of the reports on internal accounting and administrative control systems submitted to the President and the Congress under the amendments made by the Federal Managers’ Financial Integrity Act of 1982 (<ref>Public Law 97–255</ref>); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> other information the head of the agency considers appropriate to fully inform the President and the Congress concerning the financial management of the agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> monitor the financial execution of the budget of the agency in relation to actual expenditures, and prepare and submit to the head of the agency timely performance reports; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> review, on a biennial basis, the fees, royalties, rents, and other charges imposed by the agency for services and things of value it provides, and make recommendations on revising those charges to reflect costs incurred by it in providing those services and things of value.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> In addition to the authority otherwise provided by this section, each agency Chief Financial Officer—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> subject to paragraph (2), shall have access to all records, reports, audits, reviews, documents, papers, recommendations, or other material which are the property of the agency or which are available to the agency, and which relate to programs and operations with respect to which that agency Chief Financial Officer has responsibilities under this section;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> may request such information or assistance as may be necessary for carrying out the duties and responsibilities provided by this section from any Federal, State, or local governmental entity; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> to the extent and in such amounts as may be provided in advance by appropriations Acts, may—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> enter into contracts and other arrangements with public agencies and with private persons for the preparation of financial statements, studies, analyses, and other services; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> make such payments as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this section.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraph (1)(B), this subsection does not provide to an agency Chief Financial Officer any access greater than permitted under any other law to records, reports, audits, reviews, documents, papers, recommendations, or other material of any Office of Inspector General established under chapter 4 of title 5.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–576, title II, § 205(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 2843</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(b)(49)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4348</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 903.</num>
<heading> Establishment of agency Deputy Chief Financial Officers</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> There shall be within each agency described in section 901(b) an agency Deputy Chief Financial Officer, who shall report directly to the agency Chief Financial Officer on financial management matters. The position of agency Deputy Chief Financial Officer shall be a career reserved position in the Senior Executive Service.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Consistent with qualification standards developed by, and in consultation with, the agency Chief Financial Officer and the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, the head of each agency shall appoint as Deputy Chief Financial Officer an individual with demonstrated ability and experience in accounting, budget execution, financial and management analysis, and systems development, and not less than 6 years practical experience in financial management at large governmental entities.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–576, title II, § 205(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 2845</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>