<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 38—</num>
<heading>ADMINISTRATIVE REMEDIES FOR FALSE CLAIMS AND STATEMENTS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3801.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> “authority” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an executive department;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a military department;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> an establishment (as such term is defined in <ref>section 401 of title 5</ref>) which is not an executive department;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the United States Postal Service;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the National Science Foundation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> a designated Federal entity (as such term is defined under <ref>section 415(a) of title 5</ref>);</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> “authority head” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the head of an authority; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an official or employee of the authority designated, in regulations promulgated by the head of the authority, to act on behalf of the head of the authority;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> “claim” means any request, demand, or submission—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> made to an authority for property, services, or money (including money representing grants, loans, insurance, or benefits);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> made to a recipient of property, services, or money from an authority or to a party to a contract with an authority—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> for property or services if the United States—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> provided such property or services;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> provided any portion of the funds for the purchase of such property or services; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> will reimburse such recipient or party for the purchase of such property or services; or</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> for the payment of money (including money representing grants, loans, insurance, or benefits) if the United States—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> provided any portion of the money requested or demanded; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> will reimburse such recipient or party for any portion of the money paid on such request or demand; or</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> made to an authority which has the effect of concealing or improperly avoiding or decreasing an obligation to pay or transmit property, services, or money to the authority,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">except that such term does not include any claim made in any return of tax imposed by the Internal Revenue Code of 1986;</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> “investigating official” means an individual who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> in the case of an authority in which an Office of Inspector General is established by chapter 4 of title 5 or by any other Federal law, is the Inspector General of that authority or an officer or employee of such Office designated by the Inspector General;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in the case of an authority in which an Office of Inspector General is not established by chapter 4 of title 5 or by any other Federal law, is an officer or employee of the authority designated by the authority head to conduct investigations under <ref>section 3803(a)(1) of this title</ref>; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> in the case of a military department, is the Inspector General of the Department of Defense or an officer or employee of the Office of Inspector General of the Department of Defense who is designated by the Inspector General; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> who, if a member of the Armed Forces of the United States on active duty, is serving in grade O–7 or above or, if a civilian employee, is serving in a position for which the rate of basic pay is not less than the minimum rate of basic pay for grade GS–16 under the General Schedule;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> “knows or has reason to know”, for purposes of establishing liability under section 3802, means that a person, with respect to a claim or statement—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> has actual knowledge that the claim or statement is false, fictitious, or fraudulent;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> acts in deliberate ignorance of the truth or falsity of the claim or statement; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> acts in reckless disregard of the truth or falsity of the claim or statement,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">and no proof of specific intent to defraud is required;</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> “person” means any individual, partnership, corporation, association, or private organization;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<chapeau> “presiding officer” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the case of an authority to which the provisions of subchapter II of chapter 5 of title 5 apply, an administrative law judge appointed in the authority pursuant to section 3105 of such title or detailed to the authority pursuant to section 3344 of such title;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> in the case of an authority to which the provisions of such subchapter do not apply, an officer or employee of the authority who—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is selected under chapter 33 of title 5 pursuant to the competitive examination process applicable to administrative law judges;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> is appointed by the authority head to conduct hearings under <ref>section 3803 of this title</ref>;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> is assigned to cases in rotation so far as practicable;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> may not perform duties inconsistent with the duties and responsibilities of a presiding officer;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> is entitled to pay prescribed by the Office of Personnel Management independently of ratings and recommendations made by the authority and in accordance with chapter 51 of such title and subchapter III of chapter 53 of such title;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> is not subject to performance appraisal pursuant to chapter 43 of such title; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> may be removed, suspended, furloughed, or reduced in grade or pay only for good cause established and determined by the Merit Systems Protection Board on the record after opportunity for hearing by such Board; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a member of the board of contract appeals pursuant to <ref>section 7105 of title 41</ref>, if the authority does not employ an available presiding officer under subparagraph (A);</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<chapeau> “reviewing official” means any officer or employee of an authority—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> who is designated by the authority head to make the determination required under <ref>section 3803(a)(2) of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> who, if a member of the Armed Forces of the United States on active duty, is serving in grade O–7 or above or, if a civilian employee, is serving in a position for which the rate of basic pay is not less than the minimum rate of basic pay for grade GS–16 under the General Schedule; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> who is—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> not subject to supervision by, or required to report to, the investigating official; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> not employed in the organizational unit of the authority in which the investigating official is employed;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<chapeau> “statement” means any representation, certification, affirmation, document, record, or accounting or bookkeeping entry made—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> with respect to a claim or to obtain the approval or payment of a claim (including relating to eligibility to make a claim); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> with respect to (including relating to eligibility for)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a contract with, or a bid or proposal for a contract with; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a grant, loan, or benefit from,</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">an authority, or any State, political subdivision of a State, or other party, if the United States Government provides any portion of the money or property under such contract or for such grant, loan, or benefit, or if the Government will reimburse such State, political subdivision, or party for any portion of the money or property under such contract or for such grant, loan, or benefit,</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">except that such term does not include any statement made in any return of tax imposed by the Internal Revenue Code of 1986;</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> “material” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 3729(b) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> “obligation” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 3729(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of paragraph (3) of subsection (a)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> each voucher, invoice, claim form, or other individual request or demand for property, services, or money constitutes a separate claim;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> each claim for property, services, or money is subject to this chapter regardless of whether such property, services, or money is actually delivered or paid; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a claim shall be considered made, presented, or submitted to an authority, recipient, or party when such claim is actually made to an agent, fiscal intermediary, or other entity, including any State or political subdivision thereof, acting for or on behalf of such authority, recipient, or party.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of paragraph (9) of subsection (a)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> each written representation, certification, or affirmation constitutes a separate statement; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a statement shall be considered made, presented, or submitted to an authority when such statement is actually made to an agent, fiscal intermediary, or other entity, including any State or political subdivision thereof, acting for or on behalf of such authority.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> For purposes of subsection (a)(10), materiality shall be determined in the same manner as under <ref>section 3729 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–509, title VI, § 6103(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1934</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 2095</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 4(f)(1)(Q)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1362</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–69, title VII, § 7017</ref>, <date date="2007-08-09">Aug. 9, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 684</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–409, § 10</ref>, <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4314</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(b)(56)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4349</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. E, title LII, § 5203(b)(1)</ref>, (g)(1)(A), (i), <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2440</ref>, 2442, 2443.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3802.</num>
<heading> False claims and statements; liability</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Any person who makes, presents, or submits, or causes to be made, presented, or submitted, a claim that the person knows or has reason to know—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is false, fictitious, or fraudulent;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> includes or is supported by any written statement which asserts a material fact which is false, fictitious, or fraudulent;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> includes or is supported by any written statement that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> omits a material fact;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> is false, fictitious, or fraudulent as a result of such omission; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> is a statement in which the person making, presenting, or submitting such statement has a duty to include such material fact; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> is for payment for the provision of property or services which the person has not provided as claimed,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be subject to, in addition to any other remedy that may be prescribed by law, a civil penalty of not more than $5,000 for each such claim. Except as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection, such person shall also be subject to an assessment, in lieu of damages sustained by the United States because of such claim, of not more than twice the amount of such claim, or the portion of such claim, which is determined under this chapter to be in violation of the preceding sentence.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Any person who makes, presents, or submits, or causes to be made, presented, or submitted, a written statement that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> the person knows or has reason to know—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> asserts a material fact which is false, fictitious, or fraudulent; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> omits a material fact; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> is false, fictitious, or fraudulent as a result of such omission;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of a statement described in clause (ii) of subparagraph (A), is a statement in which the person making, presenting, or submitting such statement has a duty to include such material fact; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> contains or is accompanied by an express certification or affirmation of the truthfulness and accuracy of the contents of the statement,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be subject to, in addition to any other remedy that may be prescribed by law, a civil penalty of not more than $5,000 for each such statement.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Except as provided in subparagraph (B), an assessment shall not be made under the second sentence of paragraph (1) with respect to a claim if payment by the Government has not been made on such claim.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> In the case of a claim described in section 3801(a)(3)(C), an assessment shall not be made under the second sentence of paragraph (1) in an amount that is more than double the value of the property, services, or money that was wrongfully withheld from the authority.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a determination under <ref>section 3803(a)(2) of this title</ref> that there is adequate evidence to believe that a person is liable under subsection (a) of this section; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a determination under <ref>section 3803 of this title</ref> that a person is liable under subsection (a) of this section,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">may provide the authority with grounds for commencing any administrative or contractual action against such person which is authorized by law and which is in addition to any action against such person under this chapter.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A determination referred to in paragraph (1) of this subsection may be used by the authority, but shall not require such authority, to commence any administrative or contractual action which is authorized by law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> In the case of an administrative or contractual action to suspend or debar any person who is eligible to enter into contracts with the Federal Government, a determination referred to in paragraph (1) of this subsection shall not be considered as a conclusive determination of such person’s responsibility pursuant to Federal procurement laws and regulations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–509, title VI, § 6103(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1937</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. E, title LII, § 5203(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2440</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3803.</num>
<heading> Hearing and determinations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The investigating official of an authority may investigate allegations that a person is liable under <ref>section 3802 of this title</ref> and shall report the findings and conclusions of such investigation to the reviewing official of the authority. The preceding sentence does not modify any responsibility of an investigating official to report violations of criminal law to the Attorney General.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> If the reviewing official of an authority determines, based upon the report of the investigating official under paragraph (1) of this subsection, that there is adequate evidence to believe that a person is liable under <ref>section 3802 of this title</ref>, the reviewing official shall transmit to the Attorney General a written notice of the intention of such official to refer the allegations of such liability to a presiding officer of such authority. Such notice shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a statement of the reasons of the reviewing official for the referral of such allegations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a statement specifying the evidence which supports such allegations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a description of the claims or statements for which liability under <ref>section 3802 of this title</ref> is alleged;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> an estimate of the amount of money or the value of property or services requested or demanded in violation of <ref>section 3802 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> a statement of any exculpatory or mitigating circumstances which may relate to such claims or statements.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Within 90 days after receipt of a notice from a reviewing official under paragraph (2) of subsection (a), the Attorney General or an Assistant Attorney General designated by the Attorney General shall transmit a written statement to the reviewing official which specifies—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> that the Attorney General or such Assistant Attorney General approves or disapproves the referral to a presiding officer of the allegations of liability stated in such notice;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in any case in which the referral of allegations is approved, that the initiation of a proceeding under this section with respect to such allegations is appropriate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> in any case in which the referral of allegations is disapproved, the reasons for such disapproval.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A reviewing official may refer allegations of liability to a presiding officer only if the Attorney General or an Assistant Attorney General designated by the Attorney General approves the referral of such allegations in a written statement described in paragraph (1) of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> If the Attorney General or an Assistant Attorney General designated by the Attorney General transmits to an authority head a written finding that the continuation of any hearing under this section with respect to a claim or statement may adversely affect any pending or potential criminal or civil action related to such claim or statement, such hearing shall be immediately stayed and may be resumed only upon written authorization of the Attorney General.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> No allegations of liability under <ref>section 3802 of this title</ref> with respect to any claim made, presented, or submitted by any person shall be referred to a presiding officer under paragraph (2) of subsection (b) if the reviewing official determines that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an amount of money in excess of $1,000,000; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> property or services with a value in excess of $1,000,000,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">is requested or demanded in violation of <ref>section 3802 of this title</ref> in such claim or in a group of related claims which are submitted at the time such claim is submitted.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Except as provided in subparagraph (B) of this paragraph, no allegations of liability against an individual under <ref>section 3802 of this title</ref> with respect to any claim or statement made, presented, or submitted, or caused to be made, presented, or submitted, by such individual relating to any benefits received by such individual shall be referred to a presiding officer under paragraph (2) of subsection (b).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> Allegations of liability against an individual under <ref>section 3802 of this title</ref> with respect to any claim or statement made, presented, or submitted, or caused to be made, presented, or submitted, by such individual relating to any benefits received by such individual may be referred to a presiding officer under paragraph (2) of subsection (b) if—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> such claim or statement is made by such individual in making application for such benefits;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> such allegations relate to the eligibility of such individual to receive such benefits; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> with respect to such claim or statement, the individual—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> has actual knowledge that the claim or statement is false, fictitious, or fraudulent;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> acts in deliberate ignorance of the truth or falsity of the claim or statement; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> acts in reckless disregard of the truth or falsity of the claim or statement.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of this subsection, the term “benefits” means—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> benefits under the supplemental security income program under title XVI of the Social Security Act;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> old age, survivors, and disability insurance benefits under title II of the Social Security Act;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> benefits under title XVIII of the Social Security Act;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> assistance under a State program funded under part A of title IV of the Social Security Act;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> medical assistance under a State plan approved under section 1902(a) of the Social Security Act;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> benefits under title XX of the Social Security Act;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> benefits under the supplemental nutrition assistance program (as defined in section 3 of the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> benefits under chapters 11, 13, 15, 17, and 21 of title 38;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ix)</num>
<content> benefits under the Black Lung Benefits Act;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(x)</num>
<content> benefits under the special supplemental nutrition program for women, infants, and children established under section 17 of the Child Nutrition Act of 1966;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(xi)</num>
<content> benefits under section 336 of the Older Americans Act;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(xii)</num>
<content> any annuity or other benefit under the Railroad Retirement Act of 1974;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(xiii)</num>
<content> benefits under the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(xiv)</num>
<content> benefits under any housing assistance program for lower income families or elderly or handicapped persons which is administered by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development or the Secretary of Agriculture;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(xv)</num>
<content> benefits under the Low-Income Home Energy Assistance Act of 1981; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(xvi)</num>
<content> benefits under part A of the Energy Conservation in Existing Buildings Act of 1976,</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">which are intended for the personal use of the individual who receives the benefits or for a member of the individual’s family.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Adjustment for Inflation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The maximum amount in paragraph (1) shall be adjusted for inflation in the same manner and to the same extent as civil monetary penalties under the Federal Civil Penalties Inflation Adjustment Act <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002070">1</ref> (<ref>28 U.S.C. 2461</ref> note).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> On or after the date on which a reviewing official is permitted to refer allegations of liability to a presiding officer under subsection (b) of this section, the reviewing official shall mail, by registered or certified mail, or shall deliver, a notice to the person alleged to be liable under <ref>section 3802 of this title</ref>. Such notice shall specify the allegations of liability against such person and shall state the right of such person to request a hearing with respect to such allegations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> If, within 30 days after receiving a notice under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the person receiving such notice requests a hearing with respect to the allegations contained in such notice—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the reviewing official shall refer such allegations to a presiding officer for the commencement of such hearing;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> in the case of a referral to a presiding officer described in subparagraph (A) or (B) of section 3801(a)(7), the presiding officer shall commence such hearing by mailing by registered or certified mail, or by delivery of, a notice which complies with paragraphs (2)(A) and (3)(B)(i) of subsection (g) to such person; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> in the case of a referral to a presiding officer described in subparagraph (C) of section 3801(a)(7)—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<chapeau> the reviewing official shall submit a copy of the notice required by under paragraph (1) and of the response of the person receiving such notice requesting a hearing—</chapeau>
<item class="indent3">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> to the board of contract appeals that has jurisdiction over matters arising from the agency of the reviewing official pursuant to <ref>section 7105(e)(1) of title 41</ref>; or</content>
</item>
<item class="indent3">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> if the Chair of the board of contract appeals declines to accept the referral, to any other board of contract appeals; and</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the reviewing official shall simultaneously mail, by registered or certified mail, or shall deliver, notice to the person alleged to be liable under section 3802 that the referral has been made to an agency board of contract appeals with an explanation as to where the person may obtain the relevant rules of procedure promulgated by the board; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> in the case of a hearing conducted by a presiding officer described in subparagraph (C) of section 3801(a)(7)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the presiding officer shall conduct the hearing according to the rules and procedures promulgated by the board of contract appeals; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the hearing shall not be subject to the provisions in subsection (g)(2), (h), or (i).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Except as provided in subparagraph (B) of this paragraph, at any time after receiving a notice under paragraph (2)(B) of subsection (d), the person receiving such notice shall be entitled to review, and upon payment of a reasonable fee for duplication, shall be entitled to obtain a copy of, all relevant and material documents, transcripts, records, and other materials, which relate to such allegations and upon which the findings and conclusions of the investigating official under paragraph (1) of subsection (a) are based.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A person is not entitled under subparagraph (A) to review and obtain a copy of any document, transcript, record, or material which is privileged under Federal law.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> At any time after receiving a notice under paragraph (2)(B) of subsection (d), the person receiving such notice shall be entitled to obtain all exculpatory information in the possession of the investigating official or the reviewing official relating to the allegations contained in such notice. The provisions of subparagraph (B) of paragraph (1) do not apply to any document, transcript, record, or other material, or any portion thereof, in which such exculpatory information is contained.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<chapeau> Any hearing commenced under paragraph (2) of subsection (d) shall be conducted by the presiding officer on the record in order to determine—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the liability of a person under <ref>section 3802 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> if a person is determined to be liable under such section, the amount of any civil penalty or assessment to be imposed on such person.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Any such determination shall be based on the preponderance of the evidence.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Each hearing under subsection (f) of this section shall be conducted—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> in the case of an authority to which the provisions of subchapter II of chapter 5 of title 5 apply, in accordance with—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the provisions of such subchapter to the extent that such provisions are not inconsistent with the provisions of this chapter; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> procedures promulgated by the authority head under paragraph (3) of this subsection; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of an authority to which the provisions of such subchapter do not apply, in accordance with procedures promulgated by the authority head under paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> An authority head of an authority described in subparagraph (B) of paragraph (1) shall by regulation promulgate procedures for the conduct of hearings under this chapter. Such procedures shall include:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> The provision of written notice of the hearing to any person alleged to be liable under <ref>section 3802 of this title</ref>, including written notice of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the time, place, and nature of the hearing;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the legal authority and jurisdiction under which the hearing is to be held; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the matters of facts and law to be asserted.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The provision to any person alleged to be liable under <ref>section 3802 of this title</ref> of opportunities for the submission of facts, arguments, offers of settlement, or proposals of adjustment.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> Procedures to ensure that the presiding officer shall not, except to the extent required for the disposition of ex parte matters as authorized by law—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> consult a person or party on a fact in issue, unless on notice and opportunity for all parties to the hearing to participate; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> be responsible to or subject to the supervision or direction of the investigating official or the reviewing official.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Procedures to ensure that the investigating official and the reviewing official do not participate or advise in the decision required under subsection (h) of this section or the review of the decision by the authority head under subsection (i) of this section, except as provided in subsection (j) of this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The provision to any person alleged to be liable under <ref>section 3802 of this title</ref> of opportunities to present such person’s case through oral or documentary evidence, to submit rebuttal evidence, and to conduct such cross-examination as may be required for a full and true disclosure of the facts.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Procedures to permit any person alleged to be liable under <ref>section 3802 of this title</ref> to be accompanied, represented, and advised by counsel or such other qualified representative as the authority head may specify in such regulations.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(G)</num>
<chapeau> Procedures to ensure that the hearing is conducted in an impartial manner, including procedures to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> permit the presiding officer to at any time disqualify himself; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> permit the filing, in good faith, of a timely and sufficient affidavit alleging personal bias or another reason for disqualification of a presiding officer or a reviewing official.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Each authority head shall promulgate by regulation procedures described in subparagraph (B) of this paragraph for the conduct of hearings under this chapter. Such procedures shall be in addition to the procedures described in paragraph (1) or paragraph (2) of this subsection, as the case may be.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> The procedures referred to in subparagraph (A) of this paragraph are:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Procedures for the inclusion, in any written notice of a hearing under this section to any person alleged to be liable under <ref>section 3802 of this title</ref>, of a description of the procedures for the conduct of the hearing.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Procedures to permit discovery by any person alleged to be liable under <ref>section 3802 of this title</ref> only to the extent that the presiding officer determines that such discovery is necessary for the expeditious, fair, and reasonable consideration of the issues, except that such procedures shall not apply to documents, transcripts, records, or other material which a person is entitled to review under paragraph (1) of subsection (e) or to information to which a person is entitled under paragraph (2) of such subsection. Procedures promulgated under this clause shall prohibit the discovery of the notice required under subsection (a)(2) of this section.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> Each hearing under subsection (f) of this section shall be held—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the judicial district of the United States in which the person alleged to be liable under <ref>section 3802 of this title</ref> resides or transacts business;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the judicial district of the United States in which the claim or statement upon which the allegation of liability under such section was made, presented, or submitted; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> in such other place as may be agreed upon by such person and the presiding officer who will conduct such hearing.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<content> The presiding officer shall issue a written decision, including findings and determinations, after the conclusion of the hearing. Such decision shall include the findings of fact and conclusions of law which the presiding officer relied upon in determining whether a person is liable under this chapter. The presiding officer shall promptly send to each party to the hearing a copy of such decision and a statement describing the right of any person determined to be liable under <ref>section 3802 of this title</ref> to appeal the decision of the presiding officer to the authority head under paragraph (2) of subsection (i).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection and <ref>section 3805 of this title</ref>, the decision, including the findings and determinations, of the presiding officer issued under subsection (h) of this section are final.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Except as provided in clause (ii) of this subparagraph, within 30 days after the presiding officer issues a decision under subsection (h) of this section, any person determined in such decision to be liable under <ref>section 3802 of this title</ref> may appeal such decision to the authority head.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> If, within the 30-day period described in clause (i) of this subparagraph, a person determined to be liable under this chapter requests the authority head for an extension of such 30-day period to file an appeal of a decision issued by the presiding officer under subsection (h) of this section, the authority head may extend such period if such person demonstrates good cause for such extension.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Any authority head reviewing under this section the decision, findings, and determinations of a presiding officer shall not consider any objection that was not raised in the hearing conducted pursuant to subsection (f) of this section unless a demonstration is made of extraordinary circumstances causing the failure to raise the objection. If any party demonstrates to the satisfaction of the authority head that additional evidence not presented at such hearing is material and that there were reasonable grounds for the failure to present such evidence at such hearing, the authority head shall remand the matter to the presiding officer for consideration of such additional evidence.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The authority head may affirm, reduce, reverse, compromise, remand, or settle any penalty or assessment determined by the presiding officer pursuant to this section. The authority head shall promptly send to each party to the appeal a copy of the decision of the authority head and a statement describing the right of any person determined to be liable under <ref>section 3802 of this title</ref> to judicial review under <ref>section 3805 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The reviewing official has the exclusive authority to compromise or settle any allegations of liability under <ref>section 3802 of this title</ref> against a person without the consent of the presiding officer at any time after the date on which the reviewing official is permitted to refer allegations of liability to a presiding officer under subsection (b) of this section and prior to the date on which the presiding officer issues a decision under subsection (h) of this section. Any such compromise or settlement shall be in writing.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A reviewing official shall notify the Attorney General in writing not later than 30 days before entering into any agreement to compromise or settle allegations of liability under section 3802 and before the date on which the reviewing official is permitted to refer allegations of liability to a presiding officer under subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–509, title VI, § 6103(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1939</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–448, title II, § 204(w)(2)(C)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4746</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–193, title I, § 110</ref>(<i>o</i>), <date date="1996-08-22">Aug. 22, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2175</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–78, title VII, § 752(b)(13)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-22">Oct. 22, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1169</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title IV</ref>, §§ 4002(b)(1)(A), (B), (2)(S), 4115(c)(2)(E), <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1095–1097</ref>, 1110; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title IV, §§ 4002(b)(1)(A), (B), (2)(S), 4115(c)(2)(E), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1857, 1858, 1871; <ref>Pub. L. 113–79, title IV, § 4030</ref>(<i>o</i>), <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 815</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. E, title LII, § 5203(c)</ref>, (f), (g)(1)(B), <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2440–2442</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3804.</num>
<heading> Subpoena authority</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> For the purposes of an investigation under <ref>section 3803(a)(1) of this title</ref>, an investigating official is authorized to require by subpoena the production of all information, documents, reports, answers, records, accounts, papers, and data not otherwise reasonably available to the authority.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> For the purposes of conducting a hearing under <ref>section 3803(f) of this title</ref>, a presiding officer is authorized—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to administer oaths or affirmations; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to require by subpoena the attendance and testimony of witnesses and the production of all information, documents, reports, answers, records, accounts, papers, and other data and documentary evidence which the presiding officer considers relevant and material to the hearing.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> In the case of contumacy or refusal to obey a subpoena issued pursuant to subsection (a) or (b) of this section, the district courts of the United States shall have jurisdiction to issue an appropriate order for the enforcement of any such subpoena. Any failure to obey such order of the court is punishable by such court as contempt. In any case in which an authority seeks the enforcement of a subpoena issued pursuant to subsection (a) or (b) of this section, the authority shall request the Attorney General to petition any district court in which a hearing under this chapter is being conducted, or in which the person receiving the subpoena resides or conducts business, to issue such an order.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–509, title VI, § 6103(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1944</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3805.</num>
<heading> Judicial review</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A determination by a reviewing official under <ref>section 3803 of this title</ref> shall be final and shall not be subject to judicial review.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Unless a petition is filed under this section, a determination under <ref>section 3803 of this title</ref> that a person is liable under <ref>section 3802 of this title</ref> shall be final and shall not be subject to judicial review.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> Any person who has been determined to be liable under <ref>section 3802 of this title</ref> pursuant to <ref>section 3803 of this title</ref> may obtain review of such determination in—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the United States district court for the district in which such person resides or transacts business;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the United States district court for the district in which the claim or statement upon which the determination of liability is based was made, presented, or submitted; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the United States District Court for the District of Columbia.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> Such review may be obtained by filing in any such court a written petition that such determination be modified or set aside. Such petition shall be filed—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> only after such person has exhausted all administrative remedies under this chapter; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> within 60 days after the date on which the authority head sends such person a copy of the decision of such authority head under <ref>section 3803(i)(2) of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The clerk of the court shall transmit a copy of a petition filed under paragraph (1) of this subsection to the authority and to the Attorney General. Upon receipt of the copy of such petition, the authority shall transmit to the Attorney General the record in the proceeding resulting in the determination of liability under <ref>section 3802 of this title</ref>. Except as otherwise provided in this section, the district courts of the United States shall have jurisdiction to review the decision, findings, and determinations in issue and to affirm, modify, remand for further consideration, or set aside, in whole or in part, the decision, findings, and determinations of the authority, and to enforce such decision, findings, and determinations to the extent that such decision, findings, and determinations are affirmed or modified.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The decisions, findings, and determinations of the authority with respect to questions of fact shall be final and conclusive, and shall not be set aside unless such decisions, findings, and determinations are found by the court to be unsupported by substantial evidence. In concluding whether the decisions, findings, and determinations of an authority are unsupported by substantial evidence, the court shall review the whole record or those parts of it cited by a party, and due account shall be taken of the rule of prejudicial error.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Any district court reviewing under this section the decision, findings, and determinations of an authority shall not consider any objection that was not raised in the hearing conducted pursuant to <ref>section 3803(f) of this title</ref> unless a demonstration is made of extraordinary circumstances causing the failure to raise the objection. If any party demonstrates to the satisfaction of the court that additional evidence not presented at such hearing is material and that there were reasonable grounds for the failure to present such evidence at such hearing, the court shall remand the matter to the authority for consideration of such additional evidence.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> Upon a final determination by the district court that a person is liable under <ref>section 3802 of this title</ref>, the court shall enter a final judgment for the appropriate amount in favor of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–509, title VI, § 6103(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1944</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3806.</num>
<heading> Collection of civil penalties and assessments</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Attorney General shall be responsible for judicial enforcement of any civil penalty or assessment imposed pursuant to the provisions of this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Any penalty or assessment imposed in a determination which has become final pursuant to this chapter may be recovered in a civil action brought by the Attorney General. In any such action, no matter that was raised or that could have been raised in a hearing conducted under <ref>section 3803(f) of this title</ref> or pursuant to judicial review under <ref>section 3805 of this title</ref> may be raised as a defense, and the determination of liability and the determination of amounts of penalties and assessments shall not be subject to review.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The district courts of the United States shall have jurisdiction of any action commenced by the United States under subsection (b) of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Any action under subsection (b) of this section may, without regard to venue requirements, be joined and consolidated with or asserted as a counterclaim, cross-claim, or setoff by the United States in any other civil action which includes as parties the United States and the person against whom such action may be brought.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> The United States Court of Federal Claims shall have jurisdiction of any action under subsection (b) of this section to recover any penalty or assessment if the cause of action is asserted by the United States as a counterclaim in a matter pending in such court.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> The Attorney General shall have exclusive authority to compromise or settle any penalty or assessment the determination of which is the subject of a pending petition pursuant to <ref>section 3805 of this title</ref> or a pending action to recover such penalty or assessment pursuant to this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> Except as provided in paragraph (2)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any amount collected under this chapter shall be credited first to reimburse the authority or other Federal entity that expended costs in support of the investigation or prosecution of the action, including any court or hearing costs; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> amounts reimbursed under clause (i) shall—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<chapeau> be deposited in—</chapeau>
<item class="indent3">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> the appropriations account of the authority or other Federal entity from which the costs described in subparagraph (A) were obligated;</content>
</item>
<item class="indent3">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> a similar appropriations account of the authority or other Federal entity; or</content>
</item>
<item class="indent3">
<num>(cc)</num>
<content> if the authority or other Federal entity expended nonappropriated funds, another appropriate account; and</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> remain available until expended.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Any amount remaining after reimbursements described in subparagraph (A) shall be deposited as miscellaneous receipts in the Treasury of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Any amount of a penalty or assessment imposed by the United States Postal Service under this chapter shall be deposited in the Postal Service Fund established by <ref>section 2003 of title 39</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Any amount of a penalty or assessment imposed by the Secretary of Health and Human Services under this chapter with respect to a claim or statement made in connection with old age and survivors benefits under title II of the Social Security Act shall be deposited in the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Any amount of a penalty or assessment imposed by the Secretary of Health and Human Services under this chapter with respect to a claim or statement made in connection with disability benefits under title II of the Social Security Act shall be deposited in the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Any amount of a penalty or assessment imposed by the Secretary of Health and Human Services under this chapter with respect to a claim or statement made in connection with benefits under part A of title XVIII of the Social Security Act shall be deposited in the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Any amount of a penalty or assessment imposed by the Secretary of Health and Human Services under this chapter with respect to a claim or statement made in connection with benefits under part B of title XVIII of the Social Security Act shall be deposited in the Federal Supplementary Medical Insurance Trust Fund.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–509, title VI, § 6103(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1945</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–572, title IX, § 902(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4516</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. E, title LII, § 5203(d)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2440</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3807.</num>
<heading> Right to administrative offset</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The amount of any penalty or assessment which has become final under <ref>section 3803 of this title</ref>, or for which a judgment has been entered under section 3805(e) or 3806 of this title, or any amount agreed upon in a settlement or compromise under section 3803(j) or 3806(f) of this title, may be collected by administrative offset under <ref>section 3716 of this title</ref>, except that an administrative offset may not be made under this subsection against a refund of an overpayment of Federal taxes, then or later owing by the United States to the person liable for such penalty or assessment.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> All amounts collected pursuant to this section shall be remitted to the Secretary of the Treasury for deposit in accordance with <ref>section 3806(g) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–509, title VI, § 6103(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1947</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3808.</num>
<heading> Limitations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> A notice to the person alleged to be liable with respect to a claim or statement shall be mailed or delivered in accordance with section 3803(d)(1) not later than the later of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> 6 years after the date on which the violation of section 3802 is committed; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> 3 years after the date on which facts material to the action are known or reasonably should have been known by the authority head, but in no event more than 10 years after the date on which the violation is committed.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> A civil action to recover a penalty or assessment under <ref>section 3806 of this title</ref> shall be commenced within 3 years after the date on which the determination of liability for such penalty or assessment becomes final.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> If at any time during the course of proceedings brought pursuant to this chapter the authority head receives or discovers any specific information regarding bribery, gratuities, conflict of interest, or other corruption or similar activity in relation to a false claim or statement, the authority head shall immediately report such information to the Attorney General, and in the case of an authority in which an Office of Inspector General is established by chapter 4 of title 5 or by any other Federal law, to the Inspector General of that authority.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–509, title VI, § 6103(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1947</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(b)(57)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4349</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. E, title LII, § 5203(h)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2443</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3809.</num>
<heading> Regulations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Within 180 days after the date of enactment of this chapter, each authority head shall promulgate rules and regulations necessary to implement the provisions of this chapter. Such rules and regulations shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> ensure that investigating officials and reviewing officials are not responsible for conducting the hearing required in <ref>section 3803(f) of this title</ref>, making the determinations required by subsections (f) and (h) of <ref>section 3803 of this title</ref>, or making collections under <ref>section 3806 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> require a reviewing official to include in any notice required by <ref>section 3803(a)(2) of this title</ref> a statement which specifies that the reviewing official has determined that there is a reasonable prospect of collecting, from a person with respect to whom the reviewing official is referring allegations of liability in such notice, the amount for which such person may be liable.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–509, title VI, § 6103(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1947</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 3810.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 104–66, title III, § 3001(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-21">Dec. 21, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 734</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3811.</num>
<heading> Effect on other law</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> This chapter does not diminish the responsibility of any agency to comply with the provisions of chapter 35 of title 44.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> This chapter does not supersede the provisions of <ref>section 3512 of title 44</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> For purposes of this section, the term “agency” has the same meaning as in <ref>section 3502(1) of title 44</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–509, title VI, § 6103(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1948</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3812.</num>
<heading> Prohibition against delegation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any function, duty, or responsibility which this chapter specifies be carried out by the Attorney General or an Assistant Attorney General designated by the Attorney General, shall not be delegated to, or carried out by, any other officer or employee of the Department of Justice.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–509, title VI, § 6103(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1948</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>