<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 5—</num>
<heading>OFFICE OF MANAGEMENT AND BUDGET</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>ORGANIZATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 501.</num>
<heading> Office of Management and Budget</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Office of Management and Budget is an office in the Executive Office of the President.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 886</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 502.</num>
<heading> Officers</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The head of the Office of Management and Budget is the Director of the Office of Management and Budget. The Director is appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. Under the direction of the President, the Director shall administer the Office.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> The Office has a Deputy Director of the Office of Management and Budget, appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. The Deputy Director—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall carry out the duties and powers prescribed by the Director; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> acts as the Director when the Director is absent or unable to serve or when the office of Director is vacant.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Office has a Deputy Director for Management appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. The Deputy Director for Management shall be the chief official responsible for financial management in the United States Government.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The Office has 3 Assistant Directors who shall carry out the duties and powers prescribed by the Director.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> The Office may have not more than 6 additional officers, each of whom is appointed in the competitive service by the Director, with the approval of the President. Each additional officer shall carry out the duties and powers prescribed by the Director. The Director shall specify the title of each additional officer.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> When the Director and Deputy Director are absent or unable to serve or when the offices of Director and Deputy Director are vacant, the President may designate an officer of the Office to act as Director.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 886</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–576, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 2839</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 503.</num>
<heading> Functions of Deputy Director for Management</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Subject to the direction and approval of the Director, the Deputy Director for Management shall establish governmentwide financial management policies for executive agencies and shall perform the following financial management functions:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Perform all functions of the Director, including all functions delegated by the President to the Director, relating to financial management.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Provide overall direction and leadership to the executive branch on financial management matters by establishing financial management policies and requirements, and by monitoring the establishment and operation of Federal Government financial management systems.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Review agency budget requests for financial management systems and operations, and advise the Director on the resources required to develop and effectively operate and maintain Federal Government financial management systems and to correct major deficiencies in such systems.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Review and, where appropriate, recommend to the Director changes to the budget and legislative proposals of agencies to ensure that they are in accordance with financial management plans of the Office of Management and Budget.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Monitor the financial execution of the budget in relation to actual expenditures, including timely performance reports.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Oversee, periodically review, and make recommendations to heads of agencies on the administrative structure of agencies with respect to their financial management activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Develop and maintain qualification standards for agency Chief Financial Officers and for agency Deputy Chief Financial Officers appointed under sections 901 and 903, respectively (excluding any officer designated or appointed under section 901(c)).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Provide advice to agency heads with respect to the selection of agency Chief Financial Officers and Deputy Chief Financial Officers (excluding any officer designated or appointed under section 901(c)).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> Provide advice to agencies regarding the qualifications, recruitment, performance, and retention of other financial management personnel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> Assess the overall adequacy of the professional qualifications and capabilities of financial management staffs throughout the Government and make recommendations on ways to correct problems which impair the capacity of those staffs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> Settle differences that arise among agencies regarding the implementation of financial management policies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> Chair the Chief Financial Officers Council established by section 302 of the Chief Financial Officers Act of 1990.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> Communicate with the financial officers of State and local governments, and foster the exchange with those officers of information concerning financial management standards, techniques, and processes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> Issue such other policies and directives as may be necessary to carry out this section, and perform any other function prescribed by the Director.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Subject to the direction and approval of the Director, the Deputy Director for Management shall establish general management policies for executive agencies and perform the following general management functions:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Coordinate and supervise the general management functions of the Office of Management and Budget.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Perform all functions of the Director, including all functions delegated by the President to the Director, relating to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> managerial systems, including the systematic measurement of performance;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> procurement policy;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> grant, cooperative agreement, and assistance management;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> information and statistical policy;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> property management;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> human resources management;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> regulatory affairs; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> other management functions, including organizational studies, long-range planning, program evaluation, productivity improvement, and experimentation and demonstration programs.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Provide complete, reliable, and timely information to the President, the Congress, and the public regarding the management activities of the executive branch.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Facilitate actions by the Congress and the executive branch to improve the management of Federal Government operations and to remove impediments to effective administration.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Chair the Chief Information Officers Council established under <ref>section 3603 of title 44</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> Provide leadership in management innovation, through—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> experimentation, testing, and demonstration programs; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the adoption of modern management concepts and technologies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Work with State and local governments to improve and strengthen intergovernmental relations, and provide assistance to such governments with respect to intergovernmental programs and cooperative arrangements.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Review and, where appropriate, recommend to the Director changes to the budget and legislative proposals of agencies to ensure that they respond to program evaluations by, and are in accordance with general management plans of, the Office of Management and Budget.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> Provide advice to agencies on the qualification, recruitment, performance, and retention of managerial personnel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> Perform any other functions prescribed by the Director.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Program and Project Management.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subject to the direction and approval of the Director, the Deputy Director for Management or a designee shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> adopt governmentwide standards, policies, and guidelines for program and project management for executive agencies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> oversee implementation of program and project management for the standards, policies, and guidelines established under subparagraph (A);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> chair the Program Management Policy Council established under section 1126(b);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> establish standards and policies for executive agencies, consistent with widely accepted standards for program and project management planning and delivery;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> engage with the private sector to identify best practices in program and project management that would improve Federal program and project management;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> conduct portfolio reviews to address programs identified as high risk by the Government Accountability Office;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> not less than annually, conduct portfolio reviews of agency programs in coordination with Project Management Improvement Officers designated under section 1126(a)(1) to assess the quality and effectiveness of program management; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> establish a 5-year strategic plan for program and project management.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Application to department of defense</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Paragraph (1) shall not apply to the Department of Defense to the extent that the provisions of that paragraph are substantially similar to or duplicative of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the provisions of chapter 87 of title 10; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> policy, guidance, or instruction of the Department related to program management.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–576, title II, § 202(b)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 2839</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 4(f)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1361</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–58, title VI, § 638(g)</ref>, <date date="1999-09-29">Sept. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 476</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–347, title I, § 102(b)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-17">Dec. 17, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2910</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–264, § 2(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-14">Dec. 14, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1371</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title VIII, § 861(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2298</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title VIII, § 810(a)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1458</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 504.</num>
<heading> Office of Federal Financial Management</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> There is established in the Office of Management and Budget an office to be known as the “Office of Federal Financial Management”. The Office of Federal Financial Management, under the direction and control of the Deputy Director for Management of the Office of Management and Budget, shall carry out the financial management functions listed in <ref>section 503(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> There shall be at the head of the Office of Federal Financial Management a Controller, who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. The Controller shall be appointed from among individuals who possess—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> demonstrated ability and practical experience in accounting, financial management, and financial systems; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> extensive practical experience in financial management in large governmental or business entities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Controller of the Office of Federal Financial Management shall be the deputy and principal advisor to the Deputy Director for Management in the performance by the Deputy Director for Management of functions described in section 503(a).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–576, title II, § 203(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 2841</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 505.</num>
<heading> Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs, established under <ref>section 3503 of title 44</ref>, is an office in the Office of Management and Budget.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 886</ref>, § 503; renumbered § 505, <ref>Pub. L. 101–576, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 2839</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 506.</num>
<heading> Office of Federal Procurement Policy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Office of Federal Procurement Policy, established under <ref>section 1101(a) of title 41</ref>, is an office in the Office of Management and Budget.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 97–452, § 1(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="1983-01-12">Jan. 12, 1983</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2467</ref>, § 504; renumbered § 506, <ref>Pub. L. 101–576, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 2839</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 5(h)(1)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3848</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 507.</num>
<heading> Office of Electronic Government</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Office of Electronic Government, established under <ref>section 3602 of title 44</ref>, is an office in the Office of Management and Budget.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 107–347, title I, § 102(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-17">Dec. 17, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2910</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>ADMINISTRATIVE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 521.</num>
<heading> Employees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall appoint and fix the pay of employees of the Office under regulations prescribed by the President.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 886</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 522.</num>
<heading> Necessary expenditures</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director of the Office of Management and Budget may make necessary expenditures for the Office under regulations prescribed by the President.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 886</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>