<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 93—</num>
<heading>SURETIES AND SURETY BONDS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 9301.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “person” means an individual, a trust, an estate, a partnership, and a corporation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> “eligible obligation” means any security designated as acceptable in lieu of a surety bond by the Secretary of the Treasury.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1046</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–351, title IX, § 901(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-13">Oct. 13, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2007</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9302.</num>
<heading> Prohibition against surety bonds for United States Government personnel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An agency (except a mixed-ownership Government corporation) may not require or obtain a surety bond for a member of the uniformed services or an officer or employee of the United States Government in carrying out official duties. This section does not affect the personal financial liability of the member, officer, or employee.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1046</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9303.</num>
<heading> Use of eligible obligations instead of surety bonds</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> If a person is required under a law of the United States to give a surety bond, the person may give an eligible obligation as security instead of a surety bond. The obligation shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> be given to the official having authority to approve the surety bond;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> as determined by the Secretary of the Treasury, have a market value that is equal to or greater than the amount of the required surety bond; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> authorize the official receiving the obligation to collect or sell the obligation if the person defaults on a required condition.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> An official receiving an eligible obligation under subsection (a) of this section may deposit it with—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Secretary of the Treasury;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a Federal reserve bank; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a depositary designated by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary, bank, or depositary shall issue a receipt that describes the obligation deposited.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> Using an eligible obligation instead of a surety bond for security is the same as using—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a personal or corporate surety bond;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a certified check;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a bank draft;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> a post office money order; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> cash.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> When security is no longer required, an eligible obligation given instead of a surety bond shall be returned to the person giving the obligation. If a person, supplying labor or material to a contractor defaulting under sections 3131 and 3133 of title 40, files with the United States Government the application and affidavit provided under <ref>section 3133(a) of title 40</ref>, the Government—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> may return to the contractor the eligible obligation given as security (or proceeds of the eligible obligation given) under sections 3131 and 3133 of title 40 only after the 90-day period for bringing a civil action under <ref>section 3133(b) of title 40</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> if a civil action is brought in the 90-day period, shall hold the eligible obligation or the proceeds subject to the order of the court having jurisdiction of the action.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<chapeau> This section does not affect the—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> priority of a claim of the Government against an eligible obligation given under this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> right or remedy of the Government for default on an obligation provided under—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> sections 3131 and 3133 of title 40; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> this section;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> authority of a court over an eligible obligation given as security in a civil action; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> authority of an official of the Government authorized by another law to receive an eligible obligation as security.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> To avoid frequent substitution of eligible obligations, the Secretary may prescribe regulations limiting the effect of this section to an eligible obligation maturing more than one year after the date the obligation is given as security.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1046</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–217, § 3(h)(9)</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1300</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–178, § 4(f)(2)</ref>, <date date="2003-12-15">Dec. 15, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2641</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–351, title IX, § 901(b)</ref>, (c), <date date="2006-10-13">Oct. 13, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2007</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9304.</num>
<heading> Surety corporations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> When a law of the United States Government requires or permits a person to give a surety bond through a surety, the person satisfies the law if the surety bond is provided for the person by a corporation—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> incorporated under the laws of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the United States; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a State, the District of Columbia, or a territory or possession of the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> that may under those laws guarantee—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the fidelity of persons holding positions of trust; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> bonds and undertakings in judicial proceedings; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> complying with sections 9305 and 9306 of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Each surety bond shall be approved by the official of the Government required to approve or accept the bond. The official may not require that the surety bond be given through a guaranty corporation or through any particular guaranty corporation.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1047</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9305.</num>
<heading> Authority and revocation of authority of surety corporations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Before becoming a surety under <ref>section 9304 of this title</ref>, a surety corporation must file with the Secretary of the Treasury—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a copy of the articles of incorporation of the corporation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a statement of the assets and liabilities of the corporation signed and sworn to by the president and secretary of the corporation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary may authorize in writing a surety corporation to provide surety bonds under <ref>section 9304 of this title</ref> if the Secretary decides that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the articles of incorporation of the corporation authorize the corporation to do business described in <ref>section 9304(a)(2) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the corporation has paid-up capital of at least $250,000 in cash or its equivalent; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the corporation is able to carry out its contracts.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> A surety corporation authorized under subsection (b) of this section to provide surety bonds shall file with the Secretary each January, April, July, and October a statement of the assets and liabilities of the corporation signed and sworn to by the president and secretary of the corporation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall revoke the authority of a surety corporation to do new business if the Secretary decides the corporation is insolvent or is in violation of this section or section 9304 or 9306 of this title;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> may investigate the solvency of a surety corporation at any time; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> may require additional security from the person required to provide a surety bond if the Secretary decides that a surety corporation no longer is sufficient security.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<chapeau> A surety corporation providing a surety bond under <ref>section 9304 of this title</ref> may not provide any additional bond under that section if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the corporation does not pay a final judgment or order against it on the bond; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> no appeal or stay of the judgment or order is pending 30 days after the judgment or order is entered.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1047</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9306.</num>
<heading> Surety corporations acting outside area of incorporation and place of principal office</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> A surety corporation may provide a surety bond under <ref>section 9304 of this title</ref> in a judicial district outside the State, the District of Columbia, or a territory or possession of the United States under whose laws it was incorporated and in which its principal office is located only if the corporation has a resident agent for service of process for that district. The resident agent—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> may be an official of the State, the District of Columbia, the territory or possession in which the court sits who is authorized or appointed under the law of the State, District, territory or possession to receive service of process on the corporation; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> may be an individual who resides in the jurisdiction of the district court for the district in which a surety bond is to be provided and who is appointed by the corporation as provided in subsection (b) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002123">1</ref></content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> If the surety corporation meets the requirement of subsection (a) by appointing an individual under subsection (a)(2), the surety corporation shall file a certified copy of the power of attorney with the clerk of the district court for the district in which a surety bond is to be given at each place the court sits. A copy of the power of attorney may be used as evidence in a civil action under <ref>section 9307 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> If a resident agent is removed, resigns, dies, or becomes disabled, the surety corporation shall appoint another agent as described in this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Until an appointment is made under paragraph (1) of this subsection or during an absence of an agent from the district in which the surety bond is given, service of process may be made on the clerk of the court in which a civil action against the corporation is brought. The official serving process on the clerk of the court—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> immediately shall mail a copy of the process to the corporation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> shall state in the official’s return that the official served the process on the clerk of the court.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A judgment or order of a court entered or made after service of process under this section is as valid as if the corporation were served in the judicial district of the court.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1048</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(9) [title V, § 5007]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–594.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9307.</num>
<heading> Civil actions and judgments against surety corporations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> A surety corporation providing a surety bond under <ref>section 9304 of this title</ref> may be sued in a court of the United States having jurisdiction of civil actions on surety bonds in—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the judicial district in which the surety bond was provided; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the district in which the principal office of the corporation is located.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Under sections 9304–9308 of this title, a surety bond is deemed to be provided in the district—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in which the principal office of the surety corporation is located;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to which the surety bond is returnable;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> in which the surety bond is filed; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> in which the person required to provide a surety bond resided when the bond was provided.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> In a proceeding against a surety corporation providing a surety bond under <ref>section 9304 of this title</ref>, the corporation may not deny its power to provide a surety bond or to assume liability.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1049</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9308.</num>
<heading> Civil penalty</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A surety corporation is liable to the United States Government for a civil penalty of at least $500 but not more than $5,000 for violating section 9304, 9305, or 9306 of this title. A civil action under this section may be brought in a judicial district in which a civil action may be brought against the corporation under <ref>section 9307 of this title</ref>. A penalty imposed under this section does not affect the validity of a contract made by the surety corporation.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1049</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9309.</num>
<heading> Priority of sureties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">When a person required to provide a surety bond given to the United States Government is insolvent or dies having assets insufficient to pay debts, the surety, or the executor, administrator, or assignee of the surety paying the Government the amount due under the bond—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> has the same priority to amounts from the assets and estate of the person as are secured for the Government; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> personally may bring a civil action under the bond to recover amounts paid under the bond.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1049</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9310.</num>
<heading> Individual sureties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">If another applicable Federal law or regulation permits the acceptance of a bond from a surety that is not subject to sections 9305 and 9306 and is based on a pledge of assets by the surety, the assets pledged by such surety shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> consist of eligible obligations described under section 9303(a); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> be submitted to the official of the Government required to approve or accept the bond, who shall deposit the obligations as described under section 9303(b).</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title VIII, § 874(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 940</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>