<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 2—</num>
<heading>NATIONAL EMERGENCY MANAGEMENT</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 701.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this title— <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002126">1</ref></chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “Administrator” means the Administrator of the Agency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “Agency” means the Federal Emergency Management Agency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> the term “appropriate committees of Congress” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> those committees of the House of Representatives that the Speaker of the House of Representatives determines appropriate;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the term “catastrophic incident” means any natural disaster, act of terrorism, or other man-made disaster that results in extraordinary levels of casualties or damage or disruption severely affecting the population (including mass evacuations), infrastructure, environment, economy, national morale, or government functions in an area;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the term “Department” means the Department of Homeland Security;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the terms “emergency” and “major disaster” have the meanings given the terms in <ref>section 5122 of title 42</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the term “emergency management” means the governmental function that coordinates and integrates all activities necessary to build, sustain, and improve the capability to prepare for, protect against, respond to, recover from, or mitigate against threatened or actual natural disasters, acts of terrorism, or other man-made disasters;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> the term “emergency response provider” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 101 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> the term “Federal coordinating officer” means a Federal coordinating officer as described in <ref>section 5143 of title 42</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> the term “individual with a disability” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 12102 of title 42</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> the terms “local government” and “State” have the meaning given the terms in <ref>section 101 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> the term “National Incident Management System” means a system to enable effective, efficient, and collaborative incident management;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> the term “National Response Plan” means the National Response Plan or any successor plan prepared under <ref>section 314(a)(6) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> the term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Homeland Security;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<content> the term “surge capacity” means the ability to rapidly and substantially increase the provision of search and rescue capabilities, food, water, medicine, shelter and housing, medical care, evacuation capacity, staffing (including disaster assistance employees), and other resources necessary to save lives and protect property during a catastrophic incident; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(16)</num>
<content> the term “tribal government” means the government of an Indian tribe or authorized tribal organization, or in Alaska a Native village or Alaska Regional Native Corporation.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–295, title VI, § 602</ref>, <date date="2006-10-04">Oct. 4, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1394</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>PERSONNEL PROVISIONS</heading>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part A—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Federal Emergency Management Agency Personnel</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 711.</num>
<heading> Surge Capacity Force</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 6 months after <date date="2006-10-04">October 4, 2006</date>, the Administrator shall prepare and submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a plan to establish and implement a Surge Capacity Force for deployment of individuals to respond to natural disasters, acts of terrorism, and other man-made disasters, including catastrophic incidents.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the plan shall provide for individuals in the Surge Capacity Force to be trained and deployed under the authorities set forth in the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act [<ref>42 U.S.C. 5121</ref> et seq.].</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">If the Administrator determines that the existing authorities are inadequate for the training and deployment of individuals in the Surge Capacity Force, the Administrator shall report to Congress as to the additional statutory authorities that the Administrator determines necessary.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Employees designated to serve</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The plan shall include procedures under which the Secretary shall designate employees of the Department who are not employees of the Agency and shall, in conjunction with the heads of other Executive agencies, designate employees of those other Executive agencies, as appropriate, to serve on the Surge Capacity Force.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Capabilities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The plan shall ensure that the Surge Capacity Force—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> includes a sufficient number of individuals credentialed in accordance with <ref>section 320 of this title</ref> that are capable of deploying rapidly and efficiently after activation to prepare for, respond to, and recover from natural disasters, acts of terrorism, and other man-made disasters, including catastrophic incidents; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> includes a sufficient number of full-time, highly trained individuals credentialed in accordance with <ref>section 320 of this title</ref> to lead and manage the Surge Capacity Force.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Training</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The plan shall ensure that the Administrator provides appropriate and continuous training to members of the Surge Capacity Force to ensure such personnel are adequately trained on the Agency’s programs and policies for natural disasters, acts of terrorism, and other man-made disasters.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> No impact on agency personnel ceiling</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Surge Capacity Force members shall not be counted against any personnel ceiling applicable to the Federal Emergency Management Agency.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator may provide members of the Surge Capacity Force with travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, at rates authorized for employees of agencies under subchapter I of chapter 57 of title 5 for the purpose of participating in any training that relates to service as a member of the Surge Capacity Force.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Immediate implementation of Surge Capacity Force involving Federal employees</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As soon as practicable after <date date="2006-10-04">October 4, 2006</date>, the Administrator shall develop and implement—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the procedures under subsection (b); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> other elements of the plan needed to establish the portion of the Surge Capacity Force consisting of individuals designated under those procedures.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–295, title VI, § 624</ref>, <date date="2006-10-04">Oct. 4, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1419</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part B—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Emergency Management Capabilities</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 721.</num>
<heading> Evacuation preparedness technical assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator, in coordination with the heads of other appropriate Federal agencies, shall provide evacuation preparedness technical assistance to State, local, and tribal governments, including the preparation of hurricane evacuation studies and technical assistance in developing evacuation plans, assessing storm surge estimates, evacuation zones, evacuation clearance times, transportation capacity, and shelter capacity.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–295, title VI, § 632</ref>, <date date="2006-10-04">Oct. 4, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1421</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 722.</num>
<heading> Urban Search and Rescue Response System</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is in the Agency a system known as the Urban Search and Rescue Response System.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out the system for fiscal year 2008, an amount equal to the amount appropriated for the system for fiscal year 2007 and an additional $20,000,000.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–295, title VI, § 634</ref>, <date date="2006-10-04">Oct. 4, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1421</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 723.</num>
<heading> Metropolitan Medical Response Grant Program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is a Metropolitan Medical Response Program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purposes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The program shall include each purpose of the program as it existed on <date date="2006-06-01">June 1, 2006</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out the program for fiscal year 2008, an amount equal to the amount appropriated for the program for fiscal year 2007 and an additional $30,000,000.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–295, title VI, § 635</ref>, <date date="2006-10-04">Oct. 4, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1421</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 724.</num>
<heading> Logistics</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator shall develop an efficient, transparent, and flexible logistics system for procurement and delivery of goods and services necessary for an effective and timely response to natural disasters, acts of terrorism, and other man-made disasters and for real-time visibility of items at each point throughout the logistics system.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–295, title VI, § 636</ref>, <date date="2006-10-04">Oct. 4, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1422</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 725.</num>
<heading> Prepositioned equipment program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator shall establish a prepositioned equipment program to preposition standardized emergency equipment in at least 11 locations to sustain and replenish critical assets used by State, local, and tribal governments in response to (or rendered inoperable by the effects of) natural disasters, acts of terrorism, and other man-made disasters.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator shall notify State, local, and tribal officials in an area in which a location for the prepositioned equipment program will be closed not later than 60 days before the date of such closure.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–295, title VI, § 637</ref>, <date date="2006-10-04">Oct. 4, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1422</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 726.</num>
<heading> Basic life supporting first aid and education</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator shall enter into agreements with organizations to provide funds to emergency response providers to provide education and training in life supporting first aid to children.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–295, title VI, § 639</ref>, <date date="2006-10-04">Oct. 4, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1423</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 727.</num>
<heading> Improvements to information technology systems</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Measures to improve information technology systems</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Administrator, in coordination with the Chief Information Officer of the Department, shall take appropriate measures to update and improve the information technology systems of the Agency, including measures to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> ensure that the multiple information technology systems of the Agency (including the National Emergency Management Information System, the Logistics Information Management System III, and the Automated Deployment Database) are, to the extent practicable, fully compatible and can share and access information, as appropriate, from each other;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> ensure technology enhancements reach the headquarters and regional offices of the Agency in a timely fashion, to allow seamless integration;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> develop and maintain a testing environment that ensures that all system components are properly and thoroughly tested before their release;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> ensure that the information technology systems of the Agency have the capacity to track disaster response personnel, mission assignments task orders, commodities, and supplies used in response to a natural disaster, act of terrorism, or other man-made disaster;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> make appropriate improvements to the National Emergency Management Information System to address shortcomings in such system on <date date="2006-10-04">October 4, 2006</date>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> provide training, manuals, and guidance on information technology systems to personnel, including disaster response personnel, to help ensure employees can properly use information technology systems.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 270 days after <date date="2006-10-04">October 4, 2006</date>, the Administrator shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report describing the implementation of this section, including a description of any actions taken, improvements made, and remaining problems and a description of any additional funding needed to make necessary and appropriate improvements to the information technology systems of the Agency.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–295, title VI, § 640</ref>, <date date="2006-10-04">Oct. 4, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1423</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 728.</num>
<heading> Disclosure of certain information to law enforcement agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the event of circumstances requiring an evacuation, sheltering, or mass relocation, the Administrator may disclose information in any individual assistance database of the Agency in accordance with <ref>section 552a(b) of title 5</ref> (commonly referred to as the “Privacy Act”) to any law enforcement agency of the Federal Government or a State, local, or tribal government in order to identify illegal conduct or address public safety or security issues, including compliance with sex offender notification laws.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–295, title VI, § 640a</ref>, <date date="2006-10-04">Oct. 4, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1424</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>COMPREHENSIVE PREPAREDNESS SYSTEM</heading>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part A—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">National Preparedness System</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 741.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this part:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Capability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “capability” means the ability to provide the means to accomplish one or more tasks under specific conditions and to specific performance standards. A capability may be achieved with any combination of properly planned, organized, equipped, trained, and exercised personnel that achieves the intended outcome.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Credentialed; credentialing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The terms “credentialed” and “credentialing” have the meanings given those terms in <ref>section 311 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Hazard</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “hazard” has the meaning given that term under <ref>section 5195a(a)(1) of title 42</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Mission assignment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “mission assignment” means a work order issued to a Federal agency by the Agency, directing completion by that agency of a specified task and setting forth funding, other managerial controls, and guidance.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National preparedness goal</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “national preparedness goal” means the national preparedness goal established under <ref>section 743 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National preparedness system</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “national preparedness system” means the national preparedness system established under <ref>section 744 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National training program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “national training program” means the national training program established under <ref>section 748(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Operational readiness</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “operational readiness” means the capability of an organization, an asset, a system, or equipment to perform the missions or functions for which it is organized or designed.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Performance measure</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “performance measure” means a quantitative or qualitative characteristic used to gauge the results of an outcome compared to its intended purpose.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(10)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Performance metric</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “performance metric” means a particular value or characteristic used to measure the outcome that is generally expressed in terms of a baseline and a target.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(11)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prevention</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “prevention” means any activity undertaken to avoid, prevent, or stop a threatened or actual act of terrorism.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(12)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Resources</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “resources” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 311 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(13)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Type</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “type” means a classification of resources that refers to the capability of a resource.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(14)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Typed; typing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The terms “typed” and “typing” have the meanings given those terms in <ref>section 311 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–295, title VI, § 641</ref>, <date date="2006-10-04">Oct. 4, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1424</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–53, title IV, § 401(b)</ref>, <date date="2007-08-03">Aug. 3, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 302</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 742.</num>
<heading> National preparedness</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In order to prepare the Nation for all hazards, including natural disasters, acts of terrorism, and other man-made disasters, the President, consistent with the declaration of policy under <ref>section 5195 of title 42</ref> and title V of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<ref>6 U.S.C. 311</ref> et seq.), as amended by this Act, shall develop a national preparedness goal and a national preparedness system.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–295, title VI, § 642</ref>, <date date="2006-10-04">Oct. 4, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1425</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 743.</num>
<heading> National preparedness goal</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President, acting through the Administrator, shall complete, revise, and update, as necessary, a national preparedness goal that defines the target level of preparedness to ensure the Nation’s ability to prevent, respond to, recover from, and mitigate against natural disasters, acts of terrorism, and other man-made disasters.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National Incident Management System and National Response Plan</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The national preparedness goal, to the greatest extent practicable, shall be consistent with the National Incident Management System and the National Response Plan.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–295, title VI, § 643</ref>, <date date="2006-10-04">Oct. 4, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1425</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 744.</num>
<heading> Establishment of national preparedness system</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President, acting through the Administrator, shall develop a national preparedness system to enable the Nation to meet the national preparedness goal.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Components</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The national preparedness system shall include the following components:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Target capabilities and preparedness priorities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Equipment and training standards.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Training and exercises.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Comprehensive assessment system.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Remedial action management program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Federal response capability inventory.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Reporting requirements.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Federal preparedness.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National planning scenarios</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The national preparedness system may include national planning scenarios.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–295, title VI, § 644</ref>, <date date="2006-10-04">Oct. 4, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1425</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 745.</num>
<heading> National planning scenarios</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator, in coordination with the heads of appropriate Federal agencies and the National Advisory Council, may develop planning scenarios to reflect the relative risk requirements presented by all hazards, including natural disasters, acts of terrorism, and other man-made disasters, in order to provide the foundation for the flexible and adaptive development of target capabilities and the identification of target capability levels to meet the national preparedness goal.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Development</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In developing, revising, and replacing national planning scenarios, the Administrator shall ensure that the scenarios—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> reflect the relative risk of all hazards and illustrate the potential scope, magnitude, and complexity of a broad range of representative hazards; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provide the minimum number of representative scenarios necessary to identify and define the tasks and target capabilities required to respond to all hazards.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–295, title VI, § 645</ref>, <date date="2006-10-04">Oct. 4, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1425</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 746.</num>
<heading> Target capabilities and preparedness priorities</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of guidelines on target capabilities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2006-10-04">October 4, 2006</date>, the Administrator, in coordination with the heads of appropriate Federal agencies, the National Council on Disability, and the National Advisory Council, shall complete, revise, and update, as necessary, guidelines to define risk-based target capabilities for Federal, State, local, and tribal government preparedness that will enable the Nation to prevent, respond to, recover from, and mitigate against all hazards, including natural disasters, acts of terrorism, and other man-made disasters.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Distribution of guidelines</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator shall ensure that the guidelines are provided promptly to the appropriate committees of Congress and the States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Objectives</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator shall ensure that the guidelines are specific, flexible, and measurable.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Terrorism risk assessment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">With respect to analyzing and assessing the risk of acts of terrorism, the Administrator shall consider—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the variables of threat, vulnerability, and consequences related to population (including transient commuting and tourist populations), areas of high population density, critical infrastructure, coastline, and international borders; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the most current risk assessment available from the Chief Intelligence Officer of the Department of the threats of terrorism against the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Preparedness priorities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In establishing the guidelines under subsection (a), the Administrator shall establish preparedness priorities that appropriately balance the risk of all hazards, including natural disasters, acts of terrorism, and other man-made disasters, with the resources required to prevent, respond to, recover from, and mitigate against the hazards.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Mutual aid agreements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator may provide support for the development of mutual aid agreements within States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–295, title VI, § 646</ref>, <date date="2006-10-04">Oct. 4, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1426</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 747.</num>
<heading> Equipment and training standards</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Equipment standards</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Administrator, in coordination with the heads of appropriate Federal agencies and the National Advisory Council, shall support the development, promulgation, and updating, as necessary, of national voluntary consensus standards for the performance, use, and validation of equipment used by Federal, State, local, and tribal governments and nongovernmental emergency response providers.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The national voluntary consensus standards shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> be designed to achieve equipment and other capabilities consistent with the national preparedness goal, including the safety and health of emergency response providers;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to the maximum extent practicable, be consistent with existing national voluntary consensus standards;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> take into account, as appropriate, threats that may not have been contemplated when the existing standards were developed; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> focus on maximizing operability, interoperability, interchangeability, durability, flexibility, efficiency, efficacy, portability, sustainability, and safety.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Training standards</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Administrator shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> support the development, promulgation, and regular updating, as necessary, of national voluntary consensus standards for training; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> ensure that the training provided under the national training program is consistent with the standards.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation with standards organizations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In carrying out this section, the Administrator shall consult with representatives of relevant public and private sector national voluntary consensus standards development organizations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–295, title VI, § 647</ref>, <date date="2006-10-04">Oct. 4, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1426</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 748.</num>
<heading> Training and exercises</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National training program</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Beginning not later than 180 days after <date date="2006-10-04">October 4, 2006</date>, the Administrator, in coordination with the heads of appropriate Federal agencies, the National Council on Disability, and the National Advisory Council, shall carry out a national training program to implement the national preparedness goal, National Incident Management System, National Response Plan, and other related plans and strategies.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Training partners</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In developing and implementing the national training program, the Administrator shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> work with government training facilities, academic institutions, private organizations, and other entities that provide specialized, state-of-the-art training for emergency managers or emergency response providers; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> utilize, as appropriate, training courses provided by community colleges, State and local public safety academies, State and private universities, and other facilities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National exercise program</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Beginning not later than 180 days after <date date="2006-10-04">October 4, 2006</date>, the Administrator, in coordination with the heads of appropriate Federal agencies, the National Council on Disability, and the National Advisory Council, shall carry out a national exercise program to test and evaluate the national preparedness goal, National Incident Management System, National Response Plan, and other related plans and strategies.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The national exercise program—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> shall be—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> as realistic as practicable, based on current risk assessments, including credible and emerging threats, vulnerabilities, and consequences, and designed to stress the national preparedness system;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> designed, as practicable, to simulate the partial or complete incapacitation of a State, local, or tribal government;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> carried out, as appropriate, with a minimum degree of notice to involved parties regarding the timing and details of such exercises, consistent with safety considerations;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> designed to provide for the systematic evaluation of readiness and enhance operational understanding of the incident command system and relevant mutual aid agreements;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> designed to address the unique requirements of populations with special needs, including the elderly; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> designed to promptly develop after-action reports and plans for quickly incorporating lessons learned into future operations; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> shall include a selection of model exercises that State, local, and tribal governments can readily adapt for use and provide assistance to State, local, and tribal governments with the design, implementation, and evaluation of exercises (whether a model exercise program or an exercise designed locally) that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> conform to the requirements under subparagraph (A);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> are consistent with any applicable State, local, or tribal strategy or plan; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> provide for systematic evaluation of readiness.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National level exercises</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Administrator shall periodically, but not less than biennially, perform national exercises for the following purposes:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> To test and evaluate the capability of Federal, State, local, and tribal governments to detect, disrupt, and prevent threatened or actual catastrophic acts of terrorism, especially those involving weapons of mass destruction.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> To test and evaluate the readiness of Federal, State, local, and tribal governments to respond and recover in a coordinated and unified manner to catastrophic incidents.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–295, title VI, § 648</ref>, <date date="2006-10-04">Oct. 4, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1427</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–53, title IV</ref>, §§ 402, 403, <date date="2007-08-03">Aug. 3, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 302</ref>, 303; <ref>Pub. L. 116–64, § 3</ref>, <date date="2019-10-09">Oct. 9, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1123</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 748a.</num>
<heading> Prioritization of facilities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2018-10-05">October 5, 2018</date>, the Administrator shall provide guidance and training on an annual basis to State, local, and Indian tribal governments, first responders, and utility companies on—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the need to prioritize assistance to hospitals, nursing homes, and other long-term care facilities to ensure that such health care facilities remain functioning or return to functioning as soon as practicable during power outages caused by natural hazards, including severe weather events;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> how hospitals, nursing homes and other long-term care facilities should adequately prepare for power outages during a major disaster or emergency, as those terms are defined in <ref>section 5122 of title 42</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> how State, local, and Indian tribal governments, first responders, utility companies, hospitals, nursing homes, and other long-term care facilities should develop a strategy to coordinate emergency response plans, including the activation of emergency response plans, in anticipation of a major disaster, including severe weather events.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 115–254, div. D, § 1208</ref>, <date date="2018-10-05">Oct. 5, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 3441</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 749.</num>
<heading> Comprehensive assessment system</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator, in coordination with the National Council on Disability and the National Advisory Council, shall establish a comprehensive system to assess, on an ongoing basis, the Nation’s prevention capabilities and overall preparedness, including operational readiness.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Performance metrics and measures</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator shall ensure that each component of the national preparedness system, National Incident Management System, National Response Plan, and other related plans and strategies, and the reports required under <ref>section 752 of this title</ref> is developed, revised, and updated with clear and quantifiable performance metrics, measures, and outcomes.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The assessment system established under subsection (a) shall assess—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> compliance with the national preparedness system, National Incident Management System, National Response Plan, and other related plans and strategies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> capability levels at the time of assessment against target capability levels defined pursuant to the guidelines established under <ref>section 746(a) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> resource needs to meet the desired target capability levels defined pursuant to the guidelines established under <ref>section 746(a) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> performance of training, exercises, and operations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–295, title VI, § 649</ref>, <date date="2006-10-04">Oct. 4, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1428</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 750.</num>
<heading> Remedial action management program</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Administrator, in coordination with the National Council on Disability and the National Advisory Council, shall establish a remedial action management program to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> analyze training, exercises, and real-world events to identify and disseminate lessons learned and best practices;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> generate and disseminate, as appropriate, after action reports to participants in exercises and real-world events; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> conduct remedial action tracking and long-term trend analysis.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–295, title VI, § 650</ref>, <date date="2006-10-04">Oct. 4, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1428</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 751.</num>
<heading> Federal response capability inventory</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In accordance with <ref>section 5196(h)(1)(C) of title 42</ref>, the Administrator shall accelerate the completion of the inventory of Federal response capabilities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For each Federal agency with responsibilities under the National Response Plan, the inventory shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> for each capability—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the performance parameters of the capability;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the timeframe within which the capability can be brought to bear on an incident; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the readiness of the capability to respond to all hazards, including natural disasters, acts of terrorism, and other man-made disasters;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a list of personnel credentialed in accordance with <ref>section 320 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a list of resources typed in accordance with <ref>section 320 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> emergency communications assets maintained by the Federal Government and, if appropriate, State, local, and tribal governments and the private sector.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Department of Defense</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator, in coordination with the Secretary of Defense, shall develop a list of organizations and functions within the Department of Defense that may be used, pursuant to the authority provided under the National Response Plan and sections 5170a, 5170b, and 5192 of title 42, to provide support to civil authorities during natural disasters, acts of terrorism, and other man-made disasters.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Database</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Administrator shall establish an inventory database to allow—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> real-time exchange of information regarding—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> capabilities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> readiness;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the compatibility of equipment;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> credentialed personnel; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> typed resources;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> easy identification and rapid deployment of capabilities, credentialed personnel, and typed resources during an incident; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the sharing of the inventory described in subsection (a) with other Federal agencies, as appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–295, title VI, § 651</ref>, <date date="2006-10-04">Oct. 4, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1429</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–53, title IV, § 405</ref>, <date date="2007-08-03">Aug. 3, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 303</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 752.</num>
<heading> Reporting requirements</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal preparedness report</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 12 months after <date date="2006-10-04">October 4, 2006</date>, and annually thereafter, the Administrator, in coordination with the heads of appropriate Federal agencies, shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the Nation’s level of preparedness for all hazards, including natural disasters, acts of terrorism, and other man-made disasters.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Each report shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an assessment of how Federal assistance supports the national preparedness system;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the results of the comprehensive assessment carried out under <ref>section 749 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a review of the inventory described in <ref>section 751 of this title</ref>, including the number and type of credentialed personnel in each category of personnel trained and ready to respond to a natural disaster, act of terrorism, or other man-made disaster;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> an assessment of resource needs to meet preparedness priorities established under <ref>section 746(e) of this title</ref>, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an estimate of the amount of Federal, State, local, and tribal expenditures required to attain the preparedness priorities; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the extent to which the use of Federal assistance during the preceding fiscal year achieved the preparedness priorities;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<chapeau> an evaluation of the extent to which grants administered by the Department, including grants under title XX of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 [<ref>6 U.S.C. 601</ref> et seq.]—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> have contributed to the progress of State, local, and tribal governments in achieving target capabilities; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> have led to the reduction of risk from natural disasters, acts of terrorism, or other man-made disasters nationally and in State, local, and tribal jurisdictions; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<chapeau> a discussion of whether the list of credentialed personnel of the Agency described in <ref>section 751(b)(2) of this title</ref>—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> complies with the strategic human capital plan developed under <ref>section 10102 of title 5</ref>; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> is sufficient to respond to a natural disaster, act of terrorism, or other man-made disaster, including a catastrophic incident.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Catastrophic resource report</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Administrator shall develop and submit to the appropriate committees of Congress annually an estimate of the resources of the Agency and other Federal agencies needed for and devoted specifically to developing the capabilities of Federal, State, local, and tribal governments necessary to respond to a catastrophic incident.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Each estimate under paragraph (1) shall include the resources both necessary for and devoted to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> planning;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> training and exercises;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Regional Office enhancements;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> staffing, including for surge capacity during a catastrophic incident;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> additional logistics capabilities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> other responsibilities under the catastrophic incident annex and the catastrophic incident supplement of the National Response Plan;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> State, local, and tribal government catastrophic incident preparedness; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> covering increases in the fixed costs or expenses of the Agency, including rent or property acquisition costs or expenses, taxes, contributions to the working capital fund of the Department, and security costs for the year after the year in which such estimate is submitted.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State preparedness report</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 15 months after <date date="2006-10-04">October 4, 2006</date>, and annually thereafter, a State receiving Federal preparedness assistance administered by the Department shall submit a report to the Administrator on the State’s level of preparedness.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Each report shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an assessment of State compliance with the national preparedness system, National Incident Management System, National Response Plan, and other related plans and strategies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an assessment of current capability levels and a description of target capability levels; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> a discussion of the extent to which target capabilities identified in the applicable State homeland security plan and other applicable plans remain unmet and an assessment of resources needed to meet the preparedness priorities established under <ref>section 746(e) of this title</ref>, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an estimate of the amount of expenditures required to attain the preparedness priorities; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the extent to which the use of Federal assistance during the preceding fiscal year achieved the preparedness priorities.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–295, title VI, § 652</ref>, <date date="2006-10-04">Oct. 4, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1429</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–53, title I, § 103</ref>, title IV, § 406, <date date="2007-08-03">Aug. 3, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 293</ref>, 304.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 753.</num>
<heading> Federal preparedness</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agency responsibility</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In support of the national preparedness system, the President shall ensure that each Federal agency with responsibilities under the National Response Plan—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> has the operational capability to meet the national preparedness goal, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the personnel to make and communicate decisions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> organizational structures that are assigned, trained, and exercised for the missions of the agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> sufficient physical resources; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the command, control, and communication channels to make, monitor, and communicate decisions;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> complies with the National Incident Management System, including credentialing of personnel and typing of resources likely needed to respond to a natural disaster, act of terrorism, or other man-made disaster in accordance with <ref>section 320 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> develops, trains, and exercises rosters of response personnel to be deployed when the agency is called upon to support a Federal response;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> develops deliberate operational plans and the corresponding capabilities, including crisis planning, to respond effectively to natural disasters, acts of terrorism, and other man-made disasters in support of the National Response Plan to ensure a coordinated Federal response; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> regularly updates, verifies the accuracy of, and provides to the Administrator the information in the inventory required under <ref>section 751 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Operational plans</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">An operations plan developed under subsection (a)(4) shall meet the following requirements:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The operations plan shall be coordinated under a unified system with a common terminology, approach, and framework.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The operations plan shall be developed, in coordination with State, local, and tribal government officials, to address both regional and national risks.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The operations plan shall contain, as appropriate, the following elements:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Concepts of operations.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Critical tasks and responsibilities.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Detailed resource and personnel requirements, together with sourcing requirements.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Specific provisions for the rapid integration of the resources and personnel of the agency into the overall response.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> The operations plan shall address, as appropriate, the following matters:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> Support of State, local, and tribal governments in conducting mass evacuations, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> transportation and relocation;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> short- and long-term sheltering and accommodation;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> provisions for populations with special needs, keeping families together, and expeditious location of missing children; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> policies and provisions for pets.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The preparedness and deployment of public health and medical resources, including resources to address the needs of evacuees and populations with special needs.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The coordination of interagency search and rescue operations, including land, water, and airborne search and rescue operations.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The roles and responsibilities of the Senior Federal Law Enforcement Official with respect to other law enforcement entities.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The protection of critical infrastructure.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> The coordination of maritime salvage efforts among relevant agencies.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> The coordination of Department of Defense and National Guard support of civilian authorities.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> To the extent practicable, the utilization of Department of Defense, National Air and Space Administration, National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, and commercial aircraft and satellite remotely sensed imagery.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> The coordination and integration of support from the private sector and nongovernmental organizations.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> The safe disposal of debris, including hazardous materials, and, when practicable, the recycling of debris.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> The identification of the required surge capacity.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(L)</num>
<content> Specific provisions for the recovery of affected geographic areas.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Mission assignments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To expedite the provision of assistance under the National Response Plan, the President shall ensure that the Administrator, in coordination with Federal agencies with responsibilities under the National Response Plan, develops prescripted mission assignments, including logistics, communications, mass care, health services, and public safety.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall certify to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Homeland Security and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives on an annual basis that each Federal agency with responsibilities under the National Response Plan complies with subsections (a) and (b).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Construction</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit the authority of the Secretary of Defense with regard to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the command, control, training, planning, equipment, exercises, or employment of Department of Defense forces; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the allocation of Department of Defense resources.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–295, title VI, § 653</ref>, <date date="2006-10-04">Oct. 4, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1430</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–53, title IV, § 407</ref>, <date date="2007-08-03">Aug. 3, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 304</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 754.</num>
<heading> Use of existing resources</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In establishing the national preparedness goal and national preparedness system, the Administrator shall use existing preparedness documents, planning tools, and guidelines to the extent practicable and consistent with this Act.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–295, title VI, § 654</ref>, <date date="2006-10-04">Oct. 4, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1432</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part B—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Additional Preparedness</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 761.</num>
<heading> Emergency Management Assistance Compact grants</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator may make grants to administer the Emergency Management Assistance Compact consented to by the Joint Resolution entitled “Joint Resolution granting the consent of Congress to the Emergency Management Assistance Compact” (<ref>Public Law 104–321</ref>; <ref>110 Stat. 3877</ref>).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Uses</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A grant under this section shall be used—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to carry out recommendations identified in the Emergency Management Assistance Compact after-action reports for the 2004 and 2005 hurricane season;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to administer compact operations on behalf of all member States and territories;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to continue coordination with the Agency and appropriate Federal agencies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to continue coordination with State, local, and tribal government entities and their respective national organizations; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to assist State and local governments, emergency response providers, and organizations representing such providers with credentialing emergency response providers and the typing of emergency response resources.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator shall consult with the Administrator of the Emergency Management Assistance Compact to ensure effective coordination of efforts in responding to requests for assistance.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $4,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022. Such sums shall remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–295, title VI, § 661</ref>, <date date="2006-10-04">Oct. 4, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1432</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–254, div. D, § 1217(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-10-05">Oct. 5, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 3451</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 762.</num>
<heading> Emergency management performance grants program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “program” means the emergency management performance grants program described in subsection (b); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “State” has the meaning given that term in section 102 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 5122</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall continue implementation of an emergency management performance grants program, to make grants to States to assist State, local, and tribal governments in preparing for all hazards, as authorized by the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 5121</ref> et seq.).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal share</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as otherwise specifically provided by title VI of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act [<ref>42 U.S.C. 5195</ref> et seq.], the Federal share of the cost of an activity carried out using funds made available under the program shall not exceed 50 percent.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Apportionment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For fiscal year 2008, and each fiscal year thereafter, the Administrator shall apportion the amounts appropriated to carry out the program among the States as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Baseline amount</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Administrator shall first apportion 0.25 percent of such amounts to each of American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, Guam, and the Virgin Islands and 0.75 percent of such amounts to each of the remaining States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Remainder</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Administrator shall apportion the remainder of such amounts in the ratio that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the population of each State; bears to</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the population of all States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consistency in allocation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding subsection (d), in any fiscal year before fiscal year 2013 in which the appropriation for grants under this section is equal to or greater than the appropriation for emergency management performance grants in fiscal year 2007, no State shall receive an amount under this section for that fiscal year less than the amount that State received in fiscal year 2007.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out the program, for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022, $950,000,000.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–295, title VI, § 662</ref>, <date date="2006-10-04">Oct. 4, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1433</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–53, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="2007-08-03">Aug. 3, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 294</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–254, div. D, § 1217(c)</ref>, <date date="2018-10-05">Oct. 5, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 3451</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 763.</num>
<heading> Transfer of Noble Training Center</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Noble Training Center is transferred to the Center for Domestic Preparedness. The Center for Domestic Preparedness shall integrate the Noble Training Center into the program structure of the Center for Domestic Preparedness.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–295, title VI, § 663</ref>, <date date="2006-10-04">Oct. 4, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1433</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 763a.</num>
<heading> Training for Federal Government, foreign governments, or private entities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In fiscal year 2013 and thereafter: (a) the Center for Domestic Preparedness may provide training to emergency response providers from the Federal Government, foreign governments, or private entities, if the Center for Domestic Preparedness is reimbursed for the cost of such training, and any reimbursement under this subsection shall be credited to the account from which the expenditure being reimbursed was made and shall be available, without fiscal year limitation, for the purposes for which amounts in the account may be expended; (b) the head of the Center for Domestic Preparedness shall ensure that any training provided under (a) does not interfere with the primary mission of the Center to train State and local emergency response providers; and (c) subject to (b), nothing in (a) prohibits the Center for Domestic Preparedness from providing training to employees of the Federal Emergency Management Agency in existing chemical, biological, radiological, nuclear, explosives, mass casualty, and medical surge courses pursuant to <ref>5 U.S.C. 4103</ref> without reimbursement for the cost of such training.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–6, div. D, title III</ref>, <date date="2013-03-26">Mar. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 359</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 764.</num>
<heading> National exercise simulation center</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President shall establish a national exercise simulation center that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> uses a mix of live, virtual, and constructive simulations to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> prepare elected officials, emergency managers, emergency response providers, and emergency support providers at all levels of government to operate cohesively;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provide a learning environment for the homeland security personnel of all Federal agencies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> assist in the development of operational procedures and exercises, particularly those based on catastrophic incidents; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> allow incident commanders to exercise decisionmaking in a simulated environment; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> uses modeling and simulation for training, exercises, and command and control functions at the operational level.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–295, title VI, § 664</ref>, <date date="2006-10-04">Oct. 4, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1433</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 765.</num>
<heading> Real property transactions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports to the Armed Services Committees</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Director of the Office of Civil and Defense Mobilization, or his designee, may not enter into any of the following listed transactions by or for the use of that agency until after the expiration of thirty days from the date upon which a report of the facts concerning the proposed transaction is submitted to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and House of Representatives:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> An acquisition of fee title to any real property, if the estimated price is more than $50,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A lease of any real property to the United States, if the estimated annual rental is more than $50,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A lease of real property owned by the United States, if the estimated annual rental is more than $50,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> A transfer of real property owned by the United States to another Federal agency or to a State, if the estimated value is more than $50,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> A report of excess real property owned by the United States to a disposal agency, if the estimated value is more than $50,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">If a transaction covered by clause (1) or (2) is part of a project, the report must include a summarization of the general plan for that project, including an estimate of the total cost of the lands to be acquired or leases to be made.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual reports to Armed Services Committees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director of the Office of Civil and Defense Mobilization shall report annually to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives on transactions described in subsection (a) that involve an estimated value of more than $5,000 but not more than $50,000.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Real property governed by this section</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section applies only to real property in the States of the Union, the District of Columbia, and Puerto Rico. It does not apply to real property for river and harbor projects or flood-control projects, or to leases of Government-owned real property for agricultural or grazing purposes.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recital of compliance in instrument of conveyance as conclusive</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A statement in an instrument of conveyance, including a lease, that the requirements of this section have been met, or that the conveyance is not subject to this section, is conclusive.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041, § 43</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 636</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–70, § 37</ref>, <date date="1959-06-25">June 25, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 150</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–500, title V, § 512</ref>, <date date="1960-06-08">June 8, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 187</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–624, § 38</ref>, <date date="1960-06-12">June 12, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 421</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–470, title II, § 202(c)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-19">Oct. 19, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2242</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part C—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Miscellaneous Authorities</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 771.</num>
<heading> National Disaster Recovery Strategy</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator, in coordination with the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of the Treasury, the Secretary of Transportation, the Administrator of the Small Business Administration, the Assistant Secretary for Indian Affairs of the Department of the Interior, and the heads of other appropriate Federal agencies, State, local, and tribal government officials (including through the National Advisory Council), and representatives of appropriate nongovernmental organizations shall develop, coordinate, and maintain a National Disaster Recovery Strategy to serve as a guide to recovery efforts after major disasters and emergencies.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The National Disaster Recovery Strategy shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> outline the most efficient and cost-effective Federal programs that will meet the recovery needs of States, local and tribal governments, and individuals and households affected by a major disaster;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> clearly define the role, programs, authorities, and responsibilities of each Federal agency that may be of assistance in providing assistance in the recovery from a major disaster;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> promote the use of the most appropriate and cost-effective building materials (based on the hazards present in an area) in any area affected by a major disaster, with the goal of encouraging the construction of disaster-resistant buildings; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> describe in detail the programs that may be offered by the agencies described in paragraph (2), including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> discussing funding issues;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> detailing how responsibilities under the National Disaster Recovery Strategy will be shared; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> addressing other matters concerning the cooperative effort to provide recovery assistance.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 270 days after <date date="2006-10-04">October 4, 2006</date>, the Administrator shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report describing in detail the National Disaster Recovery Strategy and any additional authorities necessary to implement any portion of the National Disaster Recovery Strategy.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Update</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Administrator shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report updating the report submitted under paragraph (1)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> on the same date that any change is made to the National Disaster Recovery Strategy; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> on a periodic basis after the submission of the report under paragraph (1), but not less than once every 5 years after the date of the submission of the report under paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–295, title VI, § 682</ref>, <date date="2006-10-04">Oct. 4, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1445</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 772.</num>
<heading> National Disaster Housing Strategy</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator, in coordination with representatives of the Federal agencies, governments, and organizations listed in subsection (b)(2) of this section, the National Advisory Council, the National Council on Disability, and other entities at the Administrator’s discretion, shall develop, coordinate, and maintain a National Disaster Housing Strategy.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The National Disaster Housing Strategy shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> outline the most efficient and cost effective Federal programs that will best meet the short-term and long-term housing needs of individuals and households affected by a major disaster;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> clearly define the role, programs, authorities, and responsibilities of each entity in providing housing assistance in the event of a major disaster, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Department of Housing and Urban Development;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Department of Agriculture;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Department of Veterans Affairs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the Department of Health and Human Services;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the Bureau of Indian Affairs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> any other Federal agency that may provide housing assistance in the event of a major disaster;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> the American Red Cross; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> State, local, and tribal governments;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> describe in detail the programs that may be offered by the entities described in paragraph (2), including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> outlining any funding issues;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> detailing how responsibilities under the National Disaster Housing Strategy will be shared; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> addressing other matters concerning the cooperative effort to provide housing assistance during a major disaster;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> consider methods through which housing assistance can be provided to individuals and households where employment and other resources for living are available;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> describe programs directed to meet the needs of special needs and low-income populations and ensure that a sufficient number of housing units are provided for individuals with disabilities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> describe plans for the operation of clusters of housing provided to individuals and households, including access to public services, site management, security, and site density;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> describe plans for promoting the repair or rehabilitation of existing rental housing, including through lease agreements or other means, in order to improve the provision of housing to individuals and households under section 408 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 5174</ref>); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> describe any additional authorities necessary to carry out any portion of the strategy.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Guidance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Administrator should develop and make publicly available guidance on—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> types of housing assistance available under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 5121</ref> et seq.) to individuals and households affected by an emergency or major disaster;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> eligibility for such assistance (including, where appropriate, the continuation of such assistance); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> application procedures for such assistance.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 270 days after <date date="2006-10-04">October 4, 2006</date>, the Administrator shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report describing in detail the National Disaster Housing Strategy, including programs directed to meeting the needs of special needs populations.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Updated report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Administrator shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report updating the report submitted under paragraph (1)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> on the same date that any change is made to the National Disaster Housing Strategy; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> on a periodic basis after the submission of the report under paragraph (1), but not less than once every 5 years after the date of the submission of the report under paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–295, title VI, § 683</ref>, <date date="2006-10-04">Oct. 4, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1446</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 773.</num>
<heading> Individuals with disabilities guidelines</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 90 days after <date date="2006-10-04">October 4, 2006</date>, and in coordination with the National Advisory Council, the National Council on Disability, the Interagency Coordinating Council on Preparedness and Individuals With Disabilities established under Executive Order No. 13347, and the Disability Coordinator (established under <ref>section 321b of this title</ref>), the Administrator shall develop guidelines to accommodate individuals with disabilities, which shall include guidelines for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the accessibility of, and communications and programs in, shelters, recovery centers, and other facilities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> devices used in connection with disaster operations, including first aid stations, mass feeding areas, portable payphone stations, portable toilets, and temporary housing.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–295, title VI, § 689(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-04">Oct. 4, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1448</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 774.</num>
<heading> Reunification</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Child Locator Center</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Child Locator Center” means the National Emergency Child Locator Center established under subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Declared event</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “declared event” means a major disaster or emergency.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Displaced adult</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “displaced adult” means an individual 21 years of age or older who is displaced from the habitual residence of that individual as a result of a declared event.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Displaced child</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “displaced child” means an individual under 21 years of age who is displaced from the habitual residence of that individual as a result of a declared event.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National Emergency Child Locator Center</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2006-10-04">October 4, 2006</date>, the Administrator, in coordination with the Attorney General of the United States, shall establish within the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children the National Emergency Child Locator Center. In establishing the National Emergency Child Locator Center, the Administrator shall establish procedures to make all relevant information available to the National Emergency Child Locator Center in a timely manner to facilitate the expeditious identification and reunification of children with their families.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The purposes of the Child Locator Center are to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> enable individuals to provide to the Child Locator Center the name of and other identifying information about a displaced child or a displaced adult who may have information about the location of a displaced child;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> enable individuals to receive information about other sources of information about displaced children and displaced adults; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> assist law enforcement in locating displaced children.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Responsibilities and duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The responsibilities and duties of the Child Locator Center are to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> establish a toll-free telephone number to receive reports of displaced children and information about displaced adults that may assist in locating displaced children;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> create a website to provide information about displaced children;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> deploy its staff to the location of a declared event to gather information about displaced children;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> assist in the reunification of displaced children with their families;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> provide information to the public about additional resources for disaster assistance;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> work in partnership with Federal, State, and local law enforcement agencies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> provide technical assistance in locating displaced children;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> share information on displaced children and displaced adults with governmental agencies and nongovernmental organizations providing disaster assistance;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> use its resources to gather information about displaced children;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<chapeau> refer reports of displaced adults to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an entity designated by the Attorney General to provide technical assistance in locating displaced adults; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the National Emergency Family Registry and Locator System as defined under <ref>section 775(a) of this title</ref>;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> enter into cooperative agreements with Federal and State agencies and other organizations such as the American Red Cross as necessary to implement the mission of the Child Locator Center; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(L)</num>
<content> develop an emergency response plan to prepare for the activation of the Child Locator Center.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 270 days after <date date="2006-10-04">October 4, 2006</date>, the Administrator shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives a report describing in detail the status of the Child Locator Center, including funding issues and any difficulties or issues in establishing the Center or completing the cooperative agreements described in subsection (b)(3)(K).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–295, title VI, § 689b</ref>, <date date="2006-10-04">Oct. 4, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1449</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 775.</num>
<heading> National Emergency Family Registry and Locator System</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “displaced individual” means an individual displaced by an emergency or major disaster; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “National Emergency Family Registry and Locator System” means the National Emergency Family Registry and Locator System established under subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2006-10-04">October 4, 2006</date>, the Administrator shall establish a National Emergency Family Registry and Locator System to help reunify families separated after an emergency or major disaster.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Operation of System</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The National Emergency Family Registry and Locator System shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> allow a displaced adult (including medical patients) to voluntarily register (and allow an adult that is the parent or guardian of a displaced child to register such child), by submitting personal information to be entered into a database (such as the name, current location of residence, and any other relevant information that could be used by others seeking to locate that individual);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> ensure that information submitted under paragraph (1) is accessible to those individuals named by a displaced individual and to those law enforcement officials;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> be accessible through the Internet and through a toll-free number, to receive reports of displaced individuals; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> include a means of referring displaced children to the National Emergency Child Locator Center established under <ref>section 774 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Publication of information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 210 days after <date date="2006-10-04">October 4, 2006</date>, the Administrator shall establish a mechanism to inform the public about the National Emergency Family Registry and Locator System and its potential usefulness for assisting to reunite displaced individuals with their families.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 90 days after <date date="2006-10-04">October 4, 2006</date>, the Administrator shall enter a memorandum of understanding with the Department of Justice, the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children, the Department of Health and Human Services, and the American Red Cross and other relevant private organizations that will enhance the sharing of information to facilitate reuniting displaced individuals (including medical patients) with their families.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 270 days after <date date="2006-10-04">October 4, 2006</date>, the Administrator shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report describing in detail the status of the National Emergency Family Registry and Locator System, including any difficulties or issues in establishing the System, including funding issues.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–295, title VI, § 689c</ref>, <date date="2006-10-04">Oct. 4, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1451</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 776.</num>
<heading> Individuals and households pilot program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Pilot program</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The President, acting through the Administrator, in coordination with State, local, and tribal governments, shall establish and conduct a pilot program. The pilot program shall be designed to make better use of existing rental housing, located in areas covered by a major disaster declaration, in order to provide timely and cost-effective temporary housing assistance to individuals and households eligible for assistance under <ref>section 5174 of title 42</ref> where alternative housing options are less available or less cost-effective.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administration</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">For the purposes of the pilot program under this section, the Administrator may—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> enter into lease agreements with owners of multi-family rental property located in areas covered by a major disaster declaration to house individuals and households eligible for assistance under <ref>section 5174 of title 42</ref>;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> make improvements to properties under such lease agreements;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> use the pilot program where the program is cost effective in that the cost to the Government for the lease agreements is in proportion to the savings to the Government by not providing alternative housing; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> limit repairs to those required to ensure that the housing units shall meet Federal housing quality standards.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Improvements to leased properties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Under the terms of any lease agreement for a property described under subparagraph (A)(ii), the value of the contribution of the Agency to such improvements—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> shall be deducted from the value of the lease agreement; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> may not exceed the value of the lease agreement.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In administering the pilot program under this section, the Administrator may consult with State, local, and tribal governments.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Not later than <date date="2009-03-31">March 31, 2009</date>, the Administrator shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report regarding the effectiveness of the pilot program.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Administrator shall include in the report—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an assessment of the effectiveness of the pilot program under this section, including an assessment of cost-savings to the Federal Government and any benefits to individuals and households eligible for assistance under <ref>section 5174 of title 42</ref> under the pilot program;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> findings and conclusions of the Administrator with respect to the pilot program;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> an assessment of additional authorities needed to aid the Agency in its mission of providing disaster housing assistance to individuals and households eligible for assistance under <ref>section 5174 of title 42</ref>, either under the pilot program under this section or other potential housing programs; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> any recommendations of the Administrator for additional authority to continue or make permanent the pilot program.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Pilot program project approval</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator shall not approve a project under the pilot program after <date date="2008-12-31">December 31, 2008</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–295, title VI, § 689i</ref>, <date date="2006-10-04">Oct. 4, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1454</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 777.</num>
<heading> Public assistance pilot program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Pilot program</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The President, acting through the Administrator, and in coordination with State and local governments, shall establish and conduct a pilot program to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> reduce the costs to the Federal Government of providing assistance to States and local governments under sections 5170b(a)(3)(A), 5172, and 5173 of title 42;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> increase flexibility in the administration of sections 5170b(a)(3)(A), 5172, and 5173 of title 42; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> expedite the provision of assistance to States and local governments provided under sections 5170b(a)(3)(A), 5172, and 5173 of title 42.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Participation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Only States and local governments that elect to participate in the pilot program may participate in the pilot program for a particular project.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Innovative administration</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">For purposes of the pilot program, the Administrator shall establish new procedures to administer assistance provided under the sections referred to in paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> New procedures</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The new procedures established under subparagraph (A) may include 1 or more of the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding <ref>section 5172(c)(1)(A) of title 42</ref>, providing an option for a State or local government to elect to receive an in-lieu contribution in an amount equal to 90 percent of the Federal share of the Federal estimate of the cost of repair, restoration, reconstruction, or replacement of a public facility owned or controlled by the State or local government and of management expenses.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Making grants on the basis of estimates agreed to by the local government (or where no local government is involved, by the State government) and the Administrator to provide financial incentives and disincentives for the local government (or where no local government is involved, for the State government) for the timely or cost effective completion of projects under sections 5170b(a)(3)(A), 5172, and 5173 of title 42.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Increasing the Federal share for removal of debris and wreckage for States and local governments that have a debris management plan approved by the Administrator and have pre-qualified 1 or more debris and wreckage removal contractors before the date of declaration of the major disaster.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> Using a sliding scale for the Federal share for removal of debris and wreckage based on the time it takes to complete debris and wreckage removal.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> Using a financial incentive to recycle debris.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> Reimbursing base wages for employees and extra hires of a State or local government involved in or administering debris and wreckage removal.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Waiver</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Administrator may waive such regulations or rules applicable to the provisions of assistance under the sections referred to in paragraph (1) as the Administrator determines are necessary to carry out the pilot program under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than <date date="2009-03-31">March 31, 2009</date>, the Administrator shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report regarding the effectiveness of the pilot program under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The report submitted under paragraph (1) shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an assessment by the Administrator of any administrative or financial benefits of the pilot program;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an assessment by the Administrator of the effect, including any savings in time and cost, of the pilot program;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any identified legal or other obstacles to increasing the amount of debris recycled after a major disaster;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> any other findings and conclusions of the Administrator with respect to the pilot program; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> any recommendations of the Administrator for additional authority to continue or make permanent the pilot program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deadline for initiation of implementation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator shall initiate implementation of the pilot program under this section not later than 90 days after <date date="2006-10-04">October 4, 2006</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Pilot program project duration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator may not approve a project under the pilot program under this section after <date date="2008-12-31">December 31, 2008</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–295, title VI, § 689j</ref>, <date date="2006-10-04">Oct. 4, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1455</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part D—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Prevention of Fraud, Waste, and Abuse</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 791.</num>
<heading> Advance contracting</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initial report</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2006-10-04">October 4, 2006</date>, the Administrator shall submit a report under paragraph (2) identifying—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> recurring disaster response requirements, including specific goods and services, for which the Agency is capable of contracting for in advance of a natural disaster or act of terrorism or other man-made disaster in a cost effective manner;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> recurring disaster response requirements, including specific goods and services, for which the Agency can not contract in advance of a natural disaster or act of terrorism or other man-made disaster in a cost effective manner; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a contracting strategy that maximizes the use of advance contracts to the extent practical and cost-effective.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Submission</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The report under paragraph (1) shall be submitted to the appropriate committees of Congress.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Entering into contracts</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2006-10-04">October 4, 2006</date>, the Administrator shall enter into 1 or more contracts for each type of goods or services identified under subsection (a)(1)(A), and in accordance with the contracting strategy identified in subsection (a)(1)(C). Any contract for goods or services identified in subsection (a)(1)(A) previously awarded may be maintained in fulfilling this requirement.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Considered factors</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Before entering into any contract under this subsection, the Administrator shall consider <ref>section 5150 of title 42</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prenegotiated Federal contracts for goods and services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Administrator, in coordination with State and local governments and other Federal agencies, shall establish a process to ensure that Federal prenegotiated contracts for goods and services are coordinated with State and local governments, as appropriate.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prenegotiated State and local contracts for goods and services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Administrator shall encourage State and local governments to establish prenegotiated contracts with vendors for goods and services in advance of natural disasters and acts of terrorism or other man-made disasters.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Maintenance of contracts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">After the date described under subsection (b), the Administrator shall have the responsibility to maintain contracts for appropriate levels of goods and services in accordance with subsection (a)(1)(C).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report on contracts not using competitive procedures</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">At the end of each fiscal quarter, beginning with the first fiscal quarter occurring at least 90 days after <date date="2006-10-04">October 4, 2006</date>, the Administrator shall submit a report on each disaster assistance contract entered into by the Agency by other than competitive procedures to the appropriate committees of Congress.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Updated report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2020-12-31">December 31, 2020</date>, the Administrator shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress an updated report that contains—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the information required in the initial report under subparagraphs (A) and (B) of subsection (a)(1); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> an updated strategy described in subsection (a)(1)(C) that clearly defines—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the objectives of advance contracts;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> how advance contracts contribute to disaster response operations of the Agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> how to maximize the award of advance contracts to small business concerns, as defined in <ref>section 632 of title 15</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> whether and how advance contracts should be prioritized in relation to new post-disaster contract awards.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional Duties of the Administrator</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Head of contracting</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Administrator shall ensure that the head of contracting activity of the Agency—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> not later than 270 days after <date date="2020-12-31">December 31, 2020</date>, updates the Disaster Contracting Desk Guide of the Agency to provide specific guidance—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> on whether and under what circumstances contracting officers should consider using existing advance contracts entered into in accordance with this section prior to making new post-disaster contract awards, and include this guidance in existing semi-annual training given to contracting officers; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> for contracting officers to perform outreach to State and local governments on the potential benefits of establishing their own pre-negotiated advance contracts;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> adheres to hard copy contract file management requirements in effect to ensure that the files relating to advance contracts entered into in accordance with this section are complete and up to date, whether the files will be transferred into the Electronic Contract Filing System of the Agency or remain in hard copy format;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> notifies contracting officers of the 3-day time frame requirement for entering completed award documentation into the contract writing system of the Agency when executing notice to proceed documentation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> not later than 180 days after <date date="2020-12-31">December 31, 2020</date>, revises the reporting methodology of the Agency to ensure that all disaster contracts are included in each quarterly report submitted to the appropriate congressional committees under this section on disaster contract actions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> identifies a single centralized resource listing advance contracts entered into under this section and ensures that source is current and up to date and includes all available advance contracts; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> communicates complete and up-to-date information on available advance contracts to State and local governments to inform their advance contracting efforts.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Master acquisition planning schedule</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2020-12-31">December 31, 2020</date>, the Administrator shall update and implement guidance for program office and acquisition personnel of the Agency to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> identify acquisition planning time frames and considerations across the entire acquisition planning process of the Agency; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> clearly communicate the purpose and use of a master acquisition planning schedule.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–295, title VI, § 691</ref>, <date date="2006-10-04">Oct. 4, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1457</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–272, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-31">Dec. 31, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3349</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 792.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 117–253, § 1</ref>, <date date="2022-12-20">Dec. 20, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2360</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 793.</num>
<heading> Oversight and accountability of Federal disaster expenditures</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority of Administrator to designate funds for oversight activities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator may designate up to 1 percent of the total amount provided to a Federal agency for a mission assignment as oversight funds to be used by the recipient agency for performing oversight of activities carried out under the Agency reimbursable mission assignment process. Such funds shall remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of funds</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Types of oversight activities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Oversight funds may be used for the following types of oversight activities related to Agency mission assignments:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Monitoring, tracking, and auditing expenditures of funds.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Ensuring that sufficient management and internal control mechanisms are available so that Agency funds are spent appropriately and in accordance with all applicable laws and regulations.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Reviewing selected contracts and other activities.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Investigating allegations of fraud involving Agency funds.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Conducting and participating in fraud prevention activities with other Federal, State, and local government personnel and contractors.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Plans and reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Oversight funds may be used to issue the plans required under subsection (e) and the reports required under subsection (f).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Restriction on use of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Oversight funds may not be used to finance existing agency oversight responsibilities related to direct agency appropriations used for disaster response, relief, and recovery activities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Methods of oversight activities</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Oversight activities may be carried out by an agency under this section either directly or by contract. Such activities may include evaluations and financial and performance audits.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination of oversight activities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To the extent practicable, evaluations and audits under this section shall be performed by the inspector general of the agency.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Development of oversight plans</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If an agency receives oversight funds for a fiscal year, the head of the agency shall prepare a plan describing the oversight activities for disaster response, relief, and recovery anticipated to be undertaken during the subsequent fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Selection of oversight activities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In preparing the plan, the head of the agency shall select oversight activities based upon a risk assessment of those areas that present the greatest risk of fraud, waste, and abuse.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Schedule</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The plan shall include a schedule for conducting oversight activities, including anticipated dates of completion.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal disaster assistance accountability reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A Federal agency receiving oversight funds under this section shall submit annually to the Administrator and the appropriate committees of Congress a consolidated report regarding the use of such funds, including information summarizing oversight activities and the results achieved.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this section, the term “oversight funds” means funds referred to in subsection (a) that are designated for use in performing oversight activities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–295, title VI, § 693</ref>, <date date="2006-10-04">Oct. 4, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1458</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 794.</num>
<heading> Limitation on length of certain noncompetitive contracts</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall promulgate regulations applicable to contracts described in subsection (c) to restrict the contract period of any such contract entered into using procedures other than competitive procedures pursuant to the exception provided in paragraph (2) of <ref>section 3304(a) of title 41</ref> to the minimum contract period necessary—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to meet the urgent and compelling requirements of the work to be performed under the contract; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to enter into another contract for the required goods or services through the use of competitive procedures.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Specific contract period</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The regulations promulgated under subsection (a) shall require the contract period to not to exceed <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002127">1</ref> 150 days, unless the Secretary determines that exceptional circumstances apply.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Covered contracts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section applies to any contract in an amount greater than the simplified acquisition threshold (as defined by <ref>section 134 of title 41</ref>) entered into by the Department to facilitate response to or recovery from a natural disaster, act of terrorism, or other man-made disaster.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–295, title VI, § 695</ref>, <date date="2006-10-04">Oct. 4, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1460</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 795.</num>
<heading> Fraud, waste, and abuse controls</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Administrator shall ensure that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> all programs within the Agency administering Federal disaster relief assistance develop and maintain proper internal management controls to prevent and detect fraud, waste, and abuse;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> application databases used by the Agency to collect information on eligible recipients must record disbursements;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> such tracking is designed to highlight and identify ineligible applications; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the databases used to collect information from applications for such assistance must be integrated with disbursements and payment records.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Audits and reviews required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator shall ensure that any database or similar application processing system for Federal disaster relief assistance programs administered by the Agency undergoes a review by the Inspector General of the Agency to determine the existence and implementation of such internal controls required under this section and the amendments made by this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–295, title VI, § 696</ref>, <date date="2006-10-04">Oct. 4, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1460</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 796.</num>
<heading> Registry of disaster response contractors</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “registry” means the registry created under subsection (b); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the terms “small business concern”, “small business concern owned and controlled by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals”, “small business concern owned and controlled by women”, and “small business concern owned and controlled by service-disabled veterans” have the meanings given those terms under the Small Business Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 631</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Registry</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Administrator shall establish and maintain a registry of contractors who are willing to perform debris removal, distribution of supplies, reconstruction, and other disaster or emergency relief activities.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The registry shall include, for each business concern—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the name of the business concern;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the location of the business concern;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the area served by the business concern;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the type of good or service provided by the business concern;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the bonding level of the business concern; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<chapeau> whether the business concern is—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a small business concern;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a small business concern owned and controlled by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a small business concern owned and controlled by women; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> a small business concern owned and controlled by service-disabled veterans.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Source of information</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Submission</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Information maintained in the registry shall be submitted on a voluntary basis and be kept current by the submitting business concerns.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Attestation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Each business concern submitting information to the registry shall submit—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an attestation that the information is true; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> documentation supporting such attestation.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Verification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Administrator shall verify that the documentation submitted by each business concern supports the information submitted by that business concern.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability of registry</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The registry shall be made generally available on the Internet site of the Agency.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation of registry</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">As part of the acquisition planning for contracting for debris removal, distribution of supplies in a disaster, reconstruction, and other disaster or emergency relief activities, a Federal agency shall consult the registry.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–295, title VI, § 697</ref>, <date date="2006-10-04">Oct. 4, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1461</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 797.</num>
<heading> Fraud prevention training program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator shall develop and implement a program to provide training on the prevention of waste, fraud, and abuse of Federal disaster relief assistance relating to the response to or recovery from natural disasters and acts of terrorism or other man-made disasters and ways to identify such potential waste, fraud, and abuse.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–295, title VI, § 698</ref>, <date date="2006-10-04">Oct. 4, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1462</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part E—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Authorization of Appropriations</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 811.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this title <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002128">1</ref> and the amendments made by this title for the administration and operations of the Agency—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> for fiscal year 2008, an amount equal to the amount appropriated for fiscal year 2007 for administration and operations of the Agency, multiplied by 1.1;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> for fiscal year 2009, an amount equal to the amount described in paragraph (1), multiplied by 1.1; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> for fiscal year 2010, an amount equal to the amount described in paragraph (2), multiplied by 1.1.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–295, title VI, § 699</ref>, <date date="2006-10-04">Oct. 4, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1462</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part F—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Global Catastrophic Risk Management</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 821.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this part:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrator</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Administrator” means the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Basic need</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “basic need”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> means any good, service, or activity necessary to protect the health, safety, and general welfare of the civilian population of the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> includes—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> food;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> water;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> shelter;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> basic communication services;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> basic sanitation and health services; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> public safety.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Catastrophic incident</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “catastrophic incident”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> means any natural or man-made disaster that results in extraordinary levels of casualties or damage, mass evacuations, or disruption severely affecting the population, infrastructure, environment, economy, national morale, or government functions in an area; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> may include an incident—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> with a sustained national impact over a prolonged period of time;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> that may rapidly exceed resources available to State and local government and private sector authorities in the impacted area; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> that may significantly interrupt governmental operations and emergency services to such an extent that national security could be threatened.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Critical infrastructure</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “critical infrastructure” has the meaning given such term in <ref>section 5195c(e) of title 42</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Existential risk</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “existential risk” means the potential for an outcome that would result in human extinction.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Global catastrophic risk</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “global catastrophic risk” means the risk of events or incidents consequential enough to significantly harm or set back human civilization at the global scale.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Global catastrophic and existential threats</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “global catastrophic and existential threats” means threats that with varying likelihood may produce consequences severe enough to result in systemic failure or destruction of critical infrastructure or significant harm to human civilization. Examples of global catastrophic and existential threats include severe global pandemics, nuclear war, asteroid and comet impacts, supervolcanoes, sudden and severe changes to the climate, and intentional or accidental threats arising from the use and development of emerging technologies.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Indian Tribal government</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Indian Tribal government” has the meaning given the term “Indian tribal government” in <ref>section 5122 of title 42</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Local government; State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The terms “local government” and “State” have the meanings given such terms in <ref>section 5122 of title 42</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(10)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National exercise program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “national exercise program” means activities carried out to test and evaluate the national preparedness goal and related plans and strategies as described in <ref>section 748(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(11)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Homeland Security.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. G, title LXXIII, § 7302</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3684</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 822.</num>
<heading> Assessment of global catastrophic risk</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary and the Administrator shall coordinate an assessment of global catastrophic risk.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">When coordinating the assessment under subsection (a), the Secretary and the Administrator shall coordinate with senior designees of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Assistant to the President for National Security Affairs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the Secretary of State and the Under Secretary of State for Arms Control and International Security;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the Attorney General and the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Energy, the Under Secretary of Energy for Nuclear Security, and the Director of Science;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Assistant Secretary for Preparedness and Response, and the Assistant Secretary of Global Affairs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Commerce, the Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere, and the Under Secretary of Commerce for Standards and Technology;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> the Secretary of the Interior and the Director of the United States Geological Survey;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency and the Assistant Administrator for Water;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> the Director of the National Science Foundation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> the Secretary of the Treasury;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Defense, the Assistant Secretary of the Army for Civil Works, and the Chief of Engineers and Commanding General of the Army Corps of Engineers;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<content> the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(16)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Transportation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(17)</num>
<content> other stakeholders the Secretary and the Administrator determine appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. G, title LXXIII, § 7303</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3685</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 823.</num>
<heading> Report required</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2022-12-23">December 23, 2022</date>, and every 10 years thereafter, the Secretary, in coordination with the Administrator, shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives a report containing a detailed assessment, based on the input and coordination required under <ref>section 822 of this title</ref>, of global catastrophic and existential risk.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Matters covered</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each report required under subsection (a) shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> expert estimates of cumulative global catastrophic and existential risk in the next 30 years, including separate estimates for the likelihood of occurrence and potential consequences;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> expert-informed analyses of the risk of the most concerning specific global catastrophic and existential threats, including separate estimates, where reasonably feasible and credible, of each threat for its likelihood of occurrence and its potential consequences, as well as associated uncertainties;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a comprehensive list of potential catastrophic or existential threats, including even those that may have very low likelihood;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> technical assessments and lay explanations of the analyzed global catastrophic and existential risks, including their qualitative character and key factors affecting their likelihood of occurrence and potential consequences;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> an explanation of any factors that limit the ability of the Secretary to assess the risk both cumulatively and for particular threats, and how those limitations may be overcome through future research or with additional resources, programs, or authorities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> a forecast of if and why global catastrophic and existential risk is likely to increase or decrease significantly in the next 10 years, both qualitatively and quantitatively, as well as a description of associated uncertainties;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> proposals for how the Federal Government may more adequately assess global catastrophic and existential risk on an ongoing basis in future years;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> recommendations for legislative actions, as appropriate, to support the evaluation and assessment of global catastrophic and existential risk; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> other matters deemed appropriate by the Secretary, in coordination with the Administrator, and based on the input and coordination required under <ref>section 822 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation requirement</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In producing the report required under subsection (a), the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> regularly consult with experts on severe global pandemics, nuclear war, asteroid and comet impacts, supervolcanoes, sudden and severe changes to the climate, and intentional or accidental threats arising from the use and development of emerging technologies; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> share information gained through the consultation required under paragraph (1) with relevant Federal partners listed in <ref>section 822(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. G, title LXXIII, § 7304</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3686</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 824.</num>
<heading> Enhanced catastrophic incident annex</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary, in coordination with the Administrator and the Federal partners listed in <ref>section 822(b) of this title</ref>, shall supplement each Federal Interagency Operational Plan to include an annex containing a strategy to ensure the health, safety, and general welfare of the civilian population affected by catastrophic incidents by—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> providing for the basic needs of the civilian population of the United States that is impacted by catastrophic incidents in the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> coordinating response efforts with State, local, and Indian Tribal governments, the private sector, and nonprofit relief organizations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> promoting personal and local readiness and non-reliance on government relief during periods of heightened tension or after catastrophic incidents; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> developing international partnerships with allied nations for the provision of relief services and goods.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Elements of the strategy</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The strategy required under subsection (a) shall include a description of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> actions the Federal Government should take to ensure the basic needs of the civilian population of the United States in a catastrophic incident are met;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> how the Federal Government should coordinate with non-Federal entities to multiply resources and enhance relief capabilities, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> State and local governments;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Indian Tribal governments;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> State disaster relief agencies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> State and local disaster relief managers;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> State National Guards;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> law enforcement and first response entities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> nonprofit relief services;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> actions the Federal Government should take to enhance individual resiliency to the effects of a catastrophic incident, which actions shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> readiness alerts to the public during periods of elevated threat;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> efforts to enhance domestic supply and availability of critical goods and basic necessities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> information campaigns to ensure the public is aware of response plans and services that will be activated when necessary;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> efforts the Federal Government should undertake and agreements the Federal Government should seek with international allies to enhance the readiness of the United States to provide for the general welfare;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> how the strategy will be implemented should multiple levels of critical infrastructure be destroyed or taken offline entirely for an extended period of time; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the authorities the Federal Government should implicate in responding to a catastrophic incident.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assumptions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In designing the strategy under subsection (a), the Secretary, in coordination with the Administrator and the Federal partners listed in <ref>section 822(b) of this title</ref>, shall account for certain factors to make the strategy operationally viable, including the assumption that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> multiple levels of critical infrastructure have been taken offline or destroyed by catastrophic incidents or the effects of catastrophic incidents;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> impacted sectors may include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the transportation sector;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the communication sector;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the energy sector;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the healthcare and public health sector; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the water and wastewater sector;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> State, local, Indian Tribal, and territorial governments have been equally affected or made largely inoperable by catastrophic incidents or the effects of catastrophic incidents;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the emergency has exceeded the response capabilities of State, local, and Indian Tribal governments under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 5121</ref> et seq.) and other relevant disaster response laws; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the United States military is sufficiently engaged in armed or cyber conflict with State or non-State adversaries, or is otherwise unable to augment domestic response capabilities in a significant manner due to a catastrophic incident.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. G, title LXXIII, § 7305</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3687</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 825.</num>
<heading> Rules of construction</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrator</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this part shall be construed to supersede the civilian emergency management authority of the Administrator under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 5121</ref> et seq.) or the Post Katrina Emergency Management Reform Act <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002129">1</ref> (<ref>6 U.S.C. 701</ref> et seq.).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this part shall be construed as providing new authority to the Secretary, except to coordinate and facilitate the development of the assessments and reports required pursuant to this part.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. G, title LXXIII, § 7309</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3689</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
</subchapter>
</chapter>