<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 537—</num>
<heading>LOANS AND GUARANTEES</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>GENERAL</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 53701.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Actual cost</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “actual cost” means the sum of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> all amounts paid by or for the account of the obligor as of the date on which a determination is made under <ref>section 53715(d)(1) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> all amounts that the Secretary or Administrator reasonably estimates the obligor will become obligated to pay from time to time thereafter, for the construction, reconstruction, or reconditioning of the vessel, including guarantee fees that will become payable under <ref>section 53714 of this title</ref> in connection with all obligations issued for construction, reconstruction, or reconditioning of the vessel or equipment to be delivered, and all obligations issued for the delivered vessel or equipment.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Administrator</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “Administrator” means the Administrator of the Maritime Administration.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Construction, reconstruction, and reconditioning</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The terms “construction”, “reconstruction”, and “reconditioning” include designing, inspecting, outfitting, and equipping.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Depreciated actual cost</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “depreciated actual cost” of a vessel means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> if the vessel was not reconstructed or reconditioned, the actual cost of the vessel depreciated on a straight line basis over the useful life of the vessel as determined by the Secretary or Administrator, not to exceed 25 years from the date of delivery by the builder; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> if the vessel was reconstructed or reconditioned, the sum of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the actual cost of the vessel depreciated on a straight line basis from the date of delivery by the builder to the date of the reconstruction or reconditioning, using the original useful life of the vessel, and from the date of the reconstruction or reconditioning, using a useful life of the vessel determined by the Secretary or Administrator; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any amount paid or obligated to be paid for the reconstruction or reconditioning, depreciated on a straight line basis using a useful life of the vessel determined by the Secretary or Administrator.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Fishery facility</inline>.—</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subject to subparagraph (B), the term “fishery facility” means—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> for operations on land—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> a structure or appurtenance thereto designed for the unloading and receiving from vessels, the processing, the holding pending processing, the distribution after processing, or the holding pending distribution, of fish from a fishery;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the land necessary for the structure or appurtenance; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> equipment that is for use with the structure or appurtenance and that is necessary for performing a function referred to in subclause (I);</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> for operations not on land, a vessel built in the United States and used for, equipped to be used for, or of a type normally used for, the processing of fish; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> for aquaculture, including operations on land or elsewhere—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> a structure or appurtenance thereto designed for aquaculture;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the land necessary for the structure or appurtenance;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> equipment that is for use with the structure or appurtenance and that is necessary for performing a function referred to in subclause (I); and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> a vessel built in the United States and used for, equipped to be used for, or of a type normally used for, aquaculture.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Required ownership</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Under subparagraph (A), the structure, appurtenance, land, equipment, or vessel must be owned by—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an individual who is a citizen of the United States; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> an entity that is a citizen of the United States under <ref>section 50501 of this title</ref> and that is at least 75 percent owned (as determined under that section) by citizens of the United States.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Fishing vessel</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “fishing vessel” has the meaning given that term in section 3 of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<ref>16 U.S.C. 1802</ref>), and any reference in this chapter to a vessel designed principally for commercial use in the fishing trade or industry is deemed to be a reference to a fishing vessel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Historical uses</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “historical uses” includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> refurbishing, repairing, rebuilding, or replacing equipment on a fishing vessel, without materially increasing harvesting capacity;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> purchasing a used fishing vessel;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> purchasing, constructing, expanding, or reconditioning a fishery facility;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> refinancing existing debt;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> reducing fishing capacity; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<chapeau> making upgrades to a fishing vessel, including upgrades in technology, gear, or equipment, that improve—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> collection and reporting of fishery-dependent data;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> bycatch reduction or avoidance;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> gear selectivity;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> adverse impacts caused by fishing gear; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> safety.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Mortgage</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “mortgage” includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a preferred mortgage as defined in <ref>section 31301 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a mortgage on a vessel that will become a preferred mortgage when filed or recorded under chapter 313 of this title.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Obligation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “obligation” means an instrument of indebtedness issued for a purpose described in <ref>section 53706 of this title</ref>, except—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an obligation issued by the Secretary or Administrator under <ref>section 53723 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an obligation eligible for investment of funds under section 53715(f) or 53717 of this title.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Obligee</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “obligee” means the holder of an obligation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Obligor</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “obligor” means a party primarily liable for payment of the principal of or interest on an obligation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Ocean thermal energy conversion facility or plantship</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “ocean thermal energy conversion facility or plantship” means an at-sea facility or vessel, whether mobile, floating unmoored, moored, or standing on the seabed, that uses temperature differences in ocean water to produce electricity or another form of energy capable of being used directly to perform work, and includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> equipment installed on the facility or vessel to use the electricity or other form of energy to produce, process, refine, or manufacture a product;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a cable or pipeline used to deliver the electricity, freshwater, or product to shore; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> other associated equipment and appurtenances of the facility or vessel to the extent they are located seaward of the high water mark.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Secretary</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Commerce with respect to fishing vessels and fishery facilities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Vessel</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “vessel” means any type of vessel, whether in existence or under construction, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a cargo vessel;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a passenger vessel;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a combination cargo and passenger vessel;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a tanker;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> a tug or towboat;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> a barge;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> a dredge;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> a floating drydock with a capacity of at least 35,000 lifting tons and a beam of at least 125 feet between the wing walls;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> an oceanographic research vessel;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> an instruction vessel;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> a pollution treatment, abatement, or control vessel;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(L)</num>
<content> a fishing vessel whose ownership meets the citizenship requirements under <ref>section 50501 of this title</ref> for documenting vessels to operate in the coastwise trade; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(M)</num>
<content> an ocean thermal energy conversion facility or plantship that is or will be documented under the laws of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Vessel of national interest</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “Vessel of National Interest” means a vessel deemed to be of national interest that meets characteristics determined by the Administrator, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of the Department in which the Coast Guard is operating when it is not operating as a service in the Department of the Navy, or the heads of other Federal agencies, as described in section 53703(d).</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 8(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1601</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. C, title XXXV, § 3507(a)(1)(A)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3555</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. C, title XXXV, § 3522(a)(1)</ref>, (10)(B), (b), <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 596</ref>, 598; <ref>Pub. L. 114–120, title III, § 302(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2016-02-08">Feb. 8, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 51</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. C, title XXXV, § 3506(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1970</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 53702.</num>
<heading> General authority</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">In General.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Guarantee of payments</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary or Administrator, on terms the Secretary or Administrator may prescribe, may guarantee or make a commitment to guarantee the payment of the principal of and interest on an obligation eligible to be guaranteed under this chapter. A guarantee or commitment to guarantee shall cover 100 percent of the principal and interest.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Preferred eligible lender</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Federal Financing Bank shall be the preferred eligible lender of the principal and interest of the guaranteed obligations issued under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Direct Loans for Fisheries</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, any obligation involving a fishing vessel, fishery facility, aquaculture facility, individual fishing quota, or fishing capacity reduction program issued under this chapter after <date date="1996-10-11">October 11, 1996</date>, shall be a direct loan obligation for which the Secretary shall be the obligee, rather than an obligation issued to an obligee other than the Secretary and guaranteed by the Secretary. A direct loan obligation under this subsection shall be treated in the same manner and to the same extent as an obligation guaranteed under this chapter except with respect to provisions of this chapter that by their nature can only be applied to obligations guaranteed under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Interest rate</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, the annual rate of interest an obligor shall pay on a direct loan obligation under this subsection is 2 percent plus the additional percent the Secretary must pay as interest to borrow from the Treasury the funds to make the loan.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Minimum obligations available for historic uses</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Of the direct loan obligations issued by the Secretary under this chapter, the Secretary shall make a minimum of $59,000,000 available each fiscal year for historic uses.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of obligations in limited access fisheries</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In addition to the other eligible purposes and uses of direct loan obligations provided for in this chapter, the Secretary may issue direct loan obligations for the purpose of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> financing the construction or reconstruction of a fishing vessel in a fishery managed under a limited access system; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> financing the purchase of harvesting rights in a fishery that is federally managed under a limited access system.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 8(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1603</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. C, title XXXV, § 3507(a)(1)(C)</ref>, (d), <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3555</ref>, 3557; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. C, title XXXV, § 3522(a)(10)(B)</ref>, (b), <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 598</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–120, title III, § 302(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2016-02-08">Feb. 8, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 52</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. C, title XXXV, § 3506(b)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1971</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 53703.</num>
<heading> Application and administration</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Time for Decision</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary or Administrator shall approve or deny an application for a loan guarantee under this chapter within 270 days after the date on which the signed application is received by the Secretary or Administrator.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Extension</inline>.—</heading>
<content>On request by an applicant, the Secretary or Administrator may extend the 270-day period in paragraph (1) to a date not later than 2 years after the date on which the signed application was received by the Secretary or Administrator.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Certification of Review</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary or Administrator may not guarantee or make a commitment to guarantee an obligation under this chapter unless the Secretary or Administrator certifies that a full and fair consideration of all the regulatory requirements, including economic soundness and financial requirements applicable to the obligor and related parties, and a thorough assessment of the technical, economic, and financial aspects of the loan application, has been made.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Independent Analysis.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>To assess and mitigate the risks due to factors associated with markets, technology, financial, or legal structures related to an application or guarantee under this chapter, the Secretary or Administrator may utilize third party experts, including legal counsel, to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> process and review applications under this chapter, including conducting independent analysis and review of aspects of an application;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> represent the Secretary or Administrator in structuring and documenting the obligation guarantee;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> analyze and review aspects of, structure, and document the obligation guarantee during the term of the guarantee;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> recommend financial covenants or financial ratios to be met by the applicant during the time a guarantee under this chapter is outstanding that are—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> based on the financial covenants or financial ratios, if any, that are then applicable to the obligor under private sector credit agreements; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in lieu of other financial covenants applicable to the obligor under this chapter with respect to requirements regarding long-term debt-to-equity, minimum working capital, or minimum amount of equity; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> represent the Secretary or Administrator to protect the security interests of the Government relating to an obligation guarantee.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Private sector expert</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Independent analysis, review, and representation conducted under this subsection shall be performed by a private sector expert in the applicable field who is selected by the Secretary or Administrator.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Vessels of National Interest.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice of funding</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary or Administrator may post a notice in the Federal Register regarding the availability of funding for obligation guarantees under this chapter for the construction, reconstruction, or reconditioning of a Vessel of National Interest and include a timeline for the submission of applications for such vessels.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Vessel characteristics.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary or Administrator, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of the Department in which the Coast Guard is operating when it is not operating as service in the Department of the Navy, or the heads of other Federal agencies, shall develop and publish a list of vessel types that would be considered Vessels of National Interest.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Review</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Such list shall be reviewed and revised every four years or as necessary, as determined by the Administrator.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 8(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1604</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. C, title XXXV, § 3507(a)(1)(D)</ref>, (2)(G), (b)(7), <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3555</ref>, 3556; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. C, title XXXV, § 3522(a)(10)(B)</ref>, (b), <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 598</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. C, title XXXV, § 3506(c)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1971</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 53704.</num>
<heading> Funding limits</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General Limitations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The total unpaid principal amount of obligations guaranteed under this chapter and outstanding at one time may not exceed $12,000,000,000. Of that amount, $850,000,000 shall be limited to obligations related to fishing vessels and fishery facilities.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Additional Limitations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Additional limitations may not be imposed on new commitments to guarantee loans for any fiscal year, except in amounts established in advance by annual authorization laws. A vessel eligible for a guarantee under this chapter may not be denied eligibility because of its type.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limits Based on Risk Factors</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this subsection, the term “cost” has the meaning given that term in section 502 of the Federal Credit Reform Act of 1990 (<ref>2 U.S.C. 661a</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">System of risk categories</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary or Administrator shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> establish, and update annually, a system of risk categories for obligations guaranteed under this chapter that categorizes the relative risk of guarantees based on the risk factors set forth in paragraph (4);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> determine annually for each risk category a subsidy rate equivalent to the cost of obligations in the category, expressed as a percentage of the amount guaranteed for obligations in the category; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> ensure that each risk category is comprised of loans that are relatively homogeneous in cost and share characteristics predictive of defaults and other costs, given the facts known at the time of obligation or commitment, using a risk category system that is based on historical analysis of program data and statistical evidence concerning the likely costs of defaults or other costs that are expected to be associated with the loans in the category.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of system</inline>.—</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Placing obligation in category</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Before making a guarantee under this chapter for an obligation, and annually for projects subject to a guarantee, the Secretary or Administrator shall apply the risk factors specified in paragraph (4) to place the obligation in a risk category established under paragraph (2).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reduction of available amount</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary or Administrator shall consider the total amount available to the Secretary or Administrator for making guarantees under this chapter to be reduced by the amount determined by multiplying—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the amount guaranteed under this chapter for an obligation; by</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the subsidy rate for the category in which the obligation is placed under subparagraph (A).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Estimated cost</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The estimated cost to the United States Government of a guarantee under this chapter for an obligation is deemed to be the amount determined under subparagraph (B) for the obligation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Restriction on further guarantees</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary or Administrator may not guarantee obligations under this chapter after the total amount available to the Secretary or Administrator under appropriations laws for the cost of loan guarantees is considered to be reduced to zero under subparagraph (B).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Risk factors</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The risk factors referred to in this subsection are—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the period for which an obligation is guaranteed or to be guaranteed;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the amount of an obligation guaranteed or to be guaranteed in relation to the total cost of the project financed or to be financed by the obligation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the financial condition of an obligor or applicant for a guarantee;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> if applicable, other guarantees related to the project;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> if applicable, the projected employment of each vessel or equipment to be financed with an obligation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> if applicable, the projected market that will be served by each vessel or equipment to be financed with an obligation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> the collateral provided for a guarantee for an obligation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> the management and operating experience of an obligor or applicant for a guarantee;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> whether a guarantee under this chapter is or will be in effect during the construction period of the project; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> the concentration risk presented by an unduly large percentage of loans outstanding by any one borrower or group of affiliated borrowers.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 8(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1604</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. C, title XXXV, § 3507(a)(1)(C)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3555</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. C, title XXXV, § 3522(a)(10)(B)</ref>, (b), <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 598</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. C, title XXXV, § 3506(d)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1972</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 53705.</num>
<heading> Pledge of United States Government</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Full Faith and Credit</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The full faith and credit of the United States Government is pledged to the payment of a guarantee made under this chapter, for both principal and interest, including interest (as may be provided for in the guarantee) accruing between the date of default under a guaranteed obligation and the date of payment in full of the guarantee.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Incontestability</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A guarantee or commitment to guarantee made under this chapter is conclusive evidence of the eligibility of the obligation for the guarantee. The validity of a guarantee or commitment to guarantee made under this chapter is incontestable.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 8(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1606</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. C, title XXXV, § 3507(a)(1)(C)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3555</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. C, title XXXV, § 3522(b)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 598</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 53706.</num>
<heading> Eligible purposes of obligations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>To be eligible for a guarantee under this chapter, an obligation must aid in any of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> Financing (including reimbursement of an obligor for expenditures previously made for) the construction, reconstruction, or reconditioning of a vessel designed principally for research, or for commercial use—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> in the coastwise or intercoastal trade;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> on the Great Lakes, or on bays, sounds, rivers, harbors, or inland lakes of the United States;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> in foreign trade as defined in <ref>section 109(b) of this title</ref>;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> as an ocean thermal energy conversion facility or plantship; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> as a floating drydock in the construction, reconstruction, reconditioning, or repair of vessels.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A guarantee under subparagraph (A) may not be made more than one year after delivery of the vessel (or redelivery if the vessel was reconstructed or reconditioned) unless the proceeds of the obligation are used to finance the construction, reconstruction, or reconditioning of a vessel or of facilities or equipment related to marine operations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Financing (including reimbursement of an obligor for expenditures previously made for) the construction, reconstruction, reconditioning, or purchase of a vessel owned by citizens of the United States and designed principally for research, or for commercial use in the fishing industry.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> Financing the purchase, reconstruction, or reconditioning of a vessel or fishery facility—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> for which an obligation was guaranteed under this chapter; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> that, under subchapter II of this chapter—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is a vessel or fishery facility for which an obligation was accelerated and paid;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> was acquired by the Federal Ship Financing Fund or successor account under <ref>section 53717 of this title</ref>; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> was sold at foreclosure begun or intervened in by the Secretary or Administrator.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Financing any part of the repayment to the United States Government of any amount of a construction-differential subsidy paid for a vessel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Refinancing an existing obligation (regardless of whether guaranteed under this chapter) issued for a purpose described in paragraphs (1)–(4), including a short-term obligation incurred to obtain temporary funds with the intention of refinancing.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Financing or refinancing (including reimbursement of an obligor for expenditures previously made for) the construction, reconstruction, reconditioning, or purchase of a fishery facility.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<chapeau> Financing or refinancing—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the purchase of individual fishing quotas in accordance with section 303(d)(4) of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (including the reimbursement of obligors for expenditures previously made for such a purchase);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> activities that assist in the transition to reduced fishing capacity; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> technologies or upgrades designed to improve collection and reporting of fishery-dependent data, to reduce bycatch, to improve selectivity or reduce adverse impacts of fishing gear, or to improve safety.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Financing (including reimbursement of an obligor for expenditures previously made for) the reconstruction, reconditioning, retrofitting, repair, reconfiguration, or similar work in a shipyard located in the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Non-Vessels Treated as Vessels</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An obligation guaranteed under subsection (a)(6) or (7) shall be treated, for purposes of this chapter, in the same manner and to the same extent as an obligation that aids in financing the construction, reconstruction, reconditioning, or purchase of a vessel, except with respect to provisions that by their nature can only be applied to vessels.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Priorities for Certain Vessels.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Vessels</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In guaranteeing or making a commitment to guarantee an obligation under this chapter, the Administrator shall give priority to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a vessel that is otherwise eligible for a guarantee and is constructed with assistance under subtitle D of the Maritime Security Act of 2003 (<ref>46 U.S.C. 53101</ref> note);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> after applying subparagraph (A), a vessel that is otherwise eligible for a guarantee and that the Secretary of Defense determines—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is suitable for service as a naval auxiliary in time of war or national emergency; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> meets a shortfall in sealift capacity or capability; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> after applying subparagraphs (A) and (B), Vessels of National Interest.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Time for determination</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall determine whether a vessel satisfies paragraph (1)(B) not later than 30 days after receipt of a request from the Administrator for such a determination.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 8(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1606</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. C, title XXXV, § 3507(a)(1)(D)</ref>, (2)(A), (B), (b)(2), <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3555</ref>, 3556; <ref>Pub. L. 109–479, title II, § 209</ref>, <date date="2007-01-12">Jan. 12, 2007</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3617</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. C, title XXXV, § 3522(a)(2)</ref>, (10)(B), (b), <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 596</ref>, 598; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. C, title XXXV, § 3506(e)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1972</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. C, title XXXV, § 3536(a)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 835</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 53707.</num>
<heading> Findings related to obligors and operators</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Responsible Obligor</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary or Administrator may not guarantee or make a commitment to guarantee an obligation under this chapter unless the Secretary or Administrator finds that the obligor is responsible and has the ability, experience, financial resources, and other qualifications necessary for the adequate operation and maintenance of each vessel that will serve as security for the guarantee.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Operators of Liner Vessels</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Administrator may not guarantee or make a commitment to guarantee a loan for the construction, reconstruction, or reconditioning of a liner vessel under this chapter unless the Chairman of the Federal Maritime Commission certifies that the operator of the vessel has not been found by the Commission to have committed, within the previous 5 years—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a violation of part A of subtitle IV of this title that involves unjust or unfair discriminatory treatment or undue or unreasonable prejudice or disadvantage with respect to a United States shipper, ocean transportation intermediary, ocean common carrier, or port; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a violation of part B of subtitle IV of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Operators of Fishing Vessels</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary may not guarantee or make a commitment to guarantee a loan for the construction, reconstruction, or reconditioning of a fishing vessel under this chapter if the operator of the vessel has been—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> held liable, or the vessel has been held liable in rem, for a civil penalty under section 308 of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<ref>16 U.S.C. 1858</ref>) and the operator has not paid the penalty;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> found guilty of an offense under section 309 of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<ref>16 U.S.C. 1859</ref>) and not paid the assessed fine or served the assessed sentence;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> held liable for a civil or criminal penalty under section 105 of the Marine Mammal Protection Act of 1972 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 1375</ref>) and not paid the assessed fine or served the assessed sentence; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> held liable for a civil penalty by the Coast Guard under this title or title 33 and not paid the assessed fine.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Waivers Concerning Financial Condition</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary or Administrator shall prescribe regulations concerning circumstances under which waivers of, or exceptions to, otherwise applicable regulatory requirements concerning financial condition can be made. The regulations shall require that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the economic soundness requirements in <ref>section 53708(a) of this title</ref> are met after the waiver of the financial condition requirement; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> if the Secretary or Administrator considers necessary, the waiver shall provide for the imposition of other requirements on the obligor designed to compensate for any significant increase in risk associated with the obligor’s failure to meet regulatory requirements applicable to financial condition.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 8(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1607</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. C, title XXXV, § 3507(a)(1)(D)</ref>, (b)(3)(B), (C), (c)(1), <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3555</ref>, 3556; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. C, title XXXV, § 3522(a)(3)</ref>, (b), <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 597</ref>, 598.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 53708.</num>
<heading> Findings related to economic soundness</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">By Administrator</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Administrator may not guarantee or make a commitment to guarantee an obligation under this chapter unless the Administrator finds that the property or project for which the obligation will be executed will be economically sound. In making that finding, the Administrator shall consider—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the need in the particular segment of the maritime industry for new or additional capacity, including any impact on existing equipment for which a guarantee under this chapter is in effect;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the market potential for employment of the vessel over the life of the guarantee;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> projected revenues and expenses associated with employment of the vessel;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> any charter, contract of affreightment, transportation agreement, or similar agreement or undertaking relevant to the employment of the vessel;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> other relevant criteria; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> for inland waterways, the need for technical improvements, including increased fuel efficiency or improved safety.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">By Secretary</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary may not guarantee or make a commitment to guarantee an obligation under this chapter unless the Secretary finds, at or prior to the time the commitment is made or the guarantee becomes effective, that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the property or project for which the obligation will be executed will be economically sound; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> for a fishing vessel, the purpose of the financing or refinancing is consistent with—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the wise use of the fisheries resources and the development, advancement, management, conservation, and protection of the fisheries resources; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the need for technical improvements, including increased fuel efficiency or improved safety.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Used Fishing Vessels and Facilities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary may not guarantee or make a commitment to guarantee an obligation under this chapter for the purchase of a used fishing vessel or used fishery facility unless the vessel or facility will be—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> reconstructed or reconditioned in the United States and will contribute to the development of the United States fishing industry; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> used—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the harvesting of fish from an underused fishery; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for a purpose described in the definition of “fishery facility” in <ref>section 53701 of this title</ref> with respect to an underused fishery.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Independent Analysis</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary or Administrator may make a determination that aspects of an application under this chapter require independent analysis to be conducted by third party experts due to risk factors associated with markets, technology, or financial structures. A third party independent analysis conducted under this subsection shall be performed by a private sector expert in assessing such risk factors who is selected by the Secretary or Administrator.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Additional Equity Because of Increased Risks</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, the Secretary or Administrator may make a determination that an application under this title requires additional equity because of increased risk factors associated with markets, technology, or financial structures.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 8(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1608</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. C, title XXXV, § 3507(a)(1)(D)</ref>, (2)(D), (b)(3)(A), (4), <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3555</ref>, 3556; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. C, title XXXV, § 3522(a)(4)</ref>, (b), <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 597</ref>, 598.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 53709.</num>
<heading> Amount of obligations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The principal of an obligation may not be guaranteed in an amount greater than the amount determined by multiplying the percentage applicable under subsection (b) by—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the amount paid by or for the account of the obligor (as determined by the Secretary or Administrator, which determination shall be conclusive) for the construction, reconstruction, or reconditioning of the vessel used as security for the guarantee; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> if the obligor creates an escrow fund under <ref>section 53715 of this title</ref>, the actual cost of the vessel.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitations on Amount Borrowed</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as otherwise provided, the principal amount of an obligation guaranteed under this chapter may not exceed 75 percent of the actual cost or depreciated actual cost, as determined by the Secretary or Administrator, of the vessel used as security for the guarantee.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Certain approved vessels</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The principal amount may not exceed 87.5 percent of the actual cost or depreciated actual cost if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the size and speed of the vessel are approved by the Secretary or Administrator;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the vessel is or would have been eligible for mortgage aid for construction under section 509 of the Merchant Marine Act, 1936, or would have been eligible except that the vessel was built with a construction-differential subsidy and the subsidy has been repaid; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the vessel is of a type described in that section for which the minimum down payment required by that section is 12.5 percent of the cost of the vessel.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Fishing vessels and fishery facilities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For a fishing vessel or fishery facility, the principal amount may not exceed 80 percent of the actual cost or depreciated actual cost. However, debt for the vessel or facility may not be placed through the Federal Financing Bank.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">OTEC</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For an ocean thermal energy conversion facility or plantship constructed without a construction-differential subsidy, the principal amount may not exceed 87.5 percent of the actual cost or depreciated actual cost of the facility or plantship.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Security Involving Multiple Vessels</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The principal amount of an obligation having more than one vessel as security for the guarantee may not exceed the sum of the principal amounts allowable for all the vessels.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition on Uniform Percentage Limitations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary or Administrator may not establish a percentage under any provision of subsection (b) that is to be applied uniformly to all guarantees or commitments to guarantee made under that provision.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition on Minimum Principal Amount</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may not establish, as a condition of eligibility for a guarantee under this chapter, a minimum principal amount for an obligation covering the reconstruction or reconditioning of a fishing vessel or fishery facility. For purposes of this chapter, the reconstruction or reconditioning of a fishing vessel or fishery facility does not include the routine minor repair or maintenance of the vessel or facility.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 8(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1609</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. C, title XXXV, § 3507(a)(1)(C)</ref>, (D), <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3555</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. C, title XXXV, § 3522(a)(10)(B)</ref>, (b), <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 598</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. C, title XXXV, § 3506(f)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1972</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 53710.</num>
<heading> Contents of obligations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An obligation guaranteed under this chapter must—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provide for payments by the obligor satisfactory to the Secretary or Administrator;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provide for interest (exclusive of guarantee fees and other fees) at a rate not more than the annual rate on the unpaid principal that the Secretary or Administrator determines is reasonable, considering the range of interest rates prevailing in the private market for similar loans and the risks assumed by the Secretary or Administrator;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> have a maturity date satisfactory to the Secretary or Administrator, but—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> not more than 25 years after the date of delivery of the vessel used as security for the guarantee; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> if the vessel has been reconstructed or reconditioned, not more than the later of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> 25 years after the date of delivery of the vessel; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the remaining years of useful life of the vessel as determined by the Secretary or Administrator; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> provide, or a related agreement must provide, that if the vessel used as security for the guarantee is a delivered vessel, the vessel shall be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in class A–1, American Bureau of Shipping, or meet other standards acceptable to the Secretary or Administrator, with all required certificates, including marine inspection certificates of the Coast Guard, and with all outstanding requirements and recommendations necessary for class retention accomplished, unless the Secretary or Administrator permits a deferment of repairs necessary to meet these requirements;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> well equipped, in good repair, and in every respect seaworthy and fit for service; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> documented under the laws of the United States for the term of the guarantee of the obligation or until the obligation is paid in full, whichever is sooner.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Provisions for Certain Passenger Vessels</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>With the Administrator’s approval, if the vessel used as security for the guarantee is a passenger vessel having the tonnage, speed, passenger accommodations, and other characteristics described in section 503 of the Merchant Marine Act, 1936, an obligation guaranteed under this chapter or a related agreement may provide that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the only recourse by the United States Government against the obligor for payments under the guarantee will be repossession of the vessel and assignment of insurance claims; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the obligor’s liability for payments under the guarantee will be satisfied and discharged by the surrender of the vessel and all interest in the vessel to the Government in the condition described in paragraph (2).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Surrender of vessel</inline>.—</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>On surrender, the vessel must be—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> free and clear of all liens and encumbrances except the security interest conveyed to the Administrator under this chapter;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in class; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> in as good order and condition (ordinary wear and tear excepted) as when acquired by the obligor.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covering deficiencies by insurance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>To the extent covered by insurance, a deficiency related to a requirement in subparagraph (A) may be satisfied by assignment of the obligor’s insurance claims to the Government.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Other Provisions To Protect Security Interests and Provide for the Financial Stability of the Obligor</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An obligation guaranteed under this chapter and any related agreement must contain other provisions, which shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provisions for the protection of the security interests of the Government (including acceleration, assumption, and subrogation provisions and the issuance of notes by the obligor to the Secretary or Administrator), liens and releases of liens, payment of taxes; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any other provisions that the Secretary or Administrator may prescribe.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 8(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1610</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. C, title XXXV, § 3507(a)(1)(D)</ref>, (2)(C), <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3555</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. C, title XXXV, § 3522(a)(5)</ref>, (9)(A), (10)(B), (b), <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 598</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. C, title XXXV, § 3506(g)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1972</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 53711.</num>
<heading> Security interest</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary or Administrator may guarantee an obligation under this chapter only if the obligor conveys or agrees to convey to the Secretary or Administrator a security interest the Secretary or Administrator considers necessary to protect the interest of the United States Government.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Multiple Vessels and Types of Security</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The security interest may relate to more than one vessel and may consist of more than one type of security. If the security interest relates to more than one vessel, the obligation may have the latest maturity date allowable under <ref>section 53710(a)(3) of this title</ref> for any of the vessels used as security for the guarantee. However, the Secretary or Administrator may require such payments of principal prior to maturity, with respect to all related obligations, as the Secretary or Administrator considers necessary to maintain adequate security for the guarantee.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 8(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1612</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. C, title XXXV, § 3507(a)(1)(C)</ref>, (D), <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3555</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. C, title XXXV, § 3522(a)(10)(B)</ref>, (b), <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 598</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 53712.</num>
<heading> Monitoring financial condition and operations of obligor</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary or Administrator shall monitor the financial condition and operations of the obligor on a regular basis during the term of the guarantee. The Secretary or Administrator shall document the results of the monitoring on an annual or quarterly basis depending on the condition of the obligor. If the Secretary or Administrator determines that the financial condition of the obligor warrants additional protections to the Secretary or Administrator, the Secretary or Administrator shall take appropriate action under subsection (b). If the Secretary or Administrator determines that the financial condition of the obligor jeopardizes its continued ability to perform its responsibilities in connection with the guarantee of an obligation by the Secretary or Administrator, the Secretary or Administrator shall make an immediate determination whether default should take place and whether further measures described in subsection (b) should be taken to protect the interests of the Secretary or Administrator while ensuring that program objectives are met.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contract Provisions To Protect Secretary or Administrator</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary or Administrator shall include provisions in a loan agreement with an obligor that provides additional authority to the Secretary or Administrator to take action to limit potential losses in connection with a defaulted loan or a loan that is in jeopardy due to the deteriorating financial condition of the obligor. If the Secretary or Administrator has waived a requirement under <ref>section 53707(d) of this title</ref>, the loan agreement shall include requirements for additional payments, collateral, or equity contributions to meet the waived requirement upon the occurrence of verifiable conditions indicating that the obligor’s financial condition enables the obligor to meet the waived requirement.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 8(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1612</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. C, title XXXV, § 3507(a)(1)(D)</ref>, (b)(6), <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3555</ref>, 3556; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. C, title XXXV, § 3522(a)(6)</ref>, (10)(B), (b), <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 598</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 53713.</num>
<heading> Administrative fees</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary or Administrator shall charge and collect from the obligor fees the Secretary or Administrator considers reasonable for processing the application and monitoring the loan guarantee, including for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> investigating an application for a guarantee;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> appraising property offered as security for a guarantee;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> issuing a commitment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> providing services related to an escrow fund under <ref>section 53715 of this title</ref> or a deposit fund under <ref>section 53716 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> inspecting property during construction, reconstruction, or reconditioning; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> monitoring and providing services related to the obligor’s compliance with any terms related to the obligations, the guarantee, or maintenance of the Secretary or Administrator’s security interests under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Total Fee Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The total fees under subsection (a) may not exceed 0.5 percent of the original principal amount of the obligations to be guaranteed.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Fees for Independent Analysis.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary or Administrator may charge and collect fees to cover the costs of independent analysis under <ref>section 53703(c) of this title</ref>. Notwithstanding <ref>section 3302 of title 31</ref>, any fee collected under this subsection shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> be credited as an offsetting collection to the account that finances the administration of the loan guarantee program;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> be available for expenditure only to pay the costs of activities and services for which the fee is imposed; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> remain available until expended.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Fee limitation inapplicable</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Fees collected under this subsection are not subject to the limitation of subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 8(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1612</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. C, title XXXV, § 3507(a)(1)(D)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3555</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. C, title XXXV, § 3522(a)(10)(B)</ref>, (b), <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 598</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. C, title XXXV, § 3506(h)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1973</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 53714.</num>
<heading> Guarantee fees</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to this section, the Secretary or Administrator shall prescribe regulations to assess a fee for guaranteeing an obligation under this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Computation of Fee</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The amount of the fee for a guarantee under this chapter shall be equal to the sum of the amounts determined under paragraph (2) for the years in which the guarantee is in effect.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Present value for each year</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The amount referred to in paragraph (1) for a year in which the guarantee is in effect is the present value of the amount calculated under paragraph (3). To determine the present value, the Secretary or Administrator shall apply a discount rate determined by the Secretary of the Treasury, considering current market yields on outstanding obligations of the United States Government having periods to maturity comparable to the period to maturity for the guaranteed obligation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Calculation of amount</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The amount referred to in paragraph (2) shall be calculated by multiplying—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the estimated average unpaid principal amount of the obligation that will be outstanding during the year (excluding the average amount, other than interest, on deposit during the year in an escrow fund under <ref>section 53715 of this title</ref>); by</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the fee rate set under paragraph (4).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Setting fee rates</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>To set the fee rate referred to in paragraph (3)(B), the Secretary or Administrator shall establish a formula that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> takes into account the security provided for the guaranteed obligation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> is a sliding scale based on the creditworthiness of the obligor, using—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the lowest allowable rate under paragraph (5) for the most creditworthy obligors; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the highest allowable rate under paragraph (5) for the least creditworthy obligors.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Permissible range of rates</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The fee rate set under paragraph (4) shall be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> for a delivered vessel or equipment, at least 0.5 percent and not more than 1 percent; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for a vessel to be constructed, reconstructed, or reconditioned or equipment to be delivered, at least 0.25 percent and not more than 0.5 percent.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">When Fee Collected</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A fee for the guarantee of an obligation under this chapter shall be collected not later than the date on which an amount is first paid on the obligation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Financing the Fee</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A fee paid under this section is eligible to be financed under this chapter and shall be included in the actual cost of the obligation guaranteed.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Not Refundable</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A fee paid under this section is not refundable. However, an obligor shall receive credit for the amount paid for the remaining term of the obligation if the obligation is refinanced and guaranteed under this chapter after the refinancing.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 8(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1613</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. C, title XXXV, § 3507(a)(1)(D)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3555</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. C, title XXXV, § 3522(a)(10)(B)</ref>, (b), <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 598</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 53715.</num>
<heading> Escrow fund</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>If the proceeds of an obligation guaranteed under this chapter are to be used to finance the construction, reconstruction, or reconditioning of a vessel that will serve as security for a guarantee under this chapter, the Secretary or Administrator may accept and hold in escrow, under an escrow agreement with the obligor, a portion of the proceeds of all obligations guaranteed under this chapter whose proceeds are to be so used which is equal to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the excess of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the principal amount of all obligations whose proceeds are to be so used; over</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> 75 percent or 87.5 percent, whichever is applicable under <ref>section 53709(b) of this title</ref>, of the amount paid by or for the account of the obligor for the construction, reconstruction, or reconditioning of the vessel; plus</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any interest the Secretary or Administrator may require on the amount described in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Security Involving Both Uncompleted and Delivered Vessels</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the security for the guarantee of an obligation relates both to a vessel to be constructed, reconstructed, or reconditioned and to a delivered vessel, the principal amount of the obligation shall be prorated for purposes of subsection (a) under regulations prescribed by the Secretary or Administrator.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Disbursement Before Termination of Agreement</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Purposes</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary or Administrator shall disburse amounts in the escrow fund, as specified in the escrow agreement, to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> pay amounts the obligor is obligated to pay for—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the construction, reconstruction, or reconditioning of a vessel used as security for the guarantee; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> interest on the obligations;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> redeem the obligations under a refinancing guaranteed under this chapter; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> pay any excess interest deposits to the obligor at times provided for in the escrow agreement.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Manner of payment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If a payment becomes due under the guarantee before the termination of the escrow agreement, the amount in the escrow fund at the time the payment becomes due, including realized income not yet paid to the obligor, shall be paid into the appropriate account under <ref>section 53717 of this title</ref>. The amount shall be credited against amounts due or to become due from the obligor to the Secretary or Administrator on the guaranteed obligations or, to the extent not so required, be paid to the obligor.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Payments Required Before Disbursement</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No disbursement shall be made under subsection (c) to any person until the total amount paid by or for the account of the obligor from sources other than the proceeds of the obligation equals at least 25 percent or 12.5 percent, whichever is applicable under <ref>section 53709(b) of this title</ref>, of the aggregate actual cost of the vessel, as previously approved by the Secretary or Administrator. If the aggregate actual cost of the vessel has increased since the Secretary’s or Administrator’s initial approval or if it increases after the first disbursement is permitted under this subsection, then no further disbursements shall be made under subsection (c) until the total amount paid by or for the account of the obligor from sources other than the proceeds of the obligation equals at least 25 percent or 12.5 percent, as applicable, of the increase, as determined by the Secretary or Administrator, in the aggregate actual cost of the vessel. This paragraph does not require the Secretary or Administrator to consent to finance any increase in actual cost unless the Secretary or Administrator determines that such an increase in the obligation meets all the terms and conditions of this chapter or other applicable law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Documented proof of progress requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary or Administrator shall, by regulation, establish a transparent, independent, and risk-based process for verifying and documenting the progress of projects under construction before disbursing guaranteed loan funds. At a minimum, the process shall require documented proof of progress in connection with the construction, reconstruction, or reconditioning of a vessel or vessels before disbursements are made from the escrow fund. The Secretary or Administrator may require that the obligor provide a certificate from an independent party certifying that the requisite progress in construction, reconstruction, or reconditioning has taken place.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Disbursement on Termination of Agreement</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>If a payment has not become due under the guarantee before the termination of the escrow agreement, the balance of the escrow fund at the time of termination shall be disbursed to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> prepay the excess of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the principal amount of all obligations whose proceeds are to be used to finance the construction, reconstruction, or reconditioning of the vessel used or to be used as security for the guarantee; over</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> 75 percent or 87.5 percent, whichever is applicable under <ref>section 53709(b) of this title</ref>, of the actual cost of the vessel to the extent paid; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> pay interest on that prepaid amount of principal.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Remaining balance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any remaining balance of the escrow fund shall be paid to the obligor.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Investment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary or Administrator may invest and reinvest any part of an escrow fund in obligations of the United States Government with maturities such that the escrow fund will be available as required for purposes of the escrow agreement. Investment income shall be paid to the obligor when received.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Terms To Protect Government</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The escrow agreement shall contain other terms the Secretary or Administrator considers necessary to protect fully the interests of the Government.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 8(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1614</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. C, title XXXV, § 3507(a)(1)(H)</ref>, (3), <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3555</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. C, title XXXV, § 3522(a)(10)(B)</ref>, (11), (b), <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 598</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 53716.</num>
<heading> Deposit fund</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is a deposit fund in the Treasury for purposes of this section. The Secretary or Administrator, in accordance with an agreement under subsection (b), may deposit into and hold in the fund cash belonging to an obligor to serve as collateral for a guarantee made under this chapter with respect to the obligor.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Agreement</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary or Administrator and an obligor shall make a reserve fund or other collateral account agreement to govern the deposit, withdrawal, retention, use, and reinvestment of cash of the obligor held in the fund. The agreement shall contain—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> terms and conditions required by this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> terms that grant to the United States Government a security interest in all amounts deposited into the fund; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> any additional terms considered by the Secretary or Administrator to be necessary to protect fully the interests of the Government.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Investment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary or Administrator may invest and reinvest any part of the amounts in the fund in obligations of the Government with maturities such that amounts in the fund will be available as required for purposes of the agreement under subsection (b). Cash balances in the fund in excess of current requirements shall be maintained in a form of uninvested funds, and the Secretary of the Treasury shall pay interest on these funds.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Withdrawals</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Cash deposited into the fund may not be withdrawn without the consent of the Secretary or Administrator.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of income</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to paragraph (3), the Secretary or Administrator may pay any income earned on cash of an obligor deposited into the fund in accordance with the agreement with the obligor under subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Retention against default</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary or Administrator may retain and offset any or all of the cash of an obligor in the fund, and any income realized thereon, as part of the Secretary’s or Administrator’s recovery against the obligor in case of a default by the obligor on an obligation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 8(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1616</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. C, title XXXV, § 3507(a)(1)(H)</ref>, (3), <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3555</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. C, title XXXV, § 3522(a)(10)(B)</ref>, (11), (b), <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 598</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 53717.</num>
<heading> Management of funds in the Treasury</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “FCRA” means the Federal Credit Reform Act of 1990 (<ref>2 U.S.C. 661</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Loan Guarantees by Administrator</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">When not subject to fcra</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall account for payments and disbursements involving obligations guaranteed under this chapter and not subject to FCRA in an account in the Treasury entitled the Federal Ship Financing Fund Liquidating Account (a liquidating account as defined in FCRA).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">When subject to fcra</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall account for payments and disbursements involving obligations guaranteed under this chapter and subject to FCRA in a separate account in the Treasury entitled the Federal Ship Financing Guaranteed Loan Financing Account (a financing account as defined in FCRA).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Loan Guarantees by Secretary</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">When not subject to fcra</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall account for payments and disbursements involving obligations guaranteed under this chapter and not subject to FCRA in a separate account in the Treasury established for this purpose.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">When subject to fcra</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall account for payments and disbursements involving obligations guaranteed under this chapter and subject to FCRA in a separate account in the Treasury established for this purpose.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Direct Loans by Secretary</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall account for payments and disbursements involving direct loans made under this chapter in a separate account in the Treasury established for this purpose.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 8(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1616</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. C, title XXXV, § 3507(a)(1)(B)</ref>, (D), (c)(2), <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3555</ref>, 3556; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. C, title XXXV, § 3522(a)(7)</ref>, (9)(B), (b), <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 598</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 53718.</num>
<heading> Annual report to Congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Administrator shall report to Congress annually on the loan guarantee program under this chapter. Each report shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the size, in dollars, of the portfolio of loans guaranteed;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the size, in dollars, of projects in the portfolio facing financial difficulties;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the number and type of projects covered;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> a profile of pending loan applications;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the amount of appropriations available for new guarantees;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> a profile of each project approved since the last report; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> a profile of any defaults since the last report.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 8(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1617</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. C, title XXXV, § 3507(c)(3)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3556</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. C, title XXXV, § 3522(a)(9)(C)</ref>, (b), <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 598</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 53719.</num>
<heading> Best practices</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary or Administrator shall ensure that all standard documents and agreements that relate to loan guarantees made pursuant to this chapter are reviewed and updated every four years to ensure that such documents and agreements meet the current commercial best practices to the extent permitted by law.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. C, title XXXV, § 3506(i)(1)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1973</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>DEFAULT PROVISIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 53721.</num>
<heading> Rights of obligee</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Demands by Obligees</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Except as provided in subsection (c), if an obligor has continued in default for 30 days in the payment of principal or interest on an obligation guaranteed under this chapter, the obligee or the obligee’s agent may demand that the Secretary or Administrator pay the unpaid principal amount of the obligation and the unpaid interest on the obligation to the date of payment. The demand must be made within the earlier of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a period that may be specified in the guarantee or a related agreement; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> 90 days from the date of the default.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Payments by Secretary or Administrator</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>If a demand is made under subsection (a), the Secretary or Administrator shall pay to the obligee or the obligee’s agent the unpaid principal amount of the obligation and the unpaid interest on the obligation to the date of payment. Payment shall be made within the earlier of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a period that may be specified in the guarantee or a related agreement; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> 30 days from the date of the demand.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">If no existing default</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary or Administrator is not required to make payment under this subsection if, within the appropriate period under paragraph (1), the Secretary or Administrator finds that the obligor was not in default or that the default was remedied before the demand.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Assumption of Rights and Obligations Before Demand</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An obligee or the obligee’s agent may not demand payment under this section if the Secretary or Administrator, before the demand and on terms that may be provided in the obligation or a related agreement, has assumed the obligor’s rights and duties under the obligation and any related agreement and made any payment in default. However, the guarantee of the obligation remains in effect after the Secretary’s or Administrator’s assumption.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 8(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1617</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. C, title XXXV, § 3507(a)(1)(C)</ref>, (F), <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3555</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. C, title XXXV, § 3522(a)(10)(B)</ref>, (11), (b), <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 598</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 53722.</num>
<heading> Actions by Secretary or Administrator</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>On default under an obligation or related agreement between the Secretary or Administrator and the obligor, the Secretary or Administrator, on terms that may be provided in the obligation or agreement, may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> assume the obligor’s rights and duties under the obligation or agreement, make any payment in default, and notify the obligee or the obligee’s agent of the default and the Secretary’s or Administrator’s assumption; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> notify the obligee or the obligee’s agent of the default.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Demands by Obligees</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Demand</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>If the Secretary or Administrator proceeds under subsection (a)(2), the obligee or the obligee’s agent may demand that the Secretary or Administrator pay the unpaid principal amount of the obligation and the unpaid interest on the obligation. The demand must be made within the earlier of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a period that may be specified in the guarantee or a related agreement; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> 60 days from the date of the Secretary’s or Administrator’s notice.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Payment</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>If a demand is made under paragraph (1), the Secretary or Administrator shall pay to the obligee or the obligee’s agent the unpaid principal amount of the obligation and the unpaid interest on the obligation to the date of payment. Payment shall be made within the earlier of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a period that may be specified in the guarantee or a related agreement; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> 30 days from the date of the demand.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Continued Effect of Guarantee</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A guarantee of an obligation remains in effect after an assumption of the obligation by the Secretary or Administrator.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Additional Responses</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>If there is a default on an obligation, the Secretary or Administrator shall conduct operations under this chapter in a manner that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> maximizes the net present value return from the sale or disposition of assets associated with the obligation, including prompt referral to the Attorney General for collection as appropriate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> minimizes the amount of any loss realized in the resolution of the guarantee;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> ensures adequate competition and fair and consistent treatment of offerors; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> requires appraisal of assets by an independent appraiser.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 8(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1618</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. C, title XXXV, § 3507(a)(1)(C)</ref>, (F), <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3555</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. C, title XXXV, § 3522(a)(10)(B)</ref>, (11), (b), <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 598</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 53723.</num>
<heading> Payments by Secretary or Administrator and issuance of obligations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Cash Payment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Amounts required to be paid by the Secretary or Administrator under section 53721 or 53722 of this title shall be paid in cash.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Issuance of Obligations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If amounts in the appropriate account under <ref>section 53717 of this title</ref> are not sufficient to make a payment required under section 53721 or 53722 of this title, the Secretary or Administrator may issue obligations to the Secretary of the Treasury. The Secretary or Administrator, with the approval of the Secretary of the Treasury, shall prescribe the form, denomination, maturity, and other terms (except the interest rate) of the obligations. The Secretary of the Treasury shall set the interest rate for the obligations, considering the current average market yield on outstanding marketable obligations of the United States Government of comparable maturities during the month before the obligations are issued.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Purchase of Obligations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the Treasury shall purchase the obligations issued under this section. To purchase the obligations, the Secretary of the Treasury may use as a public debt transaction the proceeds from the sale of securities issued under chapter 31 of title 31. The purposes for which securities may be issued under that chapter are extended to include the purchase of obligations under this subsection. The Secretary of the Treasury may sell obligations purchased under this section. A redemption, purchase, or sale of the obligations by the Secretary of the Treasury is a public debt transaction of the Government.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Deposits and Redemptions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary or Administrator shall deposit amounts borrowed under this section in the appropriate account under <ref>section 53717 of this title</ref> and make redemptions of the obligations from that account.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 8(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1618</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. C, title XXXV, § 3507(a)(1)(G)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3555</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. C, title XXXV, § 3522(a)(10)(B)</ref>, (b), <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 598</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 53724.</num>
<heading> Rights to secured property</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Acquisition of Security Rights</inline>.—</heading>
<content>When the Secretary or Administrator makes a payment on, or assumes, an obligation under section 53721 or 53722 of this title, the Secretary or Administrator acquires the rights under the security agreement with the obligor in the security held by the Secretary or Administrator to guarantee the obligation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use and Disposition of Secured Property</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding any other law relating to the acquisition, handling, or disposal of property by the United States Government, the Secretary or Administrator has the right, in the Secretary’s or Administrator’s discretion, to complete, reconstruct, recondition, renovate, repair, maintain, operate, charter, or sell any property acquired under a security agreement with an obligor, or to place a vessel so acquired in the National Defense Reserve Fleet. The terms of a sale under this subsection shall be as approved by the Secretary or Administrator.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 8(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1619</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. C, title XXXV, § 3507(a)(1)(F)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3555</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. C, title XXXV, § 3522(a)(10)(B)</ref>, (11), (b), <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 598</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 53725.</num>
<heading> Actions against obligor</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For a default under a guaranteed obligation or related agreement, the Secretary or Administrator may take any action against the obligor or another liable party that the Secretary or Administrator considers necessary to protect the interests of the United States Government. A civil action may be brought in the name of the United States or the obligee. The obligee shall make available to the Government all records and evidence necessary to prosecute the action.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Title, Possession, and Purchase</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary or Administrator may—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> accept a conveyance of title to and possession of property from the obligor or another party liable to the Secretary or Administrator; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> purchase the property for an amount not greater than the unpaid principal amount of the obligation and interest thereon.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Payment of excess</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If, through the sale of property, the Secretary or Administrator receives an amount of cash greater than the unpaid principal amount of the obligation, the unpaid interest on the obligation, and the expenses of collecting those amounts, the Secretary or Administrator shall pay the excess to the obligor.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 8(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1619</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. C, title XXXV, § 3507(a)(1)(F)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3555</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. C, title XXXV, § 3522(a)(10)(B)</ref>, (b), <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 598</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>PARTICULAR PROJECTS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 53731.</num>
<heading> Commercial demonstration ocean thermal energy conversion facilities and plantships</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Under subchapter I of this chapter, the Administrator may guarantee or make a commitment to guarantee the payment of the principal of and interest on an obligation that aids in financing (including reimbursement of an obligor for expenditures previously made for) the construction, reconstruction, or reconditioning of a commercial demonstration ocean thermal energy conversion facility or plantship. This section may be used to guarantee obligations for a total of not more than 5 separate facilities and plantships or a demonstrated 400 megawatt capacity, whichever comes first.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Applicability of Other Provisions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as otherwise provided in this section, a guarantee or commitment to guarantee under this section is subject to all the provisions applicable to a guarantee or commitment to guarantee under subchapter I of this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Economic Soundness</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The required determination of economic soundness under <ref>section 53708 of this title</ref> applies to a guarantee or commitment to guarantee for that portion of a facility or plantship not to be supported with appropriated Federal funds.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reasonableness of Risk</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A guarantee or commitment to guarantee may not be made under this section unless the Secretary of Energy, in consultation with the Administrator, certifies to the Administrator that, for the facility or plantship for which the guarantee or commitment to guarantee is sought, there is sufficient guarantee of performance and payment to lower the risk to the United States Government to a reasonable level. In deciding whether to issue such a certification, the Secretary of Energy shall consider—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the successful demonstration of the technology to be used in the facility at a scale sufficient to establish the likelihood of technical and economic viability in the proposed market; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the need of the United States to develop new and renewable sources of energy and the benefits to be realized from the construction and successful operation of the facility or plantship.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Amount of Obligation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The total principal amount of an obligation guaranteed under this section may not exceed 87.5 percent of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the actual cost or depreciated actual cost of the facility or plantship; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> if the facility or plantship is supported with appropriated Federal funds, the total principal amount of that portion of the actual cost or depreciated actual cost for which the obligor is obligated to secure financing under the agreement between the obligor and the Department of Energy or other Federal agency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">OTEC Demonstration Fund</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is a special subaccount, known as the OTEC Demonstration Fund, in the account established under <ref>section 53717(b)(1) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use and operation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The OTEC Demonstration Fund shall be used for obligation guarantees authorized under this section that do not qualify under subchapter I of this chapter. Except as otherwise provided in this section, the OTEC Demonstration Fund shall be operated in the same manner as the parent account. However—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> amounts received by the Administrator under subchapter I of this chapter related to guarantees or commitments to guarantee made under this section shall be deposited only in the OTEC Demonstration Fund; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> when obligations issued by the Administrator under <ref>section 53723 of this title</ref> related to the OTEC Demonstration Fund are outstanding, any amount received by the Administrator under subchapter I of this chapter related to ocean thermal energy conversion facilities or plantships shall be deposited in the OTEC Demonstration Fund.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transfers</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Assets in the OTEC Demonstration Fund may be transferred to the parent account when and to the extent the balance in the OTEC Demonstration Fund exceeds the total guarantees or commitments to guarantee made under this section then outstanding, plus obligations issued by the Administrator under <ref>section 53723 of this title</ref> related to the OTEC Demonstration Fund.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Liability</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The parent account is not liable for a guarantee or commitment to guarantee made under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Maximum unpaid principal amount</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The total unpaid principal amount of the obligations guaranteed with the backing of the OTEC Demonstration Fund and outstanding at any one time may not exceed $1,650,000,000.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Issuance and Payment of Obligations</inline>.—</heading>
<content><ref>Section 53723 of this title</ref> applies to the OTEC Demonstration Fund. However, obligations issued by the Administrator under that section related to the OTEC Demonstration Fund shall be payable only from proceeds realized by the OTEC Demonstration Fund.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Taxation of Interest</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Interest on an obligation guaranteed under this section shall be included in gross income under chapter 1 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (26 U.S.C. ch. 1).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 8(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1620</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. C, title XXXV, § 3507(a)(2)(H)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3555</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. C, title XXXV, § 3522(a)(9)(D)</ref>, (b), <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 598</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 53732.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. C, title XXXV, § 3506(i)(2)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1974</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 53733.</num>
<heading> Shipyard modernization and improvement</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Advanced shipbuilding technology</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “advanced shipbuilding technology” includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> numerically controlled machine tools, robots, automated process control equipment, computerized flexible manufacturing systems, associated computer software, and other technology for improving shipbuilding and related industrial production that advance the state-of-the-art; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> novel techniques and processes designed to improve shipbuilding quality, productivity, and practice, and to promote sustainable development, including engineering design, quality assurance, concurrent engineering, continuous process production technology, energy efficiency, waste minimization, design for recyclability or parts reuse, inventory management, upgraded worker skills, and communications with customers and suppliers.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General shipyard facility</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “general shipyard facility” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> for operations on land—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a structure or appurtenance thereto designed for the construction, reconstruction, repair, rehabilitation, or refurbishment of a vessel, including a graving dock, building way, ship lift, wharf, or pier crane;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the land necessary for the structure or appurtenance; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> equipment that is for use with the structure or appurtenance and that is necessary for performing a function referred to in clause (i); and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for operations not on land, a vessel, floating drydock, or barge built in the United States and used for, equipped to be used for, or of a type normally used for, performing a function referred to in subparagraph (A)(i).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Modern shipbuilding technology</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “modern shipbuilding technology” means the best available proven technology, techniques, and processes appropriate to enhancing the productivity of shipyards.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Under subchapter I of this chapter, the Administrator may guarantee or make a commitment to guarantee the payment of the principal of and interest on an obligation for advanced shipbuilding technology and modern shipbuilding technology of a general shipyard facility in the United States. Only a private shipyard is eligible to receive a guarantee.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Applicability of Other Provisions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as otherwise provided in this section, a guarantee or commitment to guarantee under this section is subject to all the provisions applicable to a guarantee or commitment to guarantee under subchapter I of this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Amount of Obligation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The principal amount of an obligation guaranteed under this chapter may not exceed 87.5 percent of the actual cost of the advanced shipbuilding technology or modern shipbuilding technology.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transfer of Amounts</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator may accept the transfer of amounts from a department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States Government and may use those amounts to cover the cost (as defined in section 502 of the Federal Credit Reform Act of 1990 (<ref>2 U.S.C. 661a</ref>)) of making guarantees or commitments to guarantee under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Buy America</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Part I of subtitle A of title IX of division G of the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act (<ref>Public Law 117–58</ref>; <ref>41 U.S.C. 8301</ref> note) shall apply to any funds obligated by the Administrator under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 8(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1623</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. C, title XXXV, § 3507(a)(2)(K)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3555</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. C, title XXXV, § 3522(a)(9)(F)</ref>, (b), <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 598</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. C, title XXXV, § 3536</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2315</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 53734.</num>
<heading> Replacement of vessels because of changes in operating standards</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, the Secretary or Administrator, on terms the Secretary or Administrator may prescribe, may guarantee or make a commitment to guarantee the payment of the principal of and interest on an obligation that aids in financing or refinancing (including reimbursement of an obligor for expenditures previously made for) a contract for the construction or reconstruction of a vessel if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the vessel is designed and to be used for commercial use in coastwise, intercoastal, or foreign trade;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the construction or reconstruction is necessary to replace a vessel that cannot continue to be operated because of a change required by law in the standards for the operation of vessels, and the applicant for the guarantee or commitment would not otherwise legally be able to continue operating vessels in the trades in which the applicant operated vessels before the change;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the applicant is presently engaged in transporting cargoes in vessels of the type and class that will be constructed or reconstructed under this section and agrees to employ vessels constructed or reconstructed under this section as replacements only for vessels made obsolete by the change in operating standards;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the capacity of the vessels to be constructed or reconstructed under this section will not increase the cargo carrying capacity of the vessels being replaced;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the Secretary or Administrator has not determined that the market demand for the vessel over its useful life will diminish so as to make granting the guarantee fiduciarily imprudent;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the vessel, if to be reconstructed, will have a useful life of at least 15 years after the reconstruction; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the Secretary or Administrator has considered the criteria specified in section 53708(a)(3)–(5) of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Term and Amount of Obligation</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Term</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term of an obligation guaranteed under this section may not exceed 25 years.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Amount</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The amount of an obligation guaranteed under this section may not exceed 87.5 percent of the actual cost or depreciated actual cost to the applicant for the construction or reconstruction of the vessel. The Secretary or Administrator may not establish a percentage under this paragraph that is to be applied uniformly to all guarantees or commitments to guarantee made under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Applicability of Other Provisions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A guarantee or commitment to guarantee under this section is also subject to sections 53701, 53702(a), 53704, 53705, 53707(a), 53708(d) and (e), 53709(a), 53710(a)(1), (2), and (4) and (c), 53711(a), 53713, 53714, 53717, and 53721–53725 of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Security Against Default</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary or Administrator shall require by regulation that an applicant under this section provide adequate security against default.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Guarantee Fees</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary or Administrator may establish a fee for the guarantee of an obligation under this section that is in addition to the fee established under <ref>section 53714 of this title</ref>. The fee may be—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an annual fee of not more than an additional 1 percent added to the fee established under <ref>section 53714 of this title</ref>; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a fee based on the amount of the obligation versus the percentage of the obligor’s fleet being replaced by vessels constructed or reconstructed under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 8(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1624</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. C, title XXXV, § 3507(a)(1)(E)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3555</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. C, title XXXV, § 3522(a)(10)(B)</ref>, (b), <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 598</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 53735.</num>
<heading> Fisheries financing and capacity reduction</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “program” means a fishing capacity reduction program established under section 312 of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<ref>16 U.S.C. 1861a</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Guarantee Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may guarantee the repayment of debt obligations issued by entities under this section. Debt obligations to be guaranteed may be issued by any entity that has been approved by the Secretary and has agreed with the Secretary to conditions the Secretary considers necessary for this section to achieve the objective of the program and to protect the interest of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirements of Obligations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A debt obligation guaranteed under this section shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> be treated in the same manner and to the same extent as other obligations guaranteed under this chapter, except with respect to provisions of this chapter that by their nature cannot be applied to obligations guaranteed under this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> have the fishing fees established under the program paid into a separate subaccount of the fishing capacity reduction fund established under this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> not exceed $100,000,000 in an unpaid principal amount outstanding at any one time for a program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> have such maturity (not to exceed 20 years), take such form, and contain such conditions as the Secretary determines necessary for the program to which they relate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> have as the exclusive source of repayment (subject to the second sentence of subsection (d)(2)) and as the exclusive payment security, the fishing fees established under the program; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> at the discretion of the Secretary be issued in the public market or sold to the Federal Financing Bank.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Fishing Capacity Reduction Fund</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is a separate account in the Treasury, known as the Fishing Capacity Reduction Fund. Within the Fund, at least one subaccount shall be established for each program into which shall be paid all fishing fees established under the program and other amounts authorized for the program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Availability of amounts</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Amounts in the Fund shall be available, without appropriation or fiscal year limitation, to the Secretary to pay the cost of the program, including payments to financial institutions to pay debt obligations incurred by entities under this section. Funds available for this purpose from other amounts available for the program may also be used to pay those debt obligations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Investment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Amounts in the Fund that are not currently needed for the purpose of this section shall be kept on deposit or invested in obligations of the United States Government.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall prescribe regulations the Secretary considers necessary to carry out this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 8(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1625</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. C, title XXXV, § 3507(a)(1)(H)</ref>, (d), <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3555</ref>, 3557; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. C, title XXXV, § 3522(b)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 598</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>