<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 106—</num>
<heading>FISHING VOYAGES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 10601.</num>
<heading> Fishing agreements</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Before proceeding on a voyage, the owner, charterer, or managing operator, or a representative thereof, including the master or individual in charge, of a fishing vessel, fish processing vessel, or fish tender vessel shall make a fishing agreement in writing with each seaman employed on board if the vessel is—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> at least 20 gross tons as measured under <ref>section 14502 of this title</ref>, or an alternate tonnage measured under <ref>section 14302 of this title</ref> as prescribed by the Secretary under <ref>section 14104 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> on a voyage from a port in the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> The agreement shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> state the period of effectiveness of the agreement;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> include the terms of any wage, share, or other compensation arrangement peculiar to the fishery in which the vessel will be engaged during the period of the agreement;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> in the case of a seaman employed on a vessel that is a catcher processor or fish processing vessel that employs more than 25 crewmembers, include a requirement that each crewmember shall be served not less than three meals a day that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> total not less than 3,100 calories; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> include adequate water and minerals in accordance with the United States Recommended Daily Allowances; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> include other agreed terms.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–424, § 6(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-09">Sept. 9, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1591</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–324, title VII, § 739</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3942</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–295, title IV, § 441(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2131</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. K, title CXV, § 11526</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4145</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10602.</num>
<heading> Recovery of wages and shares of fish under agreement</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> When fish caught under an agreement under <ref>section 10601 of this title</ref> are delivered to the owner of the vessel for processing and are sold, the vessel is liable in rem for the wages and shares of the proceeds of the seamen. An action under this section must be brought within six months after the sale of the fish.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In an action under this section, the owner shall produce an accounting of the sale and division of proceeds under the agreement. If the owner fails to produce the accounting, the vessel is liable for the highest value alleged for the shares.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The owner may offset the value of general supplies provided for the voyage and other supplies provided the seaman bringing the action.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> This section does not affect a common law right of a seaman to bring an action to recover the seaman’s share of the fish or proceeds.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–424, § 6(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-09">Sept. 9, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1592</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10603.</num>
<heading> Seaman’s duty to notify employer regarding illness, disability, and injury</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> A seaman on a fishing vessel, fish processing vessel, or fish tender vessel shall notify the master or individual in charge of the vessel or other agent of the employer regarding any illness, disability, or injury suffered by the seaman when in service to the vessel not later than seven days after the date on which the illness, disability, or injury arose.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall prescribe regulations requiring that each fishing vessel, fish processing vessel, and fish tender vessel shall have on board a placard displayed in a prominent location accessible to the crew describing the seaman’s duty under subsection (a) of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–424, § 6(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-09">Sept. 9, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1592</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>