<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 89—</num>
<heading>SMALL VESSEL MANNING</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 8901.</num>
<heading> Freight vessels</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A freight vessel of less than 100 gross tons as measured under <ref>section 14502 of this title</ref>, or an alternate tonnage measured under <ref>section 14302 of this title</ref> as prescribed by the Secretary under <ref>section 14104 of this title</ref> shall be operated by an individual licensed by the Secretary to operate that type of vessel in the particular geographic area, under prescribed regulations.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 555</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–324, title VII, § 733</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3941</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8902.</num>
<heading> Small passenger vessels</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A small passenger vessel shall be operated by an individual licensed by the Secretary to operate that type of vessel in the particular geographic area, under prescribed regulations.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 555</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8903.</num>
<heading> Self-propelled, uninspected passenger vessels</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A self-propelled, uninspected passenger vessel shall be operated by an individual licensed by the Secretary to operate that type of vessel, under prescribed regulations.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 555</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–307, § 1(14)(B)</ref>, (C), <date date="1986-05-19">May 19, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 446</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8904.</num>
<heading> Towing vessels</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> A towing vessel that is at least 26 feet in length measured from end to end over the deck (excluding sheer), shall be operated by an individual licensed by the Secretary to operate that type of vessel in the particular geographic area, under prescribed regulations.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> A vessel that tows a disabled vessel for consideration shall be operated by an individual licensed by the Secretary to operate that type of vessel in the particular geographic area, under prescribed regulations.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Secretary may prescribe by regulation requirements for maximum hours of service (including recording and recordkeeping of that service) of individuals engaged on a towing vessel that is at least 26 feet in length measured from end to end over the deck (excluding the sheer).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 555</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–640, § 12(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-10">Nov. 10, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3550</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–293, title IV, § 409(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-08-09">Aug. 9, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1044</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8905.</num>
<heading> Exemptions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content><ref>Section 8903 of this title</ref> applies to a recreational vessel operated in dealer demonstrations only if the Secretary decides that the application of section 8903 is necessary for recreational vessel safety under <ref>section 4302(d) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content><ref>Section 8904 of this title</ref> does not apply to an oil spill response vessel while engaged in oil spill response or training activities.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> After consultation with the Governor of Alaska and the State boating law administrator of Alaska, the Secretary may exempt an individual operating a self-propelled uninspected passenger vessel from the requirements of <ref>section 8903 of this title</ref>, if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the individual only operates such vessel wholly within waters located in Alaska; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> such vessel is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> 26 feet or less in length; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> carrying not more than 6 passengers.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 556</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–324, title VII, § 734</ref>, title XI, § 1104(f), <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3941</ref>, 3967; <ref>Pub. L. 111–281, title VI, § 606</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2967</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXIII</ref> [LXXXIII], § 8317, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4700</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8906.</num>
<heading> Penalty</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An owner, charterer, managing operator, agent, master, or individual in charge of a vessel operated in violation of this chapter or a regulation prescribed under this chapter is liable to the United States Government for a civil penalty of not more than $25,000. The vessel also is liable in rem for the penalty.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 556</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–324, title III, § 306(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3918</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>