<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 107—</num>
<heading>EFFECTS OF DECEASED SEAMEN</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 10701.</num>
<heading> Application</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Except as otherwise specifically provided, this chapter applies to a vessel on a voyage between—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a port of the United States and a port in a foreign country (except a port in Canada, Mexico, and the West Indies); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a port of the United States on the Atlantic Ocean and a port of the United States on the Pacific Ocean.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> This chapter does not apply to a vessel on which a seaman by custom or agreement is entitled to share in the profit or result of a voyage.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> This chapter does not apply to a foreign vessel.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 572</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10702.</num>
<heading> Duties of masters</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> When a seaman dies during a voyage, the master shall take charge of the seaman’s money and property. An entry shall be made in the official logbook, signed by the master, the chief mate, and an unlicensed crewmember containing an inventory of the money and property and a statement of the wages due the seaman, with the total of the deductions to be made.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> On compliance with this chapter, the master shall obtain a written certificate of compliance from the consular officer or court clerk. Clearance may be granted to a foreign-bound vessel only when the certificate is received at the office of customs.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 572</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–206, title IV, § 422(a)</ref>, <date date="1993-12-20">Dec. 20, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 2438</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10703.</num>
<heading> Procedures of masters</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> If the vessel is proceeding to the United States when a seaman dies, the master shall deliver the seaman’s money, property, and wages when the agreement required by this part is ended, as provided in <ref>section 10706 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> If the vessel touches at a foreign port after the death of the seaman, the master shall report to the first available consular officer. The consular officer may require the master to deliver to the officer the money, property, and wages of the seaman. The consular officer shall give the master a receipt for the matters delivered and certify on the agreement the particulars of the delivery. When the agreement ends, the master shall deliver the receipt to a district court of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> If the consular officer does not require the master to deliver the seaman’s money, property, and wages, the officer shall so certify on the agreement, and the master shall dispose of the money, property, and wages as provided under <ref>section 10706 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> A deduction from the account of a deceased seaman is valid only if certified by a proper entry in the official logbook.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 573</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–206, title IV, § 418</ref>, <date date="1993-12-20">Dec. 20, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 2438</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10704.</num>
<heading> Duties of consular officers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">When a seaman dies outside the United States leaving money or property not on board a vessel, the consular officer nearest the place at which the money and property is located shall claim and take charge of it.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 573</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10705.</num>
<heading> Disposition of money, property, and wages by consular officers</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">When money, property, or wages of a deceased seaman comes into possession of a consular officer, the officer may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> sell the property and remit the proceeds and other money or wages of the seaman the officer has received, to the district court of the United States for the district in which the voyage begins or ends; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> deliver the money, property, and wages to the district court.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 573</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10706.</num>
<heading> Seamen dying in the United States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">When a seaman dies in the United States and is entitled at death to claim money, property, or wages from the master or owner of a vessel on which the seaman served, the master or owner shall deliver the money, property, and wages to a district court of the United States within one week of the seaman’s death. If the seaman’s death occurs at sea, such money, property, or wages shall be delivered to a district court or a consular officer within one week of the vessel’s arrival at the first port call after the seaman’s death.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 573</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–206, title IV, § 419</ref>, <date date="1993-12-20">Dec. 20, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 2438</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 10707.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 103–206, title IV, § 420(a)</ref>, <date date="1993-12-20">Dec. 20, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 2438</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10708.</num>
<heading> Sale of property</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A district court of the United States may direct the sale of any part of the property of a deceased seaman. Proceeds of the sale shall be held as wages of the seaman are held.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 574</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10709.</num>
<heading> Distribution</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> If the money, property, and wages of a seaman, including proceeds from the sale of property, are not more than $1,500 in value, the court, subject to deductions it allows for expenses and at least 60 days after receiving the money, property, and wages, may deliver the money, property, and wages to a claimant proving to be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the seaman’s surviving spouse or child;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> entitled to the money, property, and wages under the seaman’s will or under a law or at common law; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> entitled to secure probate, or take out letters of administration, although no probate or letters of administration have been issued.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The court is released from further liability for the money, property, and wages distributed under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Instead of acting under paragraphs (1) and (2) of this subsection, the court may require probate or letters of administration to be taken out, and then deliver the money, property, and wages to the legal representative of the seaman.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> If the money, property, and wages are more than $1,500 in value, the court, subject to deductions for expenses, shall deliver the money, property, and wages to the legal representative of the seaman.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 574</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–307, § 1(15)</ref>, <date date="1986-05-19">May 19, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 446</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10710.</num>
<heading> Unclaimed money, property, and wages</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> When a claim for the money, property, or wages of a deceased seaman held by a district court of the United States has not been substantiated within 6 years after their receipt by the court, the court, if a subsequent claim is made, may allow or refuse the claim.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> If, after money, property, and wages have been held by the court for 6 years, it appears to the court that no claim will have to be satisfied, the property shall be sold. The money and wages and the proceeds from the sale shall be deposited in the Treasury trust fund receipt account “Unclaimed Moneys of Individuals Whose Whereabouts are Unknown”.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 574</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10711.</num>
<heading> Penalties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An owner or master violating this chapter are each liable to the United States Government for a civil penalty of 3 times the value of the seaman’s money, property, and wages involved or, if the value is not determined, of $200.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 574</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>