<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 801—</num>
<heading>WRECKS AND SALVAGE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 80101.</num>
<heading> Vessel stranded on foreign coast</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duties of Consular Officer</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>When a vessel of the United States is stranded on a coast of a foreign country, the consular officer in that country shall take proper measures, to the extent the laws of that country allow, to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> save and secure the vessel and property on the vessel; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> prepare an inventory of the property that is saved.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Delivery to Owner</inline>.—</heading>
<content>After deducting the expenses, the consular officer shall deliver the property, with an inventory, to the owner of the property.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Taking Possession</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A consular officer may not take possession of property under this section when the owner, master, or consignee is present or able to take possession of the property.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 11</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1690</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 80102.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 110–375, § 1(1)</ref>, <date date="2008-10-08">Oct. 8, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4055</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 80103.</num>
<heading> Property on Florida coast to be taken to port of entry</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Property taken from a wreck, the sea, or a key or shoal, on the coast of Florida and within the jurisdiction of the United States, shall be brought to a port of entry of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Seizure and Forfeiture</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A vessel transporting property described in subsection (a) to a foreign port may be seized by, and forfeited to, the United States Government. A forfeiture under this subsection accrues half to the informer and half to the Government.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 11</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1690</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 80104.</num>
<heading> Salvaging operations by foreign vessels</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in this section or <ref>section 80105 of this title</ref>, a foreign vessel may not, under penalty of forfeiture, engage in salvaging operations on the Atlantic or Pacific coast of the United States, in any portion of the Great Lakes or their connecting or tributary waters, including any portion of the Saint Lawrence River through which the international boundary line extends, or in territorial waters of the United States on the Gulf of Mexico.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">When Suitable Vessel Not Available</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Homeland Security may authorize a foreign vessel to engage in salvaging operations in a particular locality if, on investigation, the Secretary is satisfied that there is not available in that locality a suitable vessel that is—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> owned only by citizens of the United States (including a Bowaters corporation under <ref>section 12118 of this title</ref>); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> documented under chapter 121 of this title or numbered under chapter 123 of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Operations Authorized by Treaty</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>This section does not prohibit or restrict assistance to vessels or salvaging operations authorized by treaty, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> article II of the Treaty between the United States and Great Britain concerning reciprocal rights for United States and Canada in the conveyance of prisoners and wrecking and salvage, signed at Washington, <date date="1908-05-18">May 18, 1908</date> (<ref>35 Stat. 2036</ref>); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Treaty between the United States of America and Mexico to facilitate assistance to and salvage of vessels in territorial waters, signed at Mexico City, <date date="1935-06-13">June 13, 1935</date> (<ref>49 Stat. 3359</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 11</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1691</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 80105.</num>
<heading> Canadian vessels aiding vessels in United States waters</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Canadian vessels and wrecking equipment may give aid to Canadian or other vessels and property wrecked, disabled, or in distress in the waters of the United States contiguous to Canada, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the canal and improvement of the waters between Lake Erie and Lake Huron; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Saint Marys River and canal.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reciprocity</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section does not apply after the President proclaims that privileges reciprocal to those under subsection (a) have been withdrawn or rendered inoperative by the Government of Canada.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 11</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1691</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 80106.</num>
<heading> International agreement on derelicts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President may make an international agreement with other governments interested in the navigation of the North Atlantic Ocean, providing for the reporting, marking, and removal of dangerous wrecks, derelicts, and other menaces to navigation outside the coast waters of the countries bordering the North Atlantic Ocean.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 11</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1691</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 80107.</num>
<heading> Salvors of life to share in remuneration</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Entitlement of Salvors</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A salvor of human life, who gave aid following an accident giving rise to salvage, is entitled to a fair share of the payment awarded to the salvor for salvaging the vessel or other property or preventing or minimizing damage to the environment.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Common Ownership of Vessels</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The right to remuneration for aid or salvage services is not affected by common ownership of the vessels giving and receiving the aid or salvage services.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Time Limit on Bringing Actions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A civil action to recover remuneration for giving aid or salvage services must be brought within 2 years after the date the aid or salvage services were given, unless the court in which the action is brought is satisfied that during that 2-year period there had not been a reasonable opportunity to seize the aided or salvaged vessel within the jurisdiction of the court or within the territorial waters of the country of the plaintiff’s residence or principal place of business.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Nonapplication</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section does not apply to a vessel of war or a vessel owned by the United States Government appropriated only to a public service.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 11</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1691</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>