<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 305—</num>
<heading>EXONERATION AND LIMITATION OF LIABILITY</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 30501.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered small passenger vessel</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “covered small passenger vessel”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> means a small passenger vessel, as defined in section 2101, that is—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> not a wing-in-ground craft; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> carrying—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> not more than 49 passengers on an overnight domestic voyage; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> not more than 150 passengers on any voyage that is not an overnight domestic voyage; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> includes any wooden vessel constructed prior to <date date="1996-03-11">March 11, 1996</date>, carrying at least 1 passenger for hire.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Owner</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “owner” includes a charterer that mans, supplies, and navigates a vessel at the charterer’s own expense or by the charterer’s own procurement.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 6(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1512</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. K, title CXV, § 11503(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4130</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 30502.</num>
<heading> Application</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as otherwise provided, this chapter (except section 30521) applies to seagoing vessels and vessels used on lakes or rivers or in inland navigation, including canal boats, barges, and lighters.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This chapter (except for section 30526) shall not apply to covered small passenger vessels.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 6(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1512</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. K, title CXV, § 11503(c)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4130</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>EXONERATION AND LIMITATION OF LIABILITY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 30521.</num>
<heading> Declaration of nature and value of goods</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If a shipper of an item named in subsection (b), contained in a parcel, package, or trunk, loads the item as freight or baggage on a vessel, without at the time of loading giving to the person receiving the item a written notice of the true character and value of the item and having that information entered on the bill of lading, the owner and master of the vessel are not liable as carriers. The owner and master are not liable beyond the value entered on the bill of lading.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Items</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The items referred to in subsection (a) are precious metals, gold or silver plated articles, precious stones, jewelry, trinkets, watches, clocks, glass, china, coins, bills, securities, printings, engravings, pictures, stamps, maps, papers, silks, furs, lace, and similar items of high value and small size.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 6(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1512</ref>, § 30503; renumbered § 30521, <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. K, title CXV, § 11503(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4130</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 30522.</num>
<heading> Loss by fire</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The owner of a vessel is not liable for loss or damage to merchandise on the vessel caused by a fire on the vessel unless the fire resulted from the design or neglect of the owner.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 6(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1513</ref>, § 30504; renumbered § 30522, <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. K, title CXV, § 11503(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4130</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 30523.</num>
<heading> General limit of liability</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in <ref>section 30524 of this title</ref>, the liability of the owner of a vessel for any claim, debt, or liability described in subsection (b) shall not exceed the value of the vessel and pending freight. If the vessel has more than one owner, the proportionate share of the liability of any one owner shall not exceed that owner’s proportionate interest in the vessel and pending freight.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Claims Subject to Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Unless otherwise excluded by law, claims, debts, and liabilities subject to limitation under subsection (a) are those arising from any embezzlement, loss, or destruction of any property, goods, or merchandise shipped or put on board the vessel, any loss, damage, or injury by collision, or any act, matter, or thing, loss, damage, or forfeiture, done, occasioned, or incurred, without the privity or knowledge of the owner.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Wages</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subsection (a) does not apply to a claim for wages.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 6(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1513</ref>, § 30505; renumbered § 30523 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. K, title CXV, § 11503(a)(3)</ref>, (f)(2), <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4130</ref>, 4131.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 30524.</num>
<heading> Limit of liability for personal injury or death</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Application</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section applies only to seagoing vessels, but does not apply to pleasure yachts, tugs, towboats, towing vessels, tank vessels, fishing vessels, fish tender vessels, canal boats, scows, car floats, barges, lighters, or nondescript vessels.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Minimum Liability</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the amount of the vessel owner’s liability determined under <ref>section 30523 of this title</ref> is insufficient to pay all losses in full, and the portion available to pay claims for personal injury or death is less than $420 times the tonnage of the vessel, that portion shall be increased to $420 times the tonnage of the vessel. That portion may be used only to pay claims for personal injury or death.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Calculation of Tonnage</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Under subsection (b), the tonnage of a self-propelled vessel is the gross tonnage without deduction for engine room, and the tonnage of a sailing vessel is the tonnage for documentation. However, space for the use of seamen is excluded.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Claims Arising on Distinct Occasions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Separate limits of liability apply to claims for personal injury or death arising on distinct occasions.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Privity or Knowledge</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In a claim for personal injury or death, the privity or knowledge of the master or the owner’s superintendent or managing agent, at or before the beginning of each voyage, is imputed to the owner.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 6(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1513</ref>, § 30506; renumbered § 30524 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. K, title CXV, § 11503(a)(3)</ref>, (f)(3), <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4130</ref>, 4131.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 30525.</num>
<heading> Apportionment of losses</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">If the amounts determined under sections 30523 and 30524 of this title are insufficient to pay all claims—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> all claimants shall be paid in proportion to their respective losses out of the amount determined under <ref>section 30523 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> personal injury and death claimants, if any, shall be paid an additional amount in proportion to their respective losses out of the additional amount determined under <ref>section 30524(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 6(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1513</ref>, § 30507; renumbered § 30525 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. K, title CXV, § 11503(a)(3)</ref>, (f)(4), <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4130</ref>, 4131.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 30526.</num>
<heading> Provisions requiring notice of claim or limiting time for bringing action</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Application</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section applies only to seagoing vessels, but does not apply to pleasure yachts, tugs, towboats, towing vessels, tank vessels, fishing vessels, fish tender vessels, canal boats, scows, car floats, barges, lighters, or nondescript vessels.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Minimum Time Limits</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The owner, master, manager, or agent of a vessel transporting passengers or property between ports in the United States, or between a port in the United States and a port in a foreign country, may not limit by regulation, contract, or otherwise the period for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> giving notice of, or filing a claim for, personal injury or death, in the case of seagoing vessels, to less than 6 months after the date of the injury or death, or in the case of covered small passenger vessels, to less than two years after the date of the injury or death; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> bringing a civil action for personal injury or death, in the case of seagoing vessels, to less than one year after the date of the injury or death, or in the case of covered small passenger vessels, to less than two years after the date of the injury or death.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Effect of Failure To Give Notice</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>When notice of a claim for personal injury or death is required by a contract, the failure to give the notice is not a bar to recovery if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the court finds that the owner, master, or agent of the vessel had knowledge of the injury or death and the owner has not been prejudiced by the failure;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the court finds there was a satisfactory reason why the notice could not have been given; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the owner of the vessel fails to object to the failure to give the notice.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Tolling of Period To Give Notice</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>If a claimant is a minor or mental incompetent, or if a claim is for wrongful death, any period provided by a contract for giving notice of the claim is tolled until the earlier of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the date a legal representative is appointed for the minor, incompetent, or decedent’s estate; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> 3 years after the injury or death.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 6(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1514</ref>, § 30508; renumbered § 30526 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. K, title CXV, § 11503(a)(3)</ref>, (d), <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4130</ref>, 4131.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 30527.</num>
<heading> Provisions limiting liability for personal injury or death</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The owner, master, manager, or agent of a vessel transporting passengers between ports in the United States, or between a port in the United States and a port in a foreign country, may not include in a regulation or contract a provision limiting—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the liability of the owner, master, or agent for personal injury or death caused by the negligence or fault of the owner or the owner’s employees or agents; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the right of a claimant for personal injury or death to a trial by court of competent jurisdiction.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Voidness</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A provision described in paragraph (1) is void.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Emotional Distress, Mental Suffering, and Psychological Injury</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subsection (a) does not prohibit a provision in a contract or in ticket conditions of carriage with a passenger that relieves an owner, master, manager, agent, operator, or crewmember of a vessel from liability for infliction of emotional distress, mental suffering, or psychological injury so long as the provision does not limit such liability when the emotional distress, mental suffering, or psychological injury is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the result of physical injury to the claimant caused by the negligence or fault of a crewmember or the owner, master, manager, agent, or operator;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the result of the claimant having been at actual risk of physical injury, and the risk was caused by the negligence or fault of a crewmember or the owner, master, manager, agent, or operator; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> intentionally inflicted by a crewmember or the owner, master, manager, agent, or operator.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Sexual offenses</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This subsection does not limit the liability of a crewmember or the owner, master, manager, agent, or operator of a vessel in a case involving sexual harassment, sexual assault, or rape.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 6(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1514</ref>, § 30509; renumbered § 30527, <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. K, title CXV, § 11503(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4130</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 30528.</num>
<heading> Vicarious liability for medical malpractice with regard to crew</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In a civil action by any person in which the owner or operator of a vessel or employer of a crewmember is claimed to have vicarious liability for medical malpractice with regard to a crewmember occurring at a shoreside facility, and to the extent the damages resulted from the conduct of any shoreside doctor, hospital, medical facility, or other health care provider, the owner, operator, or employer is entitled to rely on any statutory limitations of liability applicable to the doctor, hospital, medical facility, or other health care provider in the State of the United States in which the shoreside medical care was provided.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 6(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1515</ref>, § 30510; renumbered § 30528, <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. K, title CXV, § 11503(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4130</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 30529.</num>
<heading> Action by owner for limitation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The owner of a vessel may bring a civil action in a district court of the United States for limitation of liability under this chapter. The action must be brought within 6 months after a claimant gives the owner written notice of a claim.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Creation of Fund</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>When the action is brought, the owner (at the owner’s option) shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> deposit with the court, for the benefit of claimants—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an amount equal to the value of the owner’s interest in the vessel and pending freight, or approved security; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an amount, or approved security, that the court may fix from time to time as necessary to carry out this chapter; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> transfer to a trustee appointed by the court, for the benefit of claimants—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the owner’s interest in the vessel and pending freight; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an amount, or approved security, that the court may fix from time to time as necessary to carry out this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Cessation of Other Actions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>When an action has been brought under this section and the owner has complied with subsection (b), all claims and proceedings against the owner related to the matter in question shall cease.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 6(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1515</ref>, § 30511; renumbered § 30529, <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. K, title CXV, § 11503(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4130</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 30530.</num>
<heading> Liability as master, officer, or seaman not affected</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This chapter does not affect the liability of an individual as a master, officer, or seaman, even though the individual is also an owner of the vessel.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 6(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1516</ref>, § 30512; renumbered § 30530, <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. K, title CXV, § 11503(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4130</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>