<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 77—</num>
<heading>SUSPENSION AND REVOCATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7701.</num>
<heading> General</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The purpose of suspension and revocation proceedings is to promote safety at sea.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Licenses, certificates of registry, and merchant mariners’ documents may be suspended or revoked for acts described in <ref>section 7703 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> When a license, certificate of registry, or merchant mariner’s document has been revoked under this chapter, the former holder may be issued a new license, certificate of registry, or merchant mariner’s document only after—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Secretary decides, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, that the issuance is compatible with the requirement of good discipline and safety at sea; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the former holder provides satisfactory proof that the bases for revocation are no longer valid.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The Secretary may prescribe regulations to carry out this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 546</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–380, title IV, § 4103(c)</ref>, <date date="1990-08-18">Aug. 18, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 511</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7702.</num>
<heading> Administrative procedure</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Sections 551–559 of title 5 apply to each hearing under this chapter about suspending or revoking a license, certificate of registry, or merchant mariner’s document.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The individual whose license, certificate of registry, or merchant mariner’s document has been suspended or revoked under this chapter may appeal, within 30 days, the suspension or revocation to the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall request a holder of a license, certificate of registry, or merchant mariner’s document to make available to the Secretary, under <ref>section 30305(b)(7) of title 49</ref>, all information contained in the National Driver Register related to an offense described in section 205(a)(3)(A) or (B) of that Act <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002011">1</ref> committed by the individual.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall require the testing of the holder of a license, certificate of registry, or merchant mariner’s document for use of alcohol and dangerous drugs in violation of law or Federal regulation. The testing may include preemployment (with respect to dangerous drugs only), periodic, random, and reasonable cause testing, and shall include post-accident testing.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary may temporarily, for not more than 45 days, suspend and take possession of the license, certificate of registry, or merchant mariner’s document held by an individual if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> that individual performs a safety sensitive function on a vessel, as determined by the Secretary; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> there is probable cause to believe that the individual—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> has, while acting under the authority of that license, certificate, or document, performed the safety sensitive function in violation of law or Federal regulation regarding use of alcohol or a dangerous drug;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> has been convicted of an offense that would prevent the issuance or renewal of the license, certificate, or document;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> within the 3-year period preceding the initiation of a suspension proceeding, has been convicted of an offense described in section 30304(a)(3)(A) or (B) of title 49; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> is a security risk that poses a threat to the safety or security of a vessel or a public or commercial structure located within or adjacent to the marine environment.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If a license, certificate, or document is temporarily suspended under this section, an expedited hearing under subsection (a) of this section shall be held within 30 days after the temporary suspension.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 546</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–36, § 1(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1985-05-15">May 15, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 67</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–380, title IV, § 4103(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-08-18">Aug. 18, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 510</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–383, title III, § 304(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3419</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–293, title IV, § 407</ref>, title VI, § 609(2), <date date="2004-08-09">Aug. 9, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1044</ref>, 1058; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. C, title XXXV, § 3546(f)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2326</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7703.</num>
<heading> Bases for suspension or revocation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A license, certificate of registry, or merchant mariner’s document issued by the Secretary may be suspended or revoked if the holder—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> when acting under the authority of that license, certificate, or document—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> has violated or fails to comply with this subtitle, a regulation prescribed under this subtitle, or any other law or regulation intended to promote marine safety or to protect navigable waters; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> has committed an act of misconduct or negligence;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> is convicted of an offense that would prevent the issuance or renewal of a license, certificate of registry, or merchant mariner’s document;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> within the 3-year period preceding the initiation of the suspension or revocation proceeding is convicted of an offense described in section 30304(a)(3)(A) or (B) of title 49;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> has committed an act of incompetence relating to the operation of a vessel; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> is a security risk that poses a threat to the safety or security of a vessel or a public or commercial structure located within or adjacent to the marine environment.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 546</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–36, § 1(a)(9)(E)</ref>, <date date="1985-05-15">May 15, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 68</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–380, title IV, § 4103(b)</ref>, <date date="1990-08-18">Aug. 18, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 511</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–293, title IV, § 408</ref>, title VI, § 609(3), <date date="2004-08-09">Aug. 9, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1044</ref>, 1058; <ref>Pub. L. 109–241, title IX, § 901(h)(3)</ref>, <date date="2006-07-11">July 11, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 564</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7704.</num>
<heading> Dangerous drugs as grounds for revocation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> If it is shown at a hearing under this chapter that a holder of a license, certificate of registry, or merchant mariner’s document issued under this part, within 10 years before the beginning of the proceedings, has been convicted of violating a dangerous drug law of the United States or of a State, the license, certificate, or document shall be suspended or revoked.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> If it is shown that a holder has been a user of, or addicted to, a dangerous drug, the license, certificate of registry, or merchant mariner’s document shall be revoked unless the holder provides satisfactory proof that the holder is cured.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 546</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–36, § 1(a)(9)(F)</ref>, (G), <date date="1985-05-15">May 15, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 68</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–380, title IV, § 4103(a)(2)(B)</ref>, <date date="1990-08-18">Aug. 18, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 511</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–293, title IV, § 402</ref>, <date date="2004-08-09">Aug. 9, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1043</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. C, title XXXV, § 3545(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2326</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7704a.</num>
<heading> Sexual harassment or sexual assault as grounds for suspension or revocation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Sexual Harassment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If it is shown at a hearing under this chapter that a holder of a license, certificate of registry, or merchant mariner’s document issued under this part, within 5 years before the beginning of the suspension and revocation proceedings, is the subject of an official finding of sexual harassment, then the license, certificate of registry, or merchant mariner’s document may be suspended or revoked.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Sexual Assault</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If it is shown at a hearing under this chapter that a holder of a license, certificate of registry, or merchant mariner’s document issued under this part, within 10 years before the beginning of the suspension and revocation proceedings, is the subject of an official finding of sexual assault, then the license, certificate of registry, or merchant mariner’s document shall be revoked.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Official Finding.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the term “official finding” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a legal proceeding or agency finding or decision that determines the individual committed sexual harassment or sexual assault in violation of any Federal, State, local, or Tribal law or regulation; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a determination after an investigation by the Coast Guard that, by a preponderance of the evidence, the individual committed sexual harassment or sexual assault if the investigation affords appropriate due process rights to the subject of the investigation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Administrative law judge review.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Coast guard investigation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A determination under paragraph (1)(B) shall be reviewed and affirmed by an administrative law judge within the same proceeding as any suspension or revocation of a license, certificate of registry, or merchant mariner’s document under subsection (a) or (b).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Legal proceeding</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A determination under paragraph (1)(A) that an individual committed sexual harassment or sexual assault is conclusive in suspension and revocation proceedings.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. K, title CXVI, § 11603(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7705.</num>
<heading> Subpenas and oaths</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> An official designated to investigate or preside at a hearing on matters that are grounds for suspension or revocation of licenses, certificates of registry, and merchant mariners’ documents may administer oaths and issue subpenas to compel the attendance and testimony of witnesses and the production of records or other evidence during investigations and at hearings.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The jurisdictional limits of a subpena issued under this section are the same as, and are enforceable in the same manner as, subpenas issued under chapter 63 of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 547</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–36, § 1(a)(9)(H)</ref>, <date date="1985-05-15">May 15, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 68</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7706.</num>
<heading> Drug testing reporting</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Release of Drug Test Results to Coast Guard</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 2 weeks after receiving from a Medical Review Officer a report of a verified positive drug test or verified test violation by a civilian employee of a Federal agency, an applicant for employment by a Federal agency, an officer in the Public Health Services, or an officer in the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration Commissioned Officer Corps, who is employed in any capacity on board a vessel operated by the agency, the head of the agency shall release to the Commandant the report.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Standards, Procedures, and Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The head of a Federal agency shall carry out a release under subsection (a) in accordance with the standards, procedures, and regulations applicable to the disclosure and reporting to the Coast Guard of drug tests results and drug test records of individuals employed on vessels documented under the laws of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Waiver</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding section 503(e) of the Supplemental Appropriations Act, 1987 (<ref>5 U.S.C. 7301</ref> note), the report of a drug test of an employee or an applicant for employment by a Federal agency may be released under this section without the prior written consent of the employee or the applicant.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–293, title IV, § 414(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-08-09">Aug. 9, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1046</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 113–281, title III, § 304</ref>, <date date="2014-12-18">Dec. 18, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3043</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. C, title XXXV, § 3541(b)(13)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2323</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>