<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 441—</num>
<heading>EVIDENCE OF FINANCIAL RESPONSIBILITY FOR PASSENGER TRANSPORTATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 44101.</num>
<heading> Application</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">This chapter applies to a vessel that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> has berth or stateroom accommodations for at least 50 passengers; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> boards passengers at a port in the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 7</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1554</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 44102.</num>
<heading> Financial responsibility to indemnify passengers for nonperformance of transportation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Filing Requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A person in the United States may not arrange, offer, advertise, or provide transportation on a vessel to which this chapter applies unless the person has filed with the Federal Maritime Commission evidence of financial responsibility to indemnify passengers for nonperformance of the transportation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Satisfactory Evidence</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>To satisfy subsection (a), a person must file—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> information the Commission considers necessary; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a copy of a bond or other security, in such form as the Commission by regulation may require.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authorized Issuer of Bond</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If a bond is filed, it must be issued by a bonding company authorized to do business in the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 7</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1554</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 44103.</num>
<heading> Financial responsibility to pay liability for death or injury</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General Requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The owner or charterer of a vessel to which this chapter applies shall establish, under regulations prescribed by the Federal Maritime Commission, financial responsibility to meet liability for death or injury to passengers or other individuals on a voyage to or from a port in the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Amounts</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The amount of financial responsibility required under subsection (a) shall be based on the number of passenger accommodations as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> $20,000 for each of the first 500 passenger accommodations.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> $15,000 for each additional passenger accommodation between 501 and 1,000.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> $10,000 for each additional passenger accommodation between 1,001 and 1,500.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> $5,000 for each additional passenger accommodation over 1,500.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Multiple vessels</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the owner or charterer is operating more than one vessel subject to this chapter, the amount of financial responsibility shall be based on the number of passenger accommodations on the vessel with the largest number of passenger accommodations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Availability To Pay Judgment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The amount determined under subsection (b) shall be available to pay a judgment for damages (whether less than or more than $20,000) for death or injury to a passenger or other individual on a voyage to or from a port in the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Means of Establishing</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Financial responsibility under this section may be established by one or more of the following if acceptable to the Commission:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Insurance.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Surety bond issued by a bonding company authorized to do business in the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Qualification as a self-insurer.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Other evidence of financial responsibility.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 7</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1554</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 44104.</num>
<heading> Civil penalty</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A person that violates section 44102 or 44103 of this title is liable to the United States Government for a civil penalty of not more than $5,000, plus $200 for each passage sold, to be assessed by the Federal Maritime Commission. The Commission may remit or mitigate the penalty on terms the Commission considers proper.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 7</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1555</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 44105.</num>
<heading> Refusal of clearance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall refuse the clearance required by <ref>section 60105 of this title</ref>, at the port or place of departure from the United States, of a vessel that is subject to this chapter and does not have evidence issued by the Federal Maritime Commission of compliance with sections 44102 and 44103 of this title.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 7</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1555</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 44106.</num>
<heading> Conduct of proceedings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Part A of this subtitle applies to proceedings conducted by the Federal Maritime Commission under this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 7</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1555</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>