<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 504—</num>
<heading>COMMITTEES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 50401.</num>
<heading> United States Committee on the Marine Transportation System</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is established a United States Committee on the Marine Transportation System (in this section referred to as the “Committee”).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Purpose</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Committee shall serve as a Federal interagency coordinating committee for the purpose of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> assessing the adequacy of the marine transportation system (including ports, waterways, channels, and their intermodal connections);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> promoting the integration of the marine transportation system with other modes of transportation and other uses of the marine environment; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> coordinating, improving the coordination of, and making recommendations with regard to Federal policies that impact the marine transportation system.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Membership.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Committee shall consist of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Transportation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Defense;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Homeland Security;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Commerce;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the Secretary of the Treasury;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the Secretary of State;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> the Secretary of the Interior;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Agriculture;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the Attorney General;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Labor;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Energy;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(L)</num>
<content> the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(M)</num>
<content> the Chairman of the Federal Maritime Commission;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(N)</num>
<content> the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(O)</num>
<content> the head of any other Federal agency who a majority of the voting members of the Committee determines can further the purpose and activities of the Committee.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Nonvoting members</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Committee may include as many nonvoting members as a majority of the voting members of the Committee determines is appropriate to further the purpose and activities of the Committee.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Support.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Coordinating board.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is hereby established, within the Committee, a Coordinating Board. Each member of the Committee may select a senior level representative to serve on such Board. The Board shall assist the Committee in carrying out its purpose and activities.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Chair</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There shall be a Chair of the Coordinating Board. The Chair of the Coordinating Board shall rotate each year among the Secretary of Transportation, the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the Secretary of Commerce. The order of rotation shall be determined by a majority of the voting members of the Committee.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Executive director</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Transportation, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the Secretary of Commerce, shall appoint an Executive Director of the Committee.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transfers</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the head of a Federal department or agency who is a member of the Committee may—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> provide, on a reimbursable or nonreimbursable basis, facilities, equipment, services, personnel, and other support services to carry out the activities of the Committee; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> transfer funds to another Federal department or agency in order to carry out the activities of the Committee.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Marine Transportation System Assessment and Strategy</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not later than one year after the date of enactment of this Act and every 5 years thereafter, the Committee shall provide to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives a report that includes—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> steps taken to implement actions recommended in the document titled “National Strategy for the Marine Transportation System: A Framework for Action” and dated July 2008;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a conditions and performance analysis of the marine transportation system;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a discussion of the challenges the marine transportation system faces in meeting user demand, including estimates of investment levels required to ensure system infrastructure meets such demand;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> a plan, with recommended actions, for improving the marine transportation system to meet current and future challenges;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> steps taken to implement actions recommended in previous reports required under this subsection; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> a compendium of the Federal programs engaged in the maritime transportation system.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consultation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In carrying out its purpose and activities, the Committee may consult with marine transportation system-related advisory committees, interested parties, and the public.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 112–213, title III, § 310(a)</ref>, <date date="2012-12-20">Dec. 20, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1567</ref>, § 55502; renumbered § 55501, <ref>Pub. L. 113–281, title III, § 301(2)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-18">Dec. 18, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3042</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXIII</ref> [LXXXIII], § 8315, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4699</ref>; renumbered § 50401 and amended, <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. C, title XXXV, § 3512(a)(3)</ref>, (4), <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2239</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 50402.</num>
<heading> Maritime Transportation System National Advisory Committee</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is established a Maritime Transportation System National Advisory Committee (in this section referred to as the “Committee”).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Function</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Committee shall advise the Secretary of Transportation on matters relating to the United States maritime transportation system and its seamless integration with other segments of the transportation system, including the viability of the United States Merchant Marine.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Membership.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Committee shall consist of 27 members appointed by the Secretary of Transportation in accordance with this section and section 15109.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Expertise</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each member of the Committee shall have particular expertise, knowledge, and experience in matters relating to the function of the Committee.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Representation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Members of the Committee shall be appointed as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> At least one member shall represent the Environmental Protection Agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> At least one member shall represent the Department of Commerce.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> At least one member shall represent the Corps of Engineers.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> At least one member shall represent the Coast Guard.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> At least one member shall represent Customs and Border Protection.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> At least one member shall represent State and local governmental entities.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> Additional members shall represent private sector entities that reflect a cross-section of maritime industries, including port and water stakeholders, academia, and labor.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> The Secretary may appoint additional representatives from other Federal agencies as the Secretary considers appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Restrictions on members representing federal agencies</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Members of the Committee that represent Federal agencies shall not—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> comprise more than one-third of the total membership of the Committee or of any subcommittee therein; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> serve as the chair or co-chair of the Committee or of any subcommittee therein.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Administration</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For purposes of section 15109—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Committee shall be treated as a committee established under chapter 151; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Transportation shall fulfill all duties and responsibilities and have all authorities of the Secretary of Homeland Security with regard to the Committee.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXIII</ref> [LXXXIII], § 8332(a), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4703</ref>, § 55502; renumbered § 50402, <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. C, title XXXV, § 3512(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2239</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>