<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 75—</num>
<heading>GENERAL PROCEDURES FOR LICENSING, CERTIFICATION, AND DOCUMENTATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7501.</num>
<heading> Duplicates</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> If a license, certificate of registry, or merchant mariner’s document issued under this part is lost as a result of a marine casualty, the holder shall be supplied with a duplicate without cost.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> For any other loss, the holder may obtain a duplicate on payment of reasonable costs prescribed by regulation by the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 545</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–36, § 1(a)(9)(C)</ref>, <date date="1985-05-15">May 15, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 68</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXV</ref> [LXXXV], § 8505(b)(5), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4751</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7502.</num>
<heading> Records</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall maintain records, including electronic records, on the issuances, denials, suspensions, and revocations of licenses, certificates of registry, merchant mariners’ documents, and endorsements on those licenses, certificates, and documents.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Secretary may prescribe regulations requiring a vessel owner or managing operator of a commercial vessel, or the employer of a seaman on that vessel, to maintain records of each individual engaged on the vessel subject to inspection under chapter 33 on matters of engagement, discharge, and service for not less than 5 years after the date of the completion of the service of that individual on the vessel. The regulations may require that a vessel owner, managing operator, or employer shall make these records available to the individual and the Coast Guard on request.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> A person violating this section, or a regulation prescribed under this section, is liable to the United States Government for a civil penalty of not more than $5,000.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 545</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–380, title IV, § 4114(e)</ref>, <date date="1990-08-18">Aug. 18, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 517</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–281, title VI, § 605</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2967</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7503.</num>
<heading> Dangerous drugs as grounds for denial</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A license, certificate of registry, or merchant mariner’s document authorized to be issued under this part may be denied to an individual who—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> within 10 years before applying for the license, certificate, or document, has been convicted of violating a dangerous drug law of the United States or of a State; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> when applying, has ever been a user of, or addicted to, a dangerous drug unless the individual provides satisfactory proof that the individual is cured.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 545</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–36, § 1(a)(9)(D)</ref>, <date date="1985-05-15">May 15, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 68</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–380, title IV, § 4103(a)(2)(B)</ref>, <date date="1990-08-18">Aug. 18, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 511</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. C, title XXXV, § 3545(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2326</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7504.</num>
<heading> Travel and expense reimbursement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">When a requirement to qualify for the issuance of, or endorsement on, a certificate, license, or document under this part is administered at a place at the request of an applicant or an applicant’s representative, the applicant or representative may reimburse the Secretary for the travel and subsistence expenses incurred by the personnel assigned to perform the administration of the requirement. Amounts received as reimbursement under this section shall be credited to the appropriation for operations and support of the Coast Guard.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–640, § 10(b)(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-10">Nov. 10, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3549</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXV</ref> [LXXXV], § 8513(b), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4761</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7505.</num>
<heading> Review of information in National Driver Register</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall make information received from the National Driver Register under <ref>section 30305(b)(7) of title 49</ref> available to an individual for review and written comment before denying, suspending, revoking, or taking any other action relating to a license, certificate of registry, or merchant mariner’s document authorized to be issued for that individual under this part, based on that information.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–380, title IV, § 4105(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-08-18">Aug. 18, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 512</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. C, title XXXV, § 3546(e)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2326</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7506.</num>
<heading> Convention tonnage for licenses, certificates, and documents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Notwithstanding any provision of section 14302(c) or 14305 of this title, the Secretary may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> evaluate the service of an individual who is applying for a license, a certificate of registry, or a merchant mariner’s document by using the tonnage as measured under chapter 143 of this title for the vessels on which that service was acquired, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> issue the license, certificate, or document based on that service.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–324, title VII, § 745(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3942</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7507.</num>
<heading> Authority to extend the duration of licenses, certificates of registry, and merchant mariner documents</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Licenses and Certificates of Registry</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Notwithstanding sections 7106 and 7107, the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> extend for not more than one year an expiring license or certificate of registry issued for an individual under chapter 71 if the Secretary determines that the extension is required to enable the Coast Guard to eliminate a backlog in processing applications for those licenses or certificates of registry or in response to a national emergency or natural disaster, as deemed necessary by the Secretary; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> issue for not more than five years an expiring license or certificate of registry issued for an individual under chapter 71 for the exclusive purpose of aligning the expiration date of such license or certificate of registry with the expiration date of a merchant mariner’s document.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Merchant Mariner Documents</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Notwithstanding section 7302(g), the Secretary may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> extend for not more than one year an expiring merchant mariner’s document issued for an individual under chapter 73 if the Secretary determines that the extension is required to enable the Coast Guard to eliminate a backlog in processing applications for those merchant mariner documents or in response to a national emergency or natural disaster, as deemed necessary by the Secretary; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> issue for not more than five years an expiring merchant mariner’s document issued for an individual under chapter 73 for the exclusive purpose of aligning the expiration date of such merchant mariner’s document with the expiration date of a license or certificate of registry.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Manner of Extension</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any extensions granted under this section may be granted to individual seamen or a specifically identified group of seamen.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–281, title VI, § 615(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2971</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 112–213, title III, § 311</ref>, <date date="2012-12-20">Dec. 20, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1569</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title V, § 510(3)</ref>, (4), <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4274</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7508.</num>
<heading> Authority to extend the duration of medical certificates</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Granting of Extensions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary may extend for not more than one year a medical certificate issued to an individual holding a license, merchant mariner’s document, or certificate of registry issued under chapter 71 or 73 if the Secretary determines that the extension is required to enable the Coast Guard to eliminate a backlog in processing applications for medical certificates or is in response to a national emergency or natural disaster.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Manner of Extension</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An extension under this section may be granted to an individual or a specifically identified group of individuals.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 112–213, title III, § 306(a)</ref>, <date date="2012-12-20">Dec. 20, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1565</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXV</ref> [LXXXV], § 8505(b)(6), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4751</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7509.</num>
<heading> Medical certification by trusted agents</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Notwithstanding any other provision of law and pursuant to regulations prescribed by the Secretary, a trusted agent may issue a medical certificate to an individual who—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> must hold such certificate to qualify for a license, certificate of registry, or merchant mariner’s document, or endorsement thereto under this part; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> is qualified as to sight, hearing, and physical condition to perform the duties of such license, certificate, document, or endorsement, as determined by the trusted agent.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Process for Issuance of Certificates by Secretary</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A final rule implementing this section shall include a process for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating to issue medical certificates to mariners who submit applications for such certificates to the Secretary; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a trusted agent to defer to the Secretary the issuance of a medical certificate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Trusted Agent Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section the term “trusted agent” means a medical practitioner certified by the Secretary to perform physical examinations of an individual for purposes of a license, certificate of registry, or merchant mariner’s document under this part.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–120, title III, § 309(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-02-08">Feb. 8, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 56</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7510.</num>
<heading> Examinations for merchant mariner credentials</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Disclosure Not Required</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary is not required to disclose to the public—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a question from any examination for a merchant mariner credential;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the answer to such a question, including any correct or incorrect answer that may be presented with such question; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> any quality or characteristic of such a question, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the manner in which such question has been, is, or may be selected for an examination;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the frequency of such selection; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the frequency that an examinee correctly or incorrectly answered such question.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception for Certain Questions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding subsection (a), the Secretary may, for the purpose of preparation by the general public for examinations required for merchant mariner credentials, release an examination question and answer that the Secretary has retired or is not presently on or part of an examination, or that the Secretary determines is appropriate for release.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Exam Review.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of the Coast Guard Authorization Act of 2016, and once every two years thereafter, the Commandant shall commission a working group to review new questions for inclusion in examinations required for merchant mariner credentials, composed of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> 1 subject matter expert from the Coast Guard;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> representatives from training facilities and the maritime industry, of whom—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> one-half shall be representatives from approved training facilities; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> one-half shall be representatives from the appropriate maritime industry;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> at least 1 representative from the National Merchant Marine Personnel Advisory Committee;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> at least 2 representatives from the State maritime academies, of whom one shall be a representative from the deck training track and one shall be a representative of the engineer license track;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> representatives from other Coast Guard Federal advisory committees, as appropriate, for the industry segment associated with the subject examinations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> at least 1 subject matter expert from the Maritime Administration; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> at least 1 human performance technology representative.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inclusion of persons knowledgeable about examination type</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The working group shall include representatives knowledgeable about the examination type under review.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The requirement to convene a working group under paragraph (1) does not apply unless there are new examination questions to review.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Baseline review.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Within 1 year after the date of the enactment of the Coast Guard Authorization Act of 2016, the Secretary shall convene the working group to complete a baseline review of the Coast Guard’s Merchant Mariner Credentialing Examination, including review of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the accuracy of examination questions;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the accuracy and availability of examination references;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the length of merchant mariner examinations; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the use of standard technologies in administering, scoring, and analyzing the examinations.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Progress report</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Coast Guard shall provide a progress report to the appropriate congressional committees on the review under this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Full membership not required</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Coast Guard may convene the working group without all members present if any non-Coast-Guard representative is present.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Nondisclosure agreement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall require all members of the working group to sign a nondisclosure agreement with the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Treatment of members as federal employees</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A member of the working group who is not a Federal Government employee shall not be considered a Federal employee in the service or the employment of the Federal Government, except that such a member shall be considered a special government employee, as defined in <ref>section 202(a) of title 18</ref> for purposes of sections 203, 205, 207, 208, and 209 of such title and shall be subject to any administrative standards of conduct applicable to an employee of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Formal exam review</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall ensure that the Coast Guard Performance Technology Center—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> prioritizes the review of examinations required for merchant mariner credentials; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of the Coast Guard Authorization Act of 2016, completes a formal review, including an appropriate analysis, of the topics and testing methodology employed by the National Maritime Center for merchant mariner licensing.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Chapter </inline>10<inline class="small-caps"> of title </inline>5.—</heading>
<content>Chapter 10 of title 5 shall not apply to any working group created under this section to review the Coast Guard’s merchant mariner credentialing examinations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Merchant Mariner Credential Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “merchant mariner credential” means a merchant mariner license, certificate, or document that the Secretary is authorized to issue pursuant to this title.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–120, title III, § 315(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2016-02-08">Feb. 8, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 60</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. C, title XXXV, § 3503(a)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2775</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. C, title XXXV, § 3541(b)(12)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2323</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title VI, § 601(c)(3)(B)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4289</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXV</ref> [LXXXV], § 8505(b)(7), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4751</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(a)(290)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4337</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7511.</num>
<heading> Convicted sex offender as grounds for denial</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Sexual Abuse</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A license, certificate of registry, or merchant mariner’s document authorized to be issued under this part shall be denied to an individual who has been convicted of a sexual offense prohibited under—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> chapter 109A of title 18, except for subsection (b) of <ref>section 2244 of title 18</ref>; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a substantially similar offense under State, local, or Tribal law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Abusive Sexual Contact</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A license, certificate of registry, or merchant mariner’s document authorized to be issued under this part may be denied to an individual who within 5 years before applying for the license, certificate, or document, has been convicted of a sexual offense prohibited under subsection (b) of <ref>section 2244 of title 18</ref>, or a substantially similar offense under State, local, or Tribal law.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. K, title CXVI, § 11602(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>