<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 505—</num>
<heading>OTHER GENERAL PROVISIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 50501.</num>
<heading> Entities deemed citizens of the United States</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this subtitle, a corporation, partnership, or association is deemed to be a citizen of the United States only if the controlling interest is owned by citizens of the United States. However, if the corporation, partnership, or association is operating a vessel in the coastwise trade, at least 75 percent of the interest must be owned by citizens of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Additional Requirements for Corporations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this subtitle, a corporation is deemed to be a citizen of the United States only if, in addition to satisfying the requirements in subsection (a)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> it is incorporated under the laws of the United States or a State;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> its chief executive officer, by whatever title, and the chairman of its board of directors are citizens of the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> no more of its directors are noncitizens than a minority of the number necessary to constitute a quorum.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Determination of Controlling Corporate Interest</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The controlling interest in a corporation is owned by citizens of the United States under subsection (a) only if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> title to the majority of the stock in the corporation is vested in citizens of the United States free from any trust or fiduciary obligation in favor of a person not a citizen of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the majority of the voting power in the corporation is vested in citizens of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> there is no contract or understanding by which the majority of the voting power in the corporation may be exercised, directly or indirectly, in behalf of a person not a citizen of the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> there is no other means by which control of the corporation is given to or permitted to be exercised by a person not a citizen of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Determination of </inline>75<inline class="small-caps"> Percent Corporate Interest</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>At least 75 percent of the interest in a corporation is owned by citizens of the United States under subsection (a) only if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> title to at least 75 percent of the stock in the corporation is vested in citizens of the United States free from any trust or fiduciary obligation in favor of a person not a citizen of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> at least 75 percent of the voting power in the corporation is vested in citizens of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> there is no contract or understanding by which more than 25 percent of the voting power in the corporation may be exercised, directly or indirectly, in behalf of a person not a citizen of the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> there is no other means by which control of more than 25 percent of any interest in the corporation is given to or permitted to be exercised by a person not a citizen of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1566</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 50502.</num>
<heading> Applicability to receivers, trustees, successors, and assigns</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This subtitle applies to receivers, trustees, successors, and assigns of any person to whom this subtitle applies.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1567</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 50503.</num>
<heading> Oceanographic research vessels</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An oceanographic research vessel (as defined in <ref>section 2101 of this title</ref>) is deemed not to be engaged in trade or commerce.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1567</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 50504.</num>
<heading> Sailing school vessels</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the terms “sailing school instructor”, “sailing school student”, and “sailing school vessel” have the meaning given those terms in <ref>section 2101 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Not Seamen</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A sailing school student or sailing school instructor is deemed not to be a seaman under—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> parts B, F, and G of subtitle II of this title; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the maritime law doctrines of maintenance and cure or warranty of seaworthiness.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Not Merchant Vessel or Engaged in Trade or Commerce</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A sailing school vessel is deemed not to be—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a merchant vessel under section 11101(a)–(c) of this title; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a vessel engaged in trade or commerce.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Evidence of Financial Responsibility</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The owner or charterer of a sailing school vessel shall maintain evidence of financial responsibility to meet liability for death or injury to sailing school students and sailing school instructors on a voyage on the vessel. The amount of financial responsibility shall be at least $50,000 for each student and instructor. Financial responsibility under this subsection may be evidenced by insurance or other adequate financial resources.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1568</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 50505.</num>
<heading> Consistent approval of existing categorical exclusions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In accordance with <ref>section 139 of title 23</ref>, the Maritime Administrator may approve any action qualifying as a categorical exclusion applicable to the Federal Highway Administration, the Federal Transit Administration, or the Federal Railroad Administration when the applicable requirements of that categorical exclusion have been met that are in compliance with the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.), and any other applicable law. Nothing in this section shall be interpreted to limit any existing authority of the Maritime Administration to approve, promulgate, or publish categorical exclusions consistent with the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.) or any other applicable law.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. C, title XXXV, § 3511(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2306</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>