<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 461—</num>
<heading>FEDERAL MARITIME COMMISSION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 46101.</num>
<heading> General organization</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Organization</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Federal Maritime Commission is an independent establishment of the United States Government.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Commissioners</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Composition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commission is composed of 5 Commissioners, appointed by the President by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. Not more than 3 Commissioners may be appointed from the same political party.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Terms</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term of each Commissioner is 5 years. When the term of a Commissioner ends, the Commissioner may continue to serve until a successor is appointed and qualified, but for a period not to exceed 2 years. Except as provided in paragraph (3), no individual may serve more than 3 terms.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Vacancies</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A vacancy shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment. An individual appointed to fill a vacancy is appointed only for the unexpired term to which such individual is appointed. An individual appointed to fill a vacancy may serve 3 terms in addition to the remainder of the term for which such individual was appointed.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Conflicts of interest.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on relationships with regulated entities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A Commissioner may not have a pecuniary interest in, hold an official relation to, or own stocks or bonds of any entity the Commission regulates under chapter 401 of this title.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on other activities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A Commissioner may not engage in another business, vocation, or employment.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Removal</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The President may remove a Commissioner for inefficiency, neglect of duty, or malfeasance in office.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Chairman</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The President shall designate one of the Commissioners as Chairman.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Chairman is the chief executive and administrative officer of the Commission. In carrying out the duties and powers of the Commission (other than under paragraph (3)), the Chairman is subject to the policies, regulatory decisions, findings, and determinations of the Commission.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Particular duties</inline>.—</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Chairman shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> appoint and supervise officers and employees of the Commission;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> appoint the heads of major organizational units (with such appointments subject to the approval of the Commission);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> distribute the business of the Commission among personnel and organizational units;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> supervise the expenditure of money for administrative purposes;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> assign Commission personnel, including Commissioners, to perform duties and powers delegated by the Commission under <ref>section 46104 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> prepare and submit to the President and the Congress requests for appropriations for the Commission (with such requests subject to the approval of the Commission).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Nonapplication</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subparagraph (A) (other than clause (v)) does not apply to personnel employed regularly and full-time in the offices of Commissioners other than the Chairman.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Delegation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Chairman may designate officers and employees under the Chairman’s jurisdiction to perform duties and powers of the Chairman, subject to the Chairman’s supervision and direction.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Seal</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commission shall have a seal which shall be judicially recognized.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 4</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1488</ref>, § 301; <ref>Pub. L. 113–281, title IV, § 403(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-18">Dec. 18, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3056</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–120, title IV, § 402</ref>, <date date="2016-02-08">Feb. 8, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 67</ref>; renumbered § 46101 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXVI</ref> [LXXXVI], § 8605(a)(3), (b)(1), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4765</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. K, title CXVIII, § 11801(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4163</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 46102.</num>
<heading> Quorum</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A vacancy or vacancies in the membership of the Federal Maritime Commission do not impair the power of the Commission to execute its functions. The affirmative vote of a majority of the Commissioners serving on the Commission is required to dispose of any matter before the Commission.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 4</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1489</ref>, § 302; renumbered § 46102, <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXVI</ref> [LXXXVI], § 8605(a)(3), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4765</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 46103.</num>
<heading> Meetings</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Federal Maritime Commission shall be deemed to be an agency for purposes of <ref>section 552b of title 5</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Record</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commission, through its secretary, shall keep a record of its meetings and the votes taken on any action, order, contract, or financial transaction of the Commission.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Nonpublic Collaborative Discussions.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Notwithstanding <ref>section 552b of title 5</ref>, a majority of the Commissioners may hold a meeting that is not open to public observation to discuss official agency business if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> no formal or informal vote or other official agency action is taken at the meeting;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> each individual present at the meeting is a Commissioner or an employee of the Commission;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> at least 1 Commissioner from each political party is present at the meeting, if applicable; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the General Counsel of the Commission is present at the meeting.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Disclosure of nonpublic collaborative discussions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Except as provided under paragraph (3), not later than 2 business days after the conclusion of a meeting under paragraph (1), the Commission shall make available to the public, in a place easily accessible to the public—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a list of the individuals present at the meeting; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a summary of the matters discussed at the meeting, except for any matters the Commission properly determines may be withheld from the public under <ref>section 552b(c) of title 5</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the Commission properly determines matters may be withheld from the public under <ref>section 552b(c) of title 5</ref>, the Commission shall provide a summary with as much general information as possible on those matters withheld from the public.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Ongoing proceedings</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If a meeting under paragraph (1) directly relates to an ongoing proceeding before the Commission, the Commission shall make the disclosure under paragraph (2) on the date of the final Commission decision.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Preservation of open meetings requirements for agency action</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this subsection may be construed to limit the applicability of <ref>section 552b of title 5</ref> with respect to a meeting of the Commissioners other than that described in this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Statutory construction</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Nothing in this subsection may be construed—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to limit the applicability of <ref>section 552b of title 5</ref> with respect to any information which is proposed to be withheld from the public under paragraph (2)(B) of this subsection; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to authorize the Commission to withhold from any individual any record that is accessible to that individual under <ref>section 552a of title 5</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 4</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1489</ref>, § 303; <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title VII, § 711(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4297</ref>; renumbered § 46103 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXVI</ref> [LXXXVI], § 8605(a)(3), (c), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4765</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 46104.</num>
<heading> Delegation of authority</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Delegation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Federal Maritime Commission, by published order or regulation, may delegate to a division of the Commission, an individual Commissioner, an employee board, or an officer or employee of the Commission, any of its duties or powers, including those relating to hearing, determining, ordering, certifying, reporting, or otherwise acting on any matter. This subsection does not affect <ref>section 556(b) of title 5</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Review</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commission may review any action taken under a delegation of authority under subsection (a). The review may be taken on the Commission’s own initiative or on the petition of a party to or an intervenor in the action, within the time and in the manner prescribed by the Commission. The vote of a majority of the Commission, less one member, is sufficient to bring an action before the Commission for review.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Deemed Action of Commission</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the Commission declines review, or if review is not sought, within the time prescribed under subsection (b), the action taken under the delegation of authority is deemed to be the action of the Commission.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 4</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1489</ref>, § 304; renumbered § 46104, <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXVI</ref> [LXXXVI], § 8605(a)(3), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4765</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 46105.</num>
<heading> Regulations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Federal Maritime Commission may prescribe regulations to carry out its duties and powers.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Transparency.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In conjunction with the transmittal by the President to the Congress of the Budget of the United States for fiscal year 2021 and biennially thereafter, the Federal Maritime Commission shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives reports that describe the Commission’s progress toward addressing the issues raised in each unfinished regulatory proceeding, regardless of whether the proceeding is subject to a statutory or regulatory deadline.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Format of reports</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each report under paragraph (1) shall, among other things, clearly identify for each unfinished regulatory proceeding—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the popular title;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the current stage of the proceeding;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> an abstract of the proceeding;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> what prompted the action in question;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> any applicable statutory, regulatory, or judicial deadline;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the associated docket number;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> the date the rulemaking was initiated;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> a date for the next action; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> if a date for the next action identified in the previous report is not met, the reason for the delay.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 4</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1489</ref>, § 305; renumbered § 46105 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXVI</ref> [LXXXVI], §§ 8603, 8605(a)(3), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4761</ref>, 4765.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 46106.</num>
<heading> Annual report and public disclosure</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than April 1 of each year, the Federal Maritime Commission shall submit a report to Congress. The report shall include the results of its investigations, a summary of its transactions, the purposes for which all of its expenditures were made, and any recommendations for legislation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report on Foreign Laws and Practices</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Commission shall include in its annual report to Congress—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a list of the 20 foreign countries that generated the largest volume of oceanborne liner cargo for the most recent calendar year in bilateral trade with the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an analysis of conditions described in <ref>section 42302(a) of this title</ref> being investigated or found to exist in foreign countries;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> any actions being taken by the Commission to offset those conditions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> any recommendations for additional legislation to offset those conditions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> a list of petitions filed under <ref>section 42302(b) of this title</ref> that the Commission rejected and the reasons for each rejection;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> an analysis of the impacts on competition for the purchase of certain covered services by alliances of ocean common carriers acting pursuant to an agreement under this part <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002021">1</ref> between or among ocean common carriers, including a summary of actions, including corrective actions, taken by the Commission to promote such competition; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<chapeau> an identification of any otherwise concerning practices by ocean common carriers, particularly such carriers that are controlled carriers, that are—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> State-owned or State-controlled enterprises; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> owned or controlled by, a subsidiary of, or otherwise related legally or financially (other than a minority relationship or investment) to a corporation based in a country—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> identified as a nonmarket economy country (as defined in section 771(18) of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<ref>19 U.S.C. 1677(18)</ref>)) as of the date of enactment of this paragraph;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> identified by the United States Trade Representative in the most recent report required by section 182 of the Trade Act of 1974 (<ref>19 U.S.C. 2242</ref>) as a priority foreign country under subsection (a)(2) of that section; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> subject to monitoring by the United States Trade Representative under section 306 of the Trade Act of 1974 (<ref>19 U.S.C. 2416</ref>).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition of Certain Covered Services</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “certain covered services” has the meaning given the term in section 40102.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Public Disclosures</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Federal Maritime Commission shall publish, and annually update, on the website of the Commission—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> all findings by the Commission of false detention and demurrage invoice information by common carriers under <ref>section 41104(a)(15) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> all penalties imposed or assessed against common carriers, as applicable, under sections 41107, 41108, and 41109, listed by each common carrier.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 4</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1489</ref>, § 306; <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title VII, § 703</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4294</ref>; renumbered § 46106, <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXVI</ref> [LXXXVI], § 8605(a)(3), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4765</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–146</ref>, §§ 6, 14, <date date="2022-06-16">June 16, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 1274</ref>, 1279; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. C, title XXXV, § 3535(j)(1)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2315</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 46107.</num>
<heading> Expenditures</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Federal Maritime Commission may make such expenditures as are necessary in the performance of its functions from funds appropriated or otherwise made available to it, which appropriations are authorized.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding subsection (a), the Federal Maritime Commission may not expend any funds appropriated or otherwise made available to it to a non-Federal entity to issue an award, prize, commendation, or other honor that is not related to the purposes set forth in section 40101.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 4</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1490</ref>, § 307; <ref>Pub. L. 114–120, title IV, § 403</ref>, <date date="2016-02-08">Feb. 8, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 67</ref>; renumbered § 46107, <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXVI</ref> [LXXXVI], § 8605(a)(3), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4765</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 46108.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Federal Maritime Commission $32,869,000 for fiscal year 2022, $38,260,000 for fiscal year 2023, $43,720,000 for fiscal year 2024, and $49,200,000 for fiscal year 2025 for the activities of the Commission authorized under this chapter and subtitle IV.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–120, title IV, § 401(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-02-08">Feb. 8, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 67</ref>, § 308; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title VII, § 702</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4294</ref>; renumbered § 46108 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXVI</ref> [LXXXVI], §§ 8602, 8605(a)(3), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4761</ref>, 4765; <ref>Pub. L. 117–146, § 26</ref>, <date date="2022-06-16">June 16, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 1286</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>