<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 521—</num>
<heading>MISCELLANEOUS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 52101.</num>
<heading> Reemployment rights for certain merchant seamen</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An individual who is certified by the Secretary of Transportation under subsection (c) shall be entitled to reemployment rights and other benefits substantially equivalent to the rights and benefits provided for by chapter 43 of title 38 for any member of a reserve component of the armed forces of the United States who is ordered to active duty.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Time for Application</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An individual may submit an application for certification under subsection (c) to the Secretary not later than 45 days after the date the individual completes a period of employment described in subsection (c)(1)(A) with respect to which the application is submitted.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Certification Determination</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not later than 20 days after the date the Secretary receives from an individual an application for certification under this subsection, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> determine whether the individual—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> was employed in the activation or operation of a vessel—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> in the National Defense Reserve Fleet maintained under section 57100 in a period in which the vessel was in use or being activated for use under subsection (b) of that section;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> requisitioned or purchased under chapter 563 of this title; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> owned, chartered, or controlled by the United States Government and used by the Government for a war, armed conflict, national emergency, or maritime mobilization need (including for training purposes or testing for readiness and suitability for mission performance); and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> during the period of that employment, possessed a valid license, certificate of registry, or merchant mariner’s document issued under chapter 71 or 73 of this title; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> if the Secretary makes affirmative determinations under subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (1), certify that individual under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Equivalence to Military Selective Service Act Certificate</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of reemployment rights and benefits provided by this section, a certification under subsection (c) shall be considered to be the equivalent of a certificate described in section 9(a) of the Military Selective Service Act (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3808(a)</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1585</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. C, title XXXV, § 3502(b)(4)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1910</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. C, title XXXV, § 3546(m)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2327</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>