<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 517—</num>
<heading>OTHER SUPPORT FOR MERCHANT MARINE TRAINING</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 51701.</num>
<heading> United States Maritime Service</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Transportation may establish and maintain a voluntary organization, to be known as the United States Maritime Service, for the training of citizens of the United States to serve on merchant vessels of the United States and to perform functions to assist the United States merchant marine, as determined necessary by the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Specific Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> determine the number of individuals to be enrolled for training and reserve purposes in the Service;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> fix the rates of pay and allowances of the individuals without regard to chapter 51 or subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> prescribe the course of study and the periods of training for the Service; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> prescribe the uniform of the Service and the rules on providing and wearing the uniform.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Ranks, Grades, and Ratings</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The ranks, grades, and ratings for personnel of the Service shall be the same as those prescribed for personnel of the Coast Guard.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Medals and Awards</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may establish and maintain a medals and awards program to recognize distinguished service, superior achievement, professional performance, and other commendable achievement by personnel of the Service.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1582</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. C, title XXXV, § 3509</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3557</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. C, title XXXV, § 3510(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2520</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. C, title XXXV, § 3523(a)(4)</ref>, (b), <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 599</ref>, 600.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 51702.</num>
<heading> Civilian nautical schools</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “civilian nautical school” means a school operated in the United States (except the United States Merchant Marine Academy, a State maritime academy, or another school operated by the United States Government) that offers instruction to individuals quartered on a vessel primarily to train them for service in the merchant marine.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inspection</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each civilian nautical school is subject to inspection by the Secretary of Transportation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rating and Certification</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may, under regulations the Secretary may prescribe, provide for the rating and certification of civilian nautical schools as to the adequacy of their course of instruction, the competence of their instructors, and the suitability of the equipment used in their course of instruction.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1582</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 51703.</num>
<heading> Additional training</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Transportation may provide additional training on maritime subjects to supplement other training opportunities and make the training available to the personnel of the merchant marine of the United States and individuals preparing for a career in the merchant marine of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Equipment, Supplies, and Contracts</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> prepare or buy equipment or supplies required for the additional training; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> without regard to section 6101(b) to (d) of title 41, make contracts for services the Secretary considers necessary to prepare the equipment and supplies and to supervise and administer the additional training.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1583</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 5(n)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3853</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 51704.</num>
<heading> Training for maritime oil pollution prevention, response, and clean-up</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Assistance in Establishing Program</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Transportation shall assist maritime training institutions approved by the Secretary in establishing a training program for maritime oil pollution prevention, response, and clean-up.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Providing Training Vessels</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to subsection (c), the Secretary may provide, with title free of all liens, to maritime training institutions that have a program established under subsection (a), offshore supply vessels and tug/supply vessels that were built in the United States and are in the possession of the Maritime Administration because of a default on a loan guaranteed under chapter 537 of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In addition to any other requirements the Secretary considers appropriate, the following requirements apply to vessels provided under this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The vessel shall be offered to the institution at a location selected by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The institution shall use the vessel to train students and appropriate maritime industry personnel in oil spill prevention, response, clean-up, and related skills.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The institution shall make the vessel and qualified students available to appropriate Federal, State, and local oil spill response authorities when there is a maritime oil spill.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The institution may not sell, trade, charter, donate, scrap, or in any way alter or dispose of the vessel without prior approval of the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The institution may not use the vessel in competition with a privately-owned vessel documented under chapter 121 of this title or titled under the law of a State, unless necessary to carry out this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> When the institution can no longer use the vessel for its training program, the institution shall return the vessel to the Secretary. The Secretary shall take possession at the institution and thereafter may provide the vessel to another institution under this section or dispose of the vessel.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1583</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 51705.</num>
<heading> Training for use of force against piracy</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of Transportation, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating, shall certify a training curriculum for United States mariners on the use of force against pirates. The curriculum shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> information on waters designated as high-risk waters by the Commandant of the Coast Guard;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> information on current threats and patterns of attack by pirates;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> tactics for defense of a vessel, including instruction on the types, use, and limitations of security equipment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> standard rules for the use of force for self-defense as developed by the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating under section 912(c) of the Coast Guard Authorization Act of 2010 (<ref>Public Law 111–281</ref>; <ref>46 U.S.C. 8107</ref> note), including instruction on firearm safety for crewmembers of vessels carrying cargo under <ref>section 55305 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> procedures to follow to improve crewmember survivability if captured and taken hostage by pirates.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 112–213, title V, § 502(a)</ref>, <date date="2012-12-20">Dec. 20, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1574</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 51706.</num>
<heading> Centers of excellence for domestic maritime workforce training and education</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Designation.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Transportation, after consultation with the Coast Guard, may designate, for a 5-year period, as a center of excellence for domestic maritime workforce training and education an entity which is a covered training entity.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Withdrawal of designation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Transportation may withdraw a designation as a center of excellence for domestic maritime workforce training and education of a covered training entity upon discovery of adverse information, including discovery of information that the covered training entity has engaged in fraudulent or unlawful activities, or has been subjected to disciplinary or adverse administrative action by Federal, State, or other regulatory bodies.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Grant Program.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may award a maritime career training grant to a center of excellence designated under subsection (a) for the purpose of developing, offering, or improving career and technical education or training programs related to the United States maritime industry for United States workers.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Grant proposal</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>To be eligible to receive a grant under this subsection, a center of excellence designated under subsection (a) shall submit to the Secretary a grant proposal that includes a detailed description of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the specific project proposed to be funded by the grant, including a description of the manner in which the grant will be used to develop, offer, or improve a career and technical education or training program that is suited to United States maritime industry workers;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the extent to which the project for which the grant proposal is submitted will meet the educational or career training needs of United States maritime industry workers;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any previous experience of the center of excellence in providing United States maritime industry career and technical education or training programs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> how the project proposed to be funded by the grant would address shortcomings in existing educational or career training opportunities available to United States maritime industry workers; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the extent to which employers, including small and medium-sized firms, have demonstrated a commitment to employing United States maritime industry workers who would benefit from the project for which the grant proposal is submitted.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Criteria for award of grants</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subject to the appropriation of funds to carry out this section, the Secretary shall award grants under this subsection to centers of excellence based on—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an determination of the merits of a grant proposal submitted under paragraph (2) to develop, offer, or improve career and technical education or training programs to be made available to United States maritime industry workers;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an evaluation of the likely employment opportunities available to United States maritime industry workers who complete a maritime career and technical education or training program that a center proposes to develop, offer, or improve; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> an evaluation of prior demand for training programs by workers served by centers of excellence designated under subsection (a), as well as the availability and capacity of existing maritime training programs to meet future demand for training programs.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Competitive awards.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall award grants under this subsection to centers of excellence designated under subsection (a) on a competitive basis.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Timing of grant notice</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall post a Notice of Funding Opportunity regarding grants awarded under this subsection not more than 90 days after the date of the enactment of the appropriations Act for the fiscal year concerned.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Timing of grants</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall award grants under this subsection not later than 270 days after the date of the enactment of the appropriations Act for the fiscal year concerned.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reuse of unexpended grant funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding subparagraph (C), amounts awarded as a grant under this subsection that are not expended by the grantee shall remain available to the Secretary for use for grants under this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Administrative costs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not more than 3 percent of amounts made available to carry out this subsection may be used for the necessary costs of grant administration.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibited use</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A center of excellence designated under subsection (a) that has received funds awarded under section 54101(a)(2) for training purposes for a fiscal year shall not be eligible for grants under this subsection during the same fiscal year.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Eligible uses of grant funds</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A center of excellence receiving a grant under this subsection shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> carry out activities that are identified as priorities for the purpose of developing, offering, or improving educational or career training programs for the United States maritime industry workforce; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provide training to upgrade the skills of the United States maritime industry workforce, including training to acquire covered requirements as well as technical skills training for jobs in the United States maritime industry.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section,</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered training entity</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “covered training entity” means an entity that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> is located in a State that borders on the—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Gulf of Mexico;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Atlantic Ocean;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Long Island Sound;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> Pacific Ocean;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> Great Lakes; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> Mississippi River System;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> is—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a postsecondary educational institution (as such term is defined in section 3(39) of the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 (<ref>20 U.S.C. 2302</ref>));</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a postsecondary vocational institution (as such term is defined in section 102(c) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<ref>20 U.S.C. 1002(c)</ref>); <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002029">1</ref></content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a public or private nonprofit entity that offers one or more other structured experiential learning training programs for United States workers in the United States maritime industry, including a program that is offered by a labor organization or conducted in partnership with a nonprofit organization or one or more employers in the United States maritime industry;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> an entity sponsoring an apprenticeship program registered with the Office of Apprenticeship of the Employment and Training Administration of the Department of Labor or a State apprenticeship agency recognized by the Office of Apprenticeship pursuant to the Act of <date date="1937-08-16">August 16, 1937</date> (commonly known as the ‘National Apprenticeship Act’; <ref>50 Stat. 664</ref>, chapter 663; <ref>29 U.S.C. 50</ref> et seq.); or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> a maritime training center designated prior to the date of enactment of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2023;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> has a demonstrated record of success in maritime workforce training and education; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> has—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> not been subject to a disciplinary or adverse administrative action by Federal, State, or other regulatory bodies;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> no unresolved nonconformities from administrative audits by regulatory bodies; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> not been subject to any adverse criminal action by a Federal, State, or local law enforcement authority.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Arctic</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “Arctic” has the meaning that term has under section 112 of the Arctic Research and Policy Act of 1984 (<ref>15 U.S.C. 4111</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Career and technical education</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “career and technical education” has the meaning given such term in section 3(5) of the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002030">2</ref> (<ref>20 U.S.C. 2302</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Secretary</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Transportation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Training program</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “training program” means a program that provides training services, as described in section 134(c)(3)(D) of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<ref>Public Law 113–128</ref>; <ref>29 U.S.C. 3174</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">United states maritime industry</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “United States maritime industry” means the design, construction, repair, operation, manning, and supply of vessels in all segments of the maritime transportation system of the United States, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the domestic and foreign trade;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the coastal, offshore, and inland trade;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> non-commercial maritime activities, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> recreational boating; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> oceanographic and limnological research as described in section 2101(24).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. C, title XXXV, § 3507(a)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1914</ref>, § 54102; renumbered § 51706, <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. C, title XXXV, § 3507(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4405</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. C, title XXXV, § 3532(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3089</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. C, title XXXV, § 3534(k)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 834</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 51707.</num>
<heading> Merchant mariner recruitment, training, and retention strategic plan</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002031">1</ref> <inline class="small-caps">Strategic Plan.—</inline></heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this section, and at least once every five years thereafter until the termination date under paragraph (6), the Secretary of Transportation, acting through the Administrator of the Maritime Administration, shall publish in the Federal Register a plan to recruit, train, and retain merchant mariners for the five-year period following the date of publication of the most recently published plan under this paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contents</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A plan published under paragraph (1) shall contain—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a strategy to address merchant mariner recruitment, training, and retention issues in the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> demonstration and research priorities concerning merchant mariner recruitment, training, and retention.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Factors</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In developing a plan under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall take into account, at a minimum—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the availability of existing research (as of the date of publication of the plan); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the need to ensure results that have broad applicability for the United States merchant marine workforce development.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consultation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In developing a plan under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall consult with representatives of the maritime industry, labor organizations, including the Commander of the Transportation Command and the Commander of the Military Sealift Command, and other governmental entities and stakeholders in the maritime industry.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transmittal to congress</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall transmit copies of any plan published under paragraph (1) to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Termination date</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The requirement to publish a plan under this paragraph shall terminate on the date that the Administrator of the Maritime Administration determines that there is an adequate number of United States mariners for sustained strategic sealift.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. C, title XXXV, § 3508(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4405</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>