<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 511—</num>
<heading>GENERAL</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 51101.</num>
<heading> Policy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is the policy of the United States that merchant marine vessels of the United States should be operated by highly trained and efficient citizens of the United States and that the United States Navy and the merchant marine of the United States should work closely together to promote the maximum integration of the total seapower forces of the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1568</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 51102.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this part:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Academy</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “Academy” means the United States Merchant Marine Academy located at Kings Point, New York, and maintained under chapter 513 of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Cost of education provided</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “cost of education provided” means the financial costs incurred by the United States Government for providing training or financial assistance to students at the Academy and the State maritime academies, including direct financial assistance, room, board, classroom academics, and other training activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Merchant marine officer</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “merchant marine officer” means an individual issued a license by the Coast Guard authorizing service as—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> a master, mate, or pilot on a documented vessel that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is of at least 1,000 gross tons as measured under <ref>section 14502 of this title</ref> or an alternate tonnage measured under <ref>section 14302 of this title</ref> as prescribed by the Secretary under <ref>section 14104 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> operates on the oceans or the Great Lakes; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an engineer officer on a documented vessel propelled by machinery of at least 4,000 horsepower.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">State maritime academy</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “State maritime academy” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a State maritime academy or college sponsored by a State and assisted under chapter 515 of this title; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a regional maritime academy or college sponsored by a group of States and assisted under chapter 515 of this title.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1568</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 51103.</num>
<heading> General authority of Secretary of Transportation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Education and Training</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Transportation may provide for the education and training of citizens of the United States for the safe and efficient operation of the merchant marine of the United States at all times, including operation as a naval and military auxiliary in time of war or national emergency.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Property for Instructional Purposes</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may cooperate with and assist the institutions named in paragraph (2) by making vessels, fuel, shipboard equipment, and other marine equipment, owned by the United States Government and determined by the entity having custody and control of such property to be excess or surplus, available to those institutions for instructional purposes, by gift, loan, sale, lease, or charter on terms and conditions the Secretary considers appropriate. The consent of the Secretary of the Navy shall be obtained with respect to any property from National Defense Reserve Fleet vessels, if such vessels are either Ready Reserve Force vessels or other National Defense Reserve Fleet vessels determined to be of sufficient value to the Navy to warrant their further preservation and retention.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Institutions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The institutions referred to in paragraph (1) are—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the United States Merchant Marine Academy;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a State maritime academy; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a nonprofit training institution or a training institution that is an instrumentality of a State, the District of Columbia, a territory or possession of the United States, or a unit of local government thereof jointly approved by the Secretary of Transportation and the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating as offering training courses that meet Federal regulations for maritime training.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Assistance From Other Agencies</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Transportation may secure directly from an agency, on a reimbursable basis, information, facilities, and equipment necessary to carry out this part.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Detailing personnel</inline>.—</heading>
<content>At the request of the Secretary, the head of an agency (including a military department) may detail, on a reimbursable basis, personnel from the agency to the Secretary to assist in carrying out this part.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Academy Personnel</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>To carry out this part, the Secretary may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> employ an individual as a professor, lecturer, or instructor at the Academy, without regard to the provisions of title 5 governing appointments in the competitive service; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> pay the individual without regard to chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Donation for Historical Purposes.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary may convey the right, title, and interest of the United States Government in any property administered by the Maritime Administration, except real estate or vessels, if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Secretary determines that such property is not needed by the Maritime Administration; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> the recipient—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is a nonprofit organization, a State, or a political subdivision of a State;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> agrees to hold the Government harmless for any claims arising from exposure to hazardous materials, including asbestos, polychlorinated biphenyls, or lead paint, after conveyance of the property;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> provides a description and explanation of the intended use of the property to the Secretary for approval;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> has provided to the Secretary proof, as determined by the Secretary, of resources sufficient to accomplish the intended use provided under clause (iii) and to maintain the property;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<chapeau> agrees that when the recipient no longer requires the property, the recipient shall—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> return the property to the Secretary, at the recipient’s expense and in the same condition as received except for ordinary wear and tear; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> subject to the approval of the Secretary, retain, sell, or otherwise dispose of the property in a manner consistent with applicable law; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> agrees to any additional terms the Secretary considers appropriate.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reversion</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall include in any conveyance under this subsection terms under which all right, title, and interest conveyed by the Secretary shall revert to the Government if the Secretary determines the property has been used other than as approved by the Secretary under paragraph (1)(B)(iii).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1569</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–213, title IV, § 404</ref>, <date date="2012-12-20">Dec. 20, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1570</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–281, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="2014-12-18">Dec. 18, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3042</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 51104.</num>
<heading> General authority of Secretary of the Navy</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of the Navy, in cooperation with the Maritime Administrator and the head of each State maritime academy, shall ensure that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the training of future merchant marine officers at the United States Merchant Marine Academy and at State maritime academies includes programs for naval science training in the operation of merchant vessels as a naval and military auxiliary; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> naval officer training programs for future officers, insofar as possible, are maintained at designated maritime academies consistent with Navy standards and needs.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1570</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>