<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 73—</num>
<heading>MERCHANT MARINERS’ DOCUMENTS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7301.</num>
<heading> General</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> In this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “service on deck” means service in the deck department in work related to the work usually performed on board vessels by able seamen and may include service on fishing, fish processing, fish tender vessels and on public vessels of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> 360 days is equal to one year’s service; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a day is equal to 8 hours of labor or duty.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Secretary may prescribe regulations to carry out this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 541</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–364, title IV, § 402(9)(B)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-17">July 17, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 448</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7302.</num>
<heading> Issuing merchant mariners’ documents and continuous discharge books</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall issue a merchant mariner’s document to an individual required to have that document under part F of this subtitle if the individual satisfies the requirements of this part. The document serves as a certificate of identification and as a certificate of service, specifying each rating in which the holder is qualified to serve on board vessels on which that document is required under part F.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Secretary also may issue a continuous discharge book to an individual issued a merchant mariner’s document if the individual requests.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Secretary may not issue a merchant mariner’s document under this chapter unless the individual applying for the document makes available to the Secretary, under <ref>section 30305(b)(5) of title 49</ref>, any information contained in the National Driver Register related to an offense described in section 30304(a)(3)(A) or (B) of title 49 committed by the individual.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The Secretary may review the criminal record of an individual who applies for a merchant mariner’s document under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall require the testing of an individual applying for issuance or renewal of a merchant mariner’s document under this chapter for the use of a dangerous drug in violation of law or Federal regulation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Periods of Validity and Renewal of Merchant Mariners’ Documents.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in subsection (g), a merchant mariner’s document issued under this chapter is valid for a 5-year period and may be renewed for additional 5-year periods.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Advance renewals</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A renewed merchant mariner’s document may be issued under this chapter up to 8 months in advance but is not effective until the date that the previously issued merchant mariner’s document expires or until the completion of any active suspension or revocation of that previously issued merchant mariner’s document, whichever is later.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary may, pending receipt and review of information required under subsections (c) and (d), immediately issue an interim merchant mariner’s document valid for a period not to exceed 120 days, to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an individual to be employed as gaming personnel, entertainment personnel, wait staff, or other service personnel on board a passenger vessel not engaged in foreign service, with no duties, including emergency duties, related to the navigation of the vessel or the safety of the vessel, its crew, cargo or passengers; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an individual seeking renewal of, or qualifying for a supplemental endorsement to, a valid merchant mariner’s document issued under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> No more than one interim document may be issued to an individual under paragraph (1)(A) of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 542</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–380, title IV</ref>, §§ 4101(b), 4102(c), <date date="1990-08-18">Aug. 18, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 509</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–295, title III, § 324(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2104</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–293, title VI, § 609(1)</ref>, <date date="2004-08-09">Aug. 9, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1058</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–241, title IX, § 901(h)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="2006-07-11">July 11, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 564</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–281, title VI, § 614(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2970</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7303.</num>
<heading> Possession and description of merchant mariners’ documents</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A merchant mariner’s document shall be retained by the individual to whom issued. The document shall contain the signature, notations of nationality, age, and physical description, the photograph, and the home address of the individual. In addition, the document shall specify the rate or ratings in which the individual is qualified to serve.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 542</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–295, title IV, § 421</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2125</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXV</ref> [LXXXV], § 8505(b)(3), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4751</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7304.</num>
<heading> Citizenship notation on merchant mariners’ documents</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An individual applying for a merchant mariner’s document shall provide satisfactory proof that the individual is a citizen of the United States before that notation is made on the document.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 542</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7305.</num>
<heading> Oaths for holders of merchant mariners’ documents</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An applicant for a merchant mariner’s document shall take, before issuance of the document, an oath that the applicant will perform faithfully and honestly all the duties required by law, and will carry out the lawful orders of superior officers.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 542</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7306.</num>
<heading> General requirements and classifications for able seamen</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> To qualify for an endorsement as able seaman authorized by this section, an applicant must provide satisfactory proof that the applicant—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> is at least 18 years of age;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> has the service required by the applicable section of this part;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> is qualified professionally as demonstrated by an applicable examination or educational requirements; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> is qualified as to sight, hearing, and physical condition to perform the seaman’s duties.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> The classifications authorized for endorsement as able seaman are the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> able seaman—unlimited.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> able seaman—limited.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> able seaman—special.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> able seaman—offshore supply vessels.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> able seaman—sail.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> able seaman—fishing industry.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 542</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–364, title IV, § 402(9)(C)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-17">July 17, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 448</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7307.</num>
<heading> Able seamen—unlimited</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The required service for the endorsement of able seaman—unlimited, qualified for unlimited service on a vessel on any waters, is at least 3 years’ <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002008">1</ref> service on deck on board vessels operating at sea or on the Great Lakes.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 543</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7308.</num>
<heading> Able seamen—limited</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The required service for the endorsement of able seaman—limited, qualified for limited service on a vessel on any waters, is at least 18 months’ <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002009">1</ref> service on deck on board vessels of at least 100 gross tons as measured under <ref>section 14502 of this title</ref>, or an alternate tonnage measured under <ref>section 14302 of this title</ref> as prescribed by the Secretary under <ref>section 14104 of this title</ref> operating on the oceans or navigable waters of the United States (including the Great Lakes).</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 543</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–324, title VII, § 721</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3938</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7309.</num>
<heading> Able seamen—special</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The required service for the endorsement of able seaman—special, qualified for special service on a vessel on any waters, is at least 12 months’ <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002010">1</ref> service on deck on board vessels operating on the oceans or the navigable waters of the United States (including the Great Lakes).</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 543</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7310.</num>
<heading> Able seamen—offshore supply vessels</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For service on a vessel of less than 500 gross tons as measured under <ref>section 14502 of this title</ref>, or an alternate tonnage measured under <ref>section 14302 of this title</ref> as prescribed by the Secretary under <ref>section 14104 of this title</ref> engaged in support of exploration, exploitation, or production of offshore mineral or energy resources, an individual may be rated as able seaman—offshore supply vessels if the individual has at least 6 months’ service on deck on board vessels operating on the oceans or the navigable waters of the United States (including the Great Lakes).</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 543</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–324, title VII, § 722</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3938</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7311.</num>
<heading> Able seamen—sail</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For service on a sailing school vessel on any waters, an individual may be rated as able seaman—sail if the individual has at least 6 months’ service on deck on sailing school vessels, oceanographic research vessels powered primarily by sail, or equivalent sailing vessels operating on the oceans or navigable waters of the United States (including the Great Lakes).</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 543</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7311a.</num>
<heading> Able seamen—fishing industry</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For service on a fish processing vessel, an individual may be rated as able seaman—fishing industry if the individual has at least 6 months’ service on deck on board vessels operating on the oceans or the navigable waters of the United States (including the Great Lakes).</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 98–364, title IV, § 402(9)(D)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-17">July 17, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 448</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7312.</num>
<heading> Scale of employment</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Individuals qualified as able seamen—unlimited under <ref>section 7307 of this title</ref> may constitute all of the able seamen required on a vessel.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Individuals qualified as able seamen—limited under <ref>section 7308 of this title</ref> may constitute all of the able seamen required on a vessel of less than 1,600 gross tons as measured under <ref>section 14502 of this title</ref>, or an alternate tonnage measured under <ref>section 14302 of this title</ref> as prescribed by the Secretary under <ref>section 14104 of this title</ref> or on a vessel operating on the Great Lakes and the Saint Lawrence River as far east as Sept Iles. Individuals qualified as able seamen—limited may constitute not more than 50 percent of the number of able seamen required on board other vessels.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> Individuals qualified as able seamen—special under <ref>section 7309 of this title</ref> may constitute—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> all of the able seamen required on a vessel of not more than 500 gross tons as measured under <ref>section 14502 of this title</ref>, or an alternate tonnage measured under <ref>section 14302 of this title</ref> as prescribed by the Secretary under <ref>section 14104 of this title</ref> or on a seagoing barge or towing vessel; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> not more than 50 percent of the number of able seamen required on board other vessels.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Individuals qualified as able seamen—offshore. supply vessel under <ref>section 7310 of this title</ref> may constitute all of the able seamen required on board a vessel of less than 500 gross tons as measured under <ref>section 14502 of this title</ref> or 6,000 gross tons as measured under <ref>section 14302 of this title</ref> engaged in support of exploration, exploitation, or production of offshore mineral or energy resources. Individuals qualified as able seamen—limited under <ref>section 7308 of this title</ref> may constitute all of the able seamen required on board a vessel of at least 500 gross tons as measured under <ref>section 14502 of this title</ref> or 6,000 gross tons as measured under section as measured under <ref>section 14302 of this title</ref> as prescribed by the Secretary under <ref>section 14104 of this title</ref> engaged in support of exploration, exploitation, or production of offshore mineral or energy resources.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> When the service of able seamen—limited or able seamen—special is authorized for only a part of the required number of able seamen on board a vessel, the combined percentage of those individuals so qualified may not be greater than 50 percent of the required number.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<chapeau> Individuals qualified as able seamen—fishing industry under <ref>section 7311a of this title</ref> may constitute—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> all of the able seamen required on a fish processing vessel entered into service before <date date="1988-01-01">January 1, 1988</date>, and of more than 1,600 gross tons but not more than 5,000 gross tons as measured under <ref>section 14502 of this title</ref>, or an alternate tonnage measured under <ref>section 14302 of this title</ref> as prescribed by the Secretary under <ref>section 14104 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> all of the able seamen required on a fish processing vessel entered into service after <date date="1987-12-31">December 31, 1987</date>, and having more than 16 individuals on board primarily employed in the preparation of fish or fish products but of not more than 5,000 gross tons as measured under <ref>section 14502 of this title</ref>, or an alternate tonnage measured under <ref>section 14302 of this title</ref> as prescribed by the Secretary under <ref>section 14104 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 543</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–364, title IV, § 402(9)(E)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-17">July 17, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 448</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–307, § 1(11)</ref>, <date date="1986-05-19">May 19, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 445</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–324, title VII, § 723</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3938</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–281, title VI, § 617(b)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2973</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7313.</num>
<heading> General requirements for members of engine departments</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Classes of endorsement as qualified members of the engine department on vessels of at least 100 gross tons as measured under <ref>section 14502 of this title</ref>, or an alternate tonnage measured under <ref>section 14302 of this title</ref> as prescribed by the Secretary under <ref>section 14104 of this title</ref> (except vessels operating on rivers or lakes (except the Great Lakes)) may be prescribed by regulation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The ratings of wiper and coal passer are entry ratings and are not ratings as qualified members of the engine department.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> An applicant for an endorsement as qualified member of the engine department must provide satisfactory proof that the applicant—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> has the service required by <ref>section 7314 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> is qualified professionally as demonstrated by an applicable examination; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> is qualified as to sight, hearing, and physical condition to perform the member’s duties.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 544</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–324, title VII, § 724</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3939</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7314.</num>
<heading> Service requirements for qualified members of engine departments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To qualify for an endorsement as qualified member of the engine department, an applicant must provide proof that the applicant has 6 months’ service in the related entry rating as described in <ref>section 7313(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 544</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7315.</num>
<heading> Training</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Graduation from a nautical school vessel approved under law and regulation may be substituted for the service requirements under section 7307 or 7314 of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The satisfactory completion of other courses of instruction approved by the Secretary may be substituted for not more than one-third of the required service on deck at sea under sections 7307–7311 of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The satisfactory completion of other courses of instruction approved by the Secretary may be substituted for not more than one-half of the required service at sea under <ref>section 7314 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 544</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7316.</num>
<heading> Lifeboatmen</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">To qualify for an endorsement as lifeboatman, an applicant must provide satisfactory proof that the applicant—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> has the service or training required by regulation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> is qualified professionally as demonstrated by examination; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> is qualified professionally by actual demonstration.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 544</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7317.</num>
<heading> Tankermen</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall prescribe procedures, standards, and qualifications for the issuance of certificates or endorsements as tankerman, stating the types of oil or hazardous material that can be handled with safety to the vessel and the marine environment.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> An endorsement as tankerman shall indicate the grades or types of cargo the holder is qualified and authorized to handle with safety on board vessels.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 545</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7318.</num>
<heading> Radiotelegraph operators on Great Lakes</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> A radiotelegraph operator on the Great Lakes only shall have a first-class or second-class radiotelegraph operator’s license issued by the Federal Communications Commission.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> An endorsement as radiotelegraph operator on the Great Lakes only ends if the holder ceases to hold the license issued by the Commission.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 545</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7319.</num>
<heading> Records of merchant mariners’ documents</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall maintain records on each merchant mariner’s document issued, including the name and address of the individual to whom issued and the next of kin of the individual.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 545</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–293, title IV, § 403</ref>, <date date="2004-08-09">Aug. 9, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1043</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXV</ref> [LXXXV], § 8505(b)(4), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4751</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>