<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 411—</num>
<heading>PROHIBITIONS AND PENALTIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 41101.</num>
<heading> Joint ventures and consortiums</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this chapter, a joint venture or consortium of two or more common carriers operating as a single entity is deemed to be a single common carrier.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 7</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1540</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 41102.</num>
<heading> General prohibitions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Obtaining Transportation at Less Than Applicable Rates</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A person may not knowingly and willfully, directly or indirectly, by means of false billing, false classification, false weighing, false report of weight, false measurement, or any other unjust or unfair device or means, obtain or attempt to obtain ocean transportation for property at less than the rates or charges that would otherwise apply.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Operating Contrary to Agreement</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A person may not operate under an agreement required to be filed under section 40302 or 40305 of this title if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the agreement has not become effective under <ref>section 40304 of this title</ref> or has been rejected, disapproved, or canceled; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the operation is not in accordance with the terms of the agreement or any modifications to the agreement made by the Federal Maritime Commission.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Practices in Handling Property</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A common carrier, marine terminal operator, or ocean transportation intermediary may not fail to establish, observe, and enforce just and reasonable regulations and practices relating to or connected with receiving, handling, storing, or delivering property.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Retaliation and Other Discriminatory Actions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A common carrier, marine terminal operator, or ocean transportation intermediary, acting alone or in conjunction with any other person, directly or indirectly, may not—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> retaliate against a shipper, an agent of a shipper, an ocean transportation intermediary, or a motor carrier by refusing, or threatening to refuse, an otherwise-available cargo space accommodation; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> resort to any other unfair or unjustly discriminatory action for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> the reason that a shipper, an agent of a shipper, an ocean transportation intermediary, or motor carrier has—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> patronized another carrier; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> filed a complaint against the common carrier, marine terminal operator, or ocean transportation intermediary; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any other reason.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 7</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1540</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–146, § 5</ref>, <date date="2022-06-16">June 16, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 1273</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 41103.</num>
<heading> Disclosure of information</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A common carrier, marine terminal operator, or ocean freight forwarder, either alone or in conjunction with any other person, directly or indirectly, may not knowingly disclose, offer, solicit, or receive any information concerning the nature, kind, quantity, destination, consignee, or routing of any property tendered or delivered to a common carrier, without the consent of the shipper or consignee, if the information—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> may be used to the detriment or prejudice of the shipper, the consignee, or any common carrier; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> may improperly disclose its business transaction to a competitor.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exceptions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subsection (a) does not prevent providing the information—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in response to legal process;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to the Federal Maritime Commission or an agency of the United States Government; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to an independent neutral body operating within the scope of its authority to fulfill the policing obligations of the parties to an agreement effective under this part.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Disclosure for Determining Breach or Compiling Statistics</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An ocean common carrier that is a party to a conference agreement approved under this part, a receiver, trustee, lessee, agent, or employee of the carrier, or any other person authorized by the carrier to receive information—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> may give information to the conference or any person or agency designated by the conference, for the purpose of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> determining whether a shipper or consignee has breached an agreement with the conference or its member lines;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> determining whether a member of the conference has breached the conference agreement; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> compiling statistics of cargo movement; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> may not prevent the conference or its designee from soliciting or receiving information for any of those purposes.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 7</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1540</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 41104.</num>
<heading> Common carriers</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A common carrier, either alone or in conjunction with any other person, directly or indirectly, shall not—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> allow a person to obtain transportation for property at less than the rates or charges established by the carrier in its tariff or service contract by means of false billing, false classification, false weighing, false measurement, or any other unjust or unfair device or means;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> provide service in the liner trade that is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> not in accordance with the rates, charges, classifications, rules, and practices contained in a tariff published or a service contract entered into under chapter 405 of this title, unless excepted or exempted under section 40103 or 40501(a)(2) of this title; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> under a tariff or service contract that has been suspended or prohibited by the Federal Maritime Commission under chapter 407 or 423 of this title;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> unreasonably refuse cargo space accommodations when available, or resort to other unfair or unjustly discriminatory methods;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> for service pursuant to a tariff, engage in any unfair or unjustly discriminatory practice in the matter of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> rates or charges;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> cargo classifications;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> cargo space accommodations or other facilities, with due regard being given to the proper loading of the vessel and the available tonnage;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> loading and landing of freight; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> adjustment and settlement of claims;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> for service pursuant to a service contract, engage in any unfair or unjustly discriminatory practice against any commodity group or type of shipment or in the matter of rates or charges with respect to any port;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> use a vessel in a particular trade for the purpose of excluding, preventing, or reducing competition by driving another ocean common carrier out of that trade;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> offer or pay any deferred rebates;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> for service pursuant to a tariff, give any undue or unreasonable preference or advantage or impose any undue or unreasonable prejudice or disadvantage;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> for service pursuant to a service contract, give any undue or unreasonable preference or advantage or impose any undue or unreasonable prejudice or disadvantage with respect to any port;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> unreasonably refuse to deal or negotiate, including with respect to vessel space accommodations provided by an ocean common carrier;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> knowingly and willfully accept cargo from or transport cargo for the account of a non-vessel-operating common carrier that does not have a tariff as required by <ref>section 40501 of this title</ref>, or an ocean transportation intermediary that does not have a bond, insurance, or other surety as required by <ref>section 40902 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> knowingly and willfully enter into a service contract with an ocean transportation intermediary that does not have a tariff as required by <ref>section 40501 of this title</ref> and a bond, insurance, or other surety as required by <ref>section 40902 of this title</ref>, or with an affiliate of such an ocean transportation intermediary;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> continue to participate simultaneously in a rate discussion agreement and an agreement to share vessels, in the same trade, if the interplay of the authorities exercised by the specified agreements is likely, by a reduction in competition, to produce an unreasonable reduction in transportation service or an unreasonable increase in transportation cost;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> assess any party for a charge that is inconsistent or does not comply with all applicable provisions and regulations, including subsection (c) of section 41102 or part 545 of title 46, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<chapeau> invoice any party for demurrage or detention charges unless the invoice includes information as described in subsection (d) showing that such charges comply with—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> all provisions of part 545 of title 46, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> applicable provisions and regulations, including the principles of the final rule published on <date date="2020-05-18">May 18, 2020</date>, entitled “Interpretive Rule on Demurrage and Detention Under the Shipping Act” (or successor rule); or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(16)</num>
<content> for service pursuant to a service contract, give any undue or unreasonable preference or advantage or impose any undue or unreasonable prejudice or disadvantage against any commodity group or type of shipment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rule of Construction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, there is no private right of action to enforce the prohibition under subsection (a)(13).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Agreement Violation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Participants in an agreement found by the Commission to violate subsection (a)(13) shall have 90 days from the date of such Commission finding to withdraw from the agreement as necessary to comply with that subsection.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Detention and Demurrage Invoice Information.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inaccurate invoice</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the Commission determines, after an investigation in response to a submission under section 41310, that an invoice under subsection (a)(15) was inaccurate or false, penalties or refunds under section 41107 shall be applied.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contents of invoice</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An invoice under subsection (a)(15), unless otherwise determined by subsequent Commission rulemaking, shall include accurate information on each of the following, as well as minimum information as determined by the Commission:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Date that container is made available.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The port of discharge.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The container number or numbers.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> For exported shipments, the earliest return date.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The allowed free time in days.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> The start date of free time.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> The end date of free time.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> The applicable detention or demurrage rule on which the daily rate is based.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> The applicable rate or rates per the applicable rule.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> The total amount due.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> The email, telephone number, or other appropriate contact information for questions or requests for mitigation of fees.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(L)</num>
<content> A statement that the charges are consistent with any of Federal Maritime Commission rules with respect to detention and demurrage.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(M)</num>
<content> A statement that the common carrier’s performance did not cause or contribute to the underlying invoiced charges.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Safe Harbor</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If a non-vessel operating common carrier passes through to the relevant shipper an invoice made by the ocean common carrier, and the Commission finds that the non-vessel operating common carrier is not otherwise responsible for the charge, then the ocean common carrier shall be subject to refunds or penalties pursuant to subsection (d)(1).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Elimination of Charge Obligation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Failure to include the information required under subsection (d) on an invoice with any demurrage or detention charge shall eliminate any obligation of the charged party to pay the applicable charge.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 7</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1541</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title VII, § 708(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4295</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–146, § 7(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-06-16">June 16, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 1274</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 41105.</num>
<heading> Concerted action</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A conference or group of two or more common carriers may not—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> boycott or take any other concerted action resulting in an unreasonable refusal to deal;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> engage in conduct that unreasonably restricts the use of intermodal services or technological innovations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> engage in any predatory practice designed to eliminate the participation, or deny the entry, in a particular trade of a common carrier not a member of the conference, a group of common carriers, an ocean tramp, or a bulk carrier;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> negotiate with a non-ocean carrier or group of non-ocean carriers (such as truck, rail, or air operators) on any matter relating to rates or services provided to ocean common carriers within the United States by those non-ocean carriers, unless the negotiations and any resulting agreements are not in violation of the antitrust laws and are consistent with the purposes of this part, except that this paragraph does not prohibit the setting and publishing of a joint through rate by a conference, joint venture, or association of ocean common carriers;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> negotiate with a tug or towing vessel service provider on any matter relating to rates or services provided within the United States by those tugs or towing vessels;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> with respect to a vessel operated by an ocean common carrier within the United States, negotiate for the purchase of certain covered services, unless the negotiations and any resulting agreements are not in violation of the antitrust laws and are consistent with the purposes of this part, except that this paragraph does not prohibit the setting and publishing of a joint through rate by a conference, joint venture, or association of ocean common carriers;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> deny in the export foreign commerce of the United States compensation to an ocean freight forwarder or limit that compensation to less than a reasonable amount;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<chapeau> allocate shippers among specific carriers that are parties to the agreement or prohibit a carrier that is a party to the agreement from soliciting cargo from a particular shipper, except as—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> authorized by <ref>section 40303(d) of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> required by the law of the United States or the importing or exporting country; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> agreed to by a shipper in a service contract;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> for service pursuant to a service contract, engage in any unjustly discriminatory practice in the matter of rates or charges with respect to any locality, port, or person due to the person’s status as a shippers’ association or ocean transportation intermediary; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> for service pursuant to a service contract, give any undue or unreasonable preference or advantage or impose any undue or unreasonable prejudice or disadvantage with respect to any locality, port, or person due to the person’s status as a shippers’ association or ocean transportation intermediary.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 7</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1542</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title VII, § 709(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4296</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 41105A.</num>
<heading> Authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in section 41105, as amended by the Federal Maritime Commission Authorization Act of 2017, shall be construed to limit the authority of the Department of Justice regarding antitrust matters.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title VII, § 709(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4296</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 41106.</num>
<heading> Marine terminal operators</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A marine terminal operator may not—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> agree with another marine terminal operator or with a common carrier to boycott, or unreasonably discriminate in the provision of terminal services to, a common carrier or ocean tramp;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> give any undue or unreasonable preference or advantage or impose any undue or unreasonable prejudice or disadvantage with respect to any person; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> unreasonably refuse to deal or negotiate.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 7</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1543</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 41107.</num>
<heading> Monetary penalties or refunds</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A person that violates this part or a regulation or order of the Federal Maritime Commission issued under this part is liable to the United States Government for a civil penalty or, in addition to or in lieu of a civil penalty, is liable for the refund of a charge. Unless otherwise provided in this part, the amount of the penalty may not exceed $5,000 for each violation or, if the violation was willfully and knowingly committed, $25,000 for each violation. Each day of a continuing violation is a separate violation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Lien on Carrier’s Vessels</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The amount of a civil penalty or, in addition to or in lieu of a civil penalty, the refund of a charge, imposed on a common carrier under this section constitutes a lien on the vessels operated by the carrier. Any such vessel is subject to an action in rem to enforce the lien in the district court of the United States for the district in which it is found.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 7</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1543</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–146, § 8(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2022-06-16">June 16, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 1276</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 41108.</num>
<heading> Additional penalties</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Suspension of Tariffs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For a violation of paragraph (1), (2), or (7) of <ref>section 41104(a) of this title</ref>, the Federal Maritime Commission may suspend any or all tariffs of the common carrier, or that common carrier’s right to use any or all tariffs of conferences of which it is a member, for a period not to exceed 12 months.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Operating Under Suspended Tariff</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A common carrier that accepts or handles cargo for carriage under a tariff that has been suspended, or after its right to use that tariff has been suspended, is liable to the United States Government for a civil penalty of not more than $50,000 for each shipment.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Failure To Provide Information</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Penalties</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>If the Commission finds, after notice and opportunity for a hearing, that a common carrier has failed to supply information ordered to be produced or compelled by subpoena under <ref>section 41303 of this title</ref>, the Commission may—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> suspend any or all tariffs of the carrier or the carrier’s right to use any or all tariffs of conferences of which it is a member; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> request the Secretary of Homeland Security to refuse or revoke any clearance required for a vessel operated by the carrier, and when so requested, the Secretary shall refuse or revoke the clearance.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Defense based on foreign law</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If, in defense of its failure to comply with a subpoena or discovery order, a common carrier alleges that information or documents located in a foreign country cannot be produced because of the laws of that country, the Commission shall immediately notify the Secretary of State of the failure to comply and of the allegation relating to foreign laws. On receiving the notification, the Secretary of State shall promptly consult with the government of the nation within which the information or documents are alleged to be located for the purpose of assisting the Commission in obtaining the information or documents.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Impairing Access to Foreign Trade</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the Commission finds, after notice and opportunity for a hearing, that the action of a common carrier, acting alone or in concert with another person, or a foreign government has unduly impaired access of a vessel documented under the laws of the United States to ocean trade between foreign ports, the Commission shall take action that it finds appropriate, including imposing any of the penalties authorized by this section. The Commission also may take any of the actions authorized by sections 42304 and 42305 of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Submission of Order to President</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Before an order under this section becomes effective, it shall be submitted immediately to the President. The President, within 10 days after receiving it, may disapprove it if the President finds that disapproval is required for reasons of national defense or foreign policy.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 7</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1543</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–146, § 15(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-06-16">June 16, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 1279</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 41109.</num>
<heading> Assessment of penalties</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Until a matter is referred to the Attorney General, the Federal Maritime Commission may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> after notice and opportunity for a hearing, in accordance with this part—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> assess a civil penalty; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in addition to, or in lieu of, assessing a civil penalty under subparagraph (A), order a refund of money (including additional amounts in accordance with section 41305(c)), subject to subsection (b)(2); and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> compromise, modify, or remit, with or without conditions, a civil penalty or refund imposed under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Determination of Amount.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Factors for consideration</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In determining the amount of a civil penalty assessed or refund of money ordered pursuant to subsection (a), the Federal Maritime Commission shall take into consideration—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the nature, circumstances, extent, and gravity of the violation committed;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> with respect to the violator—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the degree of culpability;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any history of prior offenses;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the ability to pay; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> such other matters as justice may require; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the amount of any refund of money ordered pursuant to subsection (a)(1)(B).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Commensurate reduction in civil penalty.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In any case in which the Federal Maritime Commission orders a refund of money pursuant to subsection (a)(1)(B) in addition to assessing a civil penalty pursuant to subsection (a)(1)(A), the amount of the civil penalty assessed shall be decreased by any additional amounts included in the refund of money in excess of the actual injury (as defined in section 41305(a)).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Treatment of refunds</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A refund of money ordered pursuant to subsection (a)(1)(B) shall be—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> considered to be compensation paid to the applicable claimant; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> deducted from the total amount of damages awarded to that claimant in a civil action against the violator relating to the applicable violation.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A civil penalty or refund of money under subparagraph (A) or (B), respectively, of subsection (a)(1) may not be imposed for conspiracy to violate subsection (a) or (d) of section 41102 or paragraph (1) or (2) of section 41104(a) or to defraud the Commission by concealing such a violation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibited Basis of Penalty</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commission or a court may not order a person to pay the difference between the amount billed and agreed upon in writing with a common carrier or its agent and the amount set forth in a tariff or service contract by that common carrier for the transportation service provided.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Time Limit</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A proceeding to assess a civil penalty or order a refund of money under this section must be commenced within 5 years after the date of the violation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Review of Civil Penalty</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A person against whom a civil penalty is assessed, or that is ordered to refund money, under this section may obtain review under chapter 158 of title 28.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Civil Actions To Collect</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If a person does not pay an assessment of a civil penalty or a refund required under this section after it has become final or after the appropriate court has entered final judgment in favor of the Commission, the Attorney General at the request of the Commission may seek to collect the amount assessed in an appropriate district court of the United States. The court shall enforce the order of the Commission unless it finds that the order was not regularly made and duly issued.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 7</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1544</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–146</ref>, §§ 8(a)(2), 15(b), <date date="2022-06-16">June 16, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 1276</ref>, 1279.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 41110.</num>
<heading> Data collection</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Federal Maritime Commission shall publish on its website a calendar quarterly report that describes the total import and export tonnage and the total loaded and empty 20-foot equivalent units per vessel (making port in the United States, including any territory or possession of the United States) operated by each ocean common carrier covered under this chapter. Ocean common carriers under this chapter shall provide to the Commission all necessary information, as determined by the Commission, for completion of this report.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–146, § 9(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-06-16">June 16, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 1277</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>