<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 21—</num>
<heading>GENERAL</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2101.</num>
<heading> General definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this subtitle—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> “associated equipment”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> means—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a system, accessory, component, or appurtenance of a recreational vessel; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a marine safety article intended for use on board a recreational vessel; but</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> with the exception of emergency locator beacons for recreational vessels operating beyond 3 nautical miles from the baselines from which the territorial sea of the United States is measured or beyond 3 nautical miles from the coastline of the Great Lakes, does not include radio equipment.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> “Coast Guard” means the organization established and continued under section 1 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002001">1</ref> of title 14.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> “Commandant” means the Commandant of the Coast Guard.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> “commercial service” includes any type of trade or business involving the transportation of goods or individuals, except service performed by a combatant vessel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> “consideration” means an economic benefit, inducement, right, or profit including pecuniary payment accruing to an individual, person, or entity, but not including a voluntary sharing of the actual expenses of the voyage, by monetary contribution or donation of fuel, food, beverage, or other supplies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> “crude oil” means a liquid hydrocarbon mixture occurring naturally in the earth, whether or not treated to render it suitable for transportation, and includes crude oil from which certain distillate fractions may have been removed, and crude oil to which certain distillate fractions may have been added.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> “crude oil tanker” means a tanker engaged in the trade of carrying crude oil.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> “dangerous drug” means a narcotic drug, a controlled substance, or a controlled substance analog (as defined in section 102 of the Comprehensive Drug Abuse Prevention and Control Act of 1970 (<ref>21 U.S.C. 802</ref>)).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> “discharge”, when referring to a substance discharged from a vessel, includes spilling, leaking, pumping, pouring, emitting, emptying, or dumping, however caused.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<chapeau> “ferry” means a vessel that is used on a regular schedule—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to provide transportation only between places that are not more than 300 miles apart; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> to transport only—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> passengers; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> vehicles, or railroad cars, that are being used, or have been used, in transporting passengers or goods.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> “fish” means finfish, mollusks, crustaceans, and all other forms of marine animal and plant life, except marine mammals and birds.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> “fishing vessel” means a vessel that commercially engages in the catching, taking, or harvesting of fish or an activity that can reasonably be expected to result in the catching, taking, or harvesting of fish.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> “fish processing vessel” means a vessel that commercially prepares fish or fish products other than by gutting, decapitating, gilling, skinning, shucking, icing, freezing, or brine chilling.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> “fish tender vessel” means a vessel that commercially supplies, stores, refrigerates, or transports fish, fish products, or materials directly related to fishing or the preparation of fish to or from a fishing, fish processing, or fish tender vessel or a fish processing facility.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<content> “freight vessel” means a motor vessel of more than 15 gross tons as measured under <ref>section 14502 of this title</ref>, or an alternate tonnage measured under <ref>section 14302 of this title</ref> as prescribed by the Secretary under <ref>section 14104 of this title</ref> that carries freight for hire, except an oceanographic research vessel or an offshore supply vessel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(16)</num>
<content> “Great Lakes barge” means a non-self-propelled vessel of at least 3,500 gross tons as measured under <ref>section 14502 of this title</ref>, or an alternate tonnage measured under <ref>section 14302 of this title</ref> as prescribed by the Secretary under <ref>section 14104 of this title</ref> operating on the Great Lakes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(17)</num>
<chapeau> “hazardous material” means a liquid material or substance that is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> flammable or combustible;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> designated a hazardous substance under section 311(b) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<ref>33 U.S.C. 1321</ref>); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> designated a hazardous material under <ref>section 5103(a) of title 49</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(18)</num>
<chapeau> “major conversion” means a conversion of a vessel that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> substantially changes the dimensions or carrying capacity of the vessel;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> changes the type of the vessel;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> substantially prolongs the life of the vessel; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> otherwise so changes the vessel that it is essentially a new vessel, as decided by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(19)</num>
<chapeau> “marine environment” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the navigable waters of the United States and the land and resources in and under those waters;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the waters and fishery resources of an area over which the United States asserts exclusive fishery management authority;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the seabed and subsoil of the outer Continental Shelf of the United States, the resources of the Shelf, and the waters superjacent to the Shelf; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the recreational, economic, and scenic values of the waters and resources referred to in subclauses (A)–(C) of this clause.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(20)</num>
<content> “mobile offshore drilling unit” means a vessel capable of engaging in drilling operations for the exploration or exploitation of subsea resources.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(21)</num>
<content> “motor vessel” means a vessel propelled by machinery other than steam.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(22)</num>
<content> “nautical school vessel” means a vessel operated by or in connection with a nautical school or an educational institution under <ref>section 558 of title 40</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(23)</num>
<content> “navigable waters of the United States” includes all waters of the territorial sea of the United States as described in Presidential Proclamation No. 5928 of <date date="1988-12-27">December 27, 1988</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(24)</num>
<content> “oceanographic research vessel” means a vessel that the Secretary finds is being employed only in instruction in oceanography or limnology, or both, or only in oceanographic or limnological research, including studies about the sea such as seismic, gravity meter, and magnetic exploration and other marine geophysical or geological surveys, atmospheric research, and biological research.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(25)</num>
<content> “offshore supply vessel” means a motor vessel that regularly carries goods, supplies, individuals in addition to the crew, or equipment in support of exploration, exploitation, or production of offshore mineral or energy resources.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(26)</num>
<content> “oil” includes oil of any type or in any form, including petroleum, fuel oil, sludge, oil refuse, and oil mixed with wastes except dredged spoil.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(27)</num>
<content> “oil spill response vessel” means a vessel that is designated in its certificate of inspection as such a vessel, or that is adapted to respond to a discharge of oil or a hazardous material.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(28)</num>
<chapeau> “overall in length” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> for a foreign vessel or a vessel engaged on a foreign voyage, the greater of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> 96 percent of the length on a waterline at 85 percent of the least molded depth measured from the top of the keel (or on a vessel designed with a rake of keel, on a waterline parallel to the designed waterline); or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the length from the fore side of the stem to the axis of the rudder stock on that waterline; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for any other vessel, the horizontal distance of the hull between the foremost part of the stem and the aftermost part of the stern, excluding fittings and attachments.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(29)</num>
<chapeau> “passenger”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> means an individual carried on the vessel except—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the owner or an individual representative of the owner or, in the case of a vessel under charter, an individual charterer or individual representative of the charterer;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the master; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a member of the crew engaged in the business of the vessel who has not contributed consideration for carriage and who is paid for on board services;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> on an offshore supply vessel, means an individual carried on the vessel except—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an individual included in clause (i), (ii), or (iii) of subparagraph (A) of this paragraph;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> an employee of the owner, or of a subcontractor to the owner, engaged in the business of the owner;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> an employee of the charterer, or of a subcontractor to the charterer, engaged in the business of the charterer; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> an individual employed in a phase of exploration, exploitation, or production of offshore mineral or energy resources served by the vessel;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> on a fishing vessel, fish processing vessel, or fish tender vessel, means an individual carried on the vessel except—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an individual included in clause (i), (ii), or (iii) of subparagraph (A) of this paragraph;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a managing operator;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> an employee of the owner, or of a subcontractor to the owner, engaged in the business of the owner;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> an employee of the charterer, or of a subcontractor to the charterer, engaged in the business of the charterer; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> an observer or sea sampler on board the vessel pursuant to a requirement of State or Federal law; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> on a sailing school vessel, means an individual carried on the vessel except—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an individual included in clause (i), (ii), or (iii) of subparagraph (A) of this paragraph;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> an employee of the owner of the vessel engaged in the business of the owner, except when the vessel is operating under a demise charter;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> an employee of the demise charterer of the vessel engaged in the business of the demise charterer; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> a sailing school instructor or sailing school student.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(30)</num>
<content> “passenger for hire” means a passenger for whom consideration is contributed as a condition of carriage on the vessel, whether directly or indirectly flowing to the owner, charterer, operator, agent, or any other person having an interest in the vessel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(31)</num>
<chapeau> “passenger vessel” means a vessel of at least 100 gross tons as measured under <ref>section 14502 of this title</ref>, or an alternate tonnage measured under <ref>section 14302 of this title</ref> as prescribed by the Secretary under <ref>section 14104 of this title</ref>—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> carrying more than 12 passengers, including at least one passenger for hire;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> that is chartered and carrying more than 12 passengers;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> that is a submersible vessel carrying at least one passenger for hire; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> that is a ferry carrying a passenger.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(32)</num>
<content> “product carrier” means a tanker engaged in the trade of carrying oil except crude oil.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(33)</num>
<chapeau> “public vessel” means a vessel that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is owned, or demise chartered, and operated by the United States Government or a government of a foreign country; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is not engaged in commercial service.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(34)</num>
<chapeau> “recreational vessel” means a vessel—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> being manufactured or operated primarily for pleasure; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> leased, rented, or chartered to another for the latter’s pleasure.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(35)</num>
<content> “recreational vessel manufacturer” means a person engaged in the manufacturing, construction, assembly, or importation of recreational vessels, components, or associated equipment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(36)</num>
<chapeau> “riding gang member” means an individual who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> has not been issued a merchant mariner document under chapter 73;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> does not perform—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> watchstanding, automated engine room duty watch, or personnel safety functions; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> cargo handling functions, including any activity relating to the loading or unloading of cargo, the operation of cargo-related equipment (whether or not integral to the vessel), and the handling of mooring lines on the dock when the vessel is made fast or let go;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> does not serve as part of the crew complement required under section 8101;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> is not a member of the steward’s department; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> is not a citizen or temporary or permanent resident of a country designated by the United States as a sponsor of terrorism or any other country that the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of State and the heads of other appropriate United States agencies, determines to be a security threat to the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(37)</num>
<chapeau> “sailing instruction” means teaching, research, and practical experience in operating vessels propelled primarily by sail and may include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any subject related to that operation and to the sea, including seamanship, navigation, oceanography, other nautical and marine sciences, and maritime history and literature; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> only when in conjunction with a subject referred to in subclause (A) of this clause, instruction in mathematics and language arts skills to sailing school students having learning disabilities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(38)</num>
<content> “sailing school instructor” means an individual who is on board a sailing school vessel to provide sailing instruction, but does not include an operator or crewmember who is among those required to be on board the vessel to meet a requirement established under part F of this subtitle.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(39)</num>
<content> “sailing school student” means an individual who is on board a sailing school vessel to receive sailing instruction.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(40)</num>
<chapeau> “sailing school vessel” means a vessel—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> that is less than 500 gross tons as measured under <ref>section 14502 of this title</ref>, or an alternate tonnage measured under <ref>section 14302 of this title</ref> as prescribed by the Secretary under <ref>section 14104 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> carrying more than 6 individuals who are sailing school instructors or sailing school students;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> principally equipped for propulsion by sail, even if the vessel has an auxiliary means of propulsion; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> owned or demise chartered, and operated by an organization described in section 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (<ref>26 U.S.C. 501(c)(3)</ref>) and exempt from tax under section 501(a) of that Code, or by a State or political subdivision of a State, during times that the vessel is operated by the organization, State, or political subdivision only for sailing instruction.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(41)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Subject to subparagraph (B), “scientific personnel” means individuals on board an oceanographic research vessel only to engage in scientific research, or to instruct or receive instruction in oceanography or limnology.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> Such term includes an individual who is on board an oceanographic research vessel only to—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> engage in scientific research;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> instruct in oceanography or limnology; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> receive instruction in oceanography or limnology.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> For purposes of clause (i), the age of an individual may not be considered in determining whether the individual is described in such clause.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(42)</num>
<content> “seagoing barge” means a non-self-propelled vessel of at least 100 gross tons as measured under <ref>section 14502 of this title</ref>, or an alternate tonnage measured under <ref>section 14302 of this title</ref> as prescribed by the Secretary under <ref>section 14104 of this title</ref> making voyages beyond the Boundary Line.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(43)</num>
<content> “seagoing motor vessel” means a motor vessel of at least 300 gross tons as measured under <ref>section 14502 of this title</ref>, or an alternate tonnage measured under <ref>section 14302 of this title</ref> as prescribed by the Secretary under <ref>section 14104 of this title</ref> making voyages beyond the Boundary Line.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(44)</num>
<content> “Secretary” means the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(45)</num>
<content> “sexual assault” means any form of abuse or contact as defined in chapter 109A of title 18, or a substantially similar offense under State, local, or Tribal law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(46)</num>
<chapeau> “sexual harassment” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> conduct that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> involves unwelcome sexual advances, requests for sexual favors, or deliberate or repeated offensive comments or gestures of a sexual nature if any—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> submission to such conduct is made either explicitly or implicitly a term or condition of employment, pay, career, benefits, or entitlements of the individual;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> submission to, or rejection, of such conduct by an individual is used as a basis for decisions affecting that individual’s job, pay, career, benefits, or entitlements;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> such conduct has the purpose or effect of unreasonably interfering with an individual’s work performance or creates an intimidating, hostile, or offensive work environment; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> conduct may have been by an individual’s supervisor, a supervisor in another area, a co-worker, or another credentialed mariner; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> is so severe or pervasive that a reasonable person would perceive, and the victim does perceive, the environment as hostile or offensive;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any use or condonation associated with first-hand or personal knowledge, by any individual in a supervisory or command position, of any form of sexual behavior to control, influence, or affect the career, pay, benefits, entitlements, or employment of a subordinate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any intentional or repeated unwelcome verbal comment or gesture of a sexual nature towards or about an individual by the individual’s supervisor, a supervisor in another area, a coworker, or another credentialed mariner.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(47)</num>
<chapeau> “small passenger vessel” means a wing-in-ground craft, regardless of tonnage, carrying at least one passenger for hire, and a vessel of less than 100 gross tons as measured under <ref>section 14502 of this title</ref>, or an alternate tonnage measured under <ref>section 14302 of this title</ref> as prescribed by the Secretary under <ref>section 14104 of this title</ref>—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> carrying more than 6 passengers, including at least one passenger for hire;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> that is chartered with the crew provided or specified by the owner or the owner’s representative and carrying more than 6 passengers;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> that is chartered with no crew provided or specified by the owner or the owner’s representative and carrying more than 12 passengers;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> that is a submersible vessel carrying at least one passenger for hire; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> that is a ferry carrying more than 6 passengers.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(48)</num>
<content> “steam vessel” means a vessel propelled in whole or in part by steam, except a recreational vessel of not more than 40 feet in length.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(49)</num>
<content> “submersible vessel” means a vessel that is capable of operating below the surface of the water.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(50)</num>
<content> “tanker” means a self-propelled tank vessel constructed or adapted primarily to carry oil or hazardous material in bulk in the cargo spaces.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(51)</num>
<chapeau> “tank vessel” means a vessel that is constructed or adapted to carry, or that carries, oil or hazardous material in bulk as cargo or cargo residue, and that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is a vessel of the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> operates on the navigable waters of the United States; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> transfers oil or hazardous material in a port or place subject to the jurisdiction of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(52)</num>
<content> “towing vessel” means a commercial vessel engaged in or intending to engage in the service of pulling, pushing, or hauling along side, or any combination of pulling, pushing, or hauling along side.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(53)</num>
<chapeau> “uninspected passenger vessel” means an uninspected vessel—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> of at least 100 gross tons as measured under <ref>section 14502 of this title</ref>, or an alternate tonnage measured under <ref>section 14302 of this title</ref> as prescribed by the Secretary under <ref>section 14104 of this title</ref>—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> carrying not more than 12 passengers, including at least one passenger for hire; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> that is chartered with the crew provided or specified by the owner or the owner’s representative and carrying not more than 12 passengers; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> of less than 100 gross tons as measured under <ref>section 14502 of this title</ref>, or an alternate tonnage measured under <ref>section 14302 of this title</ref> as prescribed by the Secretary under <ref>section 14104 of this title</ref>—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> carrying not more than 6 passengers, including at least one passenger for hire; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> that is chartered with the crew provided or specified by the owner or the owner’s representative and carrying not more than 6 passengers.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(54)</num>
<content> “uninspected vessel” means a vessel not subject to inspection under <ref>section 3301 of this title</ref> that is not a recreational vessel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(55)</num>
<chapeau> “vessel of war” means a vessel—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> belonging to the armed forces of a country;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> bearing the external marks distinguishing vessels of war of that country;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> under the command of an officer commissioned by the government of that country and whose name appears in the appropriate service list or its equivalent; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> staffed by a crew under regular armed forces discipline.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(56)</num>
<content> “wing-in-ground craft” means a vessel that is capable of operating completely above the surface of the water on a dynamic air cushion created by aerodynamic lift due to the ground effect between the vessel and the water’s surface.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 501</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–364, title IV, § 402(1)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-17">July 17, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 445</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–454, title III, § 301(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-05">Oct. 5, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1734</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–557, § 34(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2876</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–307, § 1(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="1986-05-19">May 19, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 444</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–509, title V, § 5102(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1926</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 2095</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–640</ref>, §§ 10(b)(1), 11(a), 13(d), <date date="1986-11-10">Nov. 10, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3549–3551</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–239, § 6(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1988-01-11">Jan. 11, 1988</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1781</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–424, § 8(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-09">Sept. 9, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1593</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–710, title I, § 104(a)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="1988-11-23">Nov. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4749</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–225, title II, § 209</ref>, <date date="1989-12-12">Dec. 12, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1913</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–380, title IV, § 4103(a)(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="1990-08-18">Aug. 18, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 511</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–595, title VI, § 603(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 2993</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–587, title V, § 5208(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-11-04">Nov. 4, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 5075</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–206, title V</ref>, §§ 502–510, <date date="1993-12-20">Dec. 20, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 2439–2441</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 5</ref>(<i>l</i>), <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1375</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–324, title VII, § 709</ref>, title XI, § 1104(a), <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3934</ref>, 3966; <ref>Pub. L. 105–383, title III, § 301(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3417</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–217, § 3(m)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1302</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–295, title IV, § 419</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2124</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–241, title III</ref>, §§ 301, 312(b), <date date="2006-07-11">July 11, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 526</ref>, 533; <ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 15(2)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1702</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–281, title VI</ref>, §§ 617(a)(1)(A), 618, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2972</ref>, 2975; <ref>Pub. L. 111–330, § 1(9)</ref>, <date date="2010-12-22">Dec. 22, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3570</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. C, title XXXV, § 3541(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2322</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title V, § 515</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4279</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. K, title CXVI, § 11601(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4145</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2102.</num>
<heading> Limited definitions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In chapters 33, 45, 51, 81, and 87 of this title, “Aleutian trade” means the transportation of cargo (including fishery related products) for hire on board a fish tender vessel to or from a place in Alaska west of 153 degrees west longitude and east of 172 degrees east longitude, if that place receives weekly common carrier service by water, to or from a place in the United States (except a place in Alaska).</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 505</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title X, § 1011(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1013</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–509, title V, § 5102(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1926</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–595, title VI, § 602(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 2990</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–304</ref>, §§ 15(3), 16(a), <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1702</ref>, 1705.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2103.</num>
<heading> Superintendence of the merchant marine</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary has general superintendence over the merchant marine of the United States and of merchant marine personnel insofar as the enforcement of this subtitle is concerned and insofar as those vessels and personnel are not subject, under other law, to the supervision of another official of the United States Government. In the interests of marine safety and seamen’s welfare, the Secretary shall enforce this subtitle and shall carry out correctly and uniformly administer this subtitle. The Secretary may prescribe regulations to carry out the provisions of this subtitle.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 506</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–307, § 9</ref>, <date date="1986-05-19">May 19, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 447</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2104.</num>
<heading> Delegation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary may delegate the duties and powers conferred by this subtitle to any officer, employee, or member of the Coast Guard, and may provide for the subdelegation of those duties and powers.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> When this subtitle authorizes an officer or employee of the Customs Service to act in place of a Coast Guard official, the Secretary may designate that officer or employee subject to the approval of the Secretary of the Treasury.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 506</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2105.</num>
<heading> Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall provide for the investigation of the operation of this subtitle and of all laws related to marine safety, and shall require that a report be made to the Secretary annually about those matters that may require improvement or amendment.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 506</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2106.</num>
<heading> Liability in rem</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">When a vessel is made liable in rem under this subtitle, the vessel may be libeled and proceeded against in the district court of the United States for any district in which the vessel is found.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 506</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 15(4)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1702</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2107.</num>
<heading> Civil penalty procedures</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> After notice and an opportunity for a hearing, a person found by the Secretary to have violated this subtitle or subtitle VII or a regulation prescribed under this subtitle or subtitle VII for which a civil penalty is provided, is liable to the United States Government for the civil penalty provided. The amount of the civil penalty shall be assessed by the Secretary by written notice. In determining the amount of the penalty, the Secretary shall consider the nature, circumstances, extent, and gravity of the prohibited acts committed and, with respect to the violator, the degree of culpability, any history of prior offenses, ability to pay, and other matters that justice requires.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Secretary may compromise, modify, or remit, with or without consideration, a civil penalty under this subtitle or subtitle VII until the assessment is referred to the Attorney General.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> If a person fails to pay an assessment of a civil penalty after it has become final, the Secretary may refer the matter to the Attorney General for collection in an appropriate district court of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 506</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–241, title III, § 306(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-07-11">July 11, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 528</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2108.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 15(5)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1702</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2109.</num>
<heading> Public vessels</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided, this subtitle does not apply to a public vessel of the United States. However, this subtitle does apply to a vessel (except a Great Lakes St. Lawrence Seaway Development Corporation vessel) owned or operated by the Department of Transportation or by any corporation organized or controlled by the Department.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 507</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–509, title V, § 5102(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1927</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–241, title IX, § 902(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="2006-07-11">July 11, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 567</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–281, title IX, § 903(a)(5)(A)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3010</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–260, div. AA, title V, § 512(c)(6)(A)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 2756</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2110.</num>
<heading> Fees</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as otherwise provided in this title, the Secretary shall establish a fee or charge for a service or thing of value provided by the Secretary under this subtitle, in accordance with <ref>section 9701 of title 31</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary may not establish a fee or charge under paragraph (1) for inspection or examination of a non-self-propelled tank vessel under part B of this subtitle that is more than $500 annually. The Secretary may not establish a fee or charge under paragraph (1) for inspection or examination of a small passenger vessel under this title that is more than $300 annually for such vessels under 65 feet in length, or more than $600 annually for such vessels 65 feet in length and greater. The Secretary may not establish a fee or charge under paragraph (1) for inspection or examination under this title for any publicly-owned ferry.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary may, by regulation, adjust a fee or charge collected under this subsection to accommodate changes in the cost of providing a specific service or thing of value, but the adjusted fee or charge may not exceed the total cost of providing the service or thing of value for which the fee or charge is collected, including the cost of collecting the fee or charge.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Secretary may not collect a fee or charge under this subsection that is in conflict with the international obligations of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The Secretary may not collect a fee or charge under this subsection for any search or rescue service.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In addition to the collection of fees and charges established under subsection (a), in providing a service or thing of value under this subtitle the Secretary may accept in-kind transportation, travel, and subsistence.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The value of in-kind transportation, travel, and subsistence accepted under this paragraph may not exceed applicable per diem rates set forth in regulations prescribed under <ref>section 464 of title 37</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> In addition to the collection of fees and charges established under subsection (a), the Secretary may recover appropriate collection and enforcement costs associated with delinquent payments of the fees and charges.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary may employ any Federal, State, or local agency or instrumentality, or any private enterprise or business, to collect a fee or charge established under this section. A private enterprise or business selected by the Secretary to collect fees or charges—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall be subject to reasonable terms and conditions agreed to by the Secretary and the enterprise or business;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> shall provide appropriate accounting to the Secretary; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> may not institute litigation as part of that collection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A Federal agency shall account for the agency’s costs of collecting the fee or charge under this subsection as a reimbursable expense, and the costs shall be credited to the account from which expended.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> A person that violates this section by failing to pay a fee or charge established under this section is liable to the United States Government for a civil penalty of not more than $5,000 for each violation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> When requested by the Secretary, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall deny the clearance required by <ref>section 60105 of this title</ref> to a vessel for which a fee or charge established under this section has not been paid until the fee or charge is paid or until a bond is posted for the payment.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> The Secretary may exempt a person from paying a fee or charge established under this section if the Secretary determines that it is in the public interest to do so.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<content> Fees and charges collected by the Secretary under this section shall be deposited in the general fund of the Treasury as offsetting receipts of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating and ascribed to Coast Guard activities.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The collection of a fee or charge under this section does not alter or expand the functions, powers, responsibilities, or liability of the United States under any law for the performance of services or the provision of a thing of value for which a fee or charge is collected under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<content> The Secretary may not establish or collect a fee or charge for the inspection under part B of this subtitle of training vessels operated by State maritime academies.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 507</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–509, title V, § 5102(b)(4)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1927</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–710, title I, § 104(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-23">Nov. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4749</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–508, title X, § 10401(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1388–397</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–241, § 53</ref>, <date date="1991-12-19">Dec. 19, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 2232</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–582, title V, § 501(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-11-02">Nov. 2, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4909</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–587, title V, § 5207</ref>, <date date="1992-11-04">Nov. 4, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 5075</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–324, title XI, § 1112</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3970</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–383, title II, § 207</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3416</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–295, title III, § 344</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2106</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 15(6)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1702</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–281, title III, § 311(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-18">Dec. 18, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3047</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. C, title XXXV, § 3546(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2326</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2111.</num>
<heading> Pay for overtime services</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary may prescribe a reasonable rate of extra pay for overtime services of civilian officers and employees of the Coast Guard required to remain on duty between 5 p.m. and 8 a.m., or on Sundays or holidays, to perform services related to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the inspection of vessels or their equipment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the engagement and discharge of crews of vessels;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the measurement of vessels; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the documentation of vessels.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Except for Sundays and holidays, the overtime rate provided under subsection (a) of this section is one-half day’s additional pay for each 2 hours of overtime (or part of 2 hours of at least one hour). The total extra pay may be not more than 2 and one-half days’ pay for any one period from 5 p.m. to 8 a.m.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The overtime rate provided under subsection (a) of this section for Sundays and holidays is 2 additional days’ pay.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The owner, charterer, managing operator, agent, master, or individual in charge of the vessel shall pay the amount of the overtime pay provided under this section to the official designated by regulation. The official shall deposit the amount paid to the Treasury as miscellaneous receipts. Payment to the officer or employee entitled to the pay shall be made from the annual appropriations for salaries and expenses of the Coast Guard.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> The overtime pay provided under this section shall be paid if the authorized officers and employees have been ordered to report for duty and have reported, even if services requested were not performed.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 507</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2112.</num>
<heading> Authority to change working hours</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In a port at which the customary working hours begin before 8 a.m. or end after 5 p.m., the Secretary may regulate the working hours of the officers and employees referred to in <ref>section 2111 of this title</ref> so that those hours conform to the prevailing working hours of the port. However—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the total period for which overtime pay may be required under <ref>section 2111 of this title</ref> may not be more than 15 hours between any 2 periods of ordinary working hours on other than Sundays and holidays;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the length of the working day for the officers and employees involved may not be changed; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the rate of overtime pay may not be changed.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 508</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2113.</num>
<heading> Authority to exempt certain vessels</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">If the Secretary decides that the application of a provision of part B, C, F, or G of this subtitle is not necessary in performing the mission of the vessel engaged in excursions or an oceanographic research vessel, or not necessary for the safe operation of certain vessels carrying passengers, the Secretary by regulation may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> for a vessel, issue a special permit specifying the conditions of operation and equipment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> exempt an oceanographic research vessel from that provision under conditions the Secretary may specify;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> establish different operating and equipment requirements for vessels defined in <ref>section 2101(53)(A) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> maintain different structural fire protection, manning, operating, and equipment requirements for vessels that satisfied requirements set forth in the Passenger Vessel Safety Act of 1993 (<ref>Public Law 103–206</ref>) before <date date="1994-06-21">June 21, 1994</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 508</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–206, title V, § 511(a)</ref>, <date date="1993-12-20">Dec. 20, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 2441</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–324, title VII, § 710</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3935</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. C, title XXXV</ref>, §§ 3541(b)(6), 3542(a), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2323</ref>, 2324; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. K, title CXVI, § 11601(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4146</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2114.</num>
<heading> Protection of seamen against discrimination</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> A person may not discharge or in any manner discriminate against a seaman because—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the seaman in good faith has reported or is about to report to the Coast Guard or other appropriate Federal agency or department that the seaman believes that a violation of a maritime safety law or regulation prescribed under that law or regulation has occurred;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the seaman in good faith has reported or is about to report to the vessel owner, Coast Guard or other appropriate Federal agency or department sexual harassment or sexual assault against the seaman or knowledge of sexual harassment or sexual assault against another seaman;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the seaman has refused to perform duties ordered by the seaman’s employer because the seaman has a reasonable apprehension or expectation that performing such duties would result in serious injury to the seaman, other seamen, or the public;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the seaman testified in a proceeding brought to enforce a maritime safety law or regulation prescribed under that law;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the seaman notified, or attempted to notify, the vessel owner or the Secretary of a work-related personal injury or work-related illness of a seaman;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the seaman cooperated with a safety investigation by the Secretary or the National Transportation Safety Board;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> the seaman furnished information to the Secretary, the National Transportation Safety Board, or any other public official as to the facts relating to any marine casualty resulting in injury or death to an individual or damage to property occurring in connection with vessel transportation; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> the seaman accurately reported hours of duty under this part.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The circumstances causing a seaman’s apprehension of serious injury under paragraph (1)(C) must be of such a nature that a reasonable person, under similar circumstances, would conclude that there is a real danger of an injury or serious impairment of health resulting from the performance of duties as ordered by the seaman’s employer.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> To qualify for protection against the seaman’s employer under paragraph (1)(C), the employee must have sought from the employer, and been unable to obtain, correction of the unsafe condition.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> A seaman alleging discharge or discrimination in violation of subsection (a) of this section, or another person at the seaman’s request, may file a complaint with respect to such allegation in the same manner as a complaint may be filed under subsection (b) of <ref>section 31105 of title 49</ref>. Such complaint shall be subject to the procedures, requirements, and rights described in that section, including with respect to the right to file an objection, the right of a person to file for a petition for review under subsection (c) of that section, and the requirement to bring a civil action under subsection (d) of that section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 98–557, § 13(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2863</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–295, title IV, § 428</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2127</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–281, title VI, § 611(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2969</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. K, title CXVI, § 11605</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4148</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2115.</num>
<heading> Civil penalty to enforce alcohol and dangerous drug testing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any person who fails to implement or conduct, or who otherwise fails to comply with the requirements prescribed by the Secretary for, chemical testing for dangerous drugs or for evidence of alcohol use, as prescribed under this subtitle or a regulation prescribed by the Secretary to carry out the provisions of this subtitle, is liable to the United States Government for a civil penalty of not more than $5,000 for each violation. Each day of a continuing violation shall constitute a separate violation.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–324, title III, § 303(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3917</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–383, title III, § 304(b)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3419</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2116.</num>
<heading> Marine safety strategy, goals, and performance assessments</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Long-Term Strategy and Goals</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In conjunction with existing federally required strategic planning efforts, the Secretary shall develop a long-term strategy for improving vessel safety and the safety of individuals on vessels. The 5-year strategy shall include the issuance of a plan and schedule for achieving the following goals:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Reducing the number and rates of marine casualties.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Improving the consistency and effectiveness of vessel and operator enforcement and compliance programs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Identifying and targeting enforcement efforts at high-risk vessels and operators.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Improving research efforts to enhance and promote vessel and operator safety and performance.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading> 5<inline class="small-caps">-Year Strategy and Plan.—</inline></heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Measurable goals</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The 5-year strategy and plan shall include specific numeric or measurable goals designed to achieve the goals set forth in subsection (a). The purposes of the numeric or measurable goals are the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> To increase the number of safety examinations on all high-risk vessels.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> To eliminate the backlog of marine safety-related rulemakings.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> To improve the quality and effectiveness of marine safety information databases by ensuring that all Coast Guard personnel accurately and effectively report all safety, casualty, and injury information.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> To provide for a sufficient number of Coast Guard marine safety personnel, and provide adequate facilities and equipment to carry out the functions referred to in section 93(c) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002002">1</ref> of title 14.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Resource needs</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The 5-year strategy and plan shall include estimates of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the funds and staff resources needed to accomplish each activity included in the strategy and plan; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the staff skills and training needed for timely and effective accomplishment of each goal.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Submission With the President’s Budget</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 5 years after the date of the enactment of the Elijah E. Cummings Coast Guard Authorization Act of 2020, and every 5 years thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to Congress the strategy and plan not later than 60 days following the transmission of the President’s budget submission under <ref>section 1105 of title 31</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Achievement of Goals.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Progress assessment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In conjunction with the submission of the 5-year strategy and plan, the Commandant shall assess the progress of the Coast Guard toward achieving the goals set forth in subsection (b). The Commandant shall convey the Commandant’s assessment to the employees of the marine safety workforce and shall identify any deficiencies that should be remedied before the next progress assessment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Periodic briefings</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall periodically brief the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> on the performance of the marine safety program in achieving the goals of the marine safety strategy and plan under subsection (a) for the period covered by the briefing;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> on the program’s mission performance in achieving numerical measurable goals established under subsection (b), including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the number of civilian and military Coast Guard personnel assigned to marine safety positions; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> an identification of marine safety positions that are understaffed to meet the workload required to accomplish each activity included in the strategy and plan under subsection (a); and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> recommendations on how to improve performance of the program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–281, title V, § 522(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2956</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 113–281, title II, § 221(b)(1)(A)</ref>, title III, § 307(a), <date date="2014-12-18">Dec. 18, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3037</ref>, 3045; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. C, title XXXV</ref>, §§ 3541(b)(7), 3546(b), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2323</ref>, 2326; <ref>Pub. L. 115–265, title II, § 214</ref>, <date date="2018-10-11">Oct. 11, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 3751</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXII</ref> [LXXXII], § 8240(c), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4666</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2117.</num>
<heading> Termination for unsafe operation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">An individual authorized to enforce this title—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> may remove a certificate required by this title from a vessel that is operating in a condition that does not comply with the provisions of the certificate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> may order the individual in charge of a vessel that is operating that does not have on board the certificate required by this title to return the vessel to a mooring and to remain there until the vessel is in compliance with this title; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> may direct the individual in charge of a vessel to which this title applies to immediately take reasonable steps necessary for the safety of individuals on board the vessel if the official observes the vessel being operated in an unsafe condition that the official believes creates an especially hazardous condition, including ordering the individual in charge to return the vessel to a mooring and to remain there until the situation creating the hazard is corrected or ended.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–281, title VI, § 608(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2967</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2118.</num>
<heading> Establishment of equipment standards</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> In establishing standards for approved equipment required on vessels subject to part B of this subtitle, the Secretary shall establish standards that are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> based on performance using the best available technology that is economically achievable; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> operationally practical.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Using the standards established under subsection (a), the Secretary may also certify lifesaving equipment that is not required to be carried on vessels subject to part B of this subtitle to ensure that such equipment is suitable for its intended purpose.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> At least once every 10 years the Secretary shall review and revise the standards established under subsection (a) to ensure that the standards meet the requirements of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–281, title VI, § 608(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2968</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 114–120, title III, § 306(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2016-02-08">Feb. 8, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 54</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>