<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 805—</num>
<heading>SAFE CONTAINERS FOR INTERNATIONAL CARGO</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 80501.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Container</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “container” has the meaning given that term in the Convention.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Convention</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “Convention” means the International Convention for Safe Containers, and its annexes, done at Geneva, Switzerland, <date date="1972-12-02">December 2, 1972</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">International transport</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “international transport” means the transportation of a container between—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a place in a foreign country and a place in the jurisdiction of the United States; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> two places outside the United States by United States carriers.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Owner</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “owner” includes the lessee or bailee of a container if a written lease or bailment provides for the lessee or bailee to exercise the owner’s responsibility for maintaining and examining the container.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Safety approval plate</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “safety approval plate” has the meaning given that term in annex I of the Convention.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 11</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1694</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 80502.</num>
<heading> Application of Convention</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Convention applies to an owner of a container used in international transport if the owner is domiciled or has its principal office in the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 11</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1694</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 80503.</num>
<heading> General authority of the Secretary</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating shall carry out the Convention and this chapter in the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall prescribe regulations to carry out this chapter. The regulations shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> establish procedures for testing, inspecting, and initially approving containers and designs for containers, including procedures for attaching, invalidating, and removing safety approval plates for containers;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> establish procedures to be followed by the owners of containers for the periodic examination of containers as provided in the Convention; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> provide a method for developing, collecting, and disseminating information about container safety and the international transport of containers.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Safety Approval Plates</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the owner of a container without a safety approval plate establishes that the container satisfies the standards of the Convention, the Secretary may authorize a safety approval plate to be attached to the container.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Schedule of Fees</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may prescribe a schedule of fees for services performed by the Secretary, or by a person delegated authority under <ref>section 80506 of this title</ref>, for the testing, inspection, and initial approval of containers and container designs.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Encouraging Intermodal Transport</inline>.—</heading>
<content>To the maximum extent possible, the Secretary shall encourage the development and use of intermodal transport, using containers built to facilitate economical, safe, and expeditious handling of containerized cargo without intermediate reloading when it is being transported over land, air, and sea areas.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 11</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1694</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 80504.</num>
<heading> Approval and examination</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Domicile and Principal Office in United States</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A container owner domiciled and having its principal office in the United States shall have the container—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> approved initially under procedures prescribed by the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating or by the government of another country that is a party to the Convention; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> examined periodically as provided in the Convention under procedures prescribed by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Domicile or Principal Office in United States</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A container owner domiciled or having its principal office in the United States shall have the container—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> approved initially under procedures prescribed by the Secretary or by the government of another country that is a party to the Convention; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> examined periodically as provided in the Convention, under procedures prescribed by the government of the country in which the owner is domiciled or has its principal office, as long as that country is a party to the Convention.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Neither Domicile Nor Principal Office in United States</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A container owner neither domiciled nor having its principal office in the United States or another country that is a party to the Convention may submit a container for initial approval and periodic examination under procedures prescribed by the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 11</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1695</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 80505.</num>
<heading> Enforcement</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>To enforce the Convention, this chapter, and regulations prescribed under this chapter, the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> examine, or require to be examined, containers in international transport;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> approve designs for containers;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> inspect and test containers being manufactured;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> issue a detention order removing or excluding a container from service until the container owner satisfies the Secretary that the container meets the standards of the Convention, if the container—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> does not have a safety approval plate attached to it; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> has a safety approval plate attached but there is significant evidence that the container is in a condition that creates an obvious risk to safety;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> take other appropriate action, including issuing necessary orders, to remove a container from service or restrict its use if the container is not in compliance with the Convention, this chapter, or regulations prescribed under this chapter, but does not present an obvious risk to safety; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> allow a container found to be unsafe or without a safety approval plate to be moved to another location for repair or other disposition, under restrictions consistent with the intent of the Convention.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Payment of Expenses</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Examination</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The owner of a container involved in an action by the Secretary under this section related to an examination of the container shall pay or reimburse the Secretary for the expenses arising from that action, except for the costs of routine examinations of the container or a safety approval plate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Testing, inspection, and initial approval</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The owner of a container submitted to the procedure established by the Secretary for testing, inspection, and initial approval, and the manufacturer of a container that submits a design to the procedure established by the Secretary for testing, inspection, and initial approval, shall pay or reimburse the Secretary for the expenses arising from the testing, inspection, or approval.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Credit to appropriation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Amounts received by the Secretary as reimbursement shall be credited to the appropriation for operations and support of the Coast Guard.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Presumption Based on Safety Approval Plate</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A container bearing a safety approval plate authorized by a country that is a party to the Convention is presumed to be in a safe condition unless there is significant evidence that the container is in a condition that creates an obvious risk to safety.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice of Orders</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>When the Secretary issues a detention or other order under this section, the Secretary promptly shall notify in writing—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the owner of the container;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the owner’s agent; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> if the identity of the owner is not apparent from the container or shipping documents, the custodian.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Information to include</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The notification shall identify the container involved, give the location of the container, and describe the condition or situation giving rise to the order.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duration of Orders</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An order issued by the Secretary under this section remains in effect until—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Secretary declares the container to be in compliance with the standards of the Convention; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the container is removed permanently from service.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice of Defective Container to Country Issuing Safety Approval Plate</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the Secretary has reason to believe that a container bearing a safety approval plate issued by another country was defective at the time of approval, the Secretary shall notify that country.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 11</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1695</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXV</ref> [LXXXV], § 8513(b), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4761</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 80506.</num>
<heading> Delegation of authority</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating may delegate to any person, including a public or private agency or nonprofit organization, authority to grant initial approval for containers and designs and to attach safety approval plates.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Before making a delegation under this section, the Secretary shall prescribe regulations establishing—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> criteria to be followed in selecting a person to whom authority is to be delegated;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a detailed description of the duties and powers to be carried out by the person to whom authority is delegated, including the records the person shall keep; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the review the Secretary will conduct to decide whether the person is carrying out the delegated duties and powers properly.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inspection of Records</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A person delegated authority under this section shall make available to the Secretary for inspection, on request, records the person is required to keep.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Penalties and Orders</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A person delegated authority under this section may not—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> assess or collect, or attempt to assess or collect, a penalty for violation of the Convention, this chapter, or an order issued by the Secretary under this chapter; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> issue or attempt to issue a detention or other order.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Publication</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register or other appropriate publication—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the name and address of each person to whom authority is delegated;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the duties and powers delegated; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the period of the delegation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Revocation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may revoke a delegation of authority under this section at any time.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 11</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1696</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 80507.</num>
<heading> Employee protection</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A person may not discharge or discriminate against an employee because the employee has reported the existence of an unsafe container or a violation of this chapter or a regulation prescribed under this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Complaints</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An employee alleging to have been discharged or discriminated against in violation of subsection (a) may file a complaint with the Secretary of Labor. The complaint must be filed within 60 days after the violation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Enforcement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Labor may investigate the complaint. If the Secretary of Labor finds there has been a violation, the Secretary of Labor may bring a civil action in an appropriate district court of the United States. The court has jurisdiction to restrain violations of subsection (a) and order appropriate relief, including reinstatement of the employee to the employee’s former position with back pay.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice to Complainant</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Within 30 days after receiving a complaint under this section, the Secretary of Labor shall notify the complainant of the intended action on the complaint.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 11</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1697</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 80508.</num>
<heading> Amendments to Convention</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Proposals by United States</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of State, with the concurrence of the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating, may propose amendments to the Convention or request a conference for amending the Convention as provided in article IX of the Convention.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Proposals by Other Countries</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An amendment communicated to the United States under article IX(2) of the Convention may be accepted for the United States by the President, with the advice and consent of the Senate. The President may declare that the United States does not accept an amendment.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Amendments to Annexes</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of State, with the concurrence of the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> may propose amendments to the annexes to the Convention;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> may propose a conference for amending annexes to the Convention; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> shall consider and act on amendments to the annexes to the Convention adopted by the Maritime Safety Committee of the International Maritime Organization and communicated to the United States under article X(2) of the Convention.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Action following approval or objection</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If a proposed amendment to an annex is approved by the United States, the amendment shall enter into force as provided in article X of the Convention. If a proposed amendment is objected to, the Secretary of State promptly shall communicate the objection as provided in article X(3) of the Convention.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appointment of Arbitrator</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of State, with the concurrence of the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating, shall appoint an arbitrator when one is required to resolve a dispute within the meaning of article XIII of the Convention.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 11</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1697</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 80509.</num>
<heading> Civil penalty</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An owner, agent, or custodian who has been notified of an order issued under <ref>section 80505 of this title</ref> and fails to take reasonable and prompt action to prevent or stop a container subject to the order from being moved in violation of the order is liable to the United States Government for a civil penalty of not more than $5,000 for each container moved. Each day the container remains in service while the order is in effect is a separate violation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Assessment and Collection</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>After notice and an opportunity for a hearing, the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating shall assess and collect any penalty under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Factors to consider</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In determining the amount of the penalty, the Secretary shall consider the gravity of the violation, the hazards involved, and the record of the person charged with respect to violations of the Convention, this chapter, or regulations prescribed under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Remission, mitigation, or compromise</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may remit, mitigate, or compromise a penalty under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Enforcement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If a person fails to pay a penalty under this section, the Secretary shall refer the matter to the Attorney General for collection in an appropriate district court of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 11</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1698</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>