<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 115—</num>
<heading>OFFENSES AND PENALTIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 11501.</num>
<heading> Penalties for specified offenses</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">When a seaman lawfully engaged commits any of the following offenses, the seaman shall be punished as specified:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> For desertion, the seaman forfeits any part of the money or property the seaman leaves on board and any part of earned wages.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> For neglecting or refusing without reasonable cause to join the seaman’s vessel or to proceed to sea in the vessel, for absence without leave within 24 hours of the vessel’s sailing from a port (at the beginning or during the voyage), or for absence without leave from duties and without sufficient reason, the seaman forfeits from the seaman’s wages not more than 2 days’ pay or a sufficient amount to defray expenses incurred in hiring a substitute.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> For quitting the vessel without leave after the vessel’s arrival at the port of delivery and before the vessel is placed in security, the seaman forfeits from the seaman’s wages not more than one month’s pay.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> For willful disobedience to a lawful command at sea, the seaman, at the discretion of the master, may be confined until the disobedience ends, and on arrival in port forfeits from the seaman’s wages not more than 4 days’ pay or, at the discretion of the court, may be imprisoned for not more than one month.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> For continued willful disobedience to lawful command or continued willful neglect of duty at sea, the seaman, at the discretion of the master, may be confined, on water and 1,000 calories, with full rations every 5th day, until the disobedience ends, and on arrival in port forfeits, for each 24 hours’ continuance of the disobedience or neglect, not more than 12 days’ pay or, at the discretion of the court, may be imprisoned for not more than 3 months.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> For assaulting a master, mate, pilot, engineer, or staff officer, the seaman shall be imprisoned for not more than 2 years.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> For willfully damaging the vessel, or embezzling or willfully damaging any of the stores or cargo, the seaman forfeits from the seaman’s wages the amount of the loss sustained and, at the discretion of the court, may be imprisoned for not more than 12 months.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> For smuggling for which a seaman is convicted causing loss or damage to the owner or master, the seaman is liable to the owner or master for the loss or damage, and any part of the seaman’s wages may be retained to satisfy the liability. The seaman also may be imprisoned for not more than 12 months.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 582</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11502.</num>
<heading> Entry of offenses in logbook</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> When an offense listed in <ref>section 11501 of this title</ref> is committed, an entry shall be made in the vessel’s official logbook—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> on the day of the offense;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> stating the details;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> signed by the master; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> signed by the chief mate or another seaman.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Before arrival in port if the offense was committed at sea, or before departure if the offense was committed in port and the offender is still on the vessel—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the entry shall be read to the offender;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the offender shall be given a copy; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the offender shall be given the opportunity to reply.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> After subsection (b) of this section has been complied with, an entry shall be made in the official logbook—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> stating that the entry about the offense was read and a copy provided to the offender;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> stating the offender’s reply;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> signed by the master; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> signed by the chief mate or another seaman.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> In a subsequent legal proceeding, if the entries required by this section are not produced or proved, the court may refuse to receive evidence of the offense.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 583</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11503.</num>
<heading> Duties of consular officers related to insubordination</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> A consular officer shall use every means to discountenance insubordination on vessels of the United States, including employing the aid of local authorities.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> When a seaman is accused of insubordination, a consular officer shall inquire into the facts and proceed as provided in <ref>section 11106 of this title</ref>. If the consular officer discharges the seaman, the officer shall endorse the agreement required by this part and enter in the vessel’s official logbook the cause and particulars of the discharge.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 583</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11504.</num>
<heading> Enforcement of forfeitures</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">When an offense by a seaman also is a criminal violation, it is not necessary that a criminal proceeding be brought to enforce a forfeiture.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 584</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11505.</num>
<heading> Disposal of forfeitures</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Money, property, and wages forfeited under this chapter for desertion may be applied to compensate the owner or master of the vessel for expenses caused by the desertion. The balance shall be transferred to the appropriate district court of the United States when the voyage is completed.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> If it appears to the district court that the forfeiture was imposed properly, the property transferred may be sold in the same manner prescribed for the disposition of the property of deceased seamen. The court shall deposit in the Treasury as miscellaneous receipts the proceeds of the sale and any money and wages transferred to the court.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> When an owner or master fails to transfer the balance as required under subsection (a) of this section, the owner or master is liable to the United States Government for a civil penalty of 2 times the amount of the balance, recoverable by the Secretary in the same manner that seaman’s wages are recovered.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> In all other cases of forfeiture of wages, the forfeiture shall be for the benefit of the owner of the vessel.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 584</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–206, title IV, § 421</ref>, <date date="1993-12-20">Dec. 20, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 2438</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11506.</num>
<heading> Carrying sheath knives</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A seaman in the merchant marine may not wear a sheath knife on board a vessel without the consent of the master. The master of a vessel of the United States shall inform each seaman of this prohibition before engagement. A master failing to advise a seaman is liable to the United States Government for a civil penalty of $50.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 584</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11507.</num>
<heading> Surrender of offending officers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">When an officer of a vessel of the United States (except the master) has violated <ref>section 2191 of title 18</ref>, and the master has actual knowledge of the offense or if complaint is made within 3 days after reaching port, the master shall surrender the offending officer to the proper authorities. If the master fails to use diligence to comply with this section and the offender escapes, the owner, the master, and the vessel are liable for damages to the individual unlawfully punished.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 584</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>