<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 803—</num>
<heading>ICE AND DERELICTS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 80301.</num>
<heading> International agreements</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The President may make agreements with interested maritime countries to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> maintain in the North Atlantic Ocean a service of ice patrol, of study and observation of ice and current conditions, and of assistance to vessels and their crews requiring assistance within the limits of the patrol;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> maintain a service of study and observation of ice and current conditions in the waters affecting the set and drift of ice in the North Atlantic Ocean; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> take all practicable steps to ensure the destruction or removal of derelicts in the northern part of the Atlantic Ocean, east of the line drawn from Cape Sable to a point in latitude 34 degrees north, longitude 70 degrees west, if the destruction or removal is necessary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Payment Between Countries</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The President may include in an agreement under subsection (a) a provision for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> payment to the United States Government by other countries for their proportionate share of the expense of maintaining the services; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> contribution by the Government for its proportionate share if the agreement provides for another country to maintain the services.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Payments</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Payments received pursuant to subsection (b)(1) shall be credited to the appropriation for operations and support of the Coast Guard.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 11</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1692</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–281, title III, § 314(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-18">Dec. 18, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3049</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXV</ref> [LXXXV], § 8513(b), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4761</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 80302.</num>
<heading> Patrol services</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Unless the agreements made under <ref>section 80301 of this title</ref> provide otherwise, an ice patrol shall be maintained during the entire ice season in guarding the southeastern, southern, and southwestern limits of the region of icebergs in the vicinity of the Grand Banks of Newfoundland. The patrol shall inform trans-Atlantic and other passing vessels by radio and other available means of the ice conditions and the extent of the dangerous region. During the ice season, there shall be maintained a service of study of ice and current conditions, a service of providing assistance to vessels and crews requiring assistance, and a service of removing and destroying derelicts. Any of these services may be maintained during the remainder of the year as may be advisable.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Warnings to Vessels</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The ice patrol shall warn any vessel known to be approaching a dangerous area and recommend safe routes.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Recording and Reporting Incidents</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Recording</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The ice patrol shall record the name of a vessel and the facts of the case when the patrol observes or knows that the vessel—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is on other than a regular recognized or advertised route crossing the North Atlantic Ocean;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> has crossed the fishing banks of Newfoundland north of latitude 43 degrees north during the fishing season; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> has passed through regions known or believed to be endangered by ice when proceeding to and from ports of North America.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reporting</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The name of the vessel and all pertinent information about the incident shall be reported to the government of the country to which the vessel belongs if that government requests.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Administration</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commandant, under the direction of the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating, shall carry out the services provided for in this section and shall assign necessary aircraft, material, and personnel of the Coast Guard. On request of such Secretary, the head of an agency may detail personnel, lend or contribute material or equipment, or otherwise assist in carrying out the services provided for in this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Report</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commandant shall publish an annual report of the activities of the services provided for in this section. A copy of the report shall be provided to each interested foreign government and to each agency assisting in the work.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 11</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1692</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–281, title III, § 314(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-18">Dec. 18, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3049</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. C, title XXXV, § 3541(b)(16)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2324</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 80303.</num>
<heading> Speed of vessel in ice region</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The master of a vessel of the United States, when ice is reported on or near the vessel’s course, shall proceed at a moderate speed or change the course of the vessel to go well clear of the danger zone.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Civil Penalty</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A master violating this section is liable to the United States Government for a civil penalty of not more than $500.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 11</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1693</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 80304.</num>
<heading> Limitation on ice patrol data</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Notwithstanding sections 80301 and 80302, data collected by an ice patrol conducted by the Coast Guard under this chapter may not be disseminated to a vessel unless such vessel is—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> documented under the laws of the United States; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> documented under the laws of a foreign country that made the payment or contribution required under section 80301(b) for the year preceding the year in which the data is collected.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 113–281, title III, § 314(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-18">Dec. 18, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3049</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>