<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 513—</num>
<heading>UNITED STATES MERCHANT MARINE ACADEMY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 51301.</num>
<heading> Maintenance of the Academy</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Transportation shall maintain the United States Merchant Marine Academy as an institution of higher education to provide instruction to individuals to prepare them for service in the merchant marine of the United States, to conduct research with respect to maritime-related matters, and to provide such other appropriate academic support, assistance, training, and activities in accordance with the provisions of this chapter as the Secretary may authorize.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Recruitment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Transportation may, subject to the availability of appropriations, expend funds available for United States Merchant Marine Academy operating expenses for recruiting activities, including advertising, in order to obtain recruits for the Academy and cadet applicants.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Superintendent.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The immediate command of the United States Merchant Marine Academy shall be in the Superintendent of the Academy, subject to the direction of the Maritime Administrator under the general supervision of the Secretary of Transportation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appointment</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Transportation shall appoint as the Superintendent—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> an individual who has—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> attained the rank of Captain, Chief Mate, or Chief Engineer in the merchant marine of the United States, or a general or flag officer rank in the Navy, Army, Air Force, Marine Corps, Coast Guard, or National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> served at sea in any rank;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> an individual who has—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> served at sea in the merchant marine, Navy, Army, Air Force, Marine Corps, Coast Guard, or National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> held a valid Coast Guard merchant mariner credential; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> demonstrated exemplary leadership in the education of individuals in the Armed Forces or United States merchant marine; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> if a qualified individual described in subparagraph (A) or (B) does not apply for the position, an individual who has—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> attained the grade of captain or above in the merchant marine, Navy, Coast Guard, or National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration or colonel or above in the Army, Air Force, or Marine Corps; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> served at sea in any grade.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rule of construction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding paragraph (2), the Secretary of Transportation may appoint an individual who is the best qualified candidate, even if such individual does not fully meet the criteria described in paragraph (2).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1570</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. C, title XXXV, § 3504</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4518</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. C, title XXXV, § 3503</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1716</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title X, § 1076(i)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1955</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. C, title XXXV, § 3506(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2777</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. C, title XXXV, § 3503(b)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4399</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 51302.</num>
<heading> Nomination and competitive appointment of cadets</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An individual may be nominated for a competitive appointment as a cadet at the United States Merchant Marine Academy only if the individual—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> is a citizen or national of the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> meets the minimum requirements that the Secretary of Transportation shall establish.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Nominators</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Nominations for competitive appointments for the positions allocated under subsection (c) may be made as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A Senator may nominate residents of the State represented by that Senator.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A Member of the House of Representatives may nominate residents of the State in which the congressional district represented by that Member is located.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A Delegate to the House of Representatives from the District of Columbia, the Virgin Islands, Guam, the Northern Mariana Islands, or American Samoa may nominate residents of the jurisdiction represented by that Delegate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Resident Commissioner to the United States from Puerto Rico may nominate residents of Puerto Rico.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> The Panama Canal Commission may nominate—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> residents, or sons or daughters of residents, of an area or installation in Panama and made available to the United States under the Panama Canal Treaty of 1977, the agreements relating to and implementing that Treaty, signed <date date="1977-09-07">September 7, 1977</date>, and the Agreement Between the United States of America and the Republic of Panama Concerning Air Traffic Control and Related Services, concluded <date date="1979-01-08">January 8, 1979</date>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> sons or daughters of personnel of the United States Government and the Panama Canal Commission residing in Panama.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Allocation of Positions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Positions for competitive appointments shall be allocated each year as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Positions shall be allocated for residents of each State nominated by the Members of Congress from that State in proportion to the representation in Congress from that State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Four positions shall be allocated for residents of the District of Columbia nominated by the Delegate to the House of Representatives from the District of Columbia.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> One position each shall be allocated for residents of the Virgin Islands, Guam, and American Samoa nominated by the Delegates to the House of Representatives from the Virgin Islands, Guam, and American Samoa, respectively.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> One position shall be allocated for a resident of Puerto Rico nominated by the Resident Commissioner to the United States from Puerto Rico.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> One position shall be allocated for a resident of the Northern Mariana Islands nominated by the Governor of the Northern Mariana Islands.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Two positions shall be allocated for individuals nominated by the Panama Canal Commission.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Competitive System for Appointment</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment of system</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall establish a competitive system for selecting individuals nominated under subsection (b) to fill the positions allocated under subsection (c). The system must determine the relative merit of each individual based on competitive examinations, an assessment of the individual’s academic background, and other effective indicators of motivation and probability of successful completion of training at the Academy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appointments by jurisdiction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall appoint individuals to fill the positions allocated under subsection (c) for each jurisdiction in the order of merit of the individuals nominated from that jurisdiction.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Remaining unfilled positions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If positions remain unfilled after the appointments are made under paragraph (2), the Secretary shall appoint individuals to fill the positions in the order of merit of the remaining individuals nominated from all jurisdictions.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Congressional Notification in Advance of Appointments</inline>.—</heading>
<content>When a nominee of a Senator, Representative, or Delegate is selected for appointment as a cadet, the Senator, Representative, or Delegate shall be notified at least 48 hours before the official notification or announcement of the appointment is made.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1570</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. C, title XXXV, § 3503</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4518</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title V, § 566(d)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2139</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 51302a.</num>
<heading> Nomination in event of death, resignation, or expulsion from office of Senator otherwise authorized to nominate</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Senators</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In the event a Senator does not submit nominations for cadets for an academic year in accordance with <ref>section 51302(b)(1) of this title</ref> due to death, resignation from office, or expulsion from office, and the date of the swearing-in of the Senator’s successor as Senator occurs after the date of the deadline for submittal of nominations for cadets for the academic year, the nominations for cadets otherwise authorized to be made by the Senator pursuant to such section shall be made instead by the other Senator from the State concerned.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Construction of Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any nomination for cadets made by a Senator pursuant to this section is not a reallocation of a nomination. Such nominations are made in lieu of a Senator not submitting nominations for cadets for an academic year in accordance with <ref>section 51302 of this title</ref> due to death, resignation from office, or expulsion from office and the date of the swearing-in of the Senator’s successor occurs after the date of the deadline for submittal of nominations for cadets for the academic year.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. C, title XXXV, § 3537(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2316</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 51303.</num>
<heading> Non-competitive appointments</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Transportation may appoint each year without competition as cadets at the United States Merchant Marine Academy not more than 50 qualified individuals with qualities the Secretary considers to be of special value to the Academy. In making these appointments, the Secretary shall try to achieve a national demographic balance at the Academy.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appointment of Candidates Selected for Preparatory School Sponsorship</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Transportation may appoint each year as cadets at the United States Merchant Marine Academy not more than 40 qualified individuals sponsored by the Academy to attend preparatory school during the academic year prior to entrance in the Academy, and who have successfully met the terms and conditions of sponsorship set by the Academy.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1572</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. C, title XXXV, § 3516(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2789</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. C, title XXXV, § 3504</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1970</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 51304.</num>
<heading> Additional appointments from particular areas</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Other Countries in Western Hemisphere</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The President may appoint individuals from countries in the Western Hemisphere other than the United States to receive instruction at the United States Merchant Marine Academy. Not more than 12 individuals may receive instruction under this subsection at the same time, and not more than 2 individuals from the same country may receive instruction under this subsection at the same time.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Other Countries Generally</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appointment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Transportation, with the approval of the Secretary of State, may appoint individuals from countries other than the United States to receive instruction at the Academy. Not more than 30 individuals may receive instruction under this subsection at the same time.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reimbursement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Transportation shall ensure that the country from which an individual comes under this subsection will reimburse the Secretary for the cost (as determined by the Secretary) of the instruction and allowances received by the individual.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Panama</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appointment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Transportation, with the approval of the Secretary of State, may appoint individuals from Panama to receive instruction at the Academy. Individuals appointed under this subsection are in addition to those appointed under any other provision of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reimbursement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Transportation shall be reimbursed for the cost (as determined by the Secretary) of the instruction and allowances received by an individual appointed under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Allowances and Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Individuals receiving instruction under this section are entitled to the same allowances and are subject to the same regulations on admission, attendance, discipline, resignation, discharge, dismissal, and graduation, as cadets at the Academy appointed from the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1572</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 51305.</num>
<heading> Prohibited basis for appointment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Preference may not be given to an individual for appointment as a cadet at the United States Merchant Marine Academy because one or more members of the individual’s immediate family are alumni of the Academy.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1572</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 51306.</num>
<heading> Cadet commitment agreements</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Agreement Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A citizen of the United States appointed as a cadet at the United States Merchant Marine Academy shall sign, as a condition of the appointment, an agreement to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> complete the course of instruction at the Academy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> obtain a merchant mariner license, unlimited as to horsepower or tonnage, issued by the Coast Guard as an officer in the merchant marine of the United States, accompanied by the appropriate national and international endorsements and certifications required by the Coast Guard for service aboard vessels on domestic and international voyages, without limitation, before graduation from the Academy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> for at least 6 years after graduation from the Academy, maintain—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a valid merchant mariner license, unlimited as to horsepower or tonnage, issued by the Coast Guard as an officer in the merchant marine of the United States, accompanied by the appropriate national and international endorsements and certifications required by the Coast Guard for service aboard vessels on domestic and international voyages, without limitation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a valid transportation worker identification credential; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a Coast Guard medical certificate;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> apply for, and accept if tendered, an appointment as a commissioned officer in the Navy Reserve (including the Strategic Sealift Officer Program, Navy Reserve), the Coast Guard Reserve, or any other reserve component of an armed force of the United States, and, if tendered the appointment, to serve, meet the participation requirements, and maintain active status in good standing, as determined by the program manager of the appropriate military service, for at least 8 years after the date of commissioning;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> serve the foreign and domestic commerce and the national defense of the United States for at least 5 years after graduation from the Academy—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> as a merchant marine officer on a documented vessel or a vessel owned and operated by the United States Government or by a State;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> as an employee in a United States maritime-related industry, profession, or marine science (as determined by the Secretary of Transportation), if the Secretary determines that service under subparagraph (A) is not available to the individual;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> as a commissioned officer on active duty in an armed force of the United States, as a commissioned officer in the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, or in other maritime-related Federal employment which serves the national security interests of the United States, as determined by the Secretary; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> by a combination of the service alternatives referred to in subparagraphs (A)–(C); and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> report to the Secretary on compliance with this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Failure To Complete Course of Instruction</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Active duty</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the Secretary of Transportation determines that an individual who has attended the Academy for at least 2 years has failed to fulfill the part of the agreement described in subsection (a)(1), the individual may be ordered by the Secretary of Defense to serve on active duty in one of the armed forces of the United States for a period of not more than 2 years. In cases of hardship as determined by the Secretary of Transportation, the Secretary of Transportation may waive this paragraph in whole or in part.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Recovery of cost</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the Secretary of Defense is unable or unwilling to order an individual to serve on active duty under paragraph (1), or if the Secretary of Transportation determines that reimbursement of the cost of education provided would better serve the interests of the United States, the Secretary of Transportation may recover from the individual the cost of education provided by the Government.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Failure To Carry Out Other Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Active duty</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the Secretary of Transportation determines that an individual has failed to fulfill any part of the agreement described in subsection (a)(2)–(6), the individual may be ordered to serve on active duty for a period of at least 3 years but not more than the unexpired period (as determined by the Secretary) of the service required by subsection (a)(5). The Secretary of Transportation, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, shall determine in which service the individual shall serve. In cases of hardship as determined by the Secretary of Transportation, the Secretary of Transportation may waive this paragraph in whole or in part.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Recovery of cost</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the Secretary of Defense is unable or unwilling to order an individual to serve on active duty under paragraph (1), or if the Secretary of Transportation determines that reimbursement of the cost of education provided would better serve the interests of the United States, the Secretary of Transportation may recover from the individual the cost of education provided. The Secretary may reduce the amount to be recovered to reflect partial performance of service obligations and other factors the Secretary determines merit a reduction.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Actions To Recover Cost</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>To aid in the recovery of the cost of education provided by the Government under a commitment agreement under this section, the Secretary of Transportation may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> request the Attorney General to bring a civil action against the individual; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> make use of the Federal debt collection procedures in chapter 176 of title 28 or other applicable administrative remedies.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Alternative Service.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Service as commissioned officer</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An individual who, for the 5-year period following graduation from the Academy, serves as a commissioned officer on active duty in an armed force of the United States or as a commissioned officer of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration or the Public Health Service shall be excused from the requirements of paragraphs (3) through (5) of subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Modification or waiver</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may modify or waive any of the terms and conditions set forth in subsection (a) through the imposition of alternative service requirements.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Service Obligation Performance Reporting Requirement.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subject to any otherwise applicable restrictions on disclosure in <ref>section 552a of title 5</ref>, the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating, the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, and the Surgeon General of the Public Health Service—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall report the status of obligated service of an individual graduate of the Academy upon request of the Secretary; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> may, in their discretion, notify the Secretary of any failure of the graduate to perform the graduate’s duties, either on active duty or in the Ready Reserve component of their respective service, or as a commissioned officer of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration or the Public Health Service, respectively.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Information to be provided</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A report or notice under paragraph (1) shall identify any graduate determined to have failed to comply with service obligation requirements and provide all required information as to why such graduate failed to comply.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Considered as in default</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Upon receipt of such a report or notice, such graduate may be considered to be in default of the graduate’s service obligations by the Secretary, and subject to all remedies the Secretary may have with respect to such a default.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1572</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title V, § 515(g)(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3236</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. C, title XXXV</ref>, §§ 3505(a), 3506(a), <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2516</ref>, 2517; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. C, title XXXV</ref>, §§ 3523(a)(1), (b), 3526(b)(1), (c)(1), (g), <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 598</ref>, 600–602; <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. C, title XXXV, § 3506</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 1220</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 51307.</num>
<heading> Places of training</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Transportation may provide for the training of cadets at the United States Merchant Marine Academy—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> on vessels owned, subsidized by, or contracted with the United States Government;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> on other documented vessels, with the permission of the owner;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> in shipyards or plants and with industrial or educational organizations; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> on any other vessel considered by the Secretary to be necessary or appropriate or in the national interest.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Sea Year Cadets on Certain Vessels.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall require an operator of a vessel participating in the Maritime Security Program under chapter 531 of this title, the Cable Security Fleet under chapter 532 of this title, or the Tanker Security Fleet under chapter 534 of this title to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> carry on each Maritime Security Program vessel, Cable Security Fleet vessel, or Tanker Security Fleet vessel 2 United States Merchant Marine Academy cadets, if available, on each voyage; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> implement and adhere to policies, programs, criteria, and requirements established pursuant to <ref>section 51322 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Failure to implement or adhere to requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Failure to implement or adhere to the policies, programs, criteria, and requirements referred to in paragraph (1) may, as determined by the Maritime Administrator, constitute a violation of an operating agreement entered into under chapter 531, 532, or 534 of this title and the Maritime Administrator may—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> require the operator to take corrective actions; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> withhold payment due to the operator until the violation, as determined by the Maritime Administrator, has been remedied.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Withheld payments</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any payment withheld pursuant to paragraph (2)(B) may be paid, upon a determination by the Maritime Administrator that the operator is in compliance with the policies, programs, criteria, and requirements referred to in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Military Sealift Command Vessels.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the Commander of the Military Sealift Command shall require an operator of a vessel in the United States Navy’s Military Sealift Command to carry on each such vessel 2 United States Merchant Marine Academy cadets, if available, on each voyage, if the vessel—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is flagged in the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is rated at 10,000 gross tons or higher.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Waiver</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commander of the Military Sealift Command may waive the requirement under paragraph (1) at any time if the Commander determines that carrying a cadet from the United States Merchant Marine Academy would place an undue burden on the vessel or the operator of the vessel.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition of Operator</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “operator” includes a government operator and a non-government operator.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Savings Clause</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Nothing in this section may be construed as affecting—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the discretion of the Secretary to determine whether to place a United States Merchant Marine Academy cadet on a vessel;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the authority of the Coast Guard regarding a vessel security plan approved under section 70103; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the discretion of the master of the vessel to ensure the safety of all crew members.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1574</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–241, title III, § 307</ref>, <date date="2006-07-11">July 11, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 528</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. C, title XXXV, § 3525(a)(3)</ref>, (b), <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 600</ref>, 601; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. C, title XXXV, § 3512</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2311</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. C, title XXXV, § 3506</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4405</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. C, title XXXV, § 3517(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3073</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 51308.</num>
<heading> Uniforms, textbooks, and transportation allowances</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of Transportation shall provide cadets at the United States Merchant Marine Academy—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> all required uniforms and textbooks; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> allowances for transportation (including reimbursement of traveling expenses) when traveling under orders as a cadet.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1574</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 51309.</num>
<heading> Academic degree</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Bachelor’s Degree</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Superintendent of the United States Merchant Marine Academy may confer the degree of bachelor of science on an individual who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> has met the conditions prescribed by the Secretary of Transportation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> if a citizen of the United States, has passed the examination for a merchant marine officer’s license.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Effect of physical or psychological disqualification</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An individual not able or allowed to take the examination for a merchant marine officer’s license solely due to a documented medical or psychological condition shall not be denied a degree for not taking the examination.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Master’s Degree</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Superintendent of the Academy may confer a master’s degree on an individual who has met the conditions prescribed by the Secretary. A master’s degree program may be funded through non-appropriated funds. To maintain the appropriate academic standards, the program shall be accredited by the appropriate accreditation body. Nonappropriated funds received for this purpose shall be credited to the Maritime Administration’s Operations and Training appropriation, to remain available until expended, for those expenses directly related to the purpose of such receipts. The Superintendent shall maintain a separate and detailed accounting of nonappropriated fund receipts and all associated expenses. The Secretary may prescribe regulations necessary to administer such a program.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Graduation Not Entitlement To Hold License</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Graduation from the Academy does not entitle an individual to hold a license authorizing service on a merchant vessel.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition of Documented Medical or Psychological Condition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section the term “documented medical or psychological condition” means, with respect to an individual, a physical disqualification or psychological condition, including a mental health condition arising from sexual assault or sexual harassment, for which the individual has been treated or is being treated by a medical or psychological provider.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1574</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. C, title XXXV, § 3514</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2724</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. C, title XXXV, § 3511</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3065</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 51310.</num>
<heading> Deferment of service obligation under cadet commitment agreements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Transportation may defer the service commitment of an individual under <ref>section 51306(a)(5) of this title</ref> (as specified in the cadet commitment agreement) for not more than 2 years if the individual is engaged in a graduate course of study approved by the Secretary. However, deferment of service as a commissioned officer under section 51306(a)(5) must be approved by the Secretary of the military department that has jurisdiction over the service or by the Secretary of Commerce for service with the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1575</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 51311.</num>
<heading> Midshipman status in the Navy Reserve</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Application Requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Before being appointed as a cadet at the United States Merchant Marine Academy, a citizen of the United States must agree to apply for midshipman status in the Navy Reserve (including the Merchant Marine Reserve, Navy Reserve).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appointment</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A citizen of the United States appointed as a cadet at the Academy shall be appointed by the Secretary of the Navy as a midshipman in the Navy Reserve (including the Merchant Marine Reserve, Navy Reserve).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rights and privileges</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of the Navy shall provide for cadets of the Academy who are midshipmen in the United States Navy Reserve to be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> issued an identification card (referred to as a “military ID card”); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> entitled to all rights and privileges in accordance with the same eligibility criteria as apply to other members of the Ready Reserve of the reserve components of the armed forces.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Coordination</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the Navy shall carry out paragraphs (1) and (2) in coordination with the Secretary of Transportation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1575</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title V, § 515(g)(2)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3236</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. C, title XXXV, § 3523(a)(1)</ref>, (b), <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 598</ref>, 600.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 51312.</num>
<heading> Board of Visitors</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There shall be a Board of Visitors to the United States Merchant Marine Academy (referred to in this section as the “Board” and the “Academy”, respectively) to provide independent advice and recommendations on matters relating to the United States Merchant Marine Academy.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Membership.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Board shall be composed of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> 2 Senators appointed by the Chairman of the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate in consultation with the ranking member of such Committee;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> 3 Members of the House of Representatives appointed by the Chairman of the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives in consultation with the ranking member of such Committee;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> 1 Senator appointed by the Vice President, who shall be a member of the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> 2 Members of the House of Representatives appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives, in consultation with the Minority Leader, at least 1 of whom shall be a member of the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> 5 individuals appointed by the President; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<chapeau> as ex officio members—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Commander of the Military Sealift Command;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the Deputy Commandant for Operations of the Coast Guard;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the chairman of the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the chairman of the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> the chairman of the Advisory Board to the Academy established under section 51313; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> the Member of the House of Representatives for the congressional district in which the Academy is located, as a nonvoting member, unless such Member of the House of Representatives is appointed as a voting member of the Board under subparagraph (B) or (D).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Presidential appointees</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Of the individuals appointed by the President under paragraph (1)(E)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> at least 2 shall be graduates of the Academy;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> at least 1 shall be a senior corporate officer from a United States maritime shipping company that participates in the Maritime Security Program, or in any Maritime Administration program providing incentives for companies to register their vessels in the United States, and this appointment shall rotate biennially among such companies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> at least 1 shall be a representative of a maritime labor organization; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> 1 or more may be a Senate-confirmed Presidential appointee, a member of the Senior Executive Service, or an officer of flag-rank from the Coast Guard, the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, or any of the military services that commission graduates of the Academy, other than the individuals who are members of the Board under clauses (i) and (ii) of paragraph (1)(F).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Term of service.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), each member of the Board, other than an ex officio member under paragraph (1)(F), shall serve for a term of 2 years commencing at the beginning of each Congress.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Continuation of service</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any member described in subparagraph (A) whose term on the Board has expired, other than a member appointed under any of subparagraphs (A) through (D) of paragraph (1) who is no longer a Member of Congress, shall continue to serve until a successor is appointed.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Replacement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If a member of the Board is replaced, not later than 60 days after the date of the replacement, the Designated Federal Officer selected under subsection (g)(2) shall notify that member.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Vacancies</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If a member of the Board is no longer able to serve on the Board or resigns, the Designated Federal Officer selected under subsection (g)(2) shall immediately notify the person who appointed such member. Not later than 60 days after that notification, such person shall designate a replacement to serve the remainder of such member’s term.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Designation and responsibility of substitute board members.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority to designate</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A member of the Board under clause (i) or (ii) of paragraph (1)(F) or appointed under subparagraph (B) or (C) of paragraph (2) may, if unable to attend or participate in an activity described in subsection (d), (e), or (f), designate another individual to serve as a substitute member of the Board, on a temporary basis, to attend or participate in such activity.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A substitute member of the Board designated under subparagraph (A) shall be—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an individual serving in a position for which the individual was appointed by the President and confirmed by the Senate;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a member of the Senior Executive Service; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> an officer of flag-rank who is employed by—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the Coast Guard; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the Military Sealift Command.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Participation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A substitute member of the Board designated under subparagraph (A)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> shall be permitted by the Board to fully participate in the proceedings and activities of the Board;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> shall report to the member that designated the substitute member on the Board’s activities not later than 15 days following the substitute member’s participation in such activities; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> shall be permitted by the Board to participate in the preparation of reports described in paragraph <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002023">1</ref> (j) related to any proceedings or activities of the Board in which such substitute member participates.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Chairperson.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>On a biennial basis and subject to paragraph (2), the Board shall select from among its members a Member of the House of Representatives or a Senator to serve as the Chairperson.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rotation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A Member of the House of Representatives and a Member of the Senate shall alternately be selected as the Chairperson of the Board.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Term</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An individual may not serve as Chairperson for consecutive terms.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Meetings.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Board shall meet as provided for in the Charter adopted under paragraph (2)(B), including at least 1 meeting held at the Academy and 2 additional meetings, which may be held in person or virtually.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Chairperson and charter</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Designated Federal Officer selected under subsection (g)(2) shall organize a meeting of the Board for the purposes of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> selecting a Chairperson under subsection (c); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> adopting an official Charter for the Board, which shall establish the schedule of meetings of the Board.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Scheduling; notification</inline>.—</heading>
<content>When scheduling a meeting of the Board, the Designated Federal Officer shall coordinate, to the greatest extent practicable, with the members of the Board to determine the date and time of the meeting. Members of the Board shall be notified of the date of each meeting not less than 30 days prior to the meeting date.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Visiting the Academy.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual visit</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Board shall visit the Academy annually on a date selected by the Board, in consultation with the Secretary of Transportation and the Superintendent of the Academy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Other visits</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In cooperation with the Superintendent, the Board or its members may make other visits to the Academy in connection with the duties of the Board.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Access</inline>.—</heading>
<content>While visiting the Academy under this subsection, members of the Board shall have reasonable access to the grounds, facilities, midshipmen, faculty, staff, and other personnel of the Academy for the purpose of carrying out the duties of the Board.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Staff</inline>.—</heading>
<content>One or more staff of each member of the Board may accompany them on Academy visits.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Scheduling; notification</inline>.—</heading>
<content>When scheduling a visit to the Academy, the Designated Federal Officer shall coordinate, to the greatest extent practicable, with the members of the Board to determine the date and time of the visit. Members of the Board shall be notified of the date of each visit not less than 30 days prior to the visit date.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Responsibility</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Board shall inquire into the state of morale and discipline, the curriculum, instruction, physical equipment, fiscal affairs, and academic methods of the Academy, and other matters relating to the Academy that the Board decides to consider.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Department of Transportation Support</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Transportation shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provide support as deemed necessary by the Board for the performance of the Board’s functions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> select a Designated Federal Officer to support the performance of the Board’s functions; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> in cooperation with the Maritime Administrator and the Superintendent of the Academy, advise the Board of any institutional issues, consistent with applicable laws concerning the disclosure of information.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Staff</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each of the chairman and ranking member of the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the chairman and ranking member of the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives may designate staff members of such Committee to serve, without additional reimbursement (except as provided in subsection (i)), as staff for the Board. Such staff may attend meetings and may visit the Academy.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Travel Expenses</inline>.—</heading>
<content>While serving away from his or her home or regular place of business, a member of the Board or a staff member designated under subsection (h) shall be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, as authorized under <ref>section 5703 of title 5</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Reports.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual report</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 60 days after each annual visit required under subsection (e)(1), the Board shall submit to the President a written report of its actions, views, and recommendations pertaining to the Academy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Other reports</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>If the members of the Board visit the Academy under subsection (e)(2), the Board may—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> prepare a report on such visit; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> if approved by a majority of the members of the Board, submit such report to the President not later than 60 days after the date of the approval.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Advisors</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Board may call in advisers—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> for consultation regarding the execution of the Board’s responsibility under subsection (f); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to assist in the preparation of a report described in paragraph (1) or (2).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Submission</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A report submitted to the President under paragraph (1) or (2) shall be concurrently submitted to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Transportation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1575</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. C, title XXXV, § 3504(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3905</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. C, title XXXV, § 3512</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3065</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 51313.</num>
<heading> Advisory Board</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An Advisory Board to the United States Merchant Marine Academy shall be established to visit the Academy at least once during each academic year, for the purpose of examining the course of instruction and management of the Academy and advising the Maritime Administrator and the Superintendent of the Academy.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appointment and Terms</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Board shall be composed of not more than 7 individuals appointed by the Secretary of Transportation. The individuals must be distinguished in education and other fields related to the Academy. Members of the Board shall be appointed for terms of not more than 3 years and may be reappointed. The Secretary shall designate one of the members as chairman.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Travel Expenses</inline>.—</heading>
<content>When serving away from home or regular place of business, a member of the Board shall be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, as authorized by <ref>section 5703 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Relationship to Other Law</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Chapter 10 of title 5 does not apply to the Board.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1576</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(a)(292)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4338</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 51314.</num>
<heading> Limitation on charges and fees for attendance</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in subsection (b), no charge or fee for tuition, room, or board for attendance at the United States Merchant Marine Academy may be imposed unless the charge or fee is specifically authorized by a law enacted after <date date="1994-10-05">October 5, 1994</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The prohibition specified in subsection (a) does not apply with respect to any item or service provided to cadets for which a charge or fee is imposed as of <date date="1994-10-05">October 5, 1994</date>, or for calculators, computers, personal and academic supplies, midshipman services such as barber, tailor, or laundry services, and Coast Guard license fees. The Secretary of Transportation shall present at the next meeting of the Board of Visitors, and post on a publicly available website, any change made by the Academy in the amount of a charge or fee authorized under this subsection. Such fees shall be credited to the Maritime Administration’s Operations and Training appropriation, to remain available until expended, for those expenses directly related to the purposes of the fees. Fees collected in excess of actual expenses may be refunded to the Midshipmen through a mechanism approved by the Secretary. The Academy shall maintain a separate and detailed accounting of fee revenue and all associated expenses.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1576</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. C, title XXXV, § 3510</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2722</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–117, div. A, title I, § 176</ref>, <date date="2009-12-16">Dec. 16, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 3068</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–420, § 2</ref>, <date date="2019-01-03">Jan. 3, 2019</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5444</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 51315.</num>
<heading> Gifts to the Merchant Marine Academy</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Maritime Administrator may accept and use conditional or unconditional gifts of money or property for the benefit of the United States Merchant Marine Academy, including acceptance and use for non-appropriated fund instrumentalities of the Merchant Marine Academy. The Maritime Administrator may accept a gift of services in carrying out the Administrator’s duties and powers. Property accepted under this section and proceeds from that property must be used, as nearly as possible, in accordance with the terms of the gift.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment of Academy Gift Fund</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>There is established in the Treasury a fund, to be known as the “Academy Gift Fund”. Disbursements from the Fund shall be made on order of the Maritime Administrator. Unless otherwise specified by the terms of the gift, the Maritime Administrator may use monies in the Fund for appropriated or non-appropriated purposes at the Academy. The Fund consists of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> gifts of money;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> income from donated property accepted under this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> proceeds from the sale of donated property; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> income from securities under subsection (c) of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Investment of Fund Balances</inline>.—</heading>
<content>On request of the Maritime Administrator, the Secretary of the Treasury may invest and reinvest amounts in the Fund in securities of, or in securities the principal and interest of which is guaranteed by, the United States Government.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Disbursement Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There are hereby authorized to be disbursed from the Fund such sums as may be on deposit, to remain available until expended.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Deductibility of Gifts</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Gifts accepted under this section are a gift to or for the use of the Government under the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Payment of Expenses</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Maritime Administrator may pay all necessary expenses in connection with the conveyance or transfer of a gift, devise, or bequest accepted under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–417, div. C, title XXXV, § 3506(g)(1)</ref>, <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4764</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. C, title XXXV, § 3511</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1918</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 51316.</num>
<heading> Temporary appointments to the Academy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Maritime Administrator may appoint any present employee of the United States Merchant Marine Academy non-appropriated fund instrumentality to a position on the General Schedule of comparable pay. Eligible personnel shall be engaged in work permissibly funded by annual appropriations, and such appointments to the Civil Service shall be without regard to competition, for a term not to exceed 2 years.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–417, div. C, title XXXV, § 3506(h)(1)</ref>, <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4765</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 51317.</num>
<heading> Adjunct professors</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Maritime Administrator may establish a program for the purpose of contracting with individuals as personal services contractors to provide services as adjunct professors at the Academy, if the Maritime Administrator determines that there is a need for adjunct professors and the need is not of permanent duration.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contract Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each contract under the program—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> must be approved by the Maritime Administrator;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall be for a duration, including options, of not to exceed one year unless the Maritime Administrator finds that exceptional circumstances justify an extension of up to one additional year; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> shall be subject to the availability of appropriations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. C, title XXXV, § 3503(a)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2719</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. C, title XXXV, § 3509</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1916</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 51318.</num>
<heading> Policy on sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Required Policy.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Transportation shall direct the Superintendent of the United States Merchant Marine Academy to prescribe a policy on sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking applicable to the cadets and other personnel of the Academy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Matters to be specified in policy</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The policy on sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking prescribed under this subsection shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a program to promote awareness and prevention of the incidence of rape, acquaintance rape, domestic violence, dating violence, stalking, and other sexual offenses of a criminal nature that involve cadets or other Academy personnel;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> procedures for documenting, tracking, and maintaining the data required to conduct the annual assessments to determine the effectiveness of the policies, procedures, and training program of the Academy with respect to sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking involving cadets or other Academy personnel, as required by subsection (c);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> procedures that a cadet or other Academy personnel should follow in the case of an occurrence of sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> specifying the person or persons to whom an alleged occurrence of sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking should be reported by the victim and the options for confidential reporting;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> specifying any other person whom the victim should contact; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> procedures on the preservation of evidence potentially necessary for proof of a criminal sexual offense;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> procedures for investigating sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking involving a cadet or other Academy personnel to determine whether disciplinary action is necessary;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> a procedure for disciplinary action in cases of alleged criminal sexual assault involving a cadet or other Academy personnel;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> any other sanction authorized to be imposed in a substantiated case of sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking involving a cadet or other Academy personnel in rape, acquaintance rape, or any other criminal sexual offense, whether forcible or nonforcible;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<chapeau> procedures through which—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> questions regarding sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking can be confidentially asked and confidentially answered;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> victims can report incidents of sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking confidentially; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the privacy of victims of sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking will be protected; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> required training on the policy for all cadets and other Academy personnel, including the specific training required for personnel who process allegations of sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking involving Academy personnel.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Minimum training requirements for certain individuals regarding sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Maritime Administrator shall direct the Superintendent of the United States Merchant Marine Academy to develop a mandatory training program at the Academy for each individual who is involved in implementing the Academy’s student disciplinary grievance procedures, including each individual who is responsible for—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> resolving complaints of reported sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> resolving complaints of reported violations of the sexual misconduct policy of the Academy; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> conducting an interview with a victim of sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consultation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Superintendent shall develop the training program described in subparagraph (A) in consultation with national, State, or local sexual assault, dating violence, domestic violence, or stalking victim advocacy, victim services, or prevention organizations.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The training required by subparagraph (A) shall include the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Information on working with and interviewing persons subjected to sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Information on particular types of conduct that would constitute sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking, regardless of gender, including same-sex sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Information on consent and the effect that drugs or alcohol may have on an individual’s ability to consent.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> Information on the effects of trauma, including the neurobiology of trauma.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> Training regarding the use of trauma-informed interview techniques, which means asking questions of an individual who has been a victim of sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking in a manner that is focused on the experience of the victim, does not judge or blame the victim, and is informed by evidence-based research on the neurobiology of trauma.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> Training on cultural awareness regarding how dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking may impact midshipmen differently depending on their cultural background.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> Information on sexual assault dynamics, sexual assault perpetrator behavior, and barriers to reporting.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Implementation.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Development and approval schedule</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The training program required by subparagraph (A) shall be developed not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2018.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Completion of training</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each individual who is required to complete the training described in subparagraph (A) shall complete such training not later than—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> 270 days after the date of the enactment of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2018; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> 180 days after starting a position with responsibilities that include the activities described in clause (i), (ii), or (iii) of subparagraph (A).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Availability of policy</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall ensure that the policy developed under this subsection is available to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> all cadets and employees of the Academy; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the public.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consultation and assistance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In developing the policy under this subsection, the Secretary may consult with or receive assistance from such Federal, State, local, and national organizations and subject matter experts as the Secretary considers appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consistency with the higher education act of 1965</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall ensure that the policy developed under this subsection meets the requirements set out in section 485(f)(8) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<ref>20 U.S.C. 1092(f)(8)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Development Program.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Maritime Administrator shall ensure that the development program of the Academy includes a section that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> describes the relationship between honor, respect, and character development and the prevention of sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking at the Academy;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> includes a brief history of the problem of sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking in the merchant marine, in the Armed Forces, and at the Academy; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> includes information relating to reporting sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking, victims’ rights, and dismissal for offenders.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Minimum requirements to combat retaliation.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirement for plan</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2018, the Maritime Administrator shall direct the Superintendent of the United States Merchant Marine Academy to implement and maintain a plan to combat retaliation against cadets at the Academy and other Academy personnel who report sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Violation of code of conduct</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Superintendent shall consider an act of retaliation against a cadet at the Academy who reports sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking as a Class I violation of the Midshipman Regulations of the Academy or equivalent code of conduct.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Retaliation definition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Superintendent shall work with the sexual assault prevention and response staff of the Academy to define “retaliation” for purposes of this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Minimum resource requirements.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Maritime Administrator shall ensure the staff at the Academy are provided adequate and appropriate sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking prevention and response training materials and resources. Such resources shall include staff as follows:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Sexual assault response coordinator.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Prevention educator.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Civil rights officer.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> Staff member to oversee Sea Year.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Communication</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Director of the Office of Civil Rights of the Maritime Administration shall create and maintain a direct line of communication to the sexual assault response staff of the Academy that is outside of the chain of command of the Academy.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Minimum training requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Superintendent shall ensure that all cadets receive training on the sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking prevention and response sections of the development program of the Academy, as described in paragraph (1), as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> An initial training session, which shall occur not later than 7 days after a cadet’s initial arrival at the Academy.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Additional training sessions, which shall occur biannually following the cadet’s initial training session until the cadet graduates or leaves the Academy.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Annual Assessment.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary, in cooperation with the Superintendent, shall conduct an assessment at the Academy, during each Academy program year, to determine the effectiveness of the policies, procedures, and training program of the Academy with respect to sexual harassment and sexual assault involving cadets or other Academy personnel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Biennial survey</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For each assessment of the Academy under paragraph (1) during an Academy program year that begins in an odd-numbered calendar year, the Secretary shall conduct a survey of cadets and other Academy personnel—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> to measure—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the incidence, during that program year, of sexual harassment and sexual assault events involving cadets or other Academy personnel, on or off the Academy campus, that have been reported to officials of the Academy; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the incidence, during that program year, of sexual harassment and sexual assault events involving cadets or other Academy personnel, on or off the Academy campus, that have not been reported to officials of the Academy; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> to assess the perceptions of cadets and other Academy personnel on—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the policies, procedures, and training programs of the Academy on sexual harassment and sexual assault involving cadets or other Academy personnel;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the enforcement of the policies described in clause (i);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the incidence of sexual harassment and sexual assault involving cadets or other Academy personnel; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> any other issues relating to sexual harassment and sexual assault involving cadets or other Academy personnel.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Focus groups for years when survey not required</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In any year in which the Secretary is not required to conduct the survey described in paragraph (2), the Secretary shall conduct focus groups at the Academy for the purposes of ascertaining information relating to sexual assault and sexual harassment issues at the Academy.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Annual Report.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For each Academy program year, the Superintendent shall submit to the Secretary a report that provides information about sexual harassment and sexual assault involving cadets or other Academy personnel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contents</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each report submitted under paragraph (1) shall include, for the Academy program year covered by the report—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the number of sexual assaults, rapes, and other sexual offenses, including sexual harassment, involving cadets or other Academy personnel that have been reported to Academy officials;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the number of the reported cases described in subparagraph (A) that have been substantiated;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the policies, procedures, and training implemented by the Superintendent and the leadership of the Academy in response to incidents of sexual harassment and sexual assault involving cadets and other Academy personnel; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a plan for the actions that will be taken in the following Academy program year regarding prevention of, and response to, incidents of sexual harassment and sexual assault involving cadets and other Academy personnel.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Survey and focus group results.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Survey results</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each report under paragraph (1) for an Academy program year that begins in an odd-numbered calendar year shall include the results of the survey conducted in that program year under subsection (c)(2).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Focus group results</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each report under paragraph (1) for an Academy program year in which the Secretary is not required to conduct the survey described in subsection (c)(2) shall include the results of the focus group conducted in that program year under subsection (c)(3).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Reporting requirement.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">By the superintendent</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For each incident of sexual harassment or sexual assault reported to the Superintendent, the Superintendent shall provide to the Secretary and the Board of Visitors of the Academy a report that includes—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the facts surrounding the incident, except for any details that would reveal the identities of the people involved; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the Academy’s response to the incident.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">By the secretary</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than January 15 of each year, the Secretary shall submit a copy of each report received under subparagraph (A) and the Secretary’s comments on the report to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Data for Aggregate Reporting.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No requirement related to confidentiality in this section or <ref>section 51319 of this title</ref> may be construed to prevent a sexual assault response coordinator from providing information for any report required by law regarding sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Identity protection</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any information provided for a report referred to in paragraph (1) shall be provided in a manner that protects the identity of the victim or witness.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section and <ref>section 51319 of this title</ref>:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Dating violence; domestic violence; stalking</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The terms “dating violence”, “domestic violence”, and “stalking” have the meanings given those terms is <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002024">1</ref> section 40002(a) of the Violence Against Women Act of 1994 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 13925(a)</ref>).<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002025">2</ref></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Sexual assault</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “sexual assault” means an offense classified as a forcible or nonforcible sex offense under the uniform crime reporting system of the Federal Bureau of Investigation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. C, title XXXV, § 3510(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2782</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. C, title XXXV, § 3514(a)</ref>–(d)(1), <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1920–1923</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. C, title XXXV, § 3507(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2309</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 51319.</num>
<heading> Sexual assault response coordinators and sexual assault victim advocates</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Sexual Assault Response Coordinators.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirement for coordinators</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The United States Merchant Marine Academy shall employ or contract with at least 1 full-time sexual assault response coordinator who shall reside at or near the Academy. The Secretary of Transportation may assign additional full-time or part-time sexual assault response coordinators at the Academy as necessary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Selection criteria</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each sexual assault response coordinator shall be selected based on—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> experience and a demonstrated ability to effectively provide victim services related to sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> protection of the individual under applicable law to provide privileged communication.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Confidentiality</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A sexual assault response coordinator shall, to the extent authorized under applicable law, provide confidential services to a cadet at the Academy who reports being a victim of, or witness to, sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Training.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Verification</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2018, the Maritime Administrator, in consultation with the Director of the Maritime Administration Office of Civil Rights, shall develop a process to verify that each sexual assault response coordinator has completed proper training.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Training requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The training referred to in subparagraph (A) shall include training in—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> working with victims of sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the policies, procedures, and resources of the Academy related to responding to sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> national, State, and local victim services and resources available to victims of sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Completion of training</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A sexual assault response coordinator shall complete the training referred to in subparagraphs (A) and (B) not later than—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> 270 days after enactment of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2018; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> 180 days after starting in the role of sexual assault response coordinator.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duties</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A sexual assault response coordinator shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> confidentially receive a report from a victim of sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> inform the victim of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the victim’s rights under applicable law;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> options for reporting an incident of sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking to the Academy and law enforcement;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> how to access available services, including emergency medical care, medical forensic or evidentiary examinations, legal services, services provided by rape crisis centers and other victim service providers, services provided by the volunteer sexual assault victim advocates at the Academy, and crisis intervention counseling and ongoing counseling;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> such coordinator’s ability to assist in arranging access to such services, with the consent of the victim;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> available accommodations, such as allowing the victim to change living arrangements and obtain accessibility services;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> such coordinator’s ability to assist in arranging such accommodations, with the consent of the victim;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> the victim’s rights and the Academy’s responsibilities regarding orders of protection, no contact orders, restraining orders, or similar lawful orders issued by the Academy or a criminal, civil, or tribal court; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> privacy limitations under applicable law;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> represent the interests of any cadet at the Academy who reports being a victim of sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking, even if such interests are in conflict with the interests of the Academy;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> advise the victim of, and provide written materials regarding, the information described in subparagraph (B);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> liaise with appropriate staff at the Academy, with the victim’s consent, to arrange reasonable accommodations through the Academy to allow the victim to change living arrangements, obtain accessibility services, or access other accommodations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<chapeau> maintain the privacy and confidentiality of the victim, and shall not notify the Academy or any other authority of the identity of the victim or the alleged circumstances surrounding the reported incident unless—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> otherwise required by applicable law;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> requested to do so by the victim who has been fully and accurately informed about what procedures shall occur if the information is shared; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> notwithstanding clause (i) or clause (ii), there is risk of imminent harm to other individuals;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> assist the victim in contacting and reporting an incident of sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking to the Academy or law enforcement, if requested to do so by the victim who has been fully and accurately informed about what procedures shall occur if information is shared; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> submit to the Director of the Maritime Administration Office of Civil Rights an annual report summarizing how the resources supplied to the coordinator were used during the prior year, including the number of victims assisted by the coordinator.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Oversight.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">In general.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reporting</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each sexual assault response coordinator shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> report directly to the Superintendent; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> have concurrent reporting responsibility to the Executive Director of the Maritime Administration on matters related to the Maritime Administration and the Department of Transportation and upon belief that the Academy leadership is acting inappropriately regarding sexual assault prevention and response matters.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Support</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Maritime Administration Office of Civil Rights shall provide support to the sexual assault response coordinator at the Academy on all sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking prevention matters.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition on investigation by the academy</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any request by a victim for an accommodation, as described in subsection (a)(5)(E), made by a sexual assault response coordinator shall not trigger an investigation by the Academy, even if such coordinator deals only with matters relating to sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition on retaliation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A sexual assault response coordinator, victim advocate, or companion may not be disciplined, penalized, or otherwise retaliated against by the Academy for representing the interests of the victim, even if such interests are in conflict with the interests of the Academy.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Special Victims Advisor.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall designate an attorney (to be known as the “Special Victims Advisor”) for the purpose of providing legal assistance to any cadet of the Academy who is the victim of an alleged sex-related offense regarding administrative and criminal proceedings related to such offense, regardless of whether the report of that offense is restricted or unrestricted.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Special victims advisory</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall ensure that the attorney designated as the Special Victims Advisor has knowledge of the Uniform Code of Military Justice, as well as criminal and civil law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Privileged communications</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any communications between a victim of an alleged sex-related offense and the Special Victim Advisor, when acting in their capacity as such, shall have the same protection that applicable law provides for confidential attorney-client communications.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Volunteer Sexual Assault Victim Advocates.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary, acting through the Superintendent of the Academy, shall designate from among volunteers 1 or more permanent employees of the Academy to serve as advocates for victims of sexual assaults involving cadets of the Academy or other Academy personnel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Training; other duties</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each victim advocate designated under this subsection shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> have or receive training in matters relating to sexual assault and the comprehensive policy developed under section 51318; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> serve as a victim advocate voluntarily, in addition to the individual’s other duties as an employee of the Academy.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Primary duties</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>While performing the duties of a victim advocate under this subsection, a designated employee shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> support victims of sexual assault by informing them of the rights and resources available to them as victims;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> identify additional resources to ensure the safety of victims of sexual assault; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> connect victims of sexual assault to companions, as described in paragraph (4).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Companions.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>At least 1 victim advocate designated under this subsection, or a sexual assault response coordinator designated under subsection (a), while performing the duties of a victim advocate, shall act as a companion to a victim described in paragraph (1) in navigating investigative, medical, mental, and emotional health, and recovery processes relating to sexual assault.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Alternate victim advocates</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If requested by the victim, an alternate victim advocate shall be designated under this subsection to act as a companion to the victim, as described in subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Formal relationships with other entities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may enter into formal relationships with other entities to make available additional victim advocates or to implement paragraphs (3) and (4).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Unfilled Vacancies</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator of the Maritime Administration may appoint qualified candidates to positions under subsections (a) and (d) of this section without regard to sections 3309 through 3319 of title 5.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. C, title XXXV, § 3511(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2785</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. C, title XXXV, § 3515(a)</ref>, (b) (formerly § 3515(c)), <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1924</ref>, 1927, § 3515(b) renumbered § 3515(c), <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. C, title XXXV, § 3513(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-22">Dec. 22, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3068</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. C, title XXXV, § 3531(e)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3088</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 51320.</num>
<heading> Acceptance of guarantees with gifts for major projects</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Major project</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “major project” means a project estimated to cost at least $1,000,000 for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the purchase or other procurement of real or personal property; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the construction, renovation, or repair of real or personal property.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Major united states commercial bank</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “major United States commercial bank” means a commercial bank that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is an insured bank (as defined in section 3(h) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<ref>12 U.S.C. 1813(h)</ref>));</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is headquartered in the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> has total net assets of an amount considered by the Maritime Administrator to qualify the bank as a major bank.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Major united states investment management firm</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “major United States investment management firm” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any broker or dealer (as such terms are defined in section 3 of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<ref>15 U.S.C. 78c</ref>));</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any investment adviser or provider of investment supervisory services (as such terms are defined in section 202 of the Investment Advisers Act of 1940 (<ref>15 U.S.C. 80b–2</ref>)); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> a major United States commercial bank that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is headquartered in the United States; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> holds for the account of others investment assets in a total amount considered by the Maritime Administrator to qualify the bank as a major investment management firm.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Qualified guarantee</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “qualified guarantee”, with respect to a major project, means a guarantee that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is made by 1 or more persons in connection with a donation for the project of a total amount in cash or securities that the Maritime Administrator determines is sufficient to defray a substantial portion of the total cost of the project;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is made to facilitate or expedite the completion of the project in reasonable anticipation that other donors will contribute sufficient funds or other resources in amounts sufficient to pay for completion of the project;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> is set forth as a written agreement providing that the donor will furnish in cash or securities, in addition to the donor’s other gift or gifts for the project, any additional amount that may become necessary for paying the cost of completing the project by reason of a failure to obtain from other donors or sources funds or other resources in amounts sufficient to pay the cost of completing the project; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> is accompanied by—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an irrevocable and unconditional standby letter of credit for the benefit of the United States Merchant Marine Academy that is in the amount of the guarantee and is issued by a major United States commercial bank; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a qualified account control agreement.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Qualified account control agreement</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “qualified account control agreement”, with respect to a guarantee of a donor, means an agreement among the donor, the Maritime Administrator, and a major United States investment management firm that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> ensures the availability of sufficient funds or other financial resources to pay the amount guaranteed during the period of the guarantee;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provides for the perfection of a security interest in the assets of the account for the United States for the benefit of the United States Merchant Marine Academy with the highest priority available for liens and security interests under applicable law;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> requires the donor to maintain in an account with the investment management firm assets having a total value that is not less than 130 percent of the amount guaranteed; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> requires the investment management firm, whenever the value of the account is less than the value required to be maintained under subparagraph (C), to liquidate any noncash assets in the account and reinvest the proceeds in Treasury bills issued under <ref>section 3104 of title 31</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Acceptance Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to subsection (d), the Maritime Administrator may accept a qualified guarantee from a donor or donors for the completion of a major project for the benefit of the United States Merchant Marine Academy.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Obligation Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The amount of a qualified guarantee accepted under this section shall be considered as contract authority to provide obligation authority for purposes of Federal fiscal and contractual requirements. Funds available for a project for which such a guarantee has been accepted may be obligated and expended for the project without regard to whether the total amount of funds and other resources available for the project (not taking into account the amount of the guarantee) is sufficient to pay for completion of the project.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Maritime Administrator may not accept a qualified guarantee under this section for the completion of a major project until 30 days after the date on which a report of the facts concerning the proposed guarantee is submitted to Congress.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition on Commingling Funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Maritime Administrator may not enter into any contract or other transaction involving the use of a qualified guarantee and appropriated funds in the same contract or transaction.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. C, title XXXV, § 3510(a)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1916</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 51321.</num>
<heading> Grants for scientific and educational research</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Defined Term</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the term “qualifying research grant” is a grant that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> is awarded on a competitive basis by the Federal Government (except for the Department of Transportation), a State, a corporation, a fund, a foundation, an educational institution, or a similar entity that is organized and operated primarily for scientific or educational purposes; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> is to be used to carry out a research project with a scientific or educational purpose.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Acceptance of Qualifying Research Grants</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The United States Merchant Marine Academy may compete for and accept qualifying research grants if the work under the grant is to be carried out by a professor or instructor of the United States Merchant Marine Academy.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Administration of Grant Funds.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment of account</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Maritime Administrator shall establish a separate account for administering funds received from research grants under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of grant funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Superintendent shall use grant funds deposited into the account established pursuant to paragraph (1) in accordance with applicable regulations and the terms and conditions of the respective grants.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Related Expenses</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to such limitations as may be provided in appropriations Acts, appropriations available for the United States Merchant Marine Academy may be used to pay expenses incurred by the Academy in applying for, and otherwise pursuing, a qualifying research grant.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. C, title XXXV, § 3512(a)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1918</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 51322.</num>
<heading> Protection of cadets from sexual assault onboard vessels</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Safety Criteria</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Maritime Administrator, after consulting with the Commandant of the Coast Guard, shall establish—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> criteria, to which an owner or operator of a vessel engaged in commercial service shall adhere prior to carrying a cadet performing their Sea Year service from the United States Merchant Marine Academy, that addresses prevention of, and response to, sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a process for collecting pertinent information from such owners or operators and verifying their compliance with the criteria.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Training.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>As part of training that shall be provided not less than semiannually to all midshipmen of the Academy, pursuant to section 51318, the Maritime Administrator shall develop and implement comprehensive in-person sexual assault risk-reduction and response training that, to the extent practicable, conforms to best practices in the sexual assault prevention and response field and includes appropriate scenario-based training.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Development and consultation with experts</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In developing the sexual assault risk-reduction and response training under subparagraph (A), the Maritime Administrator shall consult with and incorporate, as appropriate, the recommendations and views of experts in the sexual assault field.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Minimum Standards</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>At a minimum, the criteria established under subsection (a) shall require the vessel owners or operators to have policies that address—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> communication between a cadet and an individual ashore who is trained in responding to incidents of sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the safety and security of cadet staterooms while a cadet is onboard the vessel;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> requirements for crew to report complaints or incidents of sexual assault, sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, and stalking consistent with the requirements in section 10104;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the maintenance of records of reports of sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking onboard a vessel carrying a cadet;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the maintenance of records of sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking training as required under subsection (f);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> a requirement for the owner or operator provide each cadet a copy of the policies and procedures related to sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking policies that pertain to the vessel on which they will be employed; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> any other issues the Maritime Administrator determines necessary to ensure the safety of cadets during Sea Year training.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Self-certification by Owners or Operators</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Maritime Administrator shall require the owner or operator of any commercial vessel that is carrying a cadet from the United States Merchant Marine Academy to annually certify that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the vessel owner or operator is in compliance with the criteria established under subsection (a); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the vessel is in compliance with the International Convention of Safety of Life at Sea, 1974 (32 UST 47) and sections 8106 and 70103(c).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Information, Training, and Resources</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Maritime Administrator shall ensure that a cadet participating in Sea Year—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> receives training specific to vessel safety, including sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking prevention and response training, prior to the cadet boarding a vessel for Sea Year training;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> is equipped with an appropriate means of communication and has been trained on its use;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> has access to a helpline to report incidents of sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking that is monitored by trained personnel; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> is informed of the legal requirements for vessel owners and operators to provide for the security of individuals onboard, including requirements under section 70103(c) and chapter 81.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Checks of Commercial Vessels.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not less frequently than biennially, staff of the Academy or staff of the Maritime Administration shall conduct both random and targeted unannounced checks of not less than 10 percent of the commercial vessels that host a cadet from the Academy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Access to information</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The vessel operator shall make available to staff conducting a vessel check such information as the Maritime Administrator determines is necessary to determine whether the vessel is being operated in compliance with the criteria established under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Removal of students</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>If staff of the Academy or staff of the Maritime Administration determine that a commercial vessel is not in compliance with the criteria established under subsection (a), the staff—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> may remove a cadet of the Academy from the vessel; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> shall report such determination of non-compliance to the owner or operator of the vessel.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Maintenance of Sexual Assault Training Records</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Maritime Administrator shall require the owner or operator of a commercial vessel, and the seafarer union for a commercial vessel, to maintain records of sexual assault training for any person required to have such training.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Sea Year Survey.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Maritime Administrator shall require each cadet from the Academy, upon completion of the cadet’s Sea Year, to complete a survey regarding the environment and conditions during the Sea Year of the vessel to which the cadet was assigned.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Availability</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Maritime Administrator shall make available to the public for each year—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the questions used in the survey required by paragraph (1); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the aggregated data received from such surveys.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Noncommercial Vessels.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A public vessel (as defined in section 2101) shall not be subject to the requirements of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirements for participation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Maritime Administrator may establish criteria and requirements that the operators of public vessels shall meet to participate in the Sea Year program of the United States Merchant Marine Academy that addresses prevention of, and response to, sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Sharing of Best Practices</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Maritime Administrator shall share with State maritime academies best practices for, and lessons learned with respect to, the prevention of, and response to, sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. C, title XXXV, § 3516(a)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1927</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. C, title XXXV, § 3515(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2312</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. C, title XXXV</ref>, §§ 3513(a), 3531(g), <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3066</ref>, 3088.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 51323.</num>
<heading> United States Merchant Marine Academy Advisory Council</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Transportation shall establish an advisory council, to be known as the “United States Merchant Marine Academy Advisory Council” (in this section referred to as the “Council”).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Membership.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall select not fewer than 8 and not more than 14 individuals to serve as members of the Council. Such individuals shall have such expertise as the Secretary determines necessary and appropriate for providing advice and guidance on improving the Academy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Governmental experts</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The number of members of the Council who are employees of the Federal Government may not exceed the number of members of the Council who are not employees of the Federal Government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Employee status</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Members of the Council shall not be considered employees of the United States Government by reason of their membership on the Council for any purpose and shall not receive compensation other than reimbursement of travel expenses and per diem allowance in accordance with <ref>section 5703 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Responsibilities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Council shall provide advice to the Secretary at the time and in the manner requested by the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Personally Identifiable Information</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In carrying out its responsibilities under this subsection, the Council shall comply with the obligations of the Department of Transportation to protect personally identifiable information.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. C, title XXXV, § 3501(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2238</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 51324.</num>
<heading> Unfilled vacancies</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In the event of an unfilled vacancy for any critical position at the United States Merchant Marine Academy, the Secretary of Transportation may appoint, without regard to the provisions of subchapter I of chapter 33 of title 5, other than sections 3303 and 3328 of that title, a qualified candidate for the purposes of filling up to 20 of such positions.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Critical Position Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the term “critical position” means a position that contributes to the improvement of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the culture or infrastructure of the Academy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> student health and well being;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Academy governance; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> any other priority areas identified by the Council.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. C, title XXXV, § 3501(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2238</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 51325.</num>
<heading> Sexual assault and sexual harassment prevention information management system</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Information Management System.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than <date date="2023-01-01">January 1, 2023</date>, the Maritime Administrator shall establish within the United States Merchant Marine Academy Sexual Assault prevention and Response Program, an information management system to track and maintain, in such a manner that patterns can be reasonably identified, information regarding claims and incidents involving cadets that are reportable pursuant to subsection (d) of section 51318 of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Information maintained in the system</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Information maintained in the system established under paragraph (1) shall include the following information, to the extent that information is available:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The overall number of sexual assault or sexual harassment incidents per fiscal year.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The location of each such incident, including vessel name and the name of the company operating the vessel, if applicable.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The standardized job title or position of the individuals involved in each such incident.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The general nature of each such incident, to include copies of any associated reports completed on the incidents.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The type of inquiry made into each such incident.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> A record of whether each such incident was substantiated by the relevant investigative process.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Past information included</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The information management system under this section shall include the relevant data listed in this subsection related to sexual assault and sexual harassment that the Maritime Administrator possesses, and shall not be limited to data collected after <date date="2023-01-01">January 1, 2023</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Privacy protections</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Maritime Administrator and the Chief Information Officer of the Department of Transportation shall coordinate to ensure that the information management system under this section shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> be established and maintained in a secure fashion to ensure the protection of the privacy of any individuals whose information is entered in such system; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> be free of personally identifiable information and maintain only the data required to satisfy the statistical purpose of such system.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Cybersecurity audit</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Ninety days after the implementation of the information management system, the Office of Inspector General of the Department of Transportation shall commence an audit of the cybersecurity of the system and shall submit a report containing the results of that audit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Correcting records</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In establishing the information management system, the Maritime Administrator shall create a process to ensure that if any incident report results in a final agency action or final judgement that acquits an individual of wrongdoing, all personally identifiable information about the acquitted individual is removed from that incident report in the system.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Sea Year Program</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Maritime Administrator shall provide for the establishment of in-person and virtual confidential exit interviews, to be conducted by personnel who are not involved in the assignment of the midshipmen to a Sea Year vessel, for midshipmen from the Academy upon completion of Sea Year and following completion by the midshipmen of the survey under section 51322(d).<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002026">1</ref></content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Data-informed Decisionmaking</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The data maintained in the data management system under subsection (a) and through the exit interviews under subsection (b) shall be affirmatively referenced and used to inform the creation of new policy or regulation, or changes to any existing policy or regulation, in the areas of sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. C, title XXXV, § 3531(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3083</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 51326.</num>
<heading> Student advisory board at the United States Merchant Marine Academy</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Maritime Administrator shall establish at the United States Merchant Marine Academy an advisory board to be known as the Advisory Board to the Secretary of Transportation (referred to in this section as the “Advisory Board”).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Membership</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Advisory Board shall be composed of not fewer than 12 midshipmen of the Merchant Marine Academy who are enrolled at the Merchant Marine Academy at the time of the appointment, including not fewer than 3 cadets from each class.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appointment; Term</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Midshipmen shall serve on the Advisory Board pursuant to appointment by the Maritime Administrator. Appointments shall be made not later than 60 days after the date of the swearing in of a new class of midshipmen at the Academy. The term of membership of a midshipmen on the Advisory Board shall be 1 academic year.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reappointment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Maritime Administrator may reappoint not more than 6 cadets from the previous term to serve on the Advisory Board for an additional academic year if the Maritime Administrator determines such reappointment to be in the best interests of the Merchant Marine Academy.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Meetings</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Advisory Board shall meet with the Secretary of Transportation not less than once each academic year to discuss the activities of the Advisory Board. The Advisory Board shall meet in person with the Maritime Administrator not less than 2 times each academic year to discuss the activities of the Advisory Board.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duties</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Advisory Board shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> identify health and wellbeing, diversity, and sexual assault and harassment challenges and other topics considered important by the Advisory Board facing midshipmen at the Merchant Marine Academy, off campus, and while aboard ships during Sea Year or other training opportunities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> discuss and propose possible solutions, including improvements to culture and leadership development at the Merchant Marine Academy; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> periodically review the efficacy of the program in section 51325(b), as appropriate, and provide recommendations to the Maritime Administrator for improvement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Working Groups</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Advisory Board may establish one or more working groups to assist the Advisory Board in carrying out its duties, including working groups composed in part of midshipmen at the Merchant Marine Academy who are not current members of the Advisory Board.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reports and Briefings</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Advisory Board shall regularly provide the Secretary of Transportation and the Maritime Administrator reports and briefings on the results of its duties, including recommendations for actions to be taken in light of such results. Such reports and briefings may be provided in writing, in person, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. C, title XXXV, § 3531(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3085</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 51327.</num>
<heading> Sexual Assault Advisory Council</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Transportation shall establish a Sexual Assault Advisory Council (in this section referred to as the “Council”).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Membership.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Council shall be composed of not fewer than 8 and not more than 14 individuals selected by the Secretary of Transportation who are alumni that have graduated within the last 4 years or current midshipmen of the United States Merchant Marine Academy (including midshipmen or alumni who were victims of sexual assault, to the maximum extent practicable, and midshipmen or alumni who were not victims of sexual assault) and governmental and nongovernmental experts and professionals in the sexual assault field.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Experts included</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Council shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> not less than 1 member who is licensed in the field of mental health and has prior experience working as a counselor or therapist providing mental health care to survivors of sexual assault in a victim services agency or organization; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> not less than 1 member who has prior experience developing or implementing sexual assault or sexual harassment prevention and response policies in an academic setting.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rules regarding membership</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No employee of the Department of Transportation shall be a member of the Council. The number of governmental experts appointed to the Council shall not exceed the number of nongovernmental experts.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Duties; Authorized Activities.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Council shall meet not less often than semiannually to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> review—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the policies on sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking under <ref>section 51318 of this title</ref>;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the trends and patterns of data contained in the system described under <ref>section 51325 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> related matters the Council views as appropriate; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> develop recommendations designed to ensure that such policies and such matters conform, to the extent practicable, to best practices in the field of sexual assault and sexual harassment response and prevention.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authorized activities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>To carry out this subsection, the Council may—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> interview current and former midshipmen of the United States Merchant Marine Academy (to the extent that such midshipmen provide the Department of Transportation express consent to be interviewed by the Council); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> review surveys under section 51322(d).<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002027">1</ref></content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Personally identifiable information</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In carrying out this subsection, the Council shall comply with the obligations of the Department of Transportation to protect personally identifiable information.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reports</inline>.—</heading>
<content>On an annual basis for each of the 5 years after the date of enactment of this section, and at the discretion of the Council thereafter, the Council shall submit, to the President and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives, a report on the Council’s findings based on the reviews conducted pursuant to subsection (c) and related recommendations.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Employee Status</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Members of the Council shall not be considered employees of the United States Government for any purpose and shall not receive compensation other than reimbursement of travel expenses and per diem allowance in accordance with <ref>section 5703 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Nonapplicability of FACA</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.) <sup>1</sup> shall not apply to the Council.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. C, title XXXV, § 3531(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3086</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 51328.</num>
<heading> Student support</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Maritime Administrator shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> require a biannual survey of midshipmen, faculty, and staff of the Academy assessing the environment of the Academy; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> require an annual survey of faculty and staff of the Academy assessing the Sea Year program.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. C, title XXXV, § 3531(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3087</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>