<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 63—</num>
<heading>INVESTIGATING MARINE CASUALTIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6301.</num>
<heading> Investigation of marine casualties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall prescribe regulations for the immediate investigation of marine casualties under this part to decide, as closely as possible—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the cause of the casualty, including the cause of any death;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> whether an act of misconduct, incompetence, negligence, unskillfulness, or willful violation of law committed by any individual licensed, certificated, or documented under part E of this subtitle has contributed to the cause of the casualty, or to a death involved in the casualty, so that appropriate remedial action under chapter 77 of this title may be taken;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> whether an act of misconduct, incompetence, negligence, unskillfulness, or willful violation of law committed by any person, including an officer, employee, or member of the Coast Guard, contributed to the cause of the casualty, or to a death involved in the casualty;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> whether there is evidence that an act subjecting the offender to a civil penalty under the laws of the United States has been committed, so that appropriate action may be undertaken to collect the penalty;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> whether there is evidence that a criminal act under the laws of the United States has been committed, so that the matter may be referred to appropriate authorities for prosecution; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> whether there is need for new laws or regulations, or amendment or repeal of existing laws or regulations, to prevent the recurrence of the casualty.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 537</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6302.</num>
<heading> Public investigations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each investigation conducted under this chapter and regulations prescribed under this chapter shall be open to the public, except when evidence affecting the national security is to be received.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 537</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6303.</num>
<heading> Rights of parties in interest</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In an investigation conducted under this chapter, the following shall be allowed to be represented by counsel, to cross-examine witnesses, and to call witnesses:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an owner,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any holder of a license or certificate of registry,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> any holder of a merchant mariner’s document,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> any other person whose conduct is under investigation, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> any other party in interest.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 537</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6304.</num>
<heading> Subpoena authority</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> In an investigation under this chapter, the attendance and testimony of witnesses, including parties in interest, and the production of any evidence may be compelled by subpoena. The subpoena authority granted by this section is coextensive with that of a district court of the United States, in civil matters, for the district in which the investigation is conducted.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> When a person fails to obey a subpoena issued under this section, the district court of the United States for the district in which the investigation is conducted or in which the person failing to obey is found, shall on proper application issue an order directing that person to comply with the subpoena. The court may punish as contempt any disobedience of its order.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> A witness complying with a subpoena issued under this section may be paid for actual travel and attendance at the rate provided for witnesses in the district courts of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> An official designated to conduct an investigation under this part may issue subpoenas as provided in this section and administer oaths to witnesses.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 538</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. K, title CXVIII, § 11807(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4165</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6305.</num>
<heading> Reports of investigations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall prescribe regulations about the form and manner of reports of investigations conducted under this part.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Reports of investigations conducted under this part shall be made available to the public. This subsection does not require the release of information described by <ref>section 552(b) of title 5</ref> or protected from disclosure by another law of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 538</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–383, title III, § 305</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3420</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6306.</num>
<heading> Penalty</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A person attempting to coerce a witness, or to induce a witness, to testify falsely in connection with a marine casualty, or to induce a witness to leave the jurisdiction of the United States, shall be fined $5,000, imprisoned for one year, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 538</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6307.</num>
<heading> Notifications to Congress</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall notify the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives of any hearing, before the hearing occurs, investigating a major marine casualty involving a death under <ref>section 6301 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall submit to a committee referred to in subsection (a) of this section information on a major marine casualty that is requested by that committee or the chairman of the committee if the submission of that information is not prohibited by a law of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall submit annually to Congress a summary of the marine casualties reported during the prior fiscal year, together with a brief statement of action taken concerning those casualties.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 538</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–295, title IV, § 408(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2117</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6308.</num>
<heading> Information barred in legal proceedings</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no part of a report of a marine casualty investigation conducted under <ref>section 6301 of this title</ref>, including findings of fact, opinions, recommendations, deliberations, or conclusions, shall be admissible as evidence or subject to discovery in any civil or administrative proceedings, other than an administrative proceeding initiated by the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Any member or employee of the Coast Guard investigating a marine casualty pursuant to <ref>section 6301 of this title</ref> shall not be subject to deposition or other discovery, or otherwise testify in such proceedings relevant to a marine casualty investigation, without the permission of the Secretary. The Secretary shall not withhold permission for such employee or member to testify, either orally or upon written questions, on solely factual matters at a time and place and in a manner acceptable to the Secretary if the information is not available elsewhere or is not obtainable by other means.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Nothing in this section prohibits the United States from calling the employee or member as an expert witness to testify on its behalf. Further, nothing in this section prohibits the employee or member from being called as a fact witness in any case in which the United States is a party. If the employee or member is called as an expert or fact witness, the applicable Federal Rules of Civil Procedure govern discovery. If the employee or member is called as a witness, the report of a marine casualty investigation conducted under <ref>section 6301 of this title</ref> shall not be admissible, as provided in subsections (a) and (b), and shall not be considered the report of an expert under the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The information referred to in subsections (a), (b), and (c) of this section shall not be considered an admission of liability by the United States or by any person referred to in those conclusions and statements.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–324, title III, § 313(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3921</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 109–241, title IX, § 902(e)(2)</ref>, formerly § 902(e)(2)–(4), <date date="2006-07-11">July 11, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 567</ref>, renumbered § 902(e)(2) and amended <ref>Pub. L. 111–281, title IX, § 903(a)(5)(B)</ref>–(7), <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3010</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6309.</num>
<heading> Voyage data recorder access</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Coast Guard shall have full, concurrent, and timely access to and ability to use voyage data recorder data and audio held by any Federal agency in all marine casualty investigations, regardless of which agency is the investigative lead.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–265, title II, § 207(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-10-11">Oct. 11, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 3747</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>