<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 31—</num>
<heading>GENERAL</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3101.</num>
<heading> Authority to suspend inspection</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">When the President decides that the needs of foreign commerce require, the President may suspend a provision of this part for a foreign-built vessel registered as a vessel of the United States on conditions the President may specify.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 510</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3102.</num>
<heading> Immersion suits</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall by regulation require immersion suits on vessels designated by the Secretary that operate in the Atlantic Ocean north of 32 degrees North latitude or south of 32 degrees South latitude and in all other waters north of 35 degrees North latitude or south of 35 degrees South latitude. The Secretary may not exclude a vessel from designation under this section only because that vessel carries other lifesaving equipment.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall establish standards for an immersion suit required by this section, including standards to guarantee adequate thermal protection, buoyance, and flotation stability.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The owner, charterer, managing operator, agent, master, or individual in charge of a vessel violating this section or a regulation prescribed under this section is liable to the United States Government for a civil penalty of not more than $5,000. The vessel also is liable in rem for the penalty.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The owner, charterer, managing operator, agent, master, or individual in charge of a vessel violating this section or a regulation prescribed under this section may be fined not more than $25,000, imprisoned for not more than 5 years, or both.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 98–557, § 22(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2871</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–623, title VII, § 701(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 3413</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–36, § 2</ref>, <date date="1985-05-15">May 15, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 68</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–424, § 8(a)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="1988-09-09">Sept. 9, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1592</ref>, 1593.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3103.</num>
<heading> Use of reports, documents, and records</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary may rely, as evidence of compliance with this subtitle, on—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> reports, documents, and records of other persons who have been determined by the Secretary to be reliable; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> other methods the Secretary has determined to be reliable.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–324, title VI, § 603(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3930</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3104.</num>
<heading> Survival craft</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirement To Equip</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall require that a passenger vessel be equipped with survival craft that ensures that no part of an individual is immersed in water, if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> such vessel is built or undergoes a major conversion after <date date="2016-01-01">January 1, 2016</date>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> operates in cold waters as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Higher Standard of Safety</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may revise part 117 or part 180 of title 46, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect before <date date="2016-01-01">January 1, 2016</date>, if such revision provides a higher standard of safety than is provided by the regulations in effect on or before the date of the enactment of the Coast Guard Authorization Act of 2016.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Innovative and Novel Designs</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary may, in lieu of the requirements set out in part 117 or part 180 of title 46, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on the date of the enactment of the Coast Guard Authorization Act of 2016, allow a passenger vessel to be equipped with a life-saving appliance or arrangement of an innovative or novel design that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> ensures no part of an individual is immersed in water; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provides an equal or higher standard of safety than is provided by such requirements as in effect before such date of the enactment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Built Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “built” has the meaning that term has under section 4503(d).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–281, title VI, § 609(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2968</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 112–213, title III, § 303</ref>, <date date="2012-12-20">Dec. 20, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1563</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–120, title III, § 301(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-02-08">Feb. 8, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 50</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. C, title XXXV, § 3503(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2775</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title V, § 508(e)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4273</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3105.</num>
<heading> Electronic charts</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">System Requirements.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Electronic charts in lieu of marine charts, charts, and maps</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subject to paragraph (2), the following vessels, while operating on the navigable waters of the United States, equipped with and operating electronic navigational charts that are produced by a government hydrographic office or conform to a standard acceptable to the Secretary, shall be deemed in compliance with any requirement under title 33 or title 46, Code of Federal Regulations, to have a chart, marine chart, or map on board such vessel:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A self-propelled commercial vessel of at least 65 feet in overall length.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A vessel carrying more than a number of passengers for hire determined by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> A towing vessel of more than 26 feet in overall length and 600 horsepower.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Any other vessel for which the Secretary decides that electronic charts are necessary for the safe navigation of the vessel.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exemptions and waivers</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary may—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> exempt a vessel from paragraph (1), if the Secretary finds that electronic charts are not necessary for the safe navigation of the vessel on the waters on which the vessel operates;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> waive the application of paragraph (1) with respect to operation of vessels on navigable waters of the United States specified by the Secretary, if the Secretary finds that electronic charts are not needed for safe navigation on those waters; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> permit vessels described in subparagraphs (A) through (D) of paragraph (1) that operate solely landward of the baseline from which the territorial sea of the United States is measured to utilize software-based, platform-independent electronic chart systems that the Secretary determines are capable of displaying electronic navigational charts with necessary scale and detail to ensure safe navigation for the intended voyage.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Application</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Except pursuant to an international treaty, convention, or agreement, to which the United States is a party, this section shall not apply to any foreign vessel that is not destined for, or departing from, a port or place subject to the jurisdiction of the United States and that is in—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> innocent passage through the territorial sea of the United States; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> transit through the navigable waters of the United States that form a part of an international strait.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title IV, § 402(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4263</ref>, 4264; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXIII</ref> [LXXXIII], § 8301, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4691</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3106.</num>
<heading> Master key control system</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The owner of a vessel subject to inspection under section 3301 shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> ensure that such vessel is equipped with a vessel master key control system, manual or electronic, which provides controlled access to all copies of the vessel’s master key of which access shall only be available to the individuals described in paragraph (2);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> establish a list of all crew, identified by position, allowed to access and use the master key and maintain such list upon the vessel, within owner records and included in the vessel safety management system;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> record in a log book information on all access and use of the vessel’s master key, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> dates and times of access;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the room or location accessed; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the name and rank of the crew member that used the master key; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> make the list under paragraph (2) and the log book under paragraph (3) available upon request to any agent of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, any member of the Coast Guard, and any law enforcement officer performing official duties in the course and scope of an investigation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibited Use</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Crew not included on the list described in subsection (a)(2) shall not have access to or use the master key unless in an emergency and shall immediately notify the master and owner of the vessel following use of such key.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirements for Log Book</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The log book described in subsection (a)(3) and required to be included in a safety management system under section 3203(a)(6)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> may be electronic; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall be located in a centralized location that is readily accessible to law enforcement personnel.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Penalty</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any crew member who uses the master key without having been granted access pursuant to subsection (a)(2) shall be liable to the United States Government for a civil penalty of not more than $1,000 and may be subject to suspension or revocation under section 7703.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exemption</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section shall not apply to vessels subject to section 3507(f).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. K, title CXVI, § 11608(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4151</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>