<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 556—</num>
<heading>MARINE HIGHWAYS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 55601.</num>
<heading> United States marine highway program</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Establishment.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is in the Department of Transportation a program, to be known as the “United States marine highway program”.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Additional program activities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In carrying out the program established under this subsection, the Secretary of Transportation may—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> coordinate with ports, State departments of transportation, localities, other public agencies, and appropriate private sector entities on the development of landside facilities and infrastructure to support marine highway transportation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> develop performance measures for the program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Marine Highway Transportation Routes.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary may designate a route as a marine highway transportation route, or modify such a designation, if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> such route—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> provides a coordinated and capable alternative to landside transportation;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> mitigates or relieves landside congestion;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> promotes marine highway transportation; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> uses vessels documented under chapter 121; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> such designation or modification is requested by—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the government of a State or territory;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a metropolitan planning organization;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a port authority;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> a non-Federal navigation district; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> a Tribal government.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Determination</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 180 days after the date on which the Maritime Administrator receives a request for the designation or modification of a marine highway route under paragraph (1), the Maritime Administrator shall make a determination of whether to make the requested designation or modification.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notification</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 14 days after the date on which the Maritime Administrator makes a determination under paragraph (2), the Maritime Administrator shall notify the requester of the determination.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Map of Marine Highway Program Routes.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Maritime Administrator shall make publicly available a map showing the location of marine highway routes, including such routes along the coasts, in the inland waterways, and at sea and update that map when a marine highway route is designated or modified pursuant to subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Coordination</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Maritime Administrator shall coordinate with the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration to incorporate the map referred to in paragraph (1) into the Marine Cadastre.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Assistance.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary may make grants to, or enter into contracts or cooperative agreements with, eligible entities to implement a marine highway transportation project or a component of such a project if the Secretary determines that the project or component—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> meets the criteria referred to in subsection (b)(1)(A); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> develops, expands, or promotes—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> marine highway transportation; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> shipper use of marine highway transportation.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Application.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>To be eligible to receive a grant or to enter into a contract or cooperative agreement under this subsection, an eligible entity shall submit to the Secretary an application in such form and manner, and at such time, as the Secretary may require. Such an application shall include the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> A comprehensive description of—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the marine highway route to be served by the marine highway transportation project;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the supporters of the marine highway transportation project, which may include business affiliations, private sector stakeholders, State departments of transportation, metropolitan planning organizations, municipalities, or other governmental entities (including Tribal governments), as applicable;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> the need for such project; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> the performance measure for the marine highway transportation project, such as volumes of cargo or passengers moved, or contribution to environmental mitigation, safety, reduced vehicle miles traveled, or reduced maintenance and repair costs.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> A demonstration, to the satisfaction of the Secretary, that—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the marine highway transportation project is financially viable; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the funds or other assistance provided under this subsection will be spent or used efficiently and effectively.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Such other information as the Secretary may require.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Pre-proposal.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Prior to accepting a full application under subparagraph (A), the Secretary may require that an eligible entity first submit a pre-proposal that contains a brief description of the item referred to in clauses (i) through (iii) of such subparagraph.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Feedback</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 30 days after receiving a pre-proposal under clause (i) from an eligible entity, the Secretary shall provide to the eligible entity feedback to encourage or discourage the eligible entity from submitting a full application. An eligible entity may still submit a full application even if that eligible entity is not encouraged to do so after submitting a pre-proposal.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may not require separate applications for project designation and for assistance under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Grant application feedback</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Following the award of assistance under this subsection for a particular fiscal year, the Secretary may provide feedback to an applicant to help such applicant improve future applications if the feedback is requested by that applicant.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Timing.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice of funding opportunity</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall post a notice of funding opportunity regarding grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements under this subsection not more than 60 days after the date of the enactment of the appropriations Act for the fiscal year concerned.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Awarding of assistance</inline>.—</heading>
<content> The Secretary shall award grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements under this subsection not later than 270 days after the date of the enactment of the appropriations Act for the fiscal year concerned.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Non-federal share.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), not more than 80 percent of the funding for any project for which funding is provided under this subsection may come from Federal sources.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Tribal governments and rural areas</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary may increase the Federal share of funding for the project to an amount above 80 percent in the case of an award of assistance under this subsection—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> to an eligible entity that is a Tribal government; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> for a project located in a rural area.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Preference for financially viable projects</inline>.—</heading>
<content> In awarding grants or entering into contracts or cooperative agreements under this subsection, the Secretary shall give a preference to a project or component of a project that presents the most financially viable transportation service and require the lowest percentage of Federal share of the funding.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Treatment of unexpended funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding paragraph (3)(B), amounts awarded under this subsection that are not expended by the recipient within five years after obligation of funds or that are returned shall remain available to the Secretary to make grants and enter into contracts and cooperative agreements under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Conditions on provision of assistance</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary may not provide assistance to an eligible entity under this subsection unless the Secretary determines that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> sufficient funding is available to meet the non-Federal share requirement under paragraph (4);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the marine highway project for which such assistance is provided will be completed without unreasonable delay; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the eligible entity has the authority to implement the proposed marine highway project.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibited uses</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Assistance provided under this subsection may not be used—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to improve port or land-based infrastructure outside the United States; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> unless the Secretary determines that such activities are necessary to carry out the marine highway project for which such assistance is provided, to raise sunken vessels, construct buildings or other physical facilities, or acquire land.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Geographic distribution</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In making grants, contracts, and cooperative agreements under this section the Secretary shall take such measures so as to ensure an equitable geographic distribution of funds.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Eligible entity</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this subsection, the term “eligible entity” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a State, a political subdivision of a State, or a local government;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a United States metropolitan planning organization;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a United States port authority;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a Tribal government; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> a United States private sector operator of marine highway projects or private sector owners of facilities, including an Alaska Native Corporation, with an endorsement letter from the requester of a marine highway route designation or modification referred to in subsection (b)(1)(B).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–140, title XI, § 1121(a)</ref>, <date date="2007-12-19">Dec. 19, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 1760</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. C, title XXXV, § 3515</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2724</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–213, title IV, § 405(a)</ref>, <date date="2012-12-20">Dec. 20, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1571</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXIII</ref> [LXXXIII], § 8332(d)(3), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4704</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. C, title XXXV, § 3521(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3074</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 55602.</num>
<heading> Cargo and shippers</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Memorandums of Agreement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Transportation shall enter into memorandums of understanding with the heads of other Federal entities to transport federally owned or generated cargo using a marine highway transportation project designated under section 55601 when practical or available.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Short-Term Incentives</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall consult shippers and other participants in transportation logistics and develop proposals for short-term incentives to encourage the use of marine highway transportation.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–140, title XI, § 1121(a)</ref>, <date date="2007-12-19">Dec. 19, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 1761</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXIII</ref> [LXXXIII], § 8332(d)(4), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4705</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 55603.</num>
<heading> Multistate, State, Tribal, and regional transportation planning</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary, in consultation with Federal entities, State and local governments, Tribal governments, and appropriate private sector entities, may develop strategies to encourage the use of marine highway transportation for transportation of passengers and cargo.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Strategies</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>If the Secretary develops strategies under subsection (a), the Secretary may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> assess the extent to which States, local governments, and Tribal governments include marine highway transportation and other marine transportation solutions in transportation planning;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> encourage State and Tribal departments of transportation to develop strategies, where appropriate, to incorporate marine highway transportation, ferries, and other marine transportation solutions for regional and interstate transport of freight and passengers in transportation planning; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> encourage groups of States, Tribal governments, and multistate transportation entities to determine how marine highways can address congestion, bottlenecks, and other interstate transportation challenges.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. C, title XXXV, § 3521(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3078</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 55604.</num>
<heading> Research on marine highway transportation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of Transportation, in consultation with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, may conduct research on marine highway transportation, regarding—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the economic effects of marine highway transportation on the United States economy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the effects of marine highway transportation, including with respect to the provision of additional transportation options, on rural areas;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the environmental and transportation benefits to be derived from marine highway transportation alternatives for other forms of transportation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> technology, vessel design, and other improvements that would reduce emissions, increase fuel economy, and lower costs of marine highway transportation and increase the efficiency of intermodal transfers; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> solutions to impediments to marine highway transportation projects designated under section 55601.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–140, title XI, § 1121(a)</ref>, <date date="2007-12-19">Dec. 19, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 1761</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXIII</ref> [LXXXIII], § 8332(d)(4), (5), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4705</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. C, title XXXV, § 3521(c)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3078</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 55605.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The term “marine highway transportation” means the carriage by a documented vessel of cargo (including such carriage of cargo and passengers), if such cargo—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> is—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> contained in intermodal cargo containers and loaded by crane on the vessel;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> loaded on the vessel by means of wheeled technology, including roll-on roll-off cargo;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> shipped in discrete units or packages that are handled individually, palletized, or unitized for purposes of transportation;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> bulk, liquid, or loose cargo loaded in tanks, holds, hoppers, or on deck; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> freight vehicles carried aboard commuter ferry boats; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> is—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> loaded at a port in the United States and unloaded either at another port in the United States or at a port in Canada or Mexico; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> loaded at a port in Canada or Mexico and unloaded at a port in the United States.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “Tribal government” means the recognized governing body of any Indian or Alaska Native Tribe, band, nation, pueblo, village, community, component band, or component reservation, individually identified (including parenthetically) in the list published most recently, as of the date of enactment of the James M. Inhofe National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2023, pursuant to section 104 of the Federally Recognized Indian Tribe List Act of 1994 (<ref>25 U.S.C. 5131</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “Alaska Native Corporation” has the meaning given the term “Native Corporation” under section 3 of the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<ref>43 U.S.C. 1602</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–140, title XI, § 1121(a)</ref>, <date date="2007-12-19">Dec. 19, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 1761</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 112–213, title IV, § 405(b)</ref>, <date date="2012-12-20">Dec. 20, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1571</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. C, title XXXV, § 3508</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 1223</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXIII</ref> [LXXXIII], § 8332(d)(6), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4705</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. C, title XXXV, § 3521(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3079</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>