<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 401—</num>
<heading>GENERAL</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 40101.</num>
<heading> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes of this part are to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> establish a nondiscriminatory regulatory process for the common carriage of goods by water in the foreign commerce of the United States with a minimum of government intervention and regulatory costs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> ensure an efficient, competitive, and economical transportation system in the ocean commerce of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> encourage the development of an economically sound and efficient liner fleet of vessels of the United States capable of meeting national security needs and supporting commerce; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> promote the growth and development of United States exports through a competitive and efficient system for the carriage of goods by water in the foreign commerce of the United States, and by placing a greater reliance on the marketplace.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 7</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1523</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–146, § 2</ref>, <date date="2022-06-16">June 16, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 1272</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40102.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this part:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Agreement</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “agreement”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> means a written or oral understanding, arrangement, or association, and any modification or cancellation thereof; but</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> does not include a maritime labor agreement.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Antitrust laws</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “antitrust laws” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Sherman Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 1</ref> et seq.);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> sections 73 and 74 of the Wilson Tariff Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 8</ref>, 9);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Clayton Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 12</ref> et seq.);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Act of <date date="1936-06-19">June 19, 1936</date> (<ref>15 U.S.C. 13</ref>, 13a, 13b, 21a);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the Federal Trade Commission Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 41</ref> et seq.);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the Antitrust Civil Process Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 1311</ref> et seq.); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> Acts supplementary to those Acts.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Assessment agreement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “assessment agreement” means an agreement, whether part of a collective bargaining agreement or negotiated separately, to the extent the agreement provides for the funding of collectively bargained fringe-benefit obligations on other than a uniform worker-hour basis, regardless of the cargo handled or type of vessel or equipment used.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Bulk cargo</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “bulk cargo” means cargo that is loaded and carried in bulk without mark or count.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Certain covered services</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For purposes of sections 41105 and 41307, the term “certain covered services” means, with respect to a vessel—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the berthing or bunkering of the vessel;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the loading or unloading of cargo to or from the vessel to or from a point on a wharf or terminal;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the positioning, removal, or replacement of buoys related to the movement of the vessel; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> with respect to injunctive relief under section 41307, towing vessel services provided to such a vessel.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Chemical parcel-tanker</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “chemical parcel-tanker” means a vessel that has—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> a cargo-carrying capability consisting of individual cargo tanks for bulk chemicals that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> are a permanent part of the vessel; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> have segregation capability with piping systems to permit simultaneous carriage of several bulk chemical cargoes with minimum risk of cross-contamination; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a valid certificate of fitness under the International Maritime Organization Code for the Construction and Equipment of Ships Carrying Dangerous Chemicals in Bulk.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Common carrier</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “common carrier”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> means a person that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> holds itself out to the general public to provide transportation by water of passengers or cargo between the United States and a foreign country for compensation;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> assumes responsibility for the transportation from the port or point of receipt to the port or point of destination; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> uses, for all or part of that transportation, a vessel operating on the high seas or the Great Lakes between a port in the United States and a port in a foreign country; but</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> does not include a carrier engaged in ocean transportation by ferry boat, ocean tramp, or chemical parcel-tanker, or by vessel when primarily engaged in the carriage of perishable agricultural commodities—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> if the carrier and the owner of those commodities are wholly-owned, directly or indirectly, by a person primarily engaged in the marketing and distribution of those commodities; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> only with respect to the carriage of those commodities.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Conference</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “conference”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> means an association of ocean common carriers permitted, pursuant to an approved or effective agreement, to engage in concerted activity and to use a common tariff; but</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> does not include a joint service, consortium, pooling, sailing, or transshipment agreement.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Controlled carrier</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “controlled carrier” means an ocean common carrier that is, or whose operating assets are, directly or indirectly, owned or controlled by a government, with ownership or control by a government being deemed to exist for a carrier if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a majority of the interest in the carrier is owned or controlled in any manner by that government, an agency of that government, or a public or private person controlled by that government; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> that government has the right to appoint or disapprove the appointment of a majority of the directors, the chief operating officer, or the chief executive officer of the carrier.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Deferred rebate</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “deferred rebate” means a return by a common carrier of any freight money to a shipper, where the return is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> consideration for the shipper giving all or any portion of its shipments to that or any other common carrier over a fixed period of time;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> deferred beyond the completion of the service for which it was paid; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> made only if the shipper has agreed to make a further shipment with that or any other common carrier.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Forest products</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “forest products” includes lumber in bundles, rough timber, ties, poles, piling, laminated beams, bundled siding, bundled plywood, bundled core stock or veneers, bundled particle or fiber boards, bundled hardwood, wood pulp in rolls, wood pulp in unitized bales, and paper and paper board in rolls or in pallet or skid-sized sheets.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inland division</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “inland division” means the amount paid by a common carrier to an inland carrier for the inland portion of through transportation offered to the public by the common carrier.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inland portion</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “inland portion” means the charge to the public by a common carrier for the non-ocean portion of through transportation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Loyalty contract</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “loyalty contract” means a contract with an ocean common carrier or agreement providing for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a shipper to obtain lower rates by committing all or a fixed portion of its cargo to that carrier or agreement; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a deferred rebate arrangement.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Marine terminal operator</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “marine terminal operator” means a person engaged in the United States in the business of providing wharfage, dock, warehouse, or other terminal facilities in connection with a common carrier, or in connection with a common carrier and a water carrier subject to subchapter II of chapter 135 of title 49.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(16)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Maritime labor agreement</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “maritime labor agreement”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> means—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a collective bargaining agreement between an employer subject to this part, or a group of such employers, and a labor organization representing employees in the maritime or stevedoring industry;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> an agreement preparatory to such a collective bargaining agreement among members of a multi-employer bargaining group; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> an agreement specifically implementing provisions of such a collective bargaining agreement or providing for the formation, financing, or administration of a multi-employer bargaining group; but</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> does not include an assessment agreement.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(17)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Non-vessel-operating common carrier</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “non-vessel-operating common carrier” means a common carrier that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> does not operate the vessels by which the ocean transportation is provided; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is a shipper in its relationship with an ocean common carrier.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(18)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Ocean common carrier</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “ocean common carrier” means a vessel-operating common carrier.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(19)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Ocean freight forwarder</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “ocean freight forwarder” means a person that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the United States, dispatches shipments from the United States via a common carrier and books or otherwise arranges space for those shipments on behalf of shippers; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> processes the documentation or performs related activities incident to those shipments.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(20)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Ocean transportation intermediary</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “ocean transportation intermediary” means an ocean freight forwarder or a non-vessel-operating common carrier.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(21)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Service contract</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “service contract” means a written contract, other than a bill of lading or receipt, between one or more shippers, on the one hand, and an individual ocean common carrier or an agreement between or among ocean common carriers, on the other, in which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the shipper or shippers commit to providing a certain volume or portion of cargo over a fixed time period; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the ocean common carrier or the agreement commits to a certain rate or rate schedule and a defined service level, such as assured space, transit time, port rotation, or similar service features.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(22)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Shipment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “shipment” means all of the cargo carried under the terms of a single bill of lading.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(23)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Shipper</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “shipper” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a cargo owner;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the person for whose account the ocean transportation of cargo is provided;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the person to whom delivery is to be made;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a shippers’ association; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> a non-vessel-operating common carrier that accepts responsibility for payment of all charges applicable under the tariff or service contract.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(24)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Shippers’ association</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “shippers’ association” means a group of shippers that consolidates or distributes freight on a nonprofit basis for the members of the group to obtain carload, truckload, or other volume rates or service contracts.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(25)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Through rate</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “through rate” means the single amount charged by a common carrier in connection with through transportation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(26)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Through transportation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “through transportation” means continuous transportation between origin and destination for which a through rate is assessed and which is offered or performed by one or more carriers, at least one of which is a common carrier, between a United States port or point and a foreign port or point.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 7</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1523</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title VII, § 704</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4294</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40103.</num>
<heading> Administrative exemptions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Federal Maritime Commission, on application or its own motion, may by order or regulation exempt for the future any class of agreements between persons subject to this part or any specified activity of those persons from any requirement of this part if the Commission finds that the exemption will not result in substantial reduction in competition or be detrimental to commerce. The Commission may attach conditions to an exemption and may, by order, revoke an exemption.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Opportunity for Hearing</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An order or regulation of exemption or revocation of an exemption may be issued only if the Commission has provided an opportunity for a hearing to interested persons and departments and agencies of the United States Government.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 7</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1527</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40104.</num>
<heading> Reports filed with the Commission</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Reports.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Federal Maritime Commission may require a common carrier or marine terminal operator, or an officer, receiver, trustee, lessee, agent, or employee of the common carrier or marine terminal operator to file with the Commission a periodical or special report, an account, record, rate, or charge, or a memorandum of facts and transactions related to the business of the common carrier or marine terminal operator, as applicable.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Any report, account, record, rate, charge, or memorandum required to be filed under paragraph (1) shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> be made under oath if the Commission requires; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> be filed in the form and within the time prescribed by the Commission.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Commission shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> limit the scope of any filing ordered under this section to fulfill the objective of the order; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provide a reasonable period of time for respondents to respond based upon their capabilities and the scope of the order.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Conference Minutes</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Conference minutes required to be filed with the Commission under this section may not be released to third parties or published by the Commission.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 7</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1527</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title VII, § 705</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4294</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>