<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 700—</num>
<heading>PORTS AND WATERWAYS SAFETY</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>VESSEL OPERATIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 70001.</num>
<heading> Vessel traffic services</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subject to the requirements of section 70004, the Secretary—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in any port or place under the jurisdiction of the United States, in the navigable waters of the United States, or in any area covered by an international agreement negotiated pursuant to section 70005, may construct, operate, maintain, improve, or expand vessel traffic services, that consist of measures for controlling or supervising vessel traffic or for protecting navigation and the marine environment and that may include one or more of reporting and operating requirements, surveillance and communications systems, routing systems, and fairways;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall require appropriate vessels that operate in an area of a vessel traffic service to utilize or comply with that service;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> may require vessels to install and use specified navigation equipment, communications equipment, electronic relative motion analyzer equipment, or any electronic or other device necessary to comply with a vessel traffic service or that is necessary in the interests of vessel safety, except that the Secretary shall not require fishing vessels under 300 gross tons as measured under section 14502, or an alternate tonnage measured under section 14302 as prescribed by the Secretary under section 14104, or recreational vessels 65 feet or less to possess or use the equipment or devices required by this subsection solely under the authority of this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> may control vessel traffic in areas subject to the jurisdiction of the United States that the Secretary determines to be hazardous, or under conditions of reduced visibility, adverse weather, vessel congestion, or other hazardous circumstances, by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> specifying times of entry, movement, or departure;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> establishing vessel traffic routing schemes;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> establishing vessel size, speed, or draft limitations and vessel operating conditions; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> restricting operation, in any hazardous area or under hazardous conditions, to vessels that have particular operating characteristics or capabilities that the Secretary considers necessary for safe operation under the circumstances;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> may require the receipt of prearrival messages from any vessel, destined for a port or place subject to the jurisdiction of the United States, in sufficient time to permit advance vessel traffic planning before port entry, which shall include any information that is not already a matter of record and that the Secretary determines necessary for the control of the vessel and the safety of the port or the marine environment; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> may prohibit the use on vessels of electronic or other devices that interfere with communication and navigation equipment, except that such authority shall not apply to electronic or other devices certified to transmit in the maritime services by the Federal Communications Commission and used within the frequency bands 157.1875–157.4375 MHz and 161.7875–162.0375 MHz.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">National Policy.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Establishment and update of national policy.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment of policy</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than one year after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary shall establish a national policy which is inclusive of local variances permitted under subsection (c), to be applied to all vessel traffic service centers and publish such policy in the Federal Register.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Update</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall periodically update the national policy established under subparagraph (A) and shall publish such update in the Federal Register or on a publicly available website.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The national policy established and updated under paragraph (1) shall include, at a minimum, the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Standardization of titles, roles, and responsibilities for all personnel assigned, working, or employed in a vessel traffic service center.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Standardization of organizational structure within vessel traffic service centers, to include supervisory and reporting chain and processes.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Establishment of directives for the application of authority provided to each vessel traffic service center, specifically with respect to directing or controlling vessel movement when such action is justified in the interest of safety.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Establishment of thresholds and measures for monitoring, informing, recommending, and directing vessel traffic.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Establishment of national procedures and protocols for vessel traffic management.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Standardization of training for all vessel traffic service directors, operators, and watchstanders.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> Establishment of certification and competency evaluation for all vessel traffic service directors, operators, and watchstanders.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> Establishment of standard operating language when communicating with vessel traffic users.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> Establishment of data collection, storage, management, archiving, and dissemination policies and procedures for vessel incidents and near-miss incidents.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Local Variances.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Development</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the Secretary may provide for such local variances as the Secretary considers appropriate to account for the unique vessel traffic, waterway characteristics, and any additional factors that are appropriate to enhance navigational safety in any area where vessel traffic services are provided.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Review and approval by secretary</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Captain of the Port covered by a vessel traffic service center may develop and submit to the Secretary regional policies in addition to the national policy established and updated under subsection (b) to account for variances from that national policy with respect to local vessel traffic conditions and volume, geography, water body characteristics, waterway usage, and any additional factors that the Captain considers appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Review and implementation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not later than 180 days after receiving regional policies under paragraph (2)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Secretary shall review such regional policies; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Captain of the port concerned shall implement the policies that the Secretary approves.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Maintenance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall maintain a central depository for all local variances approved under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Cooperative Agreements.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may enter into cooperative agreements with public or private agencies, authorities, associations, institutions, corporations, organizations, or other persons to carry out the functions under subsection (a)(1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">International coordination</inline>.—</heading>
<content>With respect to vessel traffic service areas that cross international boundaries, the Secretary may enter into bilateral or cooperative agreements with international partners to jointly carry out the functions under subsection (a)(1) and to jointly manage such areas to collect, share, assess, and analyze information in the possession or control of the international partner.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Limitation.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inherently governmental function</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A nongovernmental entity may not under this subsection carry out an inherently governmental function.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition of inherently governmental function</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this paragraph, the term “inherently governmental function” means any activity that is so intimately related to the public interest as to mandate performance by an officer or employee of the Federal Government, including an activity that requires either the exercise of discretion in applying the authority of the Government or the use of judgment in making a decision for the Government.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Disclosure</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commandant of the Coast Guard shall de-identify information prior to release to the public, including near miss incidents.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Performance Evaluation.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall develop and implement a standard method for evaluating the performance of vessel traffic service centers.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The standard method developed and implemented under paragraph (1) shall include, at a minimum, analysis and collection of data with respect to the following within a vessel traffic service area covered by each vessel traffic service center:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Volume of vessel traffic, categorized by type of vessel.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Total volume of flammable, combustible, or hazardous liquid cargo transported, categorized by vessel type as provided in the Notice of Arrival, if applicable, or as determined by other means.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Data on near-miss incidents.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Data on marine casualties.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Application by vessel traffic operators of traffic management authority during near-miss incidents and marine casualties.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Other additional methods as the Secretary considers appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this paragraph, and biennially thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives a report on the evaluation conducted under paragraph (1) of the performance of vessel traffic service centers, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> recommendations to improve safety and performance; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> data regarding marine casualties and near-miss incidents that have occurred during the period covered by the report.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Risk Assessment Program.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall develop a continuous risk assessment program to evaluate and mitigate safety risks for each vessel traffic service area to improve safety and reduce the risks of oil and hazardous material discharge in navigable waters.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Method for assessment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary, in coordination with stakeholders and the public, shall develop a standard method for conducting risk assessments under paragraph (1) that includes the collection and management of all information necessary to identify and analyze potential hazardous navigational trends within a vessel traffic service area.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Information to be assessed.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall ensure that a risk assessment conducted under paragraph (1) includes an assessment of the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Volume of vessel traffic, categorized by type of vessel.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Total volume of flammable, combustible, or hazardous liquid cargo transported, categorized by vessel type as provided in the Notice of Arrival, if applicable, or as determined by other means.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Data on near-miss events incidents.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> Data on marine casualties.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> Geographic locations for near-miss events incidents and marine casualties, including latitude and longitude.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> Cyclical risk factors such as weather, seasonal water body currents, tides, bathymetry, and topography.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> Weather data, in coordination with the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Information storage and management policies</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall retain all information collected under subparagraph (A) and ensure policies and procedures are in place to standardize the format in which that information is retained to facilitate statistical analysis of that information to calculate within a vessel traffic service area, at a minimum, the incident rate, intervention rate, and casualty prevention rate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Public availability.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Assessments and information</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In accordance with <ref>section 552 of title 5</ref>, the Secretary shall make any risk assessments conducted under paragraph (1) and any information collected under paragraph (3)(A) available to the public.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Information in possession or control of international partners</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall endeavor to coordinate with international partners as described in subsection (d)(2) to enter into agreements to make information collected, shared, and analyzed under that paragraph available to the public.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Disclosure</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commandant of the Coast Guard shall de-identify information prior to release to the public, including near-miss incidents.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Vessel Traffic Service Training.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Training program.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall develop a comprehensive nationwide training program for all vessel traffic service directors, operators, and watchstanders.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The comprehensive nationwide training program under subparagraph (A) and any variances to that program under subsection (c) shall include, at a minimum, the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> Realistic vessel traffic scenarios to the maximum extent practicable that integrate—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the national policy developed under subsection (b);</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> international rules under the International Navigational Rules Act of 1977 (<ref>33 U.S.C. 1601</ref> et seq.);</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> inland navigation rules under part 83 of title 33, Code of Federal Regulations;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> the application of vessel traffic authority; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(V)</num>
<content> communication with vessel traffic service users.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Proficiency training with respect to use, interpretation, and integration of available data on vessel traffic service display systems such as radar, and vessel automatic identification system feeds.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> Practical application of—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the international rules under the International Navigational Rules Act of 1977 (<ref>33 U.S.C. 1601</ref> et seq.); and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the inland navigation rules under part 83 of title 33, Code of Federal Regulations.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> Proficiency training with respect to the operation of radio communications equipment and any other applicable systems necessary to execute vessel traffic service authorities.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> Incorporation of the Standard Marine Communication Phrases adopted by the International Maritime Organization by resolution on <date date="2000-04-04">April 4, 2000</date>, as amended and consolidated, or any successor resolution.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> Incorporation to the maximum extent possible of guidance and recommendations contained in vessel traffic services operator training, vessel traffic services supervisor training, or other relevant training set forth by the International Association of Marine Aids to Navigation and Lighthouse Authorities.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> A minimum number of hours of training for an individual to complete before the individual is qualified to fill a vessel traffic services position without supervision.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> Local area geographic and operational familiarization.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ix)</num>
<content> Such additional components as the Secretary considers appropriate.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Standard competency qualification process.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall develop a standard competency qualification process to be applied to all personnel assigned, employed, or working in a vessel traffic service center.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Application of process</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The competency qualification process developed under subparagraph (A) shall include measurable thresholds for determining proficiency.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">International and inland navigation rules test.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>All personnel assigned, employed, or working in a vessel traffic service center with responsibilities that include communicating, interacting, or directing vessels within a vessel traffic service area, as determined under the national policy developed under subsection (b), shall be required to pass a United States international and inland navigation rules test developed by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Elements of test</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall determine the content and passing standard for the rules test developed under subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Testing frequency</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall establish a frequency, not to exceed once every 5 years, for personnel described in subparagraph (A) to be required to pass the rules test developed under such subparagraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Research on Vessel Traffic.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Vessel communication</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall conduct research, in consultation with subject matter experts identified by the Secretary, to develop more effective procedures for monitoring vessel communications on radio frequencies to identify and address unsafe situations in a vessel traffic service area. The Secretary shall consider data collected under subparagraph (A) of subsection (f)(3).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Professional mariner representation.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall conduct research, in consultation with local stakeholders and subject matter experts identified by the Secretary, to evaluate and determine the feasibility, costs and benefits of representation by professional mariners on the vessel traffic service watchfloor at each vessel traffic service center.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Implementation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall implement representation by professional mariners on the vessel traffic service watchfloor at those vessel traffic service centers for which it is determined feasible and beneficial pursuant to research conducted under subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Inclusion of Identification System on Certain Vessels.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The National Navigation Safety Advisory Committee shall advise and provide recommendations to the Secretary on matters relating to the practicability, economic costs, regulatory burden, and navigational impact of outfitting vessels lacking independent means of propulsion that carry flammable, combustible, or hazardous liquid cargo with vessel automatic identification systems.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Based on the evaluation under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as the Secretary considers appropriate to establish requirements relating to the outfitting of vessels described in such subparagraph with vessel automatic identification systems.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Periodic Review of Vessel Traffic Service Needs.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Based on the performance evaluation conducted under subsection (e) and the risk assessment conducted under subsection (f), the Secretary shall periodically review vessel traffic service areas to determine—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> if there are any additional vessel traffic service needs in those areas; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> if a vessel traffic service area should be moved or modified.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Information to be assessed.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall ensure that a review conducted under paragraph (1) includes an assessment of the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Volume of vessel traffic, categorized by type of vessel.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Total volume of flammable, combustible, or hazardous liquid cargo transported, categorized by vessel type as provided in the Notice of Arrival, if applicable, or as determined by other means.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Data on near miss incidents.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> Data on marine casualties.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> Geographic locations for near-miss incidents and marine casualties, including latitude and longitude.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> Cyclical risk factors such as weather, seasonal water body currents, tides, bathymetry, and topography.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> Weather data, in coordination with the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Stakeholder input</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In conducting the periodic reviews under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall seek input from port and waterway stakeholders to identify areas of increased vessel conflicts or marine casualties that could benefit from the use of routing measures or vessel traffic service special areas to improve safety, port security, and environmental protection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Disclosure</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commandant of the Coast Guard shall de-identify information prior to release to the public, including near miss incidents.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(k)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Limitation of Liability for Coast Guard Vessel Traffic Service Pilots and Non-Federal Vessel Traffic Service Operators.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Coast guard vessel traffic service pilots</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any pilot, acting in the course and scope of his or her duties while at a Coast Guard Vessel Traffic Service Center, who provides information, advice, or communication assistance while under the supervision of a Coast Guard officer, member, or employee shall not be liable for damages caused by or related to such assistance unless the acts or omissions of such pilot constitute gross negligence or willful misconduct.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Non-federal vessel traffic service operators</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An entity operating a non-Federal vessel traffic information service or advisory service pursuant to a duly executed written agreement with the Coast Guard, and any pilot acting on behalf of such entity, is not liable for damages caused by or related to information, advice, or communication assistance provided by such entity or pilot while so operating or acting unless the acts or omissions of such entity or pilot constitute gross negligence or willful misconduct.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(l)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Existing Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section shall be construed to alter the existing authorities of the Secretary to enhance navigation, vessel safety, marine environmental protection, and to ensure safety and preservation of life and property at sea.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(m)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Hazardous liquid cargo</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “hazardous liquid cargo” has the meaning given that term in regulations prescribed under <ref>section 5103 of title 49</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Marine casualty</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “marine casualty” has the meaning given that term in regulations prescribed under section 6101(a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Vessel traffic service area</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “vessel traffic service area” means an area specified in subpart C of part 161 of title 33, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Vessel traffic service center</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “vessel traffic service center” means a center for the provision of vessel traffic services in a vessel traffic service area.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Near miss incident</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “near miss incident” means any occurrence or series of occurrences having the same origin, involving one or more vessels, facilities, or any combination thereof, resulting in the substantial threat of a marine casualty.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">De-identified</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “de-identified” means the process by which all information that is likely to establish the identity of the specific persons or entities noted in the reports, data, or other information is removed from the reports, data, or other information.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title IV, § 401(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4253</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXIII</ref> [LXXXIII], § 8345, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4711</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 70002.</num>
<heading> Special powers</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary may order any vessel, in a port or place subject to the jurisdiction of the United States or in the navigable waters of the United States, to operate or anchor in a manner the Secretary directs if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Secretary has reasonable cause to believe such vessel does not comply with any regulation issued under section 70034 or any other applicable law or treaty;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Secretary determines such vessel does not satisfy the conditions for port entry set forth in section 70021 or 70022 of this title; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> by reason of weather, visibility, sea conditions, port congestion, other hazardous circumstances, or the condition of such vessel, the Secretary is satisfied such direction is justified in the interest of safety.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title IV, § 401(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4255</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXV</ref> [LXXXV], § 8508(2)(A), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4755</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 70003.</num>
<heading> Port access routes</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority To Designate</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in subsection (b) and subject to the requirements of subsection (c), in order to provide safe access routes for the movement of vessel traffic proceeding to or from ports or places subject to the jurisdiction of the United States, the Secretary shall designate necessary fairways and traffic separation schemes for vessels operating in the territorial sea of the United States and in high seas approaches, outside the territorial sea, to such ports or places. Such a designation shall recognize, within the designated area, the paramount right of navigation over all other uses.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Limitation.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>No designation may be made by the Secretary under this section if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Secretary determines such a designation, as implemented, would deprive any person of the effective exercise of a right granted by a lease or permit executed or issued under other applicable provisions of law; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> such right has become vested before the time of publication of the notice required by paragraph (1) of subsection (c).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consultation required</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall make the determination under paragraph (1)(A) after consultation with the head of the agency responsible for executing the lease or issuing the permit.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consideration of Other Uses</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Before making a designation under subsection (a), and in accordance with the requirements of section 70004, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> undertake a study of the potential traffic density and the need for safe access routes for vessels in any area for which fairways or traffic separation schemes are proposed or that may otherwise be considered and publish notice of such undertaking in the Federal Register;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in consultation with the Secretary of State, the Secretary of the Interior, the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of the Army, and the Governors of affected States, as their responsibilities may require, take into account all other uses of the area under consideration, including, as appropriate, the exploration for, or exploitation of, oil, gas, or other mineral resources, the construction or operation of deepwater ports or other structures on or above the seabed or subsoil of the submerged lands or the Outer Continental Shelf of the United States, the establishment or operation of marine or estuarine sanctuaries, and activities involving recreational or commercial fishing; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to the extent practicable, reconcile the need for safe access routes with the needs of all other reasonable uses of the area involved.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Study</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In carrying out the Secretary’s responsibilities under subsection (c), the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> proceed expeditiously to complete any study undertaken; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> after completion of such a study, promptly—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> issue a notice of proposed rulemaking for the designation contemplated; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> publish in the Federal Register a notice that no designation is contemplated as a result of the study and the reason for such determination.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Implementation of Designation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In connection with a designation made under this section, the Secretary—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall issue reasonable rules and regulations governing the use of such designated areas, including rules and regulations regarding the applicability of rules 9 and 10 of the International Regulations for Preventing Collisions at Sea, 1972, relating to narrow channels and traffic separation schemes, respectively, in waters where such regulations apply;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to the extent that the Secretary finds reasonable and necessary to effectuate the purposes of the designation, make the use of designated fairways and traffic separation schemes mandatory for specific types and sizes of vessels, foreign and domestic, operating in the territorial sea of the United States and for specific types and sizes of vessels of the United States operating on the high seas beyond the territorial sea of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> may, from time to time, as necessary, adjust the location or limits of designated fairways or traffic separation schemes in order to accommodate the needs of other uses that cannot be reasonably accommodated otherwise, except that such an adjustment may not, in the judgment of the Secretary, unacceptably adversely affect the purpose for which the existing designation was made and the need for which continues; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> shall, through appropriate channels—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> notify cognizant international organizations of any designation, or adjustment thereof; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> take action to seek the cooperation of foreign States in making it mandatory for vessels under their control to use, to the same extent as required by the Secretary for vessels of the United States, any fairway or traffic separation scheme designated under this section in any area of the high seas.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title IV, § 401(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4255</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 70004.</num>
<heading> Considerations by Secretary</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In carrying out the duties of the Secretary under sections 70001, 70002, and 70003, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> take into account all relevant factors concerning navigation and vessel safety, protection of the marine environment, and the safety and security of United States ports and waterways, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the scope and degree of the risk or hazard involved;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> vessel traffic characteristics and trends, including traffic volume, the sizes and types of vessels involved, potential interference with the flow of commercial traffic, the presence of any unusual cargoes, and other similar factors;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> port and waterway configurations and variations in local conditions of geography, climate, and other similar factors;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the need for granting exemptions for the installation and use of equipment or devices for use with vessel traffic services for certain classes of small vessels, such as self-propelled fishing vessels and recreational vessels;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the proximity of fishing grounds, oil and gas drilling and production operations, or any other potential or actual conflicting activity;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> environmental factors;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> economic impact and effects;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> existing vessel traffic services; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> local practices and customs, including voluntary arrangements and agreements within the maritime community; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> at the earliest possible time, consult with and receive and consider the views of representatives of the maritime community, ports and harbor authorities or associations, environmental groups, and other persons who may be affected by the proposed actions.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title IV, § 401(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4257</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 70005.</num>
<heading> International agreements</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transmittal of Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall transmit, via the Secretary of State, to appropriate international bodies or forums, any regulations issued under this subchapter, for consideration as international standards.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Agreements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The President is authorized and encouraged to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> enter into negotiations and conclude and execute agreements with neighboring nations, to establish compatible vessel standards and vessel traffic services, and to establish, operate, and maintain international vessel traffic services, in areas and under circumstances of mutual concern; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> enter into negotiations, through appropriate international bodies, and conclude and execute agreements to establish vessel traffic services in appropriate areas of the high seas.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Operations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary, pursuant to any agreement negotiated under subsection (b) that is binding upon the United States in accordance with constitutional requirements, may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> require vessels operating in an area of a vessel traffic service to utilize or to comply with the vessel traffic service, including the carrying or installation of equipment and devices as necessary for the use of the service; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> waive, by order or regulation, the application of any United States law or regulation concerning the design, construction, operation, equipment, personnel qualifications, and manning standards for vessels operating in waters over which the United States exercises jurisdiction if such vessel is not en route to or from a United States port or place, and if vessels en route to or from a United States port or place are accorded equivalent waivers of laws and regulations of the neighboring nation, when operating in waters over which that nation exercises jurisdiction.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Ship Reporting Systems</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary, in cooperation with the International Maritime Organization, may implement and enforce two mandatory ship reporting systems, consistent with international law, with respect to vessels subject to such reporting systems entering the following areas of the Atlantic Ocean:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Cape Cod Bay, Massachusetts Bay, and Great South Channel (in the area generally bounded by a line starting from a point on Cape Ann, Massachusetts at 42 deg. 39′ N., 70 deg. 37′ W; then northeast to 42 deg. 45′ N., 70 deg. 13′ W; then southeast to 42 deg. 10′ N., 68 deg. 31′ W, then south to 41 deg. 00′ N., 68 deg. 31′ W; then west to 41 deg. 00′ N., 69 deg. 17′ W; then northeast to 42 deg. 05′ N., 70 deg. 02′ W, then west to 42 deg. 04′ N., 70 deg. 10′ W; and then along the Massachusetts shoreline of Cape Cod Bay and Massachusetts Bay back to the point on Cape Ann at 42 deg. 39′ N., 70 deg. 37′ W).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In the coastal waters of the Southeastern United States within about 25 nm along a 90 nm stretch of the Atlantic seaboard (in an area generally extending from the shoreline east to longitude 80 deg. 51.6′ W with the southern and northern boundary at latitudes 30 deg. 00′ N., 31 deg. 27′ N., respectively).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title IV, § 401(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4257</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 70006.</num>
<heading> Establishment by Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating of anchorage grounds and regulations generally</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Homeland Security is authorized, empowered, and directed to define and establish anchorage grounds for vessels in all harbors, rivers, bays, and other navigable waters of the United States whenever it is manifest to the said Secretary that the maritime or commercial interests of the United States require such anchorage grounds for safe navigation and the establishment of such anchorage grounds shall have been recommended by the Chief of Engineers, and to adopt suitable rules and regulations in relation thereto; and such rules and regulations shall be enforced by the Coast Guard under the direction of the Secretary of Transportation: <i>Provided</i>, That at ports or places where there is no Coast Guard vessel available such rules and regulations may be enforced by the Chief of Engineers under the direction of the Secretary of Homeland Security. In the event of the violation of any such rules and regulations by the owner, master, or person in charge of any vessel, such owner, master, or person in charge of such vessel shall be liable to a penalty of up to $10,000. Each day during which a violation continues shall constitute a separate violation. The said vessel may be holden for the payment of such penalty, and may be seized and proceeded against summarily by libel for the recovery of the same in any United States district court for the district within which such vessel may be and in the name of the officer designated by the Secretary of Homeland Security.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>As used in this section “navigable waters of the United States” includes all waters of the territorial sea of the United States as described in Presidential Proclamation No. 5928 of <date date="1988-12-27">December 27, 1988</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXV</ref> [LXXXV], § 8501(a)(6), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4745</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 70007.</num>
<heading> Anchorage grounds</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Anchorage Grounds.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating shall define and establish anchorage grounds in the navigable waters of the United States for vessels operating in such waters.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Relevant factors for establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In carrying out paragraph (1), the Secretary shall take into account all relevant factors concerning navigational safety, protection of the marine environment, proximity to undersea pipelines and cables, safe and efficient use of Marine Transportation System, and national security.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Vessel Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Vessels, of certain sizes or type determined by the Secretary, shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> set and maintain an anchor alarm for the duration of an anchorage;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> comply with any directions or orders issued by the Captain of the Port; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> comply with any applicable anchorage regulations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A vessel may not—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> anchor in any Federal navigation channel unless authorized or directed to by the Captain of the Port;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> anchor in near proximity, within distances determined by the Coast Guard, to an undersea pipeline or cable, unless authorized or directed to by the Captain of the Port; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> anchor or remain anchored in an anchorage ground during any period in which the Captain of the Port orders closure of the anchorage ground due to inclement weather, navigational hazard, a threat to the environment, or other safety or security concern.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Safety Exception</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section shall be construed to prevent a vessel from taking actions necessary to maintain the safety of the vessel or to prevent the loss of life or property.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. K, title CXIII, § 11318(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4090</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>PORTS AND WATERWAYS SAFETY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 70011.</num>
<heading> Waterfront safety</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary may take such action as is necessary to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> prevent damage to, or the destruction of, any bridge or other structure on or in the navigable waters of the United States, or any land structure or shore area immediately adjacent to such waters; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> protect the navigable waters and the resources therein from harm resulting from vessel or structure damage, destruction, or loss.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Actions Authorized</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Actions authorized by subsection (a) include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> establishing procedures, measures, and standards for the handling, loading, unloading, storage, stowage, and movement on a structure (including the emergency removal, control, and disposition) of explosives or other dangerous articles and substances, including oil or hazardous material as those terms are defined in section 2101;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> prescribing minimum safety equipment requirements for a structure to assure adequate protection from fire, explosion, natural disaster, and other serious accidents or casualties;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> establishing water or waterfront safety zones, or other measures, for limited, controlled, or conditional access and activity when necessary for the protection of any vessel, structure, waters, or shore area; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> establishing procedures for examination to assure compliance with the requirements prescribed under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">State Law</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section, with respect to structures, prohibits a State or political subdivision thereof from prescribing higher safety equipment requirements or safety standards than those that may be prescribed by regulations under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title IV, § 401(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4258</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 70012.</num>
<heading> Navigational hazards</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reporting Procedure</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall establish a program to encourage fishermen and other vessel operators to report potential or existing navigational hazards involving pipelines to the Secretary through Coast Guard field offices.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Secretary’s Response.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notification by the operator of a pipeline</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Upon notification by the operator of a pipeline of a hazard to navigation with respect to that pipeline, the Secretary shall immediately notify Coast Guard headquarters, the Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety Administration, other affected Federal and State agencies, and vessel owners and operators in the pipeline’s vicinity.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notification by other persons</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Upon notification by any other person of a hazard or potential hazard to navigation with respect to a pipeline, the Secretary shall promptly determine whether a hazard exists, and if so shall immediately notify Coast Guard headquarters, the Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety Administration, other affected Federal and State agencies, vessel owners and operators in the pipeline’s vicinity, and the owner and operator of the pipeline.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Pipeline Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of this section, the term “pipeline” has the meaning given the term “pipeline facility” in <ref>section 60101(a)(18) of title 49</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title IV, § 401(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4259</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 70013.</num>
<heading> Requirement to notify Coast Guard of release of objects into the navigable waters of the United States</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>As soon as a person has knowledge of any release from a vessel or facility into the navigable waters of the United States of any object that creates an obstruction prohibited under <ref>section 10 of the Act of March 3, 1899</ref>, popularly known as the Rivers and Harbors Appropriations Act of 1899 (<ref>33 U.S.C. 403</ref>), such person shall notify the Secretary and the Secretary of the Army of such release.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Restriction on Use of Notification</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any notification provided by an individual in accordance with subsection (a) may not be used against such individual in any criminal case, except a prosecution for perjury or for giving a false statement.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title IV, § 401(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4259</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 70014.</num>
<heading> Aiming laser pointer at vessel</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>It shall be unlawful to cause the beam of a laser pointer to strike a vessel operating on the navigable waters of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exceptions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section shall not apply to a member or element of the Department of Defense or Department of Homeland Security acting in an official capacity for the purpose of research, development, operations, testing, or training.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Laser Pointer Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section the term “laser pointer” means any device designed or used to amplify electromagnetic radiation by stimulated emission that emits a beam designed to be used by the operator as a pointer or highlighter to indicate, mark, or identify a specific position, place, item, or object.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXIII, § 8342(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4709</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>CONDITION FOR ENTRY INTO PORTS IN THE UNITED STATES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 70021.</num>
<heading> Conditions for entry to ports in the United States</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>No vessel that is subject to chapter 37 shall operate in the navigable waters of the United States or transfer cargo or residue in any port or place under the jurisdiction of the United States, if such vessel—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> has a history of accidents, pollution incidents, or serious repair problems that, as determined by the Secretary, creates reason to believe that such vessel may be unsafe or may create a threat to the marine environment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> fails to comply with any applicable regulation issued under section 70034, chapter 37, or any other applicable law or treaty;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> discharges oil or hazardous material in violation of any law of the United States or in a manner or quantities inconsistent with any treaty to which the United States is a party;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> does not comply with any applicable vessel traffic service requirements;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> is manned by one or more officers who are licensed by a certificating State that the Secretary has determined, pursuant to <ref>section 9101 of title 46</ref>, does not have standards for licensing and certification of seafarers that are comparable to or more stringent than United States standards or international standards that are accepted by the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> is not manned in compliance with manning levels as determined by the Secretary to be necessary to insure the safe navigation of the vessel; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> while underway, does not have at least one licensed deck officer on the navigation bridge who is capable of clearly understanding English.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Exceptions.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may allow provisional entry of a vessel that is not in compliance with subsection (a), if the owner or operator of such vessel proves, to the satisfaction of the Secretary, that such vessel is not unsafe or a threat to the marine environment, and if such entry is necessary for the safety of the vessel or persons aboard.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Provisions not applicable</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Paragraphs (1), (2), (3), and (4) of subsection (a) of this section shall not apply to a vessel allowed provisional entry under paragraph (1) if the owner or operator of such vessel proves, to the satisfaction of the Secretary, that such vessel is no longer unsafe or a threat to the marine environment, and is no longer in violation of any applicable law, treaty, regulation, or condition, as appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title IV, § 401(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4260</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 70022.</num>
<heading> Prohibition on entry and operation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Prohibition.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as otherwise provided in this section, no vessel described in subsection (b) may enter or operate in the navigable waters of the United States or transfer cargo in any port or place under the jurisdiction of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Limitations on application.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The prohibition under paragraph (1) shall not apply with respect to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> a vessel described in subsection (b)(1), if the Secretary of State determines that—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the vessel is owned or operated by or on behalf of a country the government of which the Secretary of State determines is closely cooperating with the United States with respect to implementing the applicable United Nations Security Council resolutions (as such term is defined in section 3 of the North Korea Sanctions and Policy Enhancement Act of 2016); or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> it is in the national security interest not to apply the prohibition to such vessel; or</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a vessel described in subsection (b)(2), if the Secretary of State determines that the vessel is no longer registered as described in that subsection.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 15 days after making a determination under subparagraph (A), the Secretary of State shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate written notice of the determination and the basis upon which the determination was made.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Publication</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of State shall publish a notice in the Federal Register of each determination made under subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Vessels Described</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A vessel referred to in subsection (a) is a foreign vessel for which a notice of arrival is required to be filed under section 70001(a)(5), and that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> is on the most recent list of vessels published in Federal <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002049">1</ref> Register under subsection (c)(2); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> more than 180 days after the publication of such list, is knowingly registered, pursuant to the 1958 Convention on the High Seas entered into force on <date date="1962-09-30">September 30, 1962</date>, by a government the agents or instrumentalities of which are maintaining a registration of a vessel that is included on such list.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Information and Publication</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating, with the concurrence of the Secretary of State, shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> maintain timely information on the registrations of all foreign vessels over 300 gross tons that are known to be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> owned or operated by or on behalf of the Government of North Korea or a North Korean person;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> owned or operated by or on behalf of any country in which a sea port is located, the operator of which the President has identified in the most recent report submitted under section 205(a)(1)(A) of the North Korea Sanctions and Policy Enhancement Act of 2016; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> owned or operated by or on behalf of any country identified by the President as a country that has not complied with the applicable United Nations Security Council resolutions (as such term is defined in section 3 of such Act); and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> periodically publish in the Federal Register a list of the vessels described in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Notification of Governments.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of State shall notify each government, the agents or instrumentalities of which are maintaining a registration of a foreign vessel that is included on a list published under subsection (c)(2), not later than 30 days after such publication, that all vessels registered under such government’s authority are subject to subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Additional notification</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In the case of a government that continues to maintain a registration for a vessel that is included on such list after receiving an initial notification under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall issue an additional notification to such government not later than 120 days after the publication of a list under subsection (c)(2).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notification of Vessels</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Upon receiving a notice of arrival under section 70001(a)(5) from a vessel described in subsection (b), the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating shall notify the master of such vessel that the vessel may not enter or operate in the navigable waters of the United States or transfer cargo in any port or place under the jurisdiction of the United States, unless—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Secretary of State has made a determination under subsection (a)(2); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating allows provisional entry of the vessel, or transfer of cargo from the vessel, under subsection (f).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Provisional Entry or Cargo Transfer</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating may allow provisional entry of, or transfer of cargo from, a vessel, if such entry or transfer is necessary for the safety of the vessel or persons aboard.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Right of Innocent Passage and Right of Transit Passage</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section shall not be construed as authority to restrict the right of innocent passage or the right of transit passage as recognized under international law.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXV</ref> [LXXXV], § 8508(1), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4755</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>DEFINITIONS, REGULATIONS, ENFORCEMENT, INVESTIGATORY POWERS, APPLICABILITY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 70031.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in subchapters I through III and this subchapter, unless the context otherwise requires:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The term “marine environment” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the navigable waters of the United States and the land and resources therein and thereunder;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the waters and fishery resources of any area over which the United States asserts exclusive fishery management authority;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the seabed and subsoil of the Outer Continental Shelf of the United States, the resources thereof, and the waters superjacent thereto; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the recreational, economic, and scenic values of such waters and resources.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating, except that such term means the Secretary of Transportation with respect to the application of this chapter to the Saint Lawrence Seaway.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “navigable waters of the United States” includes all waters of the territorial sea of the United States as described in Presidential Proclamation No. 5928 of <date date="1988-12-27">December 27, 1988</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title IV, § 401(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4261</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXV</ref> [LXXXV], § 8507(a)(4), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4753</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 70032.</num>
<heading> Saint Lawrence Seaway</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The authority granted to the Secretary under sections 70001, 70002, 70003, 70004, and 70011 may not be delegated with respect to the Saint Lawrence Seaway to any agency other than the Great Lakes St. Lawrence Seaway Development Corporation. Any other authority granted the Secretary under subchapters I through III and this subchapter shall be delegated by the Secretary to the Great Lakes St. Lawrence Seaway Development Corporation to the extent the Secretary determines such delegation is necessary for the proper operation of the Saint Lawrence Seaway.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title IV, § 401(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4261</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–260, div. AA, title V, § 512(c)(6)(F)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 2757</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXV</ref> [LXXXV], § 8507(a)(5), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4753</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 70033.</num>
<heading> Limitation on application to foreign vessels</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except pursuant to international treaty, convention, or agreement, to which the United States is a party, subchapters I through III and this subchapter shall not apply to any foreign vessel that is not destined for, or departing from, a port or place subject to the jurisdiction of the United States and that is in—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> innocent passage through the territorial sea of the United States; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> transit through the navigable waters of the United States that form a part of an international strait.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title IV, § 401(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4261</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXV</ref> [LXXXV], § 8507(a)(6), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4753</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 70034.</num>
<heading> Regulations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In accordance with <ref>section 553 of title 5</ref>, the Secretary shall issue, and may from time to time amend or repeal, regulations necessary to implement subchapters I through III and this subchapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consultation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In the exercise of the regulatory authority under subchapters I through III and this subchapter, the Secretary shall consult with, and receive and consider the views of all interested persons, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> interested Federal departments and agencies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> officials of State and local governments;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> representatives of the maritime community;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> representatives of port and harbor authorities or associations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> representatives of environmental groups;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> any other interested persons who are knowledgeable or experienced in dealing with problems involving vessel safety, port and waterways safety, and protection of the marine environment; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> advisory committees consisting of all interested segments of the public when the establishment of such committees is considered necessary because the issues involved are highly complex or controversial.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title IV, § 401(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4261</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXV</ref> [LXXXV], § 8507(a)(7), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4753</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 70035.</num>
<heading> Investigatory powers</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Secretary</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may investigate any incident, accident, or act involving the loss or destruction of, or damage to, any structure subject to subchapters I through III and this subchapter, or that affects or may affect the safety or environmental quality of the ports, harbors, or navigable waters of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Powers</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In an investigation under this section, the Secretary may issue subpoenas to require the attendance of witnesses and the production of documents or other evidence relating to such incident, accident, or act. If any person refuses to obey a subpoena, the Secretary may request the Attorney General to invoke the aid of the appropriate district court of the United States to compel compliance with the subpoena. Any district court of the United States may, in the case of refusal to obey a subpoena, issue an order requiring compliance with the subpoena, and failure to obey the order may be punished by the court as contempt. Witnesses may be paid fees for travel and attendance at rates not exceeding those allowed in a district court of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title IV, § 401(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4262</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXV</ref> [LXXXV], § 8507(a)(8), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4753</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 70036.</num>
<heading> Enforcement</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Civil Penalty.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any person who is found by the Secretary, after notice and an opportunity for a hearing, to have violated subchapters I through III or this subchapter or a regulation issued under subchapters I through III or this subchapter shall be liable to the United States for a civil penalty, not to exceed $25,000 for each violation. Each day of a continuing violation shall constitute a separate violation. The amount of such civil penalty shall be assessed by the Secretary, or the Secretary’s designee, by written notice. In determining the amount of such penalty, the Secretary shall take into account the nature, circumstances, extent, and gravity of the prohibited acts committed and, with respect to the violator, the degree of culpability, any history of prior offenses, ability to pay, and such other matters as justice may require.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Compromise, modification, or remission</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may compromise, modify, or remit, with or without conditions, any civil penalty that is subject to imposition or that has been imposed under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Failure to pay penalty</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If any person fails to pay an assessment of a civil penalty after it has become final, the Secretary may refer the matter to the Attorney General of the United States, for collection in any appropriate district court of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Criminal Penalty.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Class d felony</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any person who willfully and knowingly violates subchapters I through III or this subchapter or any regulation issued thereunder commits a class D felony.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Class c felony</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any person who, in the willful and knowing violation of subchapters I through III or this subchapter or of any regulation issued thereunder, uses a dangerous weapon, or engages in conduct that causes bodily injury or fear of imminent bodily injury to any officer authorized to enforce the provisions of such a subchapter or the regulations issued under such subchapter, commits a class C felony.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In Rem Liability</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any vessel that is used in violation of subchapters I, II, or III or this subchapter, or any regulations issued under such subchapter, shall be liable in rem for any civil penalty assessed pursuant to subsection (a) and may be proceeded against in the United States district court for any district in which such vessel may be found.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Injunction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The United States district courts shall have jurisdiction to restrain violations of subchapter I, II, or III or this subchapter or of regulations issued under such subchapter, for cause shown.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Denial of Entry</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Except as provided in section 70021 or 70022, the Secretary may, subject to recognized principles of international law, deny entry by any vessel that is not in compliance with subchapter I, II, or III or this subchapter or the regulations issued under such subchapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> into the navigable waters of the United States; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to any port or place under the jurisdiction of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Withholding of Clearance.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If any owner, operator, or individual in charge of a vessel is liable for a penalty or fine under this section, or if reasonable cause exists to believe that the owner, operator, or individual in charge may be subject to a penalty or fine under this section, the Secretary of the Treasury, upon the request of the Secretary, shall with respect to such vessel refuse or revoke any clearance required by <ref>section 60105 of title 46</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Granting clearance refused or revoked</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Clearance refused or revoked under this subsection may be granted upon filing of a bond or other surety satisfactory to the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title IV, § 401(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4262</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXV</ref> [LXXXV], §§ 8507(a)(9), 8508(2)(B), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4753</ref>, 4755.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER V—</num>
<heading>REGATTAS AND MARINE PARADES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 70041.</num>
<heading> Regattas and marine parades</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commandant of the Coast Guard may issue regulations to promote the safety of life on navigable waters during regattas or marine parades.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Detail and Use of Vessels</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>To enforce regulations issued under this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Commandant may detail any public vessel in the service of the Coast Guard and make use of any private vessel tendered gratuitously for that purpose; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> upon the request of the Commandant, the head of any other Federal department or agency may enforce the regulations by means of any public vessel of such department and any private vessel tendered gratuitously for that purpose.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transfer of Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The authority of the Commandant under this section may be transferred by the President for any special occasion to the head of another Federal department or agency whenever in the President’s judgment such transfer is desirable.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Penalties.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For any violation of regulations issued pursuant to this section the following penalties shall be incurred:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A licensed officer shall be liable to suspension or revocation of license in the manner prescribed by law for incompetency or misconduct.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Any person in charge of the navigation of a vessel other than a licensed officer shall be liable to a penalty of $5,000.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The owner of a vessel (including any corporate officer of a corporation owning the vessel) actually on board shall be liable to a penalty of $5,000, unless the violation of regulations occurred without the owner’s knowledge.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Any other person shall be liable to a penalty of $2,500.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Mitigation or remission</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commandant may mitigate or remit any penalty provided for in this subsection in the manner prescribed by law for the mitigation or remission of penalties for violation of the navigation laws.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title IV, § 406(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4265</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER VI—</num>
<heading>REGULATION OF VESSELS IN TERRITORIAL WATERS OF UNITED STATES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 70051.</num>
<heading> Regulation of anchorage and movement of vessels during national emergency</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever the President by proclamation or Executive order declares a national emergency to exist by reason of actual or threatened war, insurrection, or invasion, or disturbance or threatened disturbance of the international relations of the United States, or whenever the Attorney General determines that an actual or anticipated mass migration of aliens en route to, or arriving off the coast of, the United States presents urgent circumstances requiring an immediate Federal response, the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating may make, subject to the approval of the President, rules and regulations governing the anchorage and movement of any vessel, foreign or domestic, in the territorial waters of the United States, may inspect such vessel at any time, place guards thereon, and, if necessary in his opinion in order to secure such vessels from damage or injury, or to prevent damage or injury to any harbor or waters of the United States, or to secure the observance of the rights and obligations of the United States, may take, by and with the consent of the President, for such purposes, full possession and control of such vessel and remove therefrom the officers and crew thereof and all other persons not specially authorized by him to go or remain on board thereof.</p>
<p class="indent0">Whenever the President finds that the security of the United States is endangered by reason of actual or threatened war, or invasion, or insurrection, or subversive activity, or of disturbances or threatened disturbances of the international relations of the United States, the President is authorized to institute such measures and issue such rules and regulations—</p>
<p class="indent1">(a) to govern the anchorage and movement of any foreign-flag vessels in the territorial waters of the United States, to inspect such vessels at any time, to place guards thereon, and, if necessary in his opinion in order to secure such vessels from damage or injury, or to prevent damage or injury to any harbor or waters of the United States, or to secure the observance of rights and obligations of the United States, may take for such purposes full possession and control of such vessels and remove therefrom the officers and crew thereof, and all other persons not especially authorized by him to go or remain on board thereof;</p>
<p class="indent1">(b) to safeguard against destruction, loss, or injury from sabotage or other subversive acts, accidents, or other causes of similar nature, vessels, harbors, ports, and waterfront facilities in the United States and all territory and water, continental or insular, subject to the jurisdiction of the United States.</p>
<p class="indent0 firstIndent0">The President may delegate the authority to issue such rules and regulations to the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating. Any appropriation available to any of the Executive Departments shall be available to carry out the provisions of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title IV, § 407(b)(5)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4267</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXV</ref> [LXXXV], § 8507(a)(10), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4753</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 70052.</num>
<heading> Seizure and forfeiture of vessel; fine and imprisonment</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If any owner, agent, master, officer, or person in charge, or any member of the crew of any such vessel fails to comply with any regulation or rule issued or order given under the provisions of this subchapter, or obstructs or interferes with the exercise of any power conferred by this subchapter, the vessel, together with her tackle, apparel, furniture, and equipment, shall be subject to seizure and forfeiture to the United States in the same manner as merchandise is forfeited for violation of the customs revenue laws; and the person guilty of such failure, obstruction, or interference shall be punished by imprisonment for not more than ten years and may, in the discretion of the court, be fined not more than $10,000.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Application to Others</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If any other person knowingly fails to comply with any regulation or rule issued or order given under the provisions of this subchapter, or knowingly obstructs or interferes with the exercise of any power conferred by this subchapter, he shall be punished by imprisonment for not more than ten years and may, at the discretion of the court, be fined not more than $10,000.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Civil Penalty</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A person violating this subchapter, or a regulation prescribed under this subchapter, shall be liable to the United States Government for a civil penalty of not more than $25,000 for each violation. Each day of a continuing violation shall constitute a separate violation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In Rem Liability</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any vessel that is used in violation of this subchapter, or of any regulation issued under this subchapter, shall be liable in rem for any civil penalty assessed pursuant to subsection (c) and may be proceeded against in the United States district court for any district in which such vessel may be found.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Withholding of Clearance.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If any owner, agent, master, officer, or person in charge of a vessel is liable for a penalty or fine under subsection (c), or if reasonable cause exists to believe that the owner, agent, master, officer, or person in charge may be subject to a penalty or fine under this section, the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating may, with respect to such vessel, refuse or revoke any clearance required by section 4197 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002050">1</ref> of the Revised Statutes of the United States (46 U.S.C. App. 91).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Clearance upon filing of bond or other surety</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating may require the filing of a bond or other surety as a condition of granting clearance refused or revoked under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title IV, § 407(c)(3)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4267</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXV</ref> [LXXXV], § 8507(a)(11), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4754</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 70053.</num>
<heading> Enforcement provisions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President may employ such departments, agencies, officers, or instrumentalities of the United States as he may deem necessary to carry out this subchapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title IV, § 407(d)(3)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4267</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 70054.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this subchapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">United states</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “United States” includes all territory and waters, continental or insular, subject to the jurisdiction of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Territorial waters</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “territorial waters of the United States” includes all waters of the territorial sea of the United States as described in Presidential Proclamation 5928 of <date date="1988-12-27">December 27, 1988</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title IV, § 407(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4266</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>