<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 112—</num>
<heading>MERCHANT MARINER BENEFITS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 11201.</num>
<heading> Eligibility for veterans’ burial and cemetery benefits</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Eligibility.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The qualified service of an individual referred to in paragraph (2) shall be considered to be active duty in the Armed Forces during a period of war for purposes of eligibility for benefits under the following provisions of title 38:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Chapter 23 (relating to burial benefits).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Chapter 24 (relating to interment in national cemeteries).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered individuals</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Paragraph (1) applies to an individual who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> receives an honorable service certificate under <ref>section 11203 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is not eligible under any other provision of law for benefits under laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reimbursement for Benefits Provided</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall reimburse the Secretary of Veterans Affairs for the value of benefits that the Secretary of Veterans Affairs provides for an individual by reason of eligibility under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Applicability.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General rule</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Benefits may be provided under the provisions of law referred to in subsection (a)(1) by reason of this chapter only for deaths occurring after the date of the enactment of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Burials, etc. in national cemeteries</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding paragraph (1), in the case of an initial burial or columbarium placement after the date of the enactment of this chapter, benefits may be provided under chapter 24 of title 38 by reason of this chapter (regardless of the date of death), and in such a case benefits may be provided under section 2306 of such title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 105–368, title IV, § 402(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-11">Nov. 11, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3336</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXV</ref> [LXXXV], § 8505(b)(11), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4751</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11202.</num>
<heading> Qualified service</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this chapter, an individual shall be considered to have engaged in qualified service if, between <date date="1945-08-16">August 16, 1945</date>, and <date date="1946-12-31">December 31, 1946</date>, the individual—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> was a member of the United States merchant marine (including the Army Transport Service and the Naval Transport Service) serving as a crewmember of a vessel that was—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> operated by the War Shipping Administration or the Office of Defense Transportation (or an agent of the Administration or Office);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> operated in waters other than inland waters, the Great Lakes, and other lakes, bays, and harbors of the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> under contract or charter to, or property of, the Government of the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> serving the Armed Forces; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> while so serving, was licensed or otherwise documented for service as a crewmember of such a vessel by an officer or employee of the United States authorized to license or document the individual for such service.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 105–368, title IV, § 402(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-11">Nov. 11, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3336</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXV</ref> [LXXXV], § 8505(b)(12), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4752</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11203.</num>
<heading> Documentation of qualified service</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Record of Service</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary, or in the case of personnel of the Army Transport Service or the Naval Transport Service, the Secretary of Defense, shall, upon application—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> issue a certificate of honorable service to an individual who, as determined by that Secretary, engaged in qualified service of a nature and duration that warrants issuance of the certificate; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> correct, or request the appropriate official of the Federal Government to correct, the service records of that individual to the extent necessary to reflect the qualified service and the issuance of the certificate of honorable service.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Timing of Documentation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A Secretary receiving an application under subsection (a) shall act on the application not later than 1 year after the date of that receipt.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Standards Relating to Service</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In making a determination under subsection (a)(1), the Secretary acting on the application shall apply the same standards relating to the nature and duration of service that apply to the issuance of honorable discharges under section 401(a)(1)(B) of the GI Bill Improvement Act of 1977 (<ref>38 U.S.C. 106</ref> note).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Correction of Records</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An official who is requested under subsection (a)(2) to correct the service records of an individual shall make such correction.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 105–368, title IV, § 402(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-11">Nov. 11, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3337</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXV</ref> [LXXXV], § 8505(b)(13), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4752</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11204.</num>
<heading> Processing fees</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Collection of Fees</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary, or in the case of personnel of the Army Transport Service or the Naval Transport Service, the Secretary of Defense, shall collect a fee of $30 from each applicant for processing an application submitted under <ref>section 11203(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Treatment of Fees Collected</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Amounts received by the Secretary under this section shall be deposited in the General Fund of the Treasury as offsetting receipts of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating and ascribed to Coast Guard activities. Amounts received by the Secretary of Defense under this section shall be deposited in the General Fund of the Treasury as offsetting receipts of the Department of Defense. In either case, such amounts shall be available, subject to appropriation, for the administrative costs of processing applications under <ref>section 11203 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 105–368, title IV, § 402(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-11">Nov. 11, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3337</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>