<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 141—</num>
<heading>GENERAL</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 14101.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this part—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “Convention” means the International Convention on Tonnage Measurement of Ships, 1969.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> “existing vessel” means a vessel the keel of which was laid or that was at a similar stage of construction before <date date="1982-07-18">July 18, 1982</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> “Great Lakes” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Great Lakes; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> the St. Lawrence River west of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a rhumb line drawn from Cap des Rosiers to West Point, Anticosti Island; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> on the north side of Anticosti Island, the meridian of longitude 63 degrees west.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> “vessel that engages on a foreign voyage” means a vessel—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> that arrives at a place under the jurisdiction of the United States from a place in a foreign country;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> that makes a voyage between places outside the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> that departs from a place under the jurisdiction of the United States for a place in a foreign country; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> that makes a voyage between a place within a territory or possession of the United States and another place under the jurisdiction of the United States not within that territory or possession.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–509, title V, § 5101(3)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1919</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–281, title III, § 303(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2923</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 14102.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 101–595, title VI, § 603(12)(A)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 2993</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 14103.</num>
<heading> Delegation of authority</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary may delegate to a qualified person the authority to measure a vessel and issue an International Tonnage Certificate (1969) or other appropriate certificate of measurement under this part.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, a decision of the person delegated authority under subsection (a) of this section related to measuring a vessel or issuing a certificate may be appealed to the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> For a vessel that engages on a foreign voyage, the Secretary may delegate to another country that is a party to the Convention the authority to measure the vessel and issue an International Tonnage Certificate (1969) under chapter 143 of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The Secretary may terminate a delegation made under this section after giving written notice to the person.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–509, title V, § 5101(3)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1919</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–281, title III, § 303(b)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2924</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 14104.</num>
<heading> Measurement to determine application of a law</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> When the application of a law of the United States to a vessel depends on the vessel’s tonnage, the vessel shall be measured under this part.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> If a statute allows for an alternate tonnage to be prescribed under this section, the Secretary may prescribe it by regulation. Any such regulation shall be considered to be an interpretive regulation for purposes of <ref>section 553 of title 5</ref>. Until an alternate tonnage is prescribed, the statutorily established tonnage shall apply to vessels measured under chapter 143 or chapter 145 of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The head of each Federal agency shall ensure that regulations issued by the agency that specify particular tonnages comply with the alternate tonnages implemented by the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–509, title V, § 5101(3)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1920</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–324, title VII, § 702</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3933</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>