<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 403—</num>
<heading>AGREEMENTS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 40301.</num>
<heading> Application</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Ocean Common Carrier Agreements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>This part applies to an agreement between or among ocean common carriers to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> discuss, fix, or regulate transportation rates, including through rates, cargo space accommodations, and other conditions of service;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> pool or apportion traffic, revenues, earnings, or losses;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> allot ports or regulate the number and character of voyages between ports;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> regulate the volume or character of cargo or passenger traffic to be carried;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> engage in an exclusive, preferential, or cooperative working arrangement between themselves or with a marine terminal operator;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> control, regulate, or prevent competition in international ocean transportation; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> discuss and agree on any matter related to a service contract.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Marine Terminal Operator Agreements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>This part applies to an agreement between or among marine terminal operators, or between or among one or more marine terminal operators and one or more ocean common carriers, to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> discuss, fix, or regulate rates or other conditions of service; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> engage in exclusive, preferential, or cooperative working arrangements, to the extent the agreement involves ocean transportation in the foreign commerce of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Acquisitions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This part does not apply to an acquisition by any person, directly or indirectly, of any voting security or assets of any other person.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Maritime Labor Agreements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This part does not apply to a maritime labor agreement. However, this subsection does not exempt from this part any rate, charge, regulation, or practice of a common carrier that is required to be set forth in a tariff or is an essential term of a service contract, whether or not the rate, charge, regulation, or practice arises out of, or is otherwise related to, a maritime labor agreement.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Assessment Agreements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This part (except sections 40305 and 40307(a)) does not apply to an assessment agreement.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 7</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1528</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40302.</num>
<heading> Filing requirements</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A true copy of every agreement referred to in section 40301(a) or (b) of this title shall be filed with the Federal Maritime Commission. If the agreement is oral, a complete memorandum specifying in detail the substance of the agreement shall be filed.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exceptions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subsection (a) does not apply to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an agreement related to transportation to be performed within or between foreign countries; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an agreement among common carriers to establish, operate, or maintain a marine terminal in the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commission may by regulation prescribe the form and manner in which an agreement shall be filed and any additional information and documents necessary to evaluate the agreement.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 7</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1528</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40303.</num>
<heading> Content requirements</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Ocean Common Carrier Agreements</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Restrictions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An ocean common carrier agreement may not—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> prohibit or restrict a member of the agreement from engaging in negotiations for a service contract with a shipper;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> require a member of the agreement to disclose a negotiation on a service contract, or the terms of a service contract, other than those terms required to be published under <ref>section 40502(d) of this title</ref>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> adopt mandatory rules or requirements affecting the right of an agreement member to negotiate and enter into a service contract.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Voluntary guidelines</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An ocean common carrier agreement may provide authority to adopt voluntary guidelines relating to the terms and procedures of an agreement member’s service contracts if the guidelines explicitly state the right of members of the agreement not to follow the guidelines. Any guidelines adopted shall be submitted confidentially to the Federal Maritime Commission.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Conference Agreements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each conference agreement must—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> state its purpose;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provide reasonable and equal terms for admission and readmission to conference membership for any ocean common carrier willing to serve the particular trade or route;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> permit any member to withdraw from conference membership on reasonable notice without penalty;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> at the request of any member, require an independent neutral body to police fully the obligations of the conference and its members;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> prohibit the conference from engaging in conduct prohibited by section 41105(1) or (3) of this title;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> provide for a consultation process designed to promote—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> commercial resolution of disputes; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> cooperation with shippers in preventing and eliminating malpractices;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> establish procedures for promptly and fairly considering requests and complaints of shippers; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<chapeau> provide that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any member of the conference may take independent action on a rate or service item on not more than 5 days’ notice to the conference; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> except for an exempt commodity not published in the conference tariff, the conference will include the new rate or service item in its tariff for use by that member, effective no later than 5 days after receipt of the notice, and by any other member that notifies the conference that it elects to adopt the independent rate or service item on or after its effective date, in lieu of the existing conference tariff provision for that rate or service item.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Interconference Agreements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each agreement between carriers not members of the same conference must provide the right of independent action for each carrier. Each agreement between conferences must provide the right of independent action for each conference.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Vessel Sharing Agreements</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An ocean common carrier that is the owner, operator, or bareboat, time, or slot charterer of a liner vessel documented under section 12103 or 12111(c) of this title may agree with an ocean common carrier described in paragraph (2) to which it charters or subcharters the vessel or space on the vessel that the charterer or subcharterer may not use or make available space on the vessel for the carriage of cargo reserved by law for vessels of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Carrier described</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An ocean common carrier described in this paragraph is one that is not the owner, operator, or bareboat charterer for at least one year of liner vessels of the United States that are eligible to be included in the Maritime Security Fleet Program and are enrolled in an Emergency Preparedness Program under chapter 531 of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 7</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1529</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40304.</num>
<heading> Commission action</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice of Filing</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not later than 7 days after the date an agreement is filed, the Federal Maritime Commission shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> transmit a notice of the filing to the Federal Register for publication; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> request interested persons to submit relevant information and documents.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Preliminary Review and Rejection</inline>.—</heading>
<content>After preliminary review, the Commission shall reject an agreement that it finds does not meet the requirements of sections 40302 and 40303 of this title. The Commission shall notify in writing the person filing the agreement of the reason for rejection.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Review and Effective Date</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Unless rejected under subsection (b), an agreement (other than an assessment agreement) is effective—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> on the 45th day after filing, or on the 30th day after notice of the filing is published in the Federal Register, whichever is later; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> if additional information or documents are requested under subsection (d)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> on the 45th day after the Commission receives all the additional information and documents; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> if the request is not fully complied with, on the 45th day after the Commission receives the information and documents submitted and a statement of the reasons for noncompliance with the request.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Request for Additional Information</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Before the expiration of the period specified in subsection (c)(1), the Commission may request from the person filing the agreement any additional information and documents the Commission considers necessary to make the determinations required by this part.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Modification of Review Period</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Shortening</inline>.—</heading>
<content>On request of the party filing an agreement, the Commission may shorten a period specified in subsection (c), but not to a date that is less than 14 days after notice of the filing of the agreement is published in the Federal Register.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Extension</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The period specified in subsection (c)(2) may be extended only by the United States District Court for the District of Columbia in a civil action brought by the Commission under <ref>section 41307(c) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Fixed Terms</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commission may not limit the effectiveness of an agreement to a fixed term.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 7</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1530</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title VII, § 706(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4295</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40305.</num>
<heading> Assessment agreements</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Filing Requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An assessment agreement shall be filed with the Federal Maritime Commission and is effective on filing.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Complaints</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If a complaint is filed with the Commission within 2 years after the date of an assessment agreement, the Commission shall disapprove, cancel, or modify the agreement, or an assessment or charge pursuant to the agreement, that the Commission finds, after notice and opportunity for a hearing, to be unjustly discriminatory or unfair as between carriers, shippers, or ports. The Commission shall issue its final decision in the proceeding within one year after the date the complaint is filed.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Adjustments of Assessments and Charges</inline>.—</heading>
<content>To the extent that the Commission finds under subsection (b) that an assessment or charge is unjustly discriminatory or unfair as between carriers, shippers, or ports, the Commission shall adjust the assessment or charge for the period between the filing of the complaint and the final decision by awarding prospective credits or debits to future assessments and charges. However, if the complainant has ceased activities subject to the assessment or charge, the Commission may award reparations.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 7</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1531</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40306.</num>
<heading> Nondisclosure of information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Information and documents (other than an agreement) filed with the Federal Maritime Commission under this chapter are exempt from disclosure under <ref>section 552 of title 5</ref> and may not be made public except as may be relevant to an administrative or judicial proceeding. This section does not prevent disclosure to either House of Congress or to a duly authorized committee or subcommittee of Congress.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 7</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1531</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40307.</num>
<heading> Exemption from antitrust laws</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The antitrust laws do not apply to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an agreement (including an assessment agreement) that has been filed and is effective under this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an agreement that is exempt under <ref>section 40103 of this title</ref> from any requirement of this part;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> an agreement or activity within the scope of this part, whether permitted under or prohibited by this part, undertaken or entered into with a reasonable basis to conclude that it is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> pursuant to an agreement on file with the Federal Maritime Commission and in effect when the activity takes place; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> exempt under <ref>section 40103 of this title</ref> from any filing or publication requirement of this part;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> an agreement or activity relating to transportation services within or between foreign countries, whether or not via the United States, unless the agreement or activity has a direct, substantial, and reasonably foreseeable effect on the commerce of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> an agreement or activity relating to the foreign inland segment of through transportation that is part of transportation provided in a United States import or export trade;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> an agreement or activity to provide wharfage, dock, warehouse, or other terminal facilities outside the United States; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> an agreement, modification, or cancellation approved before <date date="1984-06-18">June 18, 1984</date>, by the Commission under section 15 of the Shipping Act, 1916, or permitted under section 14b of that Act, and any properly published tariff, rate, fare, or charge, or classification, rule, or regulation explanatory thereof implementing that agreement, modification, or cancellation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exceptions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>This part does not extend antitrust immunity to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an agreement with or among air carriers, rail carriers, motor carriers, tug operators, or common carriers by water not subject to this part relating to transportation within the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a discussion or agreement among common carriers subject to this part relating to the inland divisions (as opposed to the inland portions) of through rates within the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> an agreement among common carriers subject to this part to establish, operate, or maintain a marine terminal in the United States; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> a loyalty contract.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Retroactive Effect of Determinations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A determination by an agency or court that results in the denial or removal of the immunity to the antitrust laws under subsection (a) does not remove or alter the antitrust immunity for the period before the determination.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Relief Under Clayton Act</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A person may not recover damages under section 4 of the Clayton Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 15</ref>), or obtain injunctive relief under section 16 of that Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 26</ref>), for conduct prohibited by this part.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 7</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1531</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title VII, § 709(c)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4297</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>