<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 145—</num>
<heading>REGULATORY MEASUREMENT</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>GENERAL</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 14501.</num>
<heading> Application</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">This chapter applies to the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A vessel not measured under chapter 143 of this title if the application of an international agreement or other law of the United States to the vessel depends on the vessel’s tonnage.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A vessel measured under chapter 143 of this title if the owner requests that the vessel also be measured under this chapter as provided in <ref>section 14305 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–509, title V, § 5101(3)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1923</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–281, title III, § 303(g)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2925</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 14502.</num>
<heading> Measurement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall measure a vessel to which this chapter applies in the way provided by this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–509, title V, § 5101(3)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1923</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 14503.</num>
<heading> Certificate of measurement</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall prescribe the certificate to be issued as evidence of a vessel’s measurement under this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The certificate shall be maintained as required by the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–509, title V, § 5101(3)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1923</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–281, title III, § 303(e)(2)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2925</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 14504.</num>
<heading> Remeasurement</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> To the extent necessary, the Secretary shall remeasure a vessel to which this chapter applies if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Secretary or the owner alleges an error in its measurement;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the vessel or the use of its space is changed in a way that substantially affects its tonnage;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> after being measured under subchapter III of this chapter, the vessel becomes subject to subchapter II of this chapter because the vessel or its use is changed; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> although not required to be measured under subchapter II of this chapter, the vessel was measured under subchapter II and the owner requests that the vessel be measured under subchapter III of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Except as provided in this section and chapter 143 of this title, a vessel that has been measured does not have to be remeasured to obtain another document or endorsement under chapter 121 of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–509, title V, § 5101(3)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1923</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>FORMAL SYSTEMS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 14511.</num>
<heading> Application</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">This subchapter applies to a vessel described in <ref>section 14501 of this title</ref> if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the owner requests; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the vessel is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> self-propelled;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> at least 24 meters (79 feet) overall in length; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> not operated only for pleasure.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–509, title V, § 5101(3)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1924</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 14512.</num>
<heading> Standard tonnage measurement</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall prescribe regulations for measuring the gross and net tonnages of a vessel under this subchapter. The regulations shall provide for tonnages comparable to the tonnages that could have been assigned under sections 4151 and 4153 of the Revised Statutes of the United States, as sections 4151 and 4153 existed immediately before the enactment of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> On application of the owner or master of a vessel of the United States used in foreign trade, the Secretary may attach an appendix to the vessel’s register stating the measurement of spaces that may be deducted from gross tonnage under laws and regulations of other countries but not under those of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–509, title V, § 5101(3)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1924</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 14513.</num>
<heading> Dual tonnage measurement</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> On application by the owner and approval by the Secretary, the tonnage of spaces prescribed by the Secretary may be excluded in measuring under this section the gross tonnage of a vessel measured under <ref>section 14512 of this title</ref>. The spaces prescribed by the Secretary shall be comparable to the spaces that could have been excluded under <ref>section 2 of the Act of September 29, 1965</ref> (<ref>Public Law 89–219</ref>, <ref>79 Stat. 891</ref>), as section 2 existed immediately before the enactment of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall prescribe the design, location, and dimensions of the tonnage mark to be placed on a vessel measured under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> If a vessel is assigned two sets of gross and net tonnages under this section, each certificate stating the vessel’s tonnages shall state the gross and net tonnages when the vessel’s tonnage mark is submerged and when it is not submerged.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraph (1) of this subsection, a certificate stating a vessel’s tonnages may state only one set of gross and net tonnages as assigned under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–509, title V, § 5101(3)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1924</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–281, title III, § 303(h)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2925</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 14514.</num>
<heading> Reciprocity for foreign vessels</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For a foreign vessel not measured under chapter 143, if the Secretary finds that the laws and regulations of a foreign country related to measurement of vessels are substantially similar to those of this chapter and the regulations prescribed under this chapter, the Secretary may accept the measurement and certificate of a vessel of that foreign country as complying with this chapter and the regulations prescribed under this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–281, title III, § 303(i)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2925</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>SIMPLIFIED SYSTEM</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 14521.</num>
<heading> Application</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This subchapter applies to a vessel described in <ref>section 14501 of this title</ref> that is not measured under subchapter II of this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–509, title V, § 5101(3)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1925</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 14522.</num>
<heading> Measurement</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> In this section, “length” means the horizontal distance of the hull between the foremost part of the stem and the aftermost part of the stern, excluding fittings and attachments.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall assign gross and net tonnages to a vessel based on its length, breadth, depth, other dimensions, and appropriate coefficients.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall prescribe the way dimensions (except length) are measured and which coefficients are appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The resulting gross tonnages, taken as a group, reasonably shall reflect the relative internal volumes of the vessels measured under this subchapter. The resulting net tonnages shall be in approximately the same ratios to corresponding gross tonnages as are the net and gross tonnages of comparable vessels measured under subchapter II of this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, the Secretary may determine the gross and net tonnages of a vessel representative of a designated class, model, or type, and then assign those gross and net tonnages to other vessels of the same class, model, or type.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–509, title V, § 5101(3)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1925</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>