<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 5—</num>
<heading>OTHER GENERAL PROVISIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 501.</num>
<heading> Waiver of navigation and vessel-inspection laws</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">On Request of Secretary of Defense.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>On request of the Secretary of Defense, the head of an agency responsible for the administration of the navigation or vessel-inspection laws shall waive compliance with those laws to the extent the Secretary considers necessary in the interest of national defense to address an immediate adverse effect on military operations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Submittal of explanation to congress</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 24 hours after making a request under paragraph (1), the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate a written explanation of the circumstances requiring such a waiver in the interest of national defense, including a confirmation that there are insufficient qualified vessels to meet the needs of national defense without such a waiver.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">By Head of Agency.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Upon a determination by the President that a waiver of the navigation or vessel-inspection laws is necessary in the interest of national defense, the head of an agency responsible for the administration of such laws,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002000">1</ref> may waive compliance with such laws—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> following a determination in accordance with the requirements of paragraph (3) by the Maritime Administrator, acting in the Administrator’s capacity as Director, National Shipping Authority, of the non-availability of qualified United States flag capacity to meet national defense requirements;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> not earlier than 48 hours after a waiver request is published under paragraph (6)(A); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> on a vessel specific basis to the extent, in the manner, and on the terms the head of such agency, in consultation with the Administrator, acting in such capacity, prescribes.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Duration of waiver.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to subparagraphs (B) and (C), a waiver issued under this subsection shall be for a period of not more than 10 days.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Waiver extension</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Upon the termination of the period of a waiver issued under this subsection, the head of an agency may extend the waiver for an additional period of not more than 10 days, if the Maritime Administrator makes the determination referred to in paragraph (1)(A).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Aggregate duration</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The aggregate duration of the period of all waivers and extensions of waivers under this subsection with respect to any one set of events shall not exceed 45 days.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Determinations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Maritime Administrator shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> for each determination referred to in paragraph (1)(A)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> identify any actions that could be taken to enable qualified United States flag capacity to meet national defense requirements prior to the issuance of a waiver; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> not assess the non-availability of qualified United States flag capacity to meet national defense requirements retrospectively after the date on which a waiver is requested;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provide notice of each such determination to the Secretary of Transportation and the head of the agency referred to in paragraph (1) for which the determination is made; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> publish each such determination on the Internet Web site of the Department of Transportation not later than 48 hours after notice of the determination is provided to the Secretary of Transportation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Notice to congress.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The head of an agency referred to in paragraph (1) shall notify the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> of any request for a waiver of the navigation or vessel-inspection laws under this section not later than 48 hours after receiving such a request; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> of the issuance of any such waiver not later than 48 hours after such issuance.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contents</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Such head of an agency shall include in each notification under subparagraph (A)(ii) an explanation of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the reasons the waiver is necessary; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the reasons actions referred to in paragraph (3)(A) are not feasible.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notification required for extensions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of this paragraph, an extension requested or issued under paragraph (2)(B) shall be treated in the same manner as a waiver requested or issued under this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prospective application</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No waiver shall be issued for a vessel if, at the time of the waiver request under this section, such vessel is laden with merchandise that, pursuant to the requested waiver, could be unladen at points or places to which the coastwise laws apply.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Publication requirements.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Publication of waiver requests</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Upon receiving a request for a waiver under this subsection, the head of an agency referred to in paragraph (1) shall publish such request on the website of such agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Publication of waiver denial</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 48 hours after denying a waiver requested under this subsection, the head of an agency referred to in paragraph (1) shall publish on the website of such agency an explanation for denying such waiver, including applicable findings to support the denial.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Report.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not later than 10 days after the date of the conclusion of the voyage of a vessel that, during such voyage, operated under a waiver issued under this section, the owner or operator of the vessel and the individual requesting such waiver (if not the owner or operator of the vessel) shall submit to the Maritime Administrator a report that includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the name and flag of the vessel;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the name of the owner and operator of the vessel;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the dates of the voyage;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> any relevant ports of call;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> a description of the cargo carried;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> an explanation as to why the waiver was in the interest of national defense; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> any other information the Maritime Administrator determines necessary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Publication</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 48 hours after receiving a report under paragraph (1), the Maritime Administrator shall publish such report on an appropriate website of the Department of Transportation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Termination of Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The authority granted by this section shall terminate at such time as the Congress by concurrent resolution or the President may designate.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 4</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1490</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–417, div. C, title XXXV, § 3510</ref>, <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4769</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–213, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="2012-12-20">Dec. 20, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1562</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. C, title XXXV, § 3517(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 2229</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. C, title XXXV, § 3502(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4397</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. C, title XXXV, § 3541</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3093</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 502.</num>
<heading> Cargo exempt from forfeiture</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Cargo on a vessel is exempt from forfeiture under this title if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the cargo is owned in good faith by a person not the owner, master, or crewmember of the vessel; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the customs duties on the cargo have been paid or secured for payment as provided by law.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 4</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1490</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 503.</num>
<heading> Notice of seizure</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">When a forfeiture of a vessel or cargo accrues, the official of the United States Government required to give notice of the seizure of the vessel or cargo shall include in the notice, if they are known to that official, the name and the place of residence of the owner or consignee at the time of the seizure.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 4</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1490</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 504.</num>
<heading> Remission of fees and penalties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Any part of a fee, tax, or penalty paid or a forfeiture incurred under a law or regulation relating to vessels or seamen may be remitted if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> application for the remission is made within one year after the date of the payment or forfeiture; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> it is found that the fee, tax, penalty, or forfeiture was improperly or excessively imposed.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 4</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1491</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 505.</num>
<heading> Penalty for violating regulation or order</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A person convicted of knowingly and willfully violating a regulation or order of the Federal Maritime Commission or the Secretary of Transportation under subtitle IV or V of this title, for which no penalty is expressly provided, shall be fined not more than $500. Each day of a continuing violation is a separate offense.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 4</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1491</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>