<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 45—</num>
<heading>UNINSPECTED COMMERCIAL FISHING INDUSTRY VESSELS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4501.</num>
<heading> Application</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> This chapter applies to an uninspected vessel which is a fishing vessel, fish processing vessel, or fish tender vessel.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> This chapter does not apply to the carriage of bulk dangerous cargoes regulated under chapter 37 of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 98–364, title IV, § 402(7)(C)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-17">July 17, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 446</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–424, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-09">Sept. 9, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1585</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4502.</num>
<heading> Safety standards</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary shall prescribe regulations which require that each vessel to which this chapter applies shall be equipped with—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> readily accessible fire extinguishers capable of promptly and effectively extinguishing a flammable or combustible liquid fuel fire;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> at least one readily accessible life preserver or other lifesaving device for each individual on board;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> an efficient flame arrestor, backfire trap, or other similar device on the carburetors of each inboard engine which uses gasoline as fuel;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the means to properly and efficiently ventilate enclosed spaces, including engine and fuel tank compartments, so as to remove explosive or flammable gases;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> visual distress signals;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> other equipment required to minimize the risk of injury to the crew during vessel operations, if the Secretary determines that a risk of serious injury exists that can be eliminated or mitigated by that equipment; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> a placard as required by regulations prescribed under <ref>section 10603(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> In addition to the requirements of subsection (a) of this section, the Secretary shall prescribe regulations requiring the installation, maintenance, and use of the equipment in paragraph (2) of this subsection for vessels to which this chapter applies that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> operate beyond 3 nautical miles from the baseline from which the territorial sea of the United States is measured or beyond 3 nautical miles from the coastline of the Great Lakes;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> operate with more than 16 individuals on board; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> in the case of a fish tender vessel, engage in the Aleutian trade.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The equipment to be required is as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> alerting and locating equipment, including emergency position indicating radio beacons;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> subject to paragraph (3), a survival craft that ensures that no part of an individual is immersed in water sufficient to accommodate all individuals on board;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> at least one readily accessible immersion suit for each individual on board that vessel when operating on the waters described in <ref>section 3102 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> marine radio communications equipment sufficient to effectively communicate with land-based search and rescue facilities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> navigation equipment, including compasses, nautical charts, and publications;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> first aid equipment and medical supplies sufficient for the size and area of operation of the vessel; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> ground tackle sufficient for the vessel.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> Except for a nonapplicable vessel, an auxiliary craft shall satisfy the equipment requirement under paragraph (2)(B) if such craft is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> necessary for normal fishing operations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> readily accessible during an emergency; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> capable, in accordance with the Coast Guard capacity rating, when applicable, of safely holding all individuals on board the vessel to which the craft functions as an auxiliary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> In addition to the requirements described in subsections (a) and (b) of this section, the Secretary may prescribe regulations establishing the standards in paragraph (2) of this subsection for vessels to which this chapter applies that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> were built after <date date="1988-12-31">December 31, 1988</date>, or undergo a major conversion completed after that date; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> operate with more than 16 individuals on board; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of a fish tender vessel, engage in the Aleutian trade.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The standards shall be minimum safety standards, including standards relating to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> navigation equipment, including radars and fathometers;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> lifesaving equipment, immersion suits, signaling devices, bilge pumps, bilge alarms, life rails, and grab rails;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> fire protection and firefighting equipment, including fire alarms and portable and semiportable fire extinguishing equipment;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> use and installation of insulation material;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> storage methods for flammable or combustible material; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> fuel, ventilation, and electrical systems.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary shall prescribe regulations for the operating stability of a vessel to which this chapter applies—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> that was built after <date date="1989-12-31">December 31, 1989</date>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the physical characteristics of which are substantially altered after <date date="1989-12-31">December 31, 1989</date>, in a manner that affects the vessel’s operating stability.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary may accept, as evidence of compliance with this subsection, a certification of compliance issued by the person providing insurance for the vessel or by another qualified person approved by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<chapeau> In prescribing regulations under this chapter, the Secretary—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall consider the specialized nature and economics of the operations and the character, design, and construction of the vessel; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> may not require the alteration of a vessel or associated equipment that was constructed or manufactured before the effective date of the regulation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<chapeau> To ensure compliance with the requirements of this chapter, the Secretary—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall require the individual in charge of a vessel described in subsection (b) to keep a record of equipment maintenance, and required instruction and drills;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> shall examine at dockside a vessel described in subsection (b) at least once every 5 years, but may require an exam at dockside every 2 years for vessels described in subsection (b) if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> requested by an owner or operator; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> the vessel is—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> at least 50 feet overall in length;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> built before <date date="2013-07-01">July 1, 2013</date>; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> 25 years of age or older; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> shall issue a certificate of compliance to a vessel meeting the requirements of this chapter and satisfying the requirements in paragraph (2).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The individual in charge of a vessel described in subsection (b) must pass a training program approved by the Secretary that meets the requirements in paragraph (2) of this subsection and hold a valid certificate issued under that program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The training program shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> be based on professional knowledge and skill obtained through sea service and hands-on training, including training in seamanship, stability, collision prevention, navigation, fire fighting and prevention, damage control, personal survival, emergency medical care, emergency drills, and weather;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> require an individual to demonstrate ability to communicate in an emergency situation and understand information found in navigation publications;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> recognize and give credit for recent past experience in fishing vessel operation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> provide for issuance of a certificate to an individual that has successfully completed the program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall prescribe regulations implementing this subsection. The regulations shall require that individuals who are issued a certificate under paragraph (2)(D) must complete refresher training at least once every 5 years as a condition of maintaining the validity of the certificate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall establish an electronic database listing the names of individuals who have participated in and received a certificate confirming successful completion of a training program approved by the Secretary under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<chapeau> A vessel to which this chapter applies shall be constructed in a manner that provides a level of safety equivalent to the minimum safety standards the Secretary may establish for recreational vessels under section 4302, if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> subsection (b) of this section applies to the vessel;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the vessel is less than 50 feet overall in length; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the vessel is built after <date date="2010-01-01">January 1, 2010</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall establish a Fishing Safety Training Grants Program to provide funding to municipalities, port authorities, other appropriate public entities, not-for-profit organizations, and other qualified persons that provide commercial fishing safety training—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> to conduct fishing vessel safety training for vessel operators and crewmembers that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> in the case of vessel operators, meets the requirements of subsection (g); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in the case of crewmembers, meets the requirements of subsection (g)(2)(A), such requirements of subsection (g)(2)(B) as are appropriate for crewmembers, and the requirements of subsections (g)(2)(D), (g)(3), and (g)(4); and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for purchase of safety equipment and training aids for use in those fishing vessel safety training programs.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Health and Human Services, in consultation with and based on criteria established by the Commandant of the Coast Guard <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002005">1</ref> shall award grants under this subsection on a competitive basis.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Federal share of the cost of any activity carried out with a grant under this subsection shall not exceed 75 percent.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> There is authorized to be appropriated $3,000,000 for fiscal year 2023 for grants under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall establish a Fishing Safety Research Grant Program to provide funding to individuals in academia, members of non-profit organizations and businesses involved in fishing and maritime matters, and other persons with expertise in fishing safety, to conduct research on methods of improving the safety of the commercial fishing industry, including vessel design, emergency and survival equipment, enhancement of vessel monitoring systems, communications devices, de-icing technology, and severe weather detection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Health and Human Services, in consultation with and based on criteria established by the Commandant of the Coast Guard, shall award grants under this subsection on a competitive basis.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Federal share of the cost of any activity carried out with a grant under this subsection shall not exceed 75 percent.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> There is authorized to be appropriated $3,000,000 for fiscal year 2023 for activities under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(k)</num>
<content> For the purposes of this section, the term “auxiliary craft” means a vessel that is carried onboard a fishing vessel and is normally used to support fishing operations.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 98–364, title IV, § 402(7)(C)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-17">July 17, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 447</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–557, § 33(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2876</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–424, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-09">Sept. 9, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1585</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–595, title VI, § 602(c)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 2990</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–324, title III, § 307</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3918</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–383, title III, § 301(b)(5)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3417</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–281, title VI, § 604(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2962</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–213, title III, § 305(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2012-12-20">Dec. 20, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1564</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–281, title III, § 309</ref>, <date date="2014-12-18">Dec. 18, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3045</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title V</ref>, §§ 504–506, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4271</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXIII</ref> [LXXXIII], § 8321(a), (b), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4701</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. K, title CXIII, § 11328(a)</ref>, title CXV, § 11509(a)(1), <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4098</ref>, 4137.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4503.</num>
<heading> Fishing, fish tender, and fish processing vessel certification</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> A vessel to which this subsection applies may not be operated unless the vessel—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> meets all survey and classification requirements prescribed by the American Bureau of Shipping or another similarly qualified organization approved by the Secretary; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> has on board a certificate issued by the American Bureau of Shipping or that other organization evidencing compliance with this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Subsection (a) applies to a fish processing vessel to which this chapter applies that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> is built after <date date="1990-07-27">July 27, 1990</date>; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> undergoes a major conversion completed after that date.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraph (2), subsection (a) applies to a vessel to which <ref>section 4502(b) of this title</ref> applies that is at least 50 feet overall in length and is built after <date date="2013-07-01">July 1, 2013</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Subsection (a) does not apply to a fishing vessel or fish tender vessel to which <ref>section 4502(b) of this title</ref> applies, if the vessel—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is at least 50 feet overall in length, and not more than 180 feet overall in length as listed on the vessel’s certificate of documentation or certificate of number; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is built after the date of the enactment of the Coast Guard Authorization Act of 2016; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> complies with—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the requirements described in subsection (d); or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the alternative requirements established by the Secretary under subsection (e).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> The requirements referred to in subsection (c)(2)(B)(ii)(I) are the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The vessel is designed by an individual licensed by a State as a naval architect or marine engineer, and the design incorporates standards equivalent to those prescribed by a classification society to which the Secretary has delegated authority under section 3316 or another qualified organization approved by the Secretary for purposes of this paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Construction of the vessel is overseen and certified as being in accordance with its design by a marine surveyor of an organization accepted by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The vessel—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> completes a stability test performed by a qualified individual;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> has written stability and loading instructions from a qualified individual that are provided to the owner or operator; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> has an assigned loading mark.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The vessel is not substantially altered without the review and approval of an individual licensed by a State as a naval architect or marine engineer before the beginning of such substantial alteration.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The vessel undergoes a condition survey at least twice in 5 years, not to exceed 3 years between surveys, to the satisfaction of a marine surveyor of an organization accepted by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The vessel undergoes an out-of-water survey at least once every 5 years to the satisfaction of a certified marine surveyor of an organization accepted by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Once every 5 years and at the time of a substantial alteration to such vessel, compliance of the vessel with the requirements of paragraph (3) is reviewed and updated as necessary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> For the life of the vessel, the owner of the vessel maintains records to demonstrate compliance with this subsection and makes such records readily available for inspection by an official authorized to enforce this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Not later than 10 years after the date of the enactment of the Coast Guard Authorization Act of 2016, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report that provides an analysis of the adequacy of the requirements under subsection (d) in maintaining the safety of the fishing vessels and fish tender vessels which are described in subsection (c)(2) and which comply with the requirements of subsection (d).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If the report required under this subsection includes a determination that the safety requirements under subsection (d) are not adequate or that additional safety measures are necessary, then the Secretary may establish an alternative safety compliance program for fishing vessels or fish tender vessels (or both) which are described in subsection (c)(2) and which comply with the requirements of subsection (d).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The alternative safety compliance program established under this subsection shall include requirements for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> vessel construction;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a vessel stability test;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> vessel stability and loading instructions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> an assigned vessel loading mark;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> a vessel condition survey at least twice in 5 years, not to exceed 3 years between surveys;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> an out-of-water vessel survey at least once every 5 years;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> maintenance of records to demonstrate compliance with the program, and the availability of such records for inspection; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> such other aspects of vessel safety as the Secretary considers appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of this section and section 4503a, the term “built” means, with respect to a vessel, that the vessel’s construction has reached any of the following stages:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The vessel’s keel is laid.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Construction identifiable with the vessel has begun and assembly of that vessel has commenced comprising of at least 50 metric tons or one percent of the estimated mass of all structural material, whichever is less.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In the case of a vessel greater than 79 feet overall in length, for purposes of paragraph (1)(A) a keel is deemed to be laid when a marine surveyor affirms that a structure adequate for serving as a keel for such vessel is in place and identified for use in the construction of such vessel.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 98–364, title IV, § 402(7)(C)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-17">July 17, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 447</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–557, § 33(b)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2876</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–424, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-09">Sept. 9, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1587</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–281, title VI, § 604(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2966</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–213, title III, § 305(c)</ref>, <date date="2012-12-20">Dec. 20, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1564</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–120, title III, § 318(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-02-08">Feb. 8, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 63</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. C, title XXXV, § 3503(a)</ref>, (b)(2), <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2775</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title V</ref>, §§ 507, 508(a), (b), <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4272</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. K, title CXV, § 11509(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4137</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 4503a.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. K, title CXV, § 11509(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4137</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4504.</num>
<heading> Prohibited acts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A person may not operate a vessel in violation of this chapter or a regulation prescribed under this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 98–364, title IV, § 402(7)(C)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-17">July 17, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 447</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–424, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-09">Sept. 9, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1587</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4505.</num>
<heading> Termination of unsafe operations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">An official authorized to enforce this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> may direct the individual in charge of a vessel to which this chapter applies to immediately take reasonable steps necessary for the safety of individuals on board the vessel if the official observes the vessel being operated in an unsafe condition that the official believes creates an especially hazardous condition, including ordering the individual in charge to return the vessel to a mooring and to remain there until the situation creating the hazard is corrected or ended; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> may order the individual in charge of an uninspected fish processing vessel that does not have on board the certificate required under <ref>section 4503(a)(2) of this title</ref> to return the vessel to a mooring and to remain there until the vessel is in compliance with that section, except that this paragraph shall not apply with respect to a vessel to which section 4503a <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002006">1</ref> applies.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–424, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-09">Sept. 9, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1587</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title V, § 509</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4274</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4506.</num>
<heading> Exemptions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary may exempt a vessel from any part of this chapter if, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary (including regulations on special operating conditions), the Secretary finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> good cause exists for granting an exemption; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the safety of the vessel and those on board will not be adversely affected.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–424, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-09">Sept. 9, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1587</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–587, title V, § 5222</ref>, <date date="1992-11-04">Nov. 4, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 5081</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–383, title III, § 301(b)(6)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3417</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–281, title VI, § 604(b)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2964</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–120, title III, § 306(a)(5)</ref>, <date date="2016-02-08">Feb. 8, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 54</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4507.</num>
<heading> Penalties</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The owner, charterer, managing operator, agent, master, and individual in charge of a vessel to which this chapter applies which is operated in violation of this chapter or a regulation prescribed under this chapter may each be assessed a civil penalty by the Secretary of not more than $5,000. Any vessel with respect to which a penalty is assessed under this subsection is liable in rem for the penalty.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> A person willfully violating this chapter or a regulation prescribed under this chapter shall be fined not more than $5,000, imprisoned for not more than one year, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–424, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-09">Sept. 9, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1588</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 4508.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title VI, § 601(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4289</ref>]</heading>
</section>
</chapter>