<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 71—</num>
<heading>LICENSES AND CERTIFICATES OF REGISTRY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7101.</num>
<heading> Issuing and classifying licenses and certificates of registry</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Licenses and certificates of registry are established for individuals who are required to hold licenses or certificates under this subtitle.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, the Secretary—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> issues the licenses and certificates of registry; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> may classify the licenses and certificates of registry as provided in subsections (c) and (f) of this section, based on—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the tonnage, means of propulsion, and horsepower of machine-propelled vessels;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the waters on which vessels are to be operated; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> other reasonable standards.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary may issue licenses in the following classes to applicants found qualified as to age, character, habits of life, experience, professional qualifications, and physical fitness:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> masters, mates, and engineers.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> pilots.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> operators.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> radio officers.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> In classifying individuals under subsection (c)(1) of this section, the Secretary shall establish, when possible, suitable career patterns and service and other qualifying requirements appropriate to the particular service or industry in which the individuals are engaged.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<chapeau> An individual may be issued a license under subsection (c)(2) of this section only if the applicant—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> is at least 21 years of age;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> is of sound health and has no physical limitations that would hinder or prevent the performance of a pilot’s duties;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> has a thorough physical examination each year while holding the license, except that this requirement does not apply to an individual who will serve as a pilot only on a vessel of less than 1,600 gross tons as measured under <ref>section 14502 of this title</ref>, or an alternate tonnage measured under <ref>section 14302 of this title</ref> as prescribed by the Secretary under <ref>section 14104 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> demonstrates, to the satisfaction of the Secretary, that the applicant has the requisite general knowledge and skill to hold the license;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> demonstrates proficiency in the use of electronic aids to navigation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> maintains adequate knowledge of the waters to be navigated and knowledge of regulations for the prevention of collisions in those waters;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> has sufficient experience, as decided by the Secretary, to evidence ability to handle any vessel of the type and size which the applicant may be authorized to pilot; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> meets any other requirement the Secretary considers reasonable and necessary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary may issue certificates of registry in the following classes to applicants found qualified as to character, knowledge, skill, and experience:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> pursers.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> medical doctors.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> professional nurses.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> The Secretary may not issue a license or certificate of registry under this section unless an individual applying for the license or certificate makes available to the Secretary, under section 206(b)(7) of the National Driver Register Act of 1982 (<ref>23 U.S.C. 401</ref> note), any information contained in the National Driver Register related to an offense described in section 205(a)(3)(A) or (B) of that Act committed by the individual.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<content> The Secretary may review the criminal record of an individual who applies for a license or certificate of registry under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall require the testing of an individual who applies for issuance or renewal of a license or certificate of registry under this chapter for use of a dangerous drug in violation of law or Federal regulation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary may issue a license under this section in a class under subsection (c) to an applicant that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> has at least 3 months of qualifying service on vessels of the uniformed services (as that term is defined in <ref>section 101(a) of title 10</ref>) of appropriate tonnage or horsepower within the 7-year period immediately preceding the date of application; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> satisfies all other requirements for such a license.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 539</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–557, § 29(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2873</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–380, title IV, § 4101(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-08-18">Aug. 18, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 509</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–324, title VII, § 720</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3938</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–281, title III, § 305(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-18">Dec. 18, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3043</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7102.</num>
<heading> Citizenship</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Licenses and certificates of registry for individuals on documented vessels may be issued only to citizens of the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 540</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7103.</num>
<heading> Licenses for radio officers</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> A license as radio officer may be issued only to an applicant who has a first-class or second-class radiotelegraph operator license issued by the Federal Communications Commission.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Except as provided in <ref>section 7318 of this title</ref>, this part does not affect the status of radiotelegraph operators serving on board vessels operating only on the Great Lakes.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 540</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7104.</num>
<heading> Certificates for medical doctors and nurses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A certificate of registry as a medical doctor or professional nurse may be issued only to an applicant who has a license as a medical doctor or registered nurse, respectively, issued by a State.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 540</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7105.</num>
<heading> Oaths</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An applicant for a license or certificate of registry shall take, before the issuance of the license or certificate, an oath, without concealment or reservation, that the applicant will perform faithfully and honestly, according to the best skill and judgment of the applicant, all the duties required by law.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 540</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–281, title VI, § 613</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2970</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7106.</num>
<heading> Duration of licenses</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A license issued under this part is valid for a 5-year period and may be renewed for additional 5-year periods; except that the validity of a license issued to a radio officer is conditioned on the continuous possession by the holder of a first-class or second-class radiotelegraph operator license issued by the Federal Communications Commission.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Advance Renewals</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A renewed license issued under this part may be issued up to 8 months in advance but is not effective until the date that the previously issued license expires or until the completion of any active suspension or revocation of that previously issued license, whichever is later.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 540</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–380, title IV, § 4102(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-08-18">Aug. 18, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 509</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–281, title VI, § 614(b)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2970</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title V, § 510(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4274</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7107.</num>
<heading> Duration of certificates of registry</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A certificate of registry issued under this part is valid for a 5-year period and may be renewed for additional 5-year periods; except that the validity of a certificate issued to a medical doctor or professional nurse is conditioned on the continuous possession by the holder of a license as a medical doctor or registered nurse, respectively, issued by a State.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Advance Renewals</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A renewed certificate of registry issued under this part may be issued up to 8 months in advance but is not effective until the date that the previously issued certificate of registry expires or until the completion of any active suspension or revocation of that previously issued certificate of registry, whichever is later.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 540</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–380, title IV, § 4102(b)</ref>, <date date="1990-08-18">Aug. 18, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 509</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–281, title VI, § 614(c)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2971</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title V, § 510(2)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4274</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7108.</num>
<heading> Termination of licenses and certificates of registry</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">When the holder of a license or certificate of registry, the duration of which is conditioned under section 7106 or 7107 of this title, fails to hold the license required as a condition, the license or certificate of registry issued under this part is terminated.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 540</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7109.</num>
<heading> Review of criminal records</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may review the criminal record of each holder of a license or certificate of registry issued under this part who applies for renewal of that license or certificate of registry.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 540</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–380, title IV, § 4102(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-08-18">Aug. 18, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 510</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7110.</num>
<heading> Exhibiting licenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each holder of a license issued under this part shall display, within 48 hours after employment on a vessel for which that license is required, the license in a conspicuous place on the vessel.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 541</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7111.</num>
<heading> Oral examinations for licenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An individual may take an oral examination for a license to serve on a fishing, fish processing, or fish tender vessel not required to be inspected under part B of this subtitle.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 541</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–364, title IV, § 402(8)(B)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-17">July 17, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 447</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–307, § 1(10)</ref>, <date date="1986-05-19">May 19, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 445</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7112.</num>
<heading> Licenses of masters or mates as pilots</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A master or mate licensed under this part who also qualifies as a pilot is not required to hold 2 licenses. Instead, the qualification of the master or mate as pilot shall be endorsed on the master’s or mate’s license.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 541</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7113.</num>
<heading> Exemption from draft</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A licensed master, mate, pilot, or engineer of a vessel inspected under part B of this subtitle, propelled by machinery or carrying hazardous liquid cargoes in bulk, is not liable to draft in time of war, except for performing duties authorized by the license. When performing those duties in the service of the United States Government, the master, mate, pilot, or engineer is entitled to the highest rate of wages paid in the merchant marine of the United States for similar services. If killed or wounded when performing those duties, the master, mate, pilot, or engineer, or the heirs or legal representatives of the master, mate, pilot, or engineer, are entitled to all the privileges under the pension laws of the United States provided to members of the Armed Forces.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 541</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7114.</num>
<heading> Fees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may prescribe by regulation reasonable fees for the inspection of and the issuance of a certificate, license, or permit related to small passenger vessels and sailing school vessels.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 541</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 7115.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title VI, § 601(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4289</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7116.</num>
<heading> Examinations for merchant mariner credentials</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirement for Sample Exams</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall develop a sample merchant mariner credential examination and outline of merchant mariner examination topics on an annual basis.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Public Availability</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each sample examination and outline of topics developed under subsection (a) shall be readily available to the public.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Merchant Mariner Credential Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “merchant mariner credential” has the meaning that term has in section 7510.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–120, title III, § 315(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2016-02-08">Feb. 8, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 62</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>