<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 109—</num>
<heading>ANIMAL HEALTH PROTECTION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 8301.</num>
<heading> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Congress finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the prevention, detection, control, and eradication of diseases and pests of animals are essential to protect—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> animal health;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the health and welfare of the people of the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the economic interests of the livestock and related industries of the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the environment of the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> interstate commerce and foreign commerce of the United States in animals and other articles;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> animal diseases and pests are primarily transmitted by animals and articles regulated under this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the health of animals is affected by the methods by which animals and articles are transported in interstate commerce and foreign commerce;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the Secretary must continue to conduct research on animal diseases and pests that constitute a threat to the livestock of the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> all animals and articles regulated under this chapter are in or affect interstate commerce or foreign commerce; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> regulation by the Secretary and cooperation by the Secretary with foreign countries, States or other jurisdictions, or persons are necessary—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> to prevent and eliminate burdens on interstate commerce and foreign commerce;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> to regulate effectively interstate commerce and foreign commerce; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> to protect the agriculture, environment, economy, and health and welfare of the people of the United States.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–171, title X, § 10402</ref>, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 494</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8302.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Animal</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “animal” means any member of the animal kingdom (except a human).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Article</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “article” means any pest or disease or any material or tangible object that could harbor a pest or disease.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disease</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “disease” has the meaning given the term by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Enter</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “enter” means to move into the commerce of the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Export</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “export” means to move from a place within the territorial limits of the United States to a place outside the territorial limits of the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Facility</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “facility” means any structure.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Import</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “import” means to move from a place outside the territorial limits of the United States to a place within the territorial limits of the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Indian tribe</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Indian tribe” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 5304 of title 25</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interstate commerce</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “interstate commerce” means trade, traffic, or other commerce—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> between a place in a State and a place in another State, or between places within the same State but through any place outside that State; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> within the District of Columbia or any territory or possession of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(10)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Livestock</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “livestock” means all farm-raised animals.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(11)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Means of conveyance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “means of conveyance” means any personal property used for or intended for use for the movement of any other personal property.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(12)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Move</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “move” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to carry, enter, import, mail, ship, or transport;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to aid, abet, cause, or induce carrying, entering, importing, mailing, shipping, or transporting;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to offer to carry, enter, import, mail, ship, or transport;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> to receive in order to carry, enter, import, mail, ship, or transport;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> to release into the environment; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> to allow any of the activities described in this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(13)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Pest</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “pest” means any of the following that can directly or indirectly injure, cause damage to, or cause disease in livestock:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A protozoan.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A plant.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> A bacteria.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> A fungus.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> A virus or viroid.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> An infectious agent or other pathogen.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> An arthropod.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> A parasite.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> A prion.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> A vector.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> Any organism similar to or allied with any of the organisms described in this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(14)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Agriculture.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(15)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “State” means any of the States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, the Virgin Islands of the United States, or any territory or possession of the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(16)</num>
<heading class="bold"> This chapter</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except when used in this section, the term “this chapter” includes any regulation or order issued by the Secretary under the authority of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(17)</num>
<heading class="bold"> United States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “United States” means all of the States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(18)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Veterinary countermeasure</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “veterinary countermeasure” means any biological product (including an animal vaccine or diagnostic), pharmaceutical product (including a therapeutic), non-pharmaceutical product (including a disinfectant), or other product or equipment to prevent, detect, respond to, or mitigate harm to public or animal health resulting from, animal pests or diseases.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–171, title X, § 10403</ref>, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 494</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title XII, § 12101(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4937</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–328, div. HH, title V, § 603</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 5996</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8303.</num>
<heading> Restriction on importation or entry</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">With notice to the Secretary of the Treasury and public notice as soon as practicable, the Secretary may prohibit or restrict—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the importation or entry of any animal, article, or means of conveyance, or use of any means of conveyance or facility, if the Secretary determines that the prohibition or restriction is necessary to prevent the introduction into or dissemination within the United States of any pest or disease of livestock;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the further movement of any animal that has strayed into the United States if the Secretary determines that the prohibition or restriction is necessary to prevent the introduction into or dissemination within the United States of any pest or disease of livestock; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the use of any means of conveyance in connection with the importation or entry of livestock if the Secretary determines that the prohibition or restriction is necessary because the means of conveyance has not been maintained in a clean and sanitary condition or does not have accommodations for the safe and proper movement of livestock.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Restrictions on import and entry</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may issue such orders and promulgate such regulations as are necessary to carry out subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Post importation quarantine</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may promulgate regulations requiring that any animal imported or entered be raised or handled under post-importation quarantine conditions by or under the supervision of the Secretary for the purpose of determining whether the animal is or may be affected by any pest or disease of livestock.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Destruction or removal</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary may order the destruction or removal from the United States of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any animal, article, or means of conveyance that has been imported but has not entered the United States if the Secretary determines that destruction or removal from the United States is necessary to prevent the introduction into or dissemination within the United States of any pest or disease of livestock;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any animal or progeny of any animal, article, or means of conveyance that has been imported or entered in violation of this chapter; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any animal that has strayed into the United States if the Secretary determines that destruction or removal from the United States is necessary to prevent the introduction into or dissemination within the United States of any pest or disease of livestock.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements of owners</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Orders to disinfect</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Secretary may require the disinfection of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a means of conveyance used in connection with the importation of an animal;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> an individual involved in the importation of an animal and personal articles of the individual; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> any article used in the importation of an animal.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Failure to comply with orders</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">If an owner fails to comply with an order of the Secretary under this section, the Secretary may—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> take remedial action, destroy, or remove from the United States the animal or progeny of any animal, article, or means of conveyance as authorized under paragraph (1); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> recover from the owner the costs of any care, handling, disposal, or other action incurred by the Secretary in connection with the remedial action, destruction, or removal.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–171, title X, § 10404</ref>, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 496</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8304.</num>
<heading> Exportation</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary may prohibit or restrict—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the exportation of any animal, article, or means of conveyance if the Secretary determines that the prohibition or restriction is necessary to prevent the dissemination from or within the United States of any pest or disease of livestock;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the exportation of any livestock if the Secretary determines that the livestock is unfit to be moved;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the use of any means of conveyance or facility in connection with the exportation of any animal or article if the Secretary determines that the prohibition or restriction is necessary to prevent the dissemination from or within the United States of any pest or disease of livestock; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the use of any means of conveyance in connection with the exportation of livestock if the Secretary determines that the prohibition or restriction is necessary because the means of conveyance has not been maintained in a clean and sanitary condition or does not have accommodations for the safe and proper movement and humane treatment of livestock.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements of owners</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Orders to disinfect</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary may require the disinfection of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a means of conveyance used in connection with the exportation of an animal;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an individual involved in the exportation of an animal and personal articles of the individual; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any article used in the exportation of an animal.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Failure to comply with orders</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">If an owner fails to comply with an order of the Secretary under this section, the Secretary may—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> take remedial action with respect to the animal, article, or means of conveyance referred to in paragraph (1); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> recover from the owner the costs of any care, handling, disposal, or other action incurred by the Secretary in connection with the remedial action.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may certify the classification, quality, quantity, condition, processing, handling, or storage of any animal or article intended for export.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">There is authorized to be appropriated—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> $1,500,000 for each of fiscal years 2008 through 2018 to carry out section 11010 of the Food, Conservation, and Energy Act of 2008; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 2008 through 2018 to carry out this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Funds appropriated under paragraph (1) shall remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–171, title X, § 10405</ref>, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 497</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title XI, § 11010(c)</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1360</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title XI, § 11010(c), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2121; <ref>Pub. L. 113–79, title XII, § 12101(c)</ref>, <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 978</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8305.</num>
<heading> Interstate movement</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary may prohibit or restrict—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the movement in interstate commerce of any animal, article, or means of conveyance if the Secretary determines that the prohibition or restriction is necessary to prevent the introduction or dissemination of any pest or disease of livestock; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the use of any means of conveyance or facility in connection with the movement in interstate commerce of any animal or article if the Secretary determines that the prohibition or restriction is necessary to prevent the introduction or dissemination of any pest or disease of livestock.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–171, title X, § 10406</ref>, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 498</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8306.</num>
<heading> Seizure, quarantine, and disposal</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary may hold, seize, quarantine, treat, destroy, dispose of, or take other remedial action with respect to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> any animal or progeny of any animal, article, or means of conveyance that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is moving or has been moved in interstate commerce or has been imported and entered; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Secretary has reason to believe may carry, may have carried, or may have been affected with or exposed to any pest or disease of livestock at the time of movement or that is otherwise in violation of this chapter;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any animal or progeny of any animal, article, or means of conveyance that is moving or is being handled, or has moved or has been handled, in interstate commerce in violation of this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> any animal or progeny of any animal, article, or means of conveyance that has been imported, and is moving or is being handled or has moved or has been handled, in violation of this chapter; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> any animal or progeny of any animal, article, or means of conveyance that the Secretary finds is not being maintained, or has not been maintained, in accordance with any post-importation quarantine, post-importation condition, post-movement quarantine, or post-movement condition in accordance with this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Extraordinary emergencies</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Subject to paragraph (2), if the Secretary determines that an extraordinary emergency exists because of the presence in the United States of a pest or disease of livestock and that the presence of the pest or disease threatens the livestock of the United States, the Secretary may—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> hold, seize, treat, apply other remedial actions to, destroy (including preventative slaughter), or otherwise dispose of, any animal, article, facility, or means of conveyance if the Secretary determines the action is necessary to prevent the dissemination of the pest or disease; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> prohibit or restrict the movement or use within a State, or any portion of a State of any animal or article, means of conveyance, or facility if the Secretary determines that the prohibition or restriction is necessary to prevent the dissemination of the pest or disease.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State action</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Secretary may take action in a State under this subsection only on finding that measures being taken by the State are inadequate to control or eradicate the pest or disease, after review and consultation with—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>“(i)</num>
<content> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002357">1</ref> the Governor or an appropriate animal health official of the State; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>“(ii)</num>
<content> <sup>1</sup> in the case of any animal, article, facility, or means of conveyance under the jurisdiction of an Indian tribe, the head of the Indian tribe.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Subject to subparagraph (C), before any action is taken in a State under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> notify the Governor, an appropriate animal health official of the State, or head of the Indian tribe of the proposed action;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> issue a public announcement of the proposed action; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> publish in the Federal Register—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the findings of the Secretary;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> a description of the proposed action; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> a statement of the reasons for the proposed action.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice after action</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">If it is not practicable to publish in the Federal Register the information required under subparagraph (B)(iii) before taking action under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall publish the information as soon as practicable, but not later than 10 business days, after commencement of the action.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Quarantine, disposal, or other remedial action</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary, in writing, may order the owner of any animal, article, facility, or means of conveyance referred to in subsection (a) or (b) to maintain in quarantine, dispose of, or take other remedial action with respect to the animal, article, facility, or means of conveyance, in a manner determined by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Failure to comply with orders</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">If the owner fails to comply with the order of the Secretary, the Secretary may—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> seize, quarantine, dispose of, or take other remedial action with respect to the animal, article, facility, or means of conveyance under subsection (a) or (b); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> recover from the owner the costs of any care, handling, disposal, or other remedial action incurred by the Secretary in connection with the seizure, quarantine, disposal, or other remedial action.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (3), the Secretary shall compensate the owner of any animal, article, facility, or means of conveyance that the Secretary requires to be destroyed under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amount</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Subject to subparagraphs (B) and (C), the compensation shall be based on the fair market value, as determined by the Secretary, of the destroyed animal, article, facility, or means of conveyance.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Compensation paid any owner under this subsection shall not exceed the difference between—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the fair market value of the destroyed animal, article, facility, or means of conveyance; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any compensation received by the owner from a State or other source for the destroyed animal, article, facility, or means of conveyance.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reviewability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The determination by the Secretary of the amount to be paid under this subsection shall be final and not subject to judicial review or review by any officer or employee of the Federal Government other than the Secretary or the designee of the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">No payment shall be made by the Secretary under this subsection for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any animal, article, facility, or means of conveyance that has been moved or handled by the owner in violation of an agreement for the control and eradication of diseases or pests or in violation of this chapter;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any progeny of any animal or article, which animal or article has been moved or handled by the owner of the animal or article in violation of this chapter;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any animal, article, or means of conveyance that is refused entry under this chapter; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> any animal, article, facility, or means of conveyance that becomes or has become affected with or exposed to any pest or disease of livestock because of a violation of an agreement for the control and eradication of diseases or pests or a violation of this chapter by the owner.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–171, title X, § 10407</ref>, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 498</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title XI, § 11011(1)</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1360</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title XI, § 11011(1), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2121.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8307.</num>
<heading> Inspections, seizures, and warrants</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Guidelines</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The activities authorized by this section shall be carried out consistent with guidelines approved by the Attorney General.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Warrantless inspections</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary may stop and inspect, without a warrant, any person or means of conveyance moving—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> into the United States, to determine whether the person or means of conveyance is carrying any animal or article regulated under this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in interstate commerce, on probable cause to believe that the person or means of conveyance is carrying any animal or article regulated under this chapter; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> in intrastate commerce from any State, or any portion of a State, quarantined under <ref>section 8306(b) of this title</ref>, on probable cause to believe that the person or means of conveyance is carrying any animal or article quarantined under <ref>section 8306(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inspections with warrants</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may enter, with a warrant, any premises in the United States for the purpose of making inspections and seizures under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application and issuance of warrants</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">On proper oath or affirmation showing probable cause to believe that there is on certain premises any animal, article, facility, or means of conveyance regulated under this chapter, a United States judge, a judge of a court of record in the United States, or a United States magistrate judge may issue a warrant for the entry on premises within the jurisdiction of the judge or magistrate to make any inspection or seizure under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Execution</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The warrant may be applied for and executed by the Secretary or any United States marshal.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–171, title X, § 10408</ref>, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 500</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8308.</num>
<heading> Detection, control, and eradication of diseases and pests</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may carry out operations and measures to detect, control, or eradicate any pest or disease of livestock (including the drawing of blood and diagnostic testing of animals), including animals at a slaughterhouse, stockyard, or other point of concentration.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may pay a claim arising out of the destruction of any animal, article, or means of conveyance consistent with the purposes of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Specific cooperative programs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall compensate industry participants and State agencies that cooperate with the Secretary in carrying out operations and measures under subsection (a) for 100 percent of eligible costs relating to cooperative programs involving Federal, State, and industry participants to control diseases of low pathogenicity in accordance with regulations issued by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reviewability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The action of the Secretary in carrying out paragraph (1) shall not be subject to review by any officer or employee of the Federal Government other than the Secretary or the designee of the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–171, title X, § 10409</ref>, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 501</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title XI, § 11011(2)</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1360</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title XI, § 11011(2), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2122.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8308a.</num>
<heading> Animal disease prevention and management</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National Animal Health Laboratory Network</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition of eligible laboratory</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In this subsection, the term “eligible laboratory” means a diagnostic laboratory that meets specific criteria developed by the Secretary, in consultation with State animal health officials, State veterinary diagnostic laboratories, and veterinary diagnostic laboratories at institutions of higher education (as defined in <ref>section 1001 of title 20</ref>).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary, in consultation with State veterinarians, shall offer to enter into contracts, grants, cooperative agreements, or other legal instruments with eligible laboratories for any of the following purposes:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> To enhance the capability of the Secretary to respond in a timely manner to emerging or existing bioterrorist threats to animal health.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> To provide the capacity and capability for standardized—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> test procedures, reference materials, and equipment;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> laboratory biosafety and biosecurity levels;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> quality management system requirements;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> interconnected electronic reporting and transmission of data; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> evaluation for emergency preparedness.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> To coordinate the development, implementation, and enhancement of national veterinary diagnostic laboratory capabilities, with special emphasis on surveillance planning and vulnerability analysis, technology development and validation, training, and outreach.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Priority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To the extent practicable and to the extent capacity and specialized expertise may be necessary, the Secretary shall give priority to existing Federal facilities, State facilities, and facilities at institutions of higher education.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National Animal Disease Preparedness and Response Program</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall establish a program, to be known as the National Animal Disease Preparedness and Response Program (referred to in this section as “the Program”), to address the increasing risk of the introduction and spread within the United States of animal pests and diseases affecting the economic interests of the livestock and related industries of the United States, including the maintenance and expansion of export markets.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program activities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Activities under the Program shall include, to the extent practicable, the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Enhancing animal pest and disease analysis and surveillance.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Expanding outreach and education.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Targeting domestic inspection activities at vulnerable points in the safeguarding continuum.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Enhancing and strengthening threat identification technology.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Improving biosecurity.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Enhancing emergency preparedness and response capabilities, including training additional emergency response personnel.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> Conducting technology development to enhance electronic sharing of animal health data for risk analysis between State and Federal animal health officials.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<chapeau> Enhancing the development and effectiveness of animal health technologies to treat and prevent animal disease, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> veterinary biologics and diagnostics;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> animal drugs for minor uses and minor species;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> animal medical devices; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> emerging veterinary countermeasures.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> Such other activities as determined appropriate by the Secretary, in consultation with eligible entities specified in paragraph (3).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible entities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">To carry out the Program, the Secretary shall offer to enter into cooperative agreements or other legal instruments, as authorized under <ref>section 8312 of this title</ref> (referred to in this section as “agreements”) with eligible entities, to be selected by the Secretary, which may include any of the following entities, either individually or in combination:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A State department of agriculture.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The office of the chief animal health official of a State.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> An entity eligible to receive funds under a capacity and infrastructure program (as defined in <ref>section 6971(f)(1)(C) of this title</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> A college of veterinary medicine, including a veterinary emergency team at such college.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> A State or national livestock producer organization with direct and significant economic interest in livestock production.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> A State emergency agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> A State, national, allied, or regional veterinary organization or specialty board recognized by the American Veterinary Medical Association.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> An Indian Tribe.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> A Federal agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special funding considerations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In entering into agreements under this subsection, the Secretary shall give priority to applications submitted by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a State department of agriculture or an office of the chief animal health official of a State; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> an eligible entity that will carry out program activities in a State or region in which—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an animal pest or disease is a Federal concern; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> the Secretary determines a potential exists for the spread of an animal pest or disease after taking into consideration—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the agricultural industries in the State or region;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> factors contributing to animal pest or disease in the State or region, such as the climate, natural resources, and geography of, and native and exotic wildlife species and other disease vectors in, the State or region; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> the movement of animals in the State or region.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of setting priorities under this subsection, the Secretary shall consult with eligible entities specified in paragraph (3). The Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002358">1</ref> shall not apply to consultation carried out under this paragraph.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">An eligible entity specified in paragraph (3) seeking to enter into an agreement under the Program shall submit to the Secretary an application containing such information as the Secretary may require.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Secretary shall notify each applicant of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the requirements to be imposed on the eligible entity that is the recipient of funds under the Program for auditing of, and reporting on, the use of such funds; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the criteria to be used to ensure activities supported using such funds are based on sound scientific data or thorough risk assessments.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Non-Federal contributions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">When deciding whether to enter into an agreement under the Program with an eligible entity described in paragraph (3), the Secretary—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> may take into consideration an eligible entity’s ability to contribute non-Federal funds to carry out such an agreement; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> shall not require such an eligible entity to make such a contribution as a condition to enter into an agreement.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of funds</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use consistent with terms of cooperative agreement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The recipient of funds under the Program shall use the funds for the purposes and in the manner provided in the agreement under which the funds are provided.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sub-agreement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Nothing in this section prevents an eligible entity from using funds received under the Program to enter into sub-agreements with another eligible entity or with a political subdivision of a State that has legal responsibilities relating to animal disease prevention, surveillance, or rapid response.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reporting requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 90 days after the date of completion of an activity conducted using funds provided under the Program, the recipient of such funds shall submit to the Secretary a report that describes the purposes and results of the activities.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National Animal Vaccine Bank</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall establish a national animal vaccine and veterinary countermeasures bank (to be known as the National Animal Vaccine and Veterinary Countermeasures Bank and referred to in this subsection as the “Vaccine Bank”) to benefit the domestic interests of the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Elements of Vaccine Bank</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Through the Vaccine Bank, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> maintain sufficient quantities of veterinary countermeasures to appropriately and rapidly respond to the most damaging animal diseases affecting or with potential to affect human health or the economy of the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> leverage, when appropriate, the mechanisms and infrastructure that have been developed for the management, storage, and distribution of the National Veterinary Stockpile.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Priority for response to foot and mouth disease</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall prioritize the acquisition and maintenance of sufficient quantities of foot and mouth disease vaccine and accompanying diagnostic products for the Vaccine Bank. As part of such prioritization, the Secretary may offer to enter into one or more contracts with one or more entities that are capable of producing foot and mouth disease vaccine and that have surge production capacity of the vaccine.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Funding</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Mandatory funding</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fiscal years 2019 through 2022</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Of the funds of the Commodity Credit Corporation, the Secretary shall make available to carry out this section $120,000,000 for the period of fiscal years 2019 through 2022, of which not less than $5,000,000 shall be made available for each of those fiscal years to carry out subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Subsequent fiscal years</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Of the funds of the Commodity Credit Corporation, the Secretary shall make available to carry out this section $30,000,000 for fiscal year 2023 and each fiscal year thereafter, of which not less than $18,000,000 shall be made available for each of those fiscal years to carry out subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National animal health laboratory network</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In addition to the funds made available under paragraph (1), there is authorized to be appropriated $30,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2019 through 2023 to carry out subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National Animal Disease Preparedness and Response Program; National Animal Vaccine and Veterinary Countermeasures Bank</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In addition to the funds made available under paragraph (1), there is authorized to be appropriated such sums as are necessary for each of fiscal years 2019 through 2023 to carry out subsections (b) and (c).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additionality</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The funds authorized for appropriation under this paragraph are in addition to any funds authorized or otherwise made available under this section or <ref>section 8316 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrative costs</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Of the funds made available under this section or <ref>section 8316 of this title</ref> to carry out the National Animal Health Laboratory Network under subsection (a) and the National Animal Disease Preparedness and Response Program under subsection (b), not more than 4 percent may be retained by the Secretary to pay administrative costs incurred by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible entities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Of the funds made available under this section or <ref>section 8316 of this title</ref> to carry out the National Animal Disease Preparedness and Response Program under subsection (b), not more than 10 percent may be retained by an eligible entity that receives funds under any agreement entered into under such subsection, including any sub-agreement under paragraph (7)(B) of such subsection to pay administrative costs incurred by the eligible entity to carry out activities under the Program.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duration of availability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Funds made available under this subsection, including any proceeds credited under paragraph (5), shall remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Proceeds from veterinary countermeasures sales</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Any proceeds of a sale of veterinary countermeasures from the Vaccine Bank shall be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> deposited into the Treasury of the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> credited to the account for the operation of the Vaccine Bank to be made available for expenditure without further appropriation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations on use of funds for certain purposes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Funds made available under the National Animal Health Laboratory Network, the National Animal Disease Preparedness and Response Program, and the Vaccine Bank shall not be used for the construction of a new building or facility or the acquisition or expansion of an existing building or facility, including site grading and improvement and architect fees.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability and purpose of funding</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Using the funds made available under subsection (d), the Secretary of Agriculture shall offer to enter into contracts, grants, cooperative agreements, or other legal instruments under subsections (a) through (c) during each of the fiscal years 2019 through 2023.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Nothing in paragraph (1) shall be construed to terminate a contract, grant, cooperative agreement, or other legal instrument entered into during the period specified in such paragraph.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–171, title X, § 10409A</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 113–79, title XII, § 12105</ref>, <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 980</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title XII, § 12101(b)</ref>–(d), <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4937–4940</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8309.</num>
<heading> Veterinary accreditation program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may establish a veterinary accreditation program that is consistent with this chapter, including the establishment of standards of conduct for accredited veterinarians.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall consult with State animal health officials and veterinary professionals regarding the establishment of the veterinary accreditation program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Suspension or revocation of accreditation</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may, after notice and opportunity for a hearing on the record, suspend or revoke the accreditation of any veterinarian accredited under this title <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002359">1</ref> who violates this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Final order</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The order of the Secretary suspending or revoking accreditation shall be treated as a final order reviewable under chapter 158 of title 28.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Summary suspension</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary may summarily suspend the accreditation of a veterinarian whom the Secretary has reason to believe knowingly violated this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Hearings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary shall provide the veterinarian with a subsequent notice and an opportunity for a prompt post-suspension hearing on the record.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application of penalty provisions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The criminal and civil penalties described in <ref>section 8313 of this title</ref> shall not apply to a violation of this section that is not a violation of any other provision of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–171, title X, § 10410</ref>, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 501</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8310.</num>
<heading> Cooperation</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To carry out this chapter, the Secretary may cooperate with other Federal agencies, States or political subdivisions of States, national governments of foreign countries, local governments of foreign countries, domestic or international organizations, domestic or international associations, Indian tribes, and other persons.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Responsibility</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The person or other entity cooperating with the Secretary shall be responsible for the authority necessary to carry out operations or measures—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> on all land and property within a foreign country or State, or under the jurisdiction of an Indian tribe, other than on land and property owned or controlled by the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> using other facilities and means, as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Screwworms</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may, independently or in cooperation with national governments of foreign countries or international organizations or associations, produce and sell sterile screwworms to any national government of a foreign country or international organization or association, if the Secretary determines that the livestock industry and related industries of the United States will not be adversely affected by the production and sale.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Proceeds</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Independent production and sale</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">If the Secretary independently produces and sells sterile screwworms under paragraph (1), the proceeds of the sale shall be—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> deposited into the Treasury of the United States; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> credited to the account from which the operating expenses of the facility producing the sterile screwworms have been paid.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cooperative production and sale</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">If the Secretary cooperates to produce and sell sterile screwworms under paragraph (1), the proceeds of the sale shall be divided between the United States and the cooperating national government or international organization or association in a manner determined by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Account</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">The United States portion of the proceeds shall be—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> deposited into the Treasury of the United States; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> credited to the account from which the operating expenses of the facility producing the sterile screwworms have been paid.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cooperation in program administration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may cooperate with State authorities, Indian tribe authorities, or other persons in the administration of regulations for the improvement of livestock and livestock products.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation and coordination with other Federal agencies</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall consult and coordinate with the head of a Federal agency with respect to any activity that is under the jurisdiction of the Federal agency.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Lead agency</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subject to the consultation and coordination requirement in paragraph (1), the Department of Agriculture shall be the lead agency with respect to issues related to pests and diseases of livestock.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–171, title X, § 10411</ref>, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 502</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8311.</num>
<heading> Reimbursable agreements</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority to enter into agreements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may enter into reimbursable fee agreements with persons for preclearance of animals or articles at locations outside the United States for movement into the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Funds collected for preclearance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Funds collected for preclearance activities—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> may be collected in advance of the provision of such activities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall be credited as offsetting collections to the currently applicable appropriation, account, or fund of U.S. Customs and Border Protection;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> shall remain available until expended;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> shall be available for the purposes for which such appropriation, account, or fund is authorized to be used; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> may be collected and shall be available only to the extent provided in appropriations Acts.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payment of employees</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding any other law, the Secretary may pay an officer or employee of the Department of Agriculture performing services under this chapter relating to imports into and exports from the United States for all overtime, night, or holiday work performed by the officer or employee at a rate of pay determined by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reimbursement</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary may require a person for whom the services are performed to reimburse the Secretary for any expenses paid by the Secretary for the services under this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">All funds collected under this subsection shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> be credited to the account that incurs the costs; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> remain available until expended, without fiscal year limitation.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Late payment penalties</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Collection</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">On failure by a person to reimburse the Secretary in accordance with this section, the Secretary may assess a late payment penalty against the person, including interest on overdue funds, as required by <ref>section 3717 of title 31</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Any late payment penalty and any accrued interest shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> be credited to the account that incurs the costs; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> remain available until expended, without fiscal year limitation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–171, title X, § 10412</ref>, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 503</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–125, title VIII, § 818(b)</ref>, <date date="2016-02-24">Feb. 24, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 222</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8312.</num>
<heading> Administration and claims</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administration</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">To carry out this chapter, the Secretary may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> acquire and maintain real or personal property;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> employ a person;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> make a grant; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> notwithstanding chapter 63 of title 31, enter into a contract, cooperative agreement, memorandum of understanding, or other agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tort claims</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (2), the Secretary may pay a tort claim, in the manner authorized by the first paragraph of <ref>section 2672 of title 28</ref>, if the claim arises outside the United States in connection with an activity authorized under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A claim may not be allowed under this subsection unless the claim is presented in writing to the Secretary not later than 2 years after the date on which the claim arises.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–171, title X, § 10413</ref>, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 503</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8313.</num>
<heading> Penalties</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Criminal penalties</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Offenses</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A person that knowingly violates this chapter, or knowingly forges, counterfeits, or, without authority from the Secretary, uses, alters, defaces, or destroys any certificate, permit, or other document provided for in this chapter shall be fined under title 18, imprisoned not more than 1 year, or both.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Distribution or sale</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A person that knowingly imports, enters, exports, or moves any animal or article, for distribution or sale, in violation of this chapter, shall be fined under title 18, imprisoned not more than 5 years, or both.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Multiple violations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">On the second and any subsequent conviction of a person of a violation of this chapter under paragraph (1), the person shall be fined under title 18, imprisoned not more than 10 years, or both.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Civil penalties</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Except as provided in <ref>section 8309(d) of this title</ref>, any person that violates this chapter, or that forges, counterfeits, or, without authority from the Secretary, uses, alters, defaces, or destroys any certificate, permit, or other document provided under this chapter may, after notice and opportunity for a hearing on the record, be assessed a civil penalty by the Secretary that does not exceed the greater of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> $50,000 in the case of any individual, except that the civil penalty may not exceed $1,000 in the case of an initial violation of this chapter by an individual moving regulated articles not for monetary gain;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> $250,000 in the case of any other person for each violation; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> for all violations adjudicated in a single proceeding—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> $500,000 if the violations do not include a willful violation; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> $1,000,000 if the violations include 1 or more willful violations.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> twice the gross gain or gross loss for any violation or forgery, counterfeiting, or unauthorized use, alteration, defacing or destruction of a certificate, permit, or other document provided under this chapter that results in the person’s deriving pecuniary gain or causing pecuniary loss to another person.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Factors in determining civil penalty</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In determining the amount of a civil penalty, the Secretary shall take into account the nature, circumstance, extent, and gravity of the violation or violations and the Secretary may consider, with respect to the violator—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the ability to pay;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the effect on ability to continue to do business;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any history of prior violations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the degree of culpability; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> such other factors as the Secretary considers to be appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Settlement of civil penalties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may compromise, modify, or remit, with or without conditions, any civil penalty that may be assessed under this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Finality of orders</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Final order</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The order of the Secretary assessing a civil penalty shall be treated as a final order reviewable under chapter 158 of title 28.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The validity of the order of the Secretary may not be reviewed in an action to collect the civil penalty.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interest</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Any civil penalty not paid in full when due under an order assessing the civil penalty shall thereafter accrue interest until paid at the rate of interest applicable to civil judgments of the courts of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Liability for acts of agents</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the construction and enforcement of this chapter, the act, omission, or failure of any officer, agent, or person acting for or employed by any other person within the scope of the employment or office of the officer, agent, or person, shall be deemed also to be the act, omission, or failure of the other person.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Guidelines for civil penalties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to the approval of the Attorney General, the Secretary shall establish guidelines to determine under what circumstances the Secretary may issue a civil penalty or suitable notice of warning in lieu of prosecution by the Attorney General of a violation of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–171, title X, § 10414</ref>, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 504</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title XI, § 11012(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1360</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title XI, § 11012(a), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2122.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8314.</num>
<heading> Enforcement</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Collection of information</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may gather and compile information and conduct any inspection or investigation that the Secretary considers to be necessary for the administration or enforcement of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Subpoenas</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary shall have the power to subpoena the attendance and testimony of any witness, the production of all evidence (including books, papers, documents, electronically stored information, and other tangible things that constitute or contain evidence), or to require the person to whom the subpoena is directed to permit the inspection of premises relating to the administration or enforcement of this chapter <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002360">1</ref> or any matter under investigation in connection with this chapter.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002360">1</ref></p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Location of production</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The attendance of any witness and production of evidence relevant to the inquiry may be required from any place in the United States.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Enforcement</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">In case of disobedience to a subpoena by any person, the Secretary may request the Attorney General to invoke the aid of any court of the United States within the jurisdiction in which the investigation is conducted, or where the person resides, is found, transacts business, is licensed to do business, or is incorporated, to require the attendance and testimony of any witness, the production of evidence, or the inspection of premises.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Noncompliance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">In case of a refusal to obey a subpoena issued to any person, a court may order the person to appear before the Secretary and give evidence concerning the matter in question, produce evidence, or permit the inspection of premises.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contempt</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Any failure to obey the order of the court may be punished by the court as contempt of the court.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Witnesses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">A witness summoned by the Secretary under this chapter shall be paid the same fees and mileage that are paid to a witness in a court of the United States.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Depositions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">A witness whose deposition is taken, and the person taking the deposition, shall be entitled to the same fees that are paid for similar services in a court of the United States.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(E)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Procedures</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Publication</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The Secretary shall publish procedures for the issuance of subpoenas under this section.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The procedures shall include a requirement that subpoenas be reviewed for legal sufficiency and, to be effective, be signed by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Delegation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">If the authority to sign a subpoena is delegated to an agency other than the Office of Administrative Law Judges, the agency receiving the delegation shall seek review of the subpoena for legal sufficiency outside that agency.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority of Attorney General</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Attorney General may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> prosecute, in the name of the United States, all criminal violations of this chapter that are referred to the Attorney General by the Secretary or are brought to the notice of the Attorney General by any person;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> bring an action to enjoin the violation of or to compel compliance with this chapter, or to enjoin any interference by any person with the Secretary in carrying out this chapter, in any case in which the Secretary has reason to believe that the person has violated, or is about to violate this chapter or has interfered, or is about to interfere, with the actions of the Secretary; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> bring an action for the recovery of any unpaid civil penalty, funds under a reimbursable agreement, late payment penalty, or interest assessed under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Court jurisdiction</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The United States district courts, the District Court of Guam, the District Court of the Northern Mariana Islands, the District Court of the Virgin Islands, the highest court of American Samoa, and the United States courts of the other territories and possessions are vested with jurisdiction in all cases arising under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Venue</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any action arising under this chapter may be brought, and process may be served, in the judicial district where a violation or interference occurred or is about to occur, or where the person charged with the violation, interference, impending violation, impending interference, or failure to pay resides, is found, transacts business, is licensed to do business, or is incorporated.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Paragraphs (1) and (2) do not apply to sections 8309(c) and 8313(b) of this title.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–171, title X, § 10415</ref>, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 505</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title XI, § 11012(b)</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1360</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title XI, § 11012(b), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2122.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8315.</num>
<heading> Regulations and orders</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may promulgate such regulations, and issue such orders, as the Secretary determines necessary to carry out this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–171, title X, § 10416</ref>, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 507</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8316.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as are necessary to carry out this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer of funds</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In connection with an emergency under which a pest or disease of livestock threatens any segment of agricultural production in the United States, the Secretary may transfer from other appropriations or funds available to the agencies or corporations of the Department of Agriculture such funds as the Secretary determines are necessary for the arrest, control, eradication, or prevention of the spread of the pest or disease of livestock and for related expenses.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any funds transferred under this subsection shall remain available until expended, without fiscal year limitation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reviewability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The action of any officer, employee, or agent of the Secretary in carrying out this section (including determining the amount of and making any payment authorized to be made under this chapter) shall not be subject to review by any officer or employee of the Federal Government other than the Secretary or the designee of the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In carrying out this chapter, the Secretary may use funds made available to carry out this chapter for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the employment of civilian nationals in foreign countries; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the construction and operation of research laboratories, quarantine stations, and other buildings and facilities for special purposes.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–171, title X, § 10417</ref>, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 507</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title XI, § 11011(3)</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1360</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title XI, § 11011(3), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2122.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8317.</num>
<heading> Effect on regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A regulation issued under a provision of law repealed by subsection (a) shall remain in effect until the Secretary issues a regulation under section 8303(b) or 8315 of this title that supersedes the earlier regulation.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–171, title X, § 10418(c)</ref>, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 509</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8318.</num>
<heading> Veterinary training</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture may develop a program to maintain in all regions of the United States a sufficient number of Federal and State veterinarians and veterinary teams, including those based at colleges of veterinary medicine, who are well trained in recognition and diagnosis of exotic and endemic animal diseases and who are capable of providing effective services before, during, and after emergencies.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–171, title X, § 10504</ref>, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 510</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title XII, § 12106</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4943</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8319.</num>
<heading> Surveillance of zoonotic diseases</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Health and Human Services, through the Commissioner of Food and Drugs and the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, and the Secretary of Agriculture shall coordinate the surveillance of zoonotic diseases.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–188, title III, § 313</ref>, <date date="2002-06-12">June 12, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 674</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8320.</num>
<heading> Expansion of Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service activities</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture (referred to in this section as the “Secretary”) may utilize existing authorities to give high priority to enhancing and expanding the capacity of the Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service to conduct activities to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> increase the inspection capacity of the Service at international points of origin;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> improve surveillance at ports of entry and customs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> enhance methods of protecting against the introduction of plant and animal disease organisms by terrorists;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> develop new and improve existing strategies and technologies for dealing with intentional outbreaks of plant and animal disease arising from acts of terrorism or from unintentional introduction, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> establishing cooperative agreements among Veterinary Services of the Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service, State animal health commissions and regulatory agencies for livestock and poultry health, and private veterinary practitioners to enhance the preparedness and ability of Veterinary Services and the commissions and agencies to respond to outbreaks of such animal diseases; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> strengthening planning and coordination with State and local agencies, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> State animal health commissions and regulatory agencies for livestock and poultry health; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> State agriculture departments; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> otherwise improve the capacity of the Service to protect against the threat of bioterrorism.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Automated recordkeeping system</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator of the Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service may implement a central automated recordkeeping system to provide for the reliable tracking of the status of animal and plant shipments, including those shipments on hold at ports of entry and customs. The Secretary shall ensure that such a system shall be fully accessible to or fully integrated with the Food Safety Inspection Service.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section, $30,000,000 for fiscal year 2002, and such sums as may be necessary for each subsequent fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–188, title III, § 331</ref>, <date date="2002-06-12">June 12, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 678</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8321.</num>
<heading> Pest and Disease Response Fund</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established on the books of the Treasury an account to be known as the “Pest and Disease Response Fund”. There shall be deposited into the Fund any proceeds received by the Secretary of Agriculture as reimbursement for services provided by the Secretary using amounts in the Fund.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Amounts in the Fund shall remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of Fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In implementing the Animal Health Protection Act (<ref>7 U.S.C. 8301</ref> et seq.) and the Plant Protection Act (<ref>7 U.S.C. 7701</ref> et seq.), the Secretary of Agriculture shall have complete discretion regarding the use of amounts in the Fund to support emergency eradication and research activities in response to economic and health threats posed by pests and diseases affecting agricultural commodities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For each of the fiscal years 2005 through 2009, there is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Agriculture $1,000,000 for deposit in the Fund.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–465, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="2004-12-21">Dec. 21, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3886</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8322.</num>
<heading> National aquatic animal health plan</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture may enter into a cooperative agreement with an eligible entity to carry out a project under a national aquatic animal health plan under the authority of the Secretary under section 10411 of the Animal Health Protection Act (<ref>7 U.S.C. 8310</ref>) for the purpose of detecting, controlling, or eradicating diseases of aquaculture species and promoting species-specific best management practices.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cooperative agreements between eligible entities and the Secretary</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">As a condition of entering into a cooperative agreement with the Secretary under this section, an eligible entity shall agree to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> assume responsibility for the non-Federal share of the cost of carrying out the project under the national aquatic health plan, as determined by the Secretary in accordance with paragraph (2); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> act in accordance with applicable disease and species specific best management practices relating to activities to be carried out under such project.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Non-Federal share</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall determine the non-Federal share of the cost of carrying out a project under the national aquatic health plan on a case-by-case basis for each such project. Such non-Federal share may be provided in cash or in-kind.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability of other laws</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In carrying out this section, the Secretary may make use of the authorities under the Animal Health Protection Act (<ref>7 U.S.C. 8301</ref> et seq.), including the authority to carry out operations and measures to detect, control, and eradicate pests and diseases and the authority to pay claims arising out of the destruction of any animal, article, or means of conveyance.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible entity defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this section, the term “eligible entity” means a State, a political subdivision of a State, Indian tribe, or other appropriate entity, as determined by the Secretary of Agriculture.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title XI, § 11013</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1361</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title XI, § 11013, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2122; <ref>Pub. L. 113–79, title XII, § 12103</ref>, <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 979</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title XII, § 12105</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4943</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>