<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 98—</num>
<heading>DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE REORGANIZATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6901.</num>
<heading> Purpose</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The purpose of this chapter is to provide the Secretary of Agriculture with the necessary authority to streamline and reorganize the Department of Agriculture to achieve greater efficiency, effectiveness, and economies in the organization and management of the programs and activities carried out by the Department.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–354, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3209</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6902.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except where the context requires otherwise, for purposes of this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Department</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Department” means the Department of Agriculture.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National Appeals Division</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “National Appeals Division” means the National Appeals Division of the Department established under <ref>section 6992 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Agriculture.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Function</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “function” means an administrative, financial, or regulatory activity of an agency, office, officer, or employee of the Department.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–354, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3209</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>GENERAL REORGANIZATION AUTHORITIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6911.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title XII, § 12414(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4981</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6912.</num>
<heading> Authority of Secretary to delegate transferred functions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Delegation of authority</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Delegation authorized</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subject to paragraph (2), the Secretary may delegate to any agency, office, officer, or employee of the Department the authority to perform any function transferred to the Secretary under section 6911(a) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002313">1</ref> of this title or any other function vested in the Secretary as of <date date="1994-10-13">October 13, 1994</date>. The authority provided in the preceding sentence includes the authority to establish, consolidate, alter, or discontinue any agency, office, or other administrative unit of the Department.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Condition on authority</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The delegation authority provided by paragraph (1) shall be subject to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> sections 6942, 6971(f), 6993, and 2204e of this title and subsections (a) and (b)(1) of <ref>section 6981 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> sections 5692 and 5693 of this title; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content><ref>section 590h(b)(5) of title 16</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cost-benefit analysis required for name change</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Analysis required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (2), the Secretary shall conduct a cost-benefit analysis before changing the name of any agency, office, division, or other unit of the Department to ensure that the benefits to be derived from changing the name of the agency, office, division, or other unit outweigh the expense of executing the name change.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Paragraph (1) shall not apply with respect to any name change required or authorized by this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public comment on proposed reorganization</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">To the extent that the implementation of the authority provided to the Secretary by this chapter to reorganize the Department involves the creation of new agencies or offices within the Department or the delegation of major functions or major groups of functions to any agency or office of the Department (or the officers or employees of such agency or office), the Secretary shall, to the extent considered practicable by the Secretary—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> give appropriate advance public notice of the proposed reorganization action or delegation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> afford appropriate opportunity for interested parties to comment on the proposed reorganization action or delegation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interagency transfer of records, property, personnel, and funds</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Related transfers</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Subject to paragraph (2), as part of the transfer or delegation of a function of the Department made or authorized by this chapter, the Secretary may transfer within the Department—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any of the records, property, or personnel affected by the transfer or delegation of the function; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> unexpended balances (available or to be made available for use in connection with the transferred or delegated function) of appropriations, allocations, or other funds of the Department.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicable law relating to funds transfer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1"><ref>Section 1531 of title 31</ref> shall apply to any transfer of funds under paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exhaustion of administrative appeals</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a person shall exhaust all administrative appeal procedures established by the Secretary or required by law before the person may bring an action in a court of competent jurisdiction against—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Secretary;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Department; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> an agency, office, officer, or employee of the Department.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–354, title II, § 212</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3210</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title VII, § 7511(c)(27)</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1270</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title VII, § 7511(c)(27), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2031.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 6913, 6914.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title XII, § 12414(a)(2)</ref>, (3), <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4981</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6915.</num>
<heading> Combination of field offices</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Combination of offices required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Where practicable and to the extent consistent with efficient, effective, and improved service, the Secretary shall combine field offices of agencies within the Department to reduce personnel and duplicative overhead expenses.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Joint use of resources and offices required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">When two or more agencies of the Department share a common field office, the Secretary shall require the agencies to jointly use office space, equipment, office supplies, administrative personnel, and clerical personnel associated with that field office.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–354, title II, § 215</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3211</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6916.</num>
<heading> Improvement of information sharing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever the Secretary procures or uses computer systems, as may be provided for in advance in appropriations Acts, the Secretary shall do so in a manner that enhances efficiency, productivity, and client services and is consistent with the goal of promoting computer information sharing among agencies of the Department.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–354, title II, § 216</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3212</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6917.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title XII, § 12414(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4981</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6918.</num>
<heading> Assistant Secretaries of Agriculture</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to establish in the Department the positions of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Assistant Secretary of Agriculture for Congressional Relations and Intergovernmental Affairs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Assistant Secretary of Agriculture for Administration; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Assistant Secretary of Agriculture for Civil Rights.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Confirmation required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the Secretary establishes any position of Assistant Secretary authorized under paragraph (1) or (3) of subsection (a), the Assistant Secretary shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties of Assistant Secretary of Agriculture for Civil Rights</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary may delegate to the Assistant Secretary for Civil Rights responsibility for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> ensuring compliance with all civil rights and related laws by all agencies and under all programs of the Department;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> coordinating administration of civil rights laws (including regulations) within the Department for employees of, and participants in, programs of the Department; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> ensuring that necessary and appropriate civil rights components are properly incorporated into all strategic planning initiatives of the Department and agencies of the Department.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–354, title II, § 218</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3212</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. A, § 101(a) [title X, § 1001(1)]</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681</ref>, 2681–41; <ref>Pub. L. 107–171, title X, § 10704(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 518</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–166, § 2(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2012-08-10">Aug. 10, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1283</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title XII</ref>, §§ 12401(a), 12415(b)(1), <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4971</ref>, 4981.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6919.</num>
<heading> Military Veterans Agricultural Liaison</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish in the Department the position of Military Veterans Agricultural Liaison.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Military Veterans Agricultural Liaison shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provide information to returning veterans about, and connect returning veterans with, beginning farmer training and agricultural vocational and rehabilitation programs appropriate to the needs and interests of returning veterans, including assisting veterans in using Federal veterans educational benefits for purposes relating to beginning a farming or ranching career;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provide information to veterans concerning the availability of, and eligibility requirements for, participation in agricultural programs, with particular emphasis on beginning farmer and rancher programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> serve as a resource for assisting veteran farmers and ranchers, and potential farmers and ranchers, in applying for participation in agricultural programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> advocate on behalf of veterans in interactions with employees of the Department;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> establish and periodically update the website described in subsection (d); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> in carrying out the duties described in paragraphs (1) through (5), consult with and provide technical assistance to any Federal agency, including the Department of Defense, the Department of Veterans Affairs, the Small Business Administration, and the Department of Labor.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contracts and cooperative agreements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of carrying out the duties under subsection (b), the Military Veterans Agricultural Liaison may enter into contracts or cooperative agreements with the research centers of the Agricultural Research Service, institutions of higher education (as defined in <ref>section 1001 of title 20</ref>), or nonprofit organizations for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the conduct of regional research on the profitability of small farms;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the development of educational materials;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the conduct of workshops, courses, and certified vocational training;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the conduct of mentoring activities; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the provision of internship opportunities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Website required</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The website required under subsection (b)(5) shall include the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Positions identified within the Department of Agriculture that are available to veterans for apprenticeships.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Apprenticeships, programs of training on the job, and programs of education that are approved for purposes of chapter 36 of title 38.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Employment skills training programs for members of the Armed Forces carried out pursuant to <ref>section 1143(e) of title 10</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> Information designed to assist businesses, nonprofit entities, educational institutions, and farmers interested in developing apprenticeships, on-the-job training, educational, or entrepreneurial programs for veterans in navigating the process of having a program approved by a State approving agency for purposes of chapter 36 of title 38, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> contact information for relevant offices in the Department of Defense, Department of Veterans Affairs, Department of Labor, and Small Business Administration;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> basic requirements for approval by each State approving agency;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> recommendations with respect to training and coursework to be used during apprenticeships or on-the-job training that will enable a veteran to be eligible for agricultural programs; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> examples of successful programs and curriculums that have been approved for purposes of chapter 36 of title 38 (with consent of the organization and without any personally identifiable information).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review of website</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Not later than 5 years after <date date="2018-12-20">December 20, 2018</date>, and once every 5 years thereafter, the Secretary shall conduct a study to determine if the website required under subsection (b)(5) is effective in providing veterans the information required under paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Ineffective website</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">If the Secretary determines that the website is not effective under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> notify the agriculture and veterans committees described in subparagraph (C) of that determination; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> not earlier than 180 days after the date on which the Secretary provides notice under clause (i), terminate the website.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agriculture and veterans committees</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The agriculture and veterans committees referred to in subparagraph (B)(i) are—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall consult with organizations that serve veterans.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2018-12-20">December 20, 2018</date>, and annually thereafter, the Military Veterans Agricultural Liaison shall submit a report on beginning farmer training for veterans and agricultural vocational and rehabilitation programs for veterans to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents of report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The report submitted under paragraph (1) shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a summary of the measures taken to carry out subsections (b) and (c);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a description of the information provided to veterans under paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (b);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> recommendations for best informing veterans of the programs described in paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (b);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a summary of the contracts or cooperative agreements entered into under subsection (c);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> a description of the programs implemented under subsection (c);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> a summary of the employment outreach activities directed to veterans;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> recommendations for how opportunities for veterans in agriculture should be developed or expanded;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> a summary of veteran farm lending data and a summary of shortfalls, if any, identified by the Military Veterans Agricultural Liaison in collecting data with respect to veterans engaged in agriculture; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> recommendations, if any, on how to improve activities under subsection (b).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public dissemination of information</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2018-12-20">December 20, 2018</date>, and annually thereafter, the Military Veterans Agricultural Liaison shall make publicly available and share broadly, including by posting on the website of the Department—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the report of the Military Veterans Agricultural Liaison on beginning farmer training for veterans and agricultural vocational and rehabilitation programs; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the information disseminated under paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (b).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Further dissemination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than the day before the date on which the Military Veterans Agricultural Liaison makes publicly available the information under paragraph (1), the Military Veterans Agricultural Liaison shall provide that information to the Department of Defense, the Department of Veterans Affairs, the Small Business Administration, and the Department of Labor.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–354, title II, § 219</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 113–79, title XII, § 12304</ref>, <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 985</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title XII, § 12402</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4971</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6920.</num>
<heading> Office of Energy Policy and New Uses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish for the Department, in the Office of the Secretary, an Office of Energy Policy and New Uses.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–354, title II, § 220</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 105–185, title VI, § 602</ref>, <date date="1998-06-23">June 23, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 585</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6921.</num>
<heading> Office of Tribal Relations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall maintain in the Office of the Secretary an Office of Tribal Relations, which shall advise the Secretary on policies related to Indian tribes and carry out such other functions as the Secretary considers appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tribal Advisory Committee</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In this subsection:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Indian tribe</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “Indian tribe” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 5304 of title 25</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Relevant committees of Congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “relevant committees of Congress” means—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the Committee on Indian Affairs of the Senate.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tribal organization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “tribal organization” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 5304 of title 25</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of committee</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary shall establish an advisory committee, to be known as the Tribal Advisory Committee (referred to in this subsection as the “Committee”) to provide advice and guidance to the Secretary on matters relating to Tribal and Indian affairs.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Facilitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Committee shall facilitate, but not supplant, government-to-government consultation between the Department of Agriculture (referred to in this subsection as the “Department”) and Indian tribes.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Membership</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Composition</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Committee shall be composed of 11 members, of whom—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> 3 shall be appointed by the Secretary;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> 1 shall be appointed by the chairperson of the Committee on Indian Affairs of the Senate;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> 1 shall be appointed by the ranking member of the Committee on Indian Affairs of the Senate;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> 1 shall be appointed by the chairperson of the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> 1 shall be appointed by the ranking member of the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> 2 shall be appointed by the chairperson of the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> 2 shall be appointed by the ranking member of the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nominations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Secretary shall accept nominations for members of the Committee from any of the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> An Indian tribe.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> A tribal organization.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> A national or regional organization with expertise in issues relating to the duties of the Committee described in paragraph (4).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Diversity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">To the maximum extent feasible, the Secretary shall ensure that the members of the Committee represent a diverse set of expertise on issues relating to geographic regions, Indian tribes, and the agricultural industry.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">No member of the Committee shall be an officer or employee of the Federal Government.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(E)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Period of appointment; vacancies</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">Each member of the Committee—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> subject to clause (ii), shall be appointed to a 3-year term; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> may be reappointed to not more than 3 consecutive terms.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initial staggering</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The first 3 appointments by the Secretary under paragraph (3)(A)(i) shall be for a 2-year term.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Vacancies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Any vacancy in the Committee shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment not more than 90 days after the date on which the position becomes vacant.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(F)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Meetings</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The Committee shall meet in person not less than twice each year.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Office of Tribal Relations representative</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Not fewer than 1 representative from the Office of Tribal Relations of the Department shall be present at each meeting of the Committee.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Department of Interior representative</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The Assistant Secretary for Indian Affairs of the Department of the Interior (or a designee) shall be present at each meeting of the Committee.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iv)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonvoting representatives</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The individuals described in clauses (ii) and (iii) shall be nonvoting representatives at meetings of the Committee.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties of Committee</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Committee shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> identify evolving issues of relevance to Indian tribes relating to programs of the Department;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> communicate to the Secretary the issues identified under subparagraph (A);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> submit to the Secretary recommendations for, and solutions to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the issues identified under subparagraph (A);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> issues raised at the Tribal, regional, or national level; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> issues relating to any Tribal consultation carried out by the Department;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> discuss issues and proposals for changes to the regulations, policies, and procedures of the Department that impact Indian tribes;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> identify priorities and provide advice on appropriate strategies for Tribal consultation on issues at the Tribal, regional, or national level regarding the Department;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> ensure that pertinent issues of the Department are brought to the attention of an Indian tribe in a timely manner so that timely feedback from an Indian tribe can be obtained; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> identify and propose solutions to any interdepartmental barrier between the Department and other Federal agencies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Not less frequently than once each year, the Committee shall submit to the Secretary and the relevant committees of Congress a report that describes—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the activities of the Committee during the previous year; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> recommendations for legislative or administrative action for the following year.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Response from Secretary</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Not more than 45 days after the date on which the Secretary receives a report under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall submit a written response to that report to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Committee; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the relevant committees of Congress.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation of members</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Members of the Committee shall be compensated at a rate equal to the daily equivalent of the annual rate of basic pay prescribed for level IV of the Executive Schedule under <ref>section 5315 of title 5</ref> for each day (including travel time) during which the member is engaged in the performance of the duties of the Committee.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal Advisory Committee Act exemption</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Section 14 of the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002314">1</ref> shall not apply to the Committee.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–354, title III, § 309</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 113–79, title XII, § 12303</ref>, <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 985</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title XII, § 12303</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4962</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6922.</num>
<heading> Office of Homeland Security</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition of agriculture and food defense</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this section, the term “agriculture and food defense” means any action to prevent, protect against, mitigate the effects of, respond to, or recover from a naturally occurring, unintentional, or intentional threat to the agriculture and food system.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish in the Department the Office of Homeland Security.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Executive Director</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Office of Homeland Security shall be headed by an Executive Director, who shall be known as the Executive Director of Homeland Security.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Executive Director of Homeland Security shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> serve as the principal advisor to the Secretary on homeland security, including emergency management and agriculture and food defense;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> coordinate activities of the Department, including policies, processes, budget needs, and oversight relating to homeland security, including emergency management and agriculture and food defense;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> act as the primary liaison on behalf of the Department with other Federal departments and agencies in activities relating to homeland security, including emergency management and agriculture and food defense, and provide for interagency coordination and data sharing;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> coordinate in the Department the gathering of information relevant to early warning and awareness of threats and risks to the food and agriculture critical infrastructure sector; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> share that information with, and provide assistance with interpretation and risk characterization of that information to, the intelligence community (as defined in <ref>section 3003 of title 50</ref>), law enforcement agencies, the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, and State fusion centers (as defined in <ref>section 124h(j) of title 6</ref> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002315">1</ref> ;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> liaise with the Director of National Intelligence to assist in the development of periodic assessments and intelligence estimates, or other intelligence products, that support the defense of the food and agriculture critical infrastructure sector;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> coordinate the conduct, evaluation, and improvement of exercises to identify and eliminate gaps in preparedness and response;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> produce a Department-wide centralized strategic coordination plan to provide a high-level perspective of the operations of the Department relating to homeland security, including emergency management and agriculture and food defense; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> carry out other appropriate duties, as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agriculture and food threat awareness partnership program</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interagency exchange program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary, in partnership with the intelligence community (as defined in <ref>section 3003 of title 50</ref>) and fusion centers (as defined in <ref>section 124h(j) of title 6</ref> <sup>1</sup> that have analysis and intelligence capabilities relating to the defense of the food and agriculture critical infrastructure sector, shall establish and carry out an interagency exchange program of personnel and information to improve communication and analysis for the defense of the food and agriculture critical infrastructure sector.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Collaboration with Federal, State, and local authorities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">To carry out the program established under paragraph (1), the Secretary may—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> enter into 1 or more cooperative agreements or contracts with Federal, State, or local authorities that have analysis and intelligence capabilities and expertise relating to the defense of the food and agriculture critical infrastructure sector; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> carry out any other activity under any other authority of the Secretary that is appropriate to engage the authorities described in subparagraph (A) for the defense of the food and agriculture critical infrastructure sector, as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–354, title II, § 221</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title XII, § 12202</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4944</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6923.</num>
<heading> Office of Urban Agriculture and Innovative Production</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Office</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall establish in the Department an Office of Urban Agriculture and Innovative Production.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Director</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall appoint a senior official to serve as the Director of the Office of Urban Agriculture and Innovative Production (referred to in this section as the “Director”).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Mission</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The mission of the Office of Urban Agriculture and Innovative Production shall be to encourage and promote urban, indoor, and other emerging agricultural practices, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> community gardens and farms located in urban areas, suburbs, and urban clusters;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> rooftop farms, outdoor vertical production, and green walls;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> indoor farms, greenhouses, and high-tech vertical technology farms;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> hydroponic, aeroponic, and aquaponic farm facilities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> other innovations in agricultural production, as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Responsibilities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Director shall be responsible for engaging in activities to carry out the mission described in paragraph (3), including by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> managing programs, including for community gardens, urban farms, rooftop agriculture, and indoor vertical production;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> advising the Secretary;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> coordinating with the agencies and officials of the Department to update relevant programs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> engaging in stakeholder relations and developing external partnerships;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> identifying common State and municipal best practices for navigating local policies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> coordinating networks of community gardens and facilitating connections to local food banks, in partnership with the Food and Nutrition Service; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> collaborating with other Federal agencies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Urban Agriculture and Innovative Production Advisory Committee</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2018-12-20">December 20, 2018</date>, the Secretary shall establish an Urban Agriculture and Innovative Production Advisory Committee (referred to in this subsection as the “Committee”) to advise the Secretary on—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the development of policies and outreach relating to urban, indoor, and other emerging agricultural production practices; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any other aspects of the implementation of this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Membership</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Committee shall be composed of 12 members, of whom—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> 4 shall be individuals who are agricultural producers, of whom—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> 2 individuals shall be agricultural producers located in an urban area or urban cluster; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> 2 individuals shall be farmers that use innovative technology;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> 2 shall be representatives from an institution of higher education or extension program;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> 1 shall be an individual who represents a nonprofit organization, which may include a public health, environmental, or community organization;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> 1 shall be an individual who represents business and economic development, which may include a business development entity, a chamber of commerce, a city government, or a planning organization;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> 1 shall be an individual with supply chain experience, which may include a food aggregator, wholesale food distributor, food hub, or an individual who has direct-to-consumer market experience;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> 1 shall be an individual from a financing entity; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> 2 shall be individuals with related experience or expertise in urban, indoor, and other emerging agriculture production practices, as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initial appointments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary shall appoint the members of the Committee not later than 180 days after <date date="2018-12-20">December 20, 2018</date>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Period of appointment; vacancies</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), a member of the Committee shall be appointed for a term of 3 years.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initial appointments</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Of the members first appointed to the Committee—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> 4 of the members, as determined by the Secretary, shall be appointed for a term of 3 years;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> 4 of the members, as determined by the Secretary, shall be appointed for a term of 2 years; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> 4 of the members, as determined by the Secretary, shall be appointed for a term of 1 year.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Vacancies</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Any vacancy in the Committee—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> shall not affect the powers of the Committee; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> shall be filled as soon as practicable in the same manner as the original appointment.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consecutive terms</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">An initial appointee of the committee may serve an additional consecutive term if the member is reappointed by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Meetings</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Frequency</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Committee shall meet not fewer than 3 times per year.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initial meeting</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Not later than 180 days after the date on which the members are appointed under paragraph (2)(B), the Committee shall hold the first meeting of the Committee.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Committee shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> develop recommendations and advise the Director on policies, initiatives, and outreach administered by the Office of Urban Agriculture and Innovative Production;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> evaluate and review ongoing research and extension activities relating to urban, indoor, and other innovative agricultural practices;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> identify new and existing barriers to successful urban, indoor, and other emerging agricultural production practices; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> provide additional assistance and advice to the Director as appropriate.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Not later than 1 year after the date on which the Committee is established, and every 2 years through 2023, the Committee shall submit to the Secretary, the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate a report describing the recommendations developed under subparagraph (A).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Personnel matters</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A member of the Committee shall serve without compensation.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Travel expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A member of the Committee shall be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, in accordance with <ref>section 5703 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Subject to subparagraph (B), the Committee shall terminate on the date that is 5 years after the date on which the members are appointed under paragraph (2)(B).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Extensions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Before the date on which the Committee terminates, the Secretary may renew the Committee for 1 or more 2-year periods.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grants</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Director shall award competitive grants to support the development of urban agriculture and innovative production to any of the following eligible entities:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A nonprofit organization.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A unit of local government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A Tribal government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Any school that serves any of grades kindergarten through grade 12.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Pilot projects</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Urban and suburban county committees</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2018-12-20">December 20, 2018</date>, the Secretary shall establish a pilot program for not fewer than 5 years that establishes 10 county committees in accordance with <ref>section 590h(b)(5)(B)(ii)(II) of title 16</ref> to operate in counties located in urban or suburban areas with a high concentration of urban or suburban farms.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Nothing in this paragraph requires or precludes the establishment of a Farm Service Agency office in a county in which a county committee is established under subparagraph (A).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">For fiscal year 2019 and each fiscal year thereafter through fiscal year 2023, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate a report describing a summary of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the status of the pilot program under subparagraph (A);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> meetings and other activities of the committees established under that subparagraph; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the types and volume of assistance and services provided to farmers in counties in which county committees are established under that subparagraph.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Increasing community compost and reducing food waste</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary, acting through the Director, shall carry out pilot projects under which the Secretary shall offer to enter into cooperative agreements with local or municipal governments in not fewer than 10 States to develop and test strategies for planning and implementing municipal compost plans and food waste reduction plans.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible entities and purposes of pilot projects</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Under a cooperative agreement entered into under this paragraph, the Secretary shall provide assistance to municipalities, counties, local governments, or city planners, as appropriate, to carry out planning and implementing activities that will—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> generate compost;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> increase access to compost for agricultural producers;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> reduce reliance on, and limit the use of, fertilizer;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> improve soil quality;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> encourage waste management and permaculture business development;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> increase rainwater absorption;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> reduce municipal food waste; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> divert food waste from landfills.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Evaluation and ranking of applications</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Criteria</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2018-12-20">December 20, 2018</date>, the Secretary shall establish criteria for the selection of pilot projects under this paragraph.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consideration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">In selecting, undertaking, or funding pilot projects under this paragraph, the Secretary shall consider any commonly known significant impact on existing food waste recovery and disposal by commercial, marketing, or business relationships.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Priority</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">In selecting a pilot project under this paragraph, the Secretary shall give priority to an application for a pilot project that—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> anticipates or demonstrates economic benefits;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> incorporates plans to make compost easily accessible to agricultural producers, including community gardeners;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> integrates other food waste strategies, including food recovery efforts; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> provides for collaboration with multiple partners.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Matching requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The recipient of assistance for a pilot project under this paragraph shall provide funds, in-kind contributions, or a combination of both from sources other than funds provided through the grant in an amount equal to not less than 25 percent of the amount of the grant.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(E)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Evaluation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Secretary shall conduct an evaluation of the pilot projects funded under this paragraph to assess different solutions for increasing access to compost and reducing municipal food waste, including an evaluation of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the amount of Federal funds used for each project; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a measurement of the outcomes of each project.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section and the amendments made by this section $25,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2019 through 2023.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–354, title II, § 222</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title XII, § 12302</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4958</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6924.</num>
<heading> Food Loss and Waste Reduction Liaison</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish a Food Loss and Waste Reduction Liaison to coordinate Federal, State, local, and nongovernmental programs, and other efforts, to measure and reduce the incidence of food loss and waste in accordance with this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Food Loss and Waste Reduction Liaison shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> coordinate food loss and waste reduction efforts within the Department of Agriculture and with other Federal agencies, including the Environmental Protection Agency and the Food and Drug Administration;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> support and promote Federal programs to measure and reduce the incidence of food loss and waste and increase food recovery;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> provide information to, and serve as a resource for, entities engaged in food loss and waste reduction and food recovery, including information about the availability of, and eligibility requirements for, participation in Federal, State, local, and nongovernmental programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> raise awareness of the liability protections afforded under the Bill Emerson Good Samaritan Food Donation Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 1791</ref>) to persons engaged in food loss and waste reduction and food recovery; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> make recommendations with respect to expanding innovative food recovery models and reducing the incidence of food loss and waste.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cooperative agreements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of carrying out the duties under subsection (b), the Food Loss and Waste Reduction Liaison may enter into contracts or cooperative agreements with the research centers of the Research, Education, and Economics mission area, institutions of higher education (as defined in <ref>section 1001 of title 20</ref>), or nonprofit organizations for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the development of educational materials;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the conduct of workshops and courses; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the conduct of research on best practices with respect to food loss and waste reduction and food recovery.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Study on food waste</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall conduct a study, in consultation with the Food Loss and Waste Reduction Liaison, to evaluate and determine—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> methods of measuring food waste;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> standards for the volume of food waste;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> factors that contribute to food waste;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the cost and volume of food loss;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the effectiveness of existing liability protections afforded under the Bill Emerson Good Samaritan Food Donation Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 1791</ref>); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> measures to ensure that programs contemplated, undertaken, or funded by the Department of Agriculture do not disrupt existing food waste recovery and disposal efforts by commercial, marketing, or business relationships.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initial report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2018-12-20">December 20, 2018</date>, the Food Loss and Waste Liaison shall submit to the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate a report that describes the results of the study conducted under subsection (d).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 1 year after the date of the submission of the report under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate a report that contains, with respect to the preceding year—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an estimate of the quantity of food waste during such year; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the results of the food waste reduction and loss prevention activities carried out or led by the Department of Agriculture.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–354, title II, § 224</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title XII, § 12504</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4987</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6925.</num>
<heading> Food Access Liaison</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish the position of Food Access Liaison to coordinate Department programs to reduce barriers to food access and monitor and evaluate the progress of such programs in accordance with this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Food Access Liaison shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> coordinate the efforts of the Department, including regional offices, to experiment and consider programs and policies aimed at reducing barriers to food access for consumers, including but not limited to participants in nutrition assistance programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provide outreach to entities engaged in activities to reduce barriers to food access in accordance with the statutory authorization for each program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> provide outreach to entities engaged in activities to reduce barriers to food access, including retailers, markets, producers, and others involved in food production and distribution, with respect to the availability of, and eligibility for, Department programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> raise awareness of food access issues in interactions with employees of the Department;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> make recommendations to the Secretary with respect to efforts to reduce barriers to food access; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> submit to Congress an annual report with respect to the efforts of the Department to reduce barriers to food access.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–354, title II, § 225</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title XII, § 12614(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5014</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>FARM PRODUCTION AND CONSERVATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6931.</num>
<heading> Under Secretary of Agriculture for Farm Production and Conservation</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to establish in the Department the position of Under Secretary of Agriculture for Farm Production and Conservation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Confirmation required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the Secretary establishes the position of Under Secretary of Agriculture for Farm Production and Conservation authorized under subsection (a), the Under Secretary shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Functions of Undersecretary <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002316">1</ref></heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Under Secretary of Agriculture for Farm Production and Conservation shall perform such functions and duties as the Secretary shall prescribe.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Succession</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any official who is serving as Under Secretary of Agriculture for Farm and Foreign Agricultural Services on <date date="2018-03-23">March 23, 2018</date>, and who was appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, shall not be required to be reappointed under subsection (b) to the successor position authorized under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–354, title II, § 225</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3213</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. A, title VII, § 772(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 397</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6932.</num>
<heading> Farm Service Agency</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to establish and maintain in the Department a Farm Service Agency.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Functions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">If the Secretary establishes the Farm Service Agency under subsection (a), the Secretary is authorized to assign to the Agency jurisdiction over the following functions:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Agricultural price and income support programs, production adjustment programs, and related programs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title I, § 194(c)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 946</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Agricultural credit programs assigned before <date date="1994-10-13">October 13, 1994</date>, by law to the Farmers Home Administration (including farm ownership and operating, emergency, and disaster loan programs) and other lending programs for agricultural producers and others engaged in the production of agricultural commodities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Subchapter B of chapter 1 of subtitle D of title XII of the Food Security Act of 1985 [<ref>16 U.S.C. 3831</ref> et seq.].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Such other functions as the Secretary considers appropriate, except for those programs assigned by the Secretary to the Natural Resources Conservation Service or another agency of the Department under <ref>section 6936(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special concurrence requirements for certain functions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In carrying out the programs specified in subsection (b)(4), the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> acting on the recommendations of the Farm Service Agency, with the concurrence of the Natural Resources Conservation Service, issue regulations to carry out such programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> ensure that the Farm Service Agency, in establishing policies, priorities, and guidelines for such programs, does so with the concurrence of the Natural Resources Conservation Service at national, State, and local levels;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> ensure that, in reaching such concurrence at the local level, the Natural Resources Conservation Service works in cooperation with Soil and Water Conservation Districts or similar organizations established under State law;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> ensure that officials of county and area committees established under <ref>section 590h(b)(5) of title 16</ref> meet annually with officials of such Districts or similar organizations to consider local conservation priorities and guidelines; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> take steps to ensure that the concurrence process does not interfere with the effective delivery of such programs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Jurisdiction over conservation program appeals</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Until such time as an adverse decision described in this paragraph is referred to the National Appeals Division for consideration, the Farm Service Agency shall have initial jurisdiction over any administrative appeal resulting from an adverse decision made under title XII of the Food Security Act of 1985 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 3801</ref> et seq.), including an adverse decision involving technical determinations made by the Natural Resources Conservation Service.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment of technical determination</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">With respect to administrative appeals involving a technical determination made by the Natural Resources Conservation Service, the Farm Service Agency, by rule with the concurrence of the Natural Resources Conservation Service, shall establish procedures for obtaining review by the Natural Resources Conservation Service of the technical determinations involved. Such rules shall ensure that technical criteria established by the Natural Resources Conservation Service shall be used by the Farm Service Agency as the basis for any decisions regarding technical determinations. If no review is requested, the technical determination of the Natural Resources Conservation Service shall be the technical basis for any decision rendered by a county or area committee established under <ref>section 590h(b)(5) of title 16</ref>. If the committee requests a review by the Natural Resources Conservation Service of a wetlands determination of the Service, the Farm Service Agency shall consult with other Federal agencies whenever required by law or under a memorandum of agreement in existence on <date date="1994-10-13">October 13, 1994</date>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Economic hardship</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">After a technical determination has been made, on a producer’s request, if a county or area committee determines that the application of the producer’s conservation system would impose an undue economic hardship on the producer, the committee shall provide the producer with relief to avoid the hardship.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reinstatement of program benefits</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Rules issued to carry out this subsection shall provide for the prompt reinstatement of benefits to a producer who is determined in an administrative appeal to meet the requirements of title XII of the Food Security Act of 1985 [<ref>16 U.S.C. 3801</ref> et seq.] applicable to the producer.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of Federal and non-Federal employees</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use authorized</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In the implementation of programs and activities assigned to the Farm Service Agency, the Secretary may use interchangeably in local offices of the Agency both Federal employees of the Department and non-Federal employees of county and area committees established under <ref>section 590h(b)(5) of title 16</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding paragraph (1), no personnel action (as defined in <ref>section 2302(a)(2)(A) of title 5</ref>) may be taken with respect to a Federal employee unless such action is taken by another Federal employee.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Collocation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">To the maximum extent practicable, the Secretary shall collocate county offices of the Farm Service Agency with county offices of the Natural Resources Conservation Service in order to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> maximize savings from shared equipment, office space, and administrative support;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> simplify paperwork and regulatory requirements;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> provide improved services to agricultural producers and landowners affected by programs administered by the Agency and the Service; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> achieve computer compatibility between the Agency and the Service to maximize efficiency and savings.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Savings provision</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of subsections (c) through (f) of this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A reference to the “Farm Service Agency” includes any other office, agency, or administrative unit of the Department assigned the functions authorized for the Farm Service Agency under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A reference to the “Natural Resources Conservation Service” includes any other office, agency, or administrative unit of the Department assigned the functions authorized for the Natural Resources Conservation Service under <ref>section 6936(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–354, title II, § 226</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3214</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title I, § 194(c)</ref>, title III, §§ 315(b), 336(a)(2)(C), <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 946</ref>, 985, 1005; <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title XII</ref>, §§ 12404(a), 12410(c)(2)(A), <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4974</ref>, 4978.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6932a.</num>
<heading> Prohibition on closure or relocation of county offices for the Farm Service Agency</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Temporary prohibition</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subject to paragraph (2), until the date that is two years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Agriculture may not close or relocate a county or field office of the Farm Service Agency.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Paragraph (1) shall not apply to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an office that is located not more than 20 miles from another office of the Farm Service Agency; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the relocation of an office within the same county in the course of routine leasing operations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on closure; notice</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">After the period referred to in subsection (a)(1), the Secretary shall, before closing any office of the Farm Service Agency that is located more than 20 miles from another office of the Farm Service Agency, to the maximum extent practicable, first close any offices of the Farm Service Agency that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> are located less than 20 miles from another office of the Farm Service Agency; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> have two or fewer permanent full-time employees.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">After the period referred to in subsection (a)(1), the Secretary of Agriculture may not close a county or field office of the Farm Service Agency unless—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> not later than 30 days after the Secretary proposes to close such office, the Secretary holds a public meeting regarding the proposed closure in the county in which such office is located; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> after the public meeting referred to in subparagraph (A), but not less than 90 days before the date on which the Secretary approves the closure of such office, the Secretary notifies the Committee on Agriculture and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, each Senator representing the State in which the office proposed to be closed is located, and the member of the House of Representatives who represents the Congressional district in which the office proposed to be closed is located of the proposed closure of such office.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title XIV, § 14212</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1465</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title XIV, § 14212, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2227.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6933.</num>
<heading> Office of Risk Management</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish and maintain in the Department an independent Office of Risk Management.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Functions of Office of Risk Management</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Office of Risk Management shall have jurisdiction over the following functions:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Supervision of the Federal Crop Insurance Corporation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Administration and oversight of all aspects, including delivery through local offices of the Department, of all programs authorized under the Federal Crop Insurance Act (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1501</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Any pilot or other programs involving revenue insurance, risk management savings accounts, or the use of the futures market to manage risk and support farm income that may be established under the Federal Crop Insurance Act or other law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Such other functions as the Secretary considers appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrator</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Office of Risk Management shall be headed by an Administrator who shall be appointed by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Manager</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Administrator of the Office of Risk Management shall also serve as Manager of the Federal Crop Insurance Corporation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Resources</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Functional coordination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Certain functions of the Office of Risk Management, such as human resources, public affairs, and legislative affairs, may be provided by a consolidation of such functions under the Under Secretary of Agriculture for Farm Production and Conservation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Minimum provisions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding paragraph (1) or any other provision of law or order of the Secretary, the Secretary shall provide the Office of Risk Management with human and capital resources sufficient for the Office to carry out its functions in a timely and efficient manner.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–354, title II, § 226A</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title I, § 194(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 945</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title XII</ref>, §§ 12405(a), 12415(a), <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4975</ref>, 4981.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6934.</num>
<heading> Office of Partnerships and Public Engagement</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Beginning farmer or rancher</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “beginning farmer or rancher” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 1991(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Office</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Office” means the Office of Partnerships and Public Engagement established under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Socially disadvantaged farmer or rancher</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “socially disadvantaged farmer or rancher” has the meaning given the term in section 2279(e) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002317">1</ref> of this title.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment and purpose</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary shall establish within the executive operations of the Department an office to be known as the “Office of Partnerships and Public Engagement”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to improve access to programs of the Department;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> to improve the viability and profitability of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> small farms and ranches;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> beginning farmers or ranchers;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> socially disadvantaged farmers or ranchers;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> limited resource producers; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> veteran farmers and ranchers; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to promote youth outreach.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Director</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Office shall be headed by a Director, to be appointed by the Secretary from among the competitive service.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The duties of the Office shall be to ensure small farms and ranches, beginning farmers or ranchers, veteran farmers and ranchers, and socially disadvantaged farmers or ranchers access to, and equitable participation in, programs and services of the Department by—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> establishing and monitoring the goals and objectives of the Department to increase participation in programs of the Department by small, beginning, socially disadvantaged, or veteran farmers or ranchers;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> assessing the effectiveness of Department outreach programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> developing and implementing a plan to coordinate outreach activities and services provided by the Department;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> providing input to the agencies and offices on programmatic and policy decisions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> measuring outcomes of the programs and activities of the Department on small farms and ranches, beginning farmers or ranchers, veteran farmers or ranchers, and socially disadvantaged farmers or ranchers programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> recommending new initiatives and programs to the Secretary; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> carrying out any other related duties that the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Socially disadvantaged farmers group</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall establish within the Office the Socially Disadvantaged Farmers Group.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Outreach and assistance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Socially Disadvantaged Farmers Group—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall carry out <ref>section 2279 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of activities described in section 2279(a) <sup>1</sup> of this title, may conduct such activities through other agencies and offices of the Department.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Socially disadvantaged farmers and farmworkers</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Socially Disadvantaged Farmers Group shall oversee the operations of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Advisory Committee on Minority Farmers established under section 14009 of the Food, Conservation, and Energy Act of 2008; <sup>1</sup> and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the position of Farmworker Coordinator established under subsection (f).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other duties</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Socially Disadvantaged Farmers Group may carry out other duties to improve access to, and participation in, programs of the Department by socially disadvantaged farmers or ranchers, as determined by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Office of Outreach and Diversity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Office of Partnerships and Public Engagement shall carry out the functions and duties of the Office of Outreach and Diversity carried out by the Assistant Secretary for Civil Rights as such functions and duties existed immediately before the date of the enactment of this section.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Small Farms and Beginning Farmers and Ranchers Group</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall establish within the Office the Small Farms and Beginning Farmers and Ranchers Group.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Oversee offices</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Small Farms and Beginning Farmers and Ranchers Group shall oversee the operations of the Office of Small Farms Coordination established by Departmental Regulation 9700–1 (<date date="2006-08-03">August 3, 2006</date>).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Beginning farmer and rancher development program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Small Farms and Beginning Farmers and Ranchers Group shall consult with the National Institute for Food and Agriculture on the administration of the beginning farmer and rancher development grant program established under subsection (d) of <ref>section 2279 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Advisory Committee for Beginning Farmers and Ranchers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Small Farms and Beginning Farmers and Ranchers Group shall coordinate the activities of the Group with the Advisory Committee for Beginning Farmers and Ranchers established under section 5(b) of the Agricultural Credit Improvement Act of 1992 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1621</ref> <sup>1</sup> note; <ref>Public Law 102–554</ref>).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other duties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Small Farms and Beginning Farmers and Ranchers Group may carry out other duties to improve access to, and participation in, programs of the Department by small farms and ranches and beginning farmers or ranchers, as determined by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Farmworker Coordinator</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall establish within the Office the position of Farmworker Coordinator (referred to in this subsection as the “Coordinator”).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary shall delegate to the Coordinator responsibility for the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Assisting in administering the program established by <ref>section 5177a of title 42</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Serving as a liaison to community-based nonprofit organizations that represent and have demonstrated experience serving low-income migrant and seasonal farmworkers.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Coordinating with the Department, other Federal agencies, and State and local governments to ensure that farmworker needs are assessed and met during declared disasters and other emergencies.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Consulting within the Office and with other entities to better integrate farmworker perspectives, concerns, and interests into the ongoing programs of the Department.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Consulting with appropriate institutions on research, program improvements, or agricultural education opportunities that assist low-income and migrant seasonal farmworkers.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Assisting farmworkers in becoming agricultural producers or landowners.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> such sums as are necessary for each of fiscal years 2009 through 2013; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> $2,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2014 through 2023.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–354, title II, § 226B</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title XIV, § 14013(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1450</ref>, and <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title XIV, § 14013(a), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2212; amended <ref>Pub. L. 113–79, title XII, § 12202</ref>, <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 984</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title XII</ref>, §§ 12301(a)(2)(A), 12406(a)(1), (b), (c), <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4950</ref>, 4975, 4976.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6934a.</num>
<heading> Beginning farmer and rancher coordination</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Beginning farmer or rancher</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “beginning farmer or rancher” has the meaning given such term in <ref>section 2279(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National Coordinator</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “National Coordinator” means the National Beginning Farmer and Rancher Coordinator established under subsection (b)(1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State coordinator</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “State coordinator” means a State beginning farmer and rancher coordinator designated under subsection (c)(1)(A).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State office</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “State office” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> a State office of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Farm Service Agency;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the Natural Resources Conservation Service;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the Rural Business-Cooperative Service; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the Rural Utilities Service; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a regional office of the Risk Management Agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National Beginning Farmer and Rancher Coordinator</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall establish in the Department the position of National Beginning Farmer and Rancher Coordinator.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The National Coordinator shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> advise the Secretary and coordinate activities of the Department on programs, policies, and issues relating to beginning farmers and ranchers; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in consultation with the applicable State food and agriculture council, determine whether to approve a plan submitted by a State coordinator under subsection (c)(3)(B).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Discretionary duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Additional duties of the National Coordinator may include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> developing and implementing new strategies—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> for outreach to beginning farmers and ranchers; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> to assist beginning farmers and ranchers with connecting to owners or operators that have ended, or expect to end within 5 years, actively owning or operating a farm or ranch; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> facilitating interagency and interdepartmental collaboration on issues relating to beginning farmers and ranchers.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not less frequently than once each year, the National Coordinator shall distribute within the Department and make publicly available a report describing the status of steps taken to carry out the duties described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (2).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contracts and cooperative agreements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In carrying out the duties under paragraph (2), the National Coordinator may enter into a contract or cooperative agreement with an institution of higher education (as defined in <ref>section 1001 of title 20</ref>), cooperative extension services (as defined in <ref>section 3103 of this title</ref>), or a nonprofit organization—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to conduct research on the profitability of new farms in operation for not less than 5 years in a region;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to develop educational materials;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to conduct workshops, courses, training, or certified vocational training; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> to conduct mentoring activities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State beginning farmer and rancher coordinators</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Designation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The National Coordinator, in consultation with State food and agriculture councils and directors of State offices, shall designate in each State a State beginning farmer and rancher coordinator from among employees of State offices.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">To be designated as a State coordinator, an employee shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> be familiar with issues relating to beginning farmers and ranchers; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> have the ability to coordinate with other Federal departments and agencies.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Training</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall develop a training plan to provide to each State coordinator knowledge of programs and services available from the Department for beginning farmers and ranchers, taking into consideration the needs of all production types and sizes of agricultural operations.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A State coordinator shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> coordinate technical assistance at the State level to assist beginning farmers and ranchers in accessing programs of the Department;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> develop and submit to the National Coordinator for approval under subsection (b)(2)(A)(ii) a State plan to improve the coordination, delivery, and efficacy of programs of the Department to beginning farmers and ranchers, taking into consideration the needs of all types of production methods and sizes of agricultural operation, at each county and area office in the State;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> oversee implementation of an approved State plan described in subparagraph (B);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> work with outreach coordinators in the State offices to ensure appropriate information about technical assistance is available at outreach events and activities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> coordinate partnerships and joint outreach efforts with other organizations and government agencies serving beginning farmers and ranchers.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–171, title VII, § 7404</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title XII, § 12304</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4965</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6934b.</num>
<heading> Agricultural Youth Organization Coordinator</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish in the Department the position of Agricultural Youth Organization Coordinator.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Agricultural Youth Organization Coordinator shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> promote the role of youth-serving organizations and school-based agricultural education in motivating and preparing young people to pursue careers in the agriculture, food, and natural resources systems;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> work to help build youth awareness of the reach and importance of agriculture, across a diversity of fields and disciplines;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> identify short-term and long-term interests of the Department and provide opportunities, resources, input, and coordination with programs and agencies of the Department to youth-serving organizations and school-based agricultural education, including the development of internship opportunities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> share, internally and externally, the extent to which active steps are being taken to encourage collaboration with, and support of, youth-serving organizations and school-based agricultural education;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> provide information to youth involved in food and agriculture organizations concerning the availability of, and eligibility requirements for, participation in agricultural programs, with particular emphasis on beginning farmer and rancher programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> serve as a resource for assisting youth involved in food and agriculture organizations in applying for participation in agriculture; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> advocate on behalf of youth involved in food and agriculture organizations in interactions with employees of the Department.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contracts and cooperative agreements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of carrying out the duties under subsection (b), the Agricultural Youth Organization Coordinator shall consult with the cooperative extension and the land-grant university systems, and may enter into contracts or cooperative agreements with the research centers of the Agricultural Research Service, cooperative extension and the land-grant university systems, non-land-grant colleges of agriculture, or nonprofit organizations for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the conduct of regional research on the profitability of small farms;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the development of educational materials;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the conduct of workshops, courses, and certified vocational training;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the conduct of mentoring activities; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the provision of internship opportunities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–171, title VII, § 7405</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title XII, § 12305</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4967</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6935.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title XII, § 12414(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4981</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6936.</num>
<heading> Natural Resources Conservation Service</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to establish and maintain within the Department a Natural Resources Conservation Service.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Functions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">If the Secretary establishes the Natural Resources Conservation Service under subsection (a), the Secretary is authorized to assign to the Service jurisdiction over the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Water Bank Act (<ref>16 U.S.C. 1301</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Title XII of the Food Security Act of 1985 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 3801</ref> et seq.), except subchapter B of chapter 1 of subtitle D of such title [<ref>16 U.S.C. 3831</ref> et seq.].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Salinity control measures under <ref>section 1592(c) of title 43</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Farms for the Future Act of 1990 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 4201</ref> note; <ref>Public Law 101–624</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Such other functions as the Secretary considers appropriate, except functions under subchapter B of chapter 1 of subtitle D of title XII of the Food Security Act of 1985 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 3831</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special concurrence requirements for certain functions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In carrying out the programs specified in paragraphs (1) and (3) of subsection (b), the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> acting on the recommendations of the Natural Resources Conservation Service, with the concurrence of the Farm Service Agency, issue regulations to carry out such programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> ensure that the Natural Resources Conservation Service, in establishing policies, priorities, and guidelines for each such program, does so with the concurrence of the Farm Service Agency at national, State, and local levels;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> ensure that, in reaching such concurrence at the local level, the Natural Resources Conservation Service works in cooperation with Soil and Water Conservation Districts or similar organizations established under State law;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> ensure that officials of county and area committees established under <ref>section 590h(b)(5) of title 16</ref> meet annually with officials of such Districts or similar organizations to consider local conservation priorities and guidelines; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> take steps to ensure that the concurrence process does not interfere with the effective delivery of such programs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of Federal and non-Federal employees</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use authorized</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In the implementation of functions assigned to the Natural Resources Conservation Service, the Secretary may use interchangeably in local offices of the Service both Federal employees of the Department and non-Federal employees of county and area committees established under <ref>section 590h(b)(5) of title 16</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding paragraph (1), no personnel action (as defined in <ref>section 2302(a)(2)(A) of title 5</ref>) may be taken with respect to a Federal employee unless such action is taken by another Federal employee.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Savings provision</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of subsections (c) and (d) of this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A reference to the “Natural Resources Conservation Service” includes any other office, agency, or administrative unit of the Department assigned the functions authorized for the Natural Resources Conservation Service under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A reference to the “Farm Service Agency” includes any other office, agency, or administrative unit of the Department assigned the functions authorized for the Farm Service Agency under <ref>section 6932 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Field offices</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall not close any field office of the Natural Resources Conservation Service unless, not later than 30 days before the date of the closure, the Secretary submits to the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate a notification of the closure.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Employees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall not permanently relocate any field-based employees of the Natural Resources Conservation Service or the rural development mission area if doing so would result in a field office of the Natural Resources Conservation Service or the rural development mission area with 2 or fewer employees, unless, not later than 30 days before the date of the permanent relocation, the Secretary submits to the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate a notification of the permanent relocation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sunset</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The requirements under paragraphs (1) and (2) shall cease to be effective on <date date="2023-09-30">September 30, 2023</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–354, title II, § 228</ref>, formerly § 246, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3223</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title III, § 336(a)(2)(D)</ref>, (b)(2)(B), (c)(3), (d)(2), <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1005</ref>, 1006; <ref>Pub. L. 107–171, title VIII, § 8002(c)</ref>, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 473</ref>; renumbered § 228 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title XII</ref>, §§ 12404(b)(1), 12410(a)–(c)(1), <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4975</ref>, 4977, 4978.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>RURAL ECONOMIC AND COMMUNITY DEVELOPMENT</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6941.</num>
<heading> Under Secretary of Agriculture for Rural Development</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish in the Department the position of Under Secretary of Agriculture for Rural Development.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Confirmation required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Under Secretary of Agriculture for Rural Development shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Functions of Under Secretary</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Principal functions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Upon establishment, the Secretary shall delegate to the Under Secretary of Agriculture for Rural Development those functions under the jurisdiction of the Department that are related to rural economic and community development.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional functions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Under Secretary of Agriculture for Rural Development shall perform such other functions as may be required by law or prescribed by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Succession</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any official who is serving as Under Secretary of Agriculture for Small Community and Rural Development on <date date="1994-10-13">October 13, 1994</date>, and who was appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, shall not be required to be reappointed under subsection (b) to the successor position authorized under subsection (a) if the Secretary establishes the position, and the official occupies the new position, within 180 days after <date date="1994-10-13">October 13, 1994</date> (or such later date set by the Secretary if litigation delays rapid succession).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Loan approval authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Approval authority for loans and loan guarantees in connection with the electric and telephone loan and loan guarantee programs authorized by the Rural Electrification Act of 1936 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 901</ref> et seq.) shall not be transferred to, or conditioned on review of, a State director or other employee whose primary duty is not the review and approval of such loans or the provision of assistance to such borrowers.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–354, title II, § 231</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3218</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title VII, § 794(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1155</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title XII, § 12407</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4976</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6941a.</num>
<heading> Coordinator for Chronically Underserved Rural Areas</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture shall establish a Coordinator for Chronically Underserved Rural Areas (in this section referred to as the “Coordinator”), to be located in the Rural Development Mission Area.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Mission</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The mission of the Coordinator shall be to direct Department of Agriculture resources to high need, high poverty rural areas.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Coordinator shall consult with other offices in directing technical assistance, strategic regional planning, at the State and local level, for developing rural economic development that leverages the resources of State and local governments and non-profit and community development organizations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary such sums as necessary to carry out this section for fiscal years 2008 through 2012.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title XIV, § 14218</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1482</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title XIV, § 14218, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2244.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6942.</num>
<heading> Rural Utilities Service</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish and maintain within the Department the Rural Utilities Service and assign to the Service such functions as the Secretary considers appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrator</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Rural Utilities Service shall be headed by an Administrator who shall be appointed by the President.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Administrator of the Rural Utilities Service shall receive basic pay at a rate not to exceed the maximum amount of compensation payable to a member of the Senior Executive Service under subsection (b) of <ref>section 5382 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Functions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall carry out through the Rural Utilities Service the following functions that are under the jurisdiction of the Department:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Electric and telephone loan programs and water and waste facility activities authorized by law, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Rural Electrification Act of 1936 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 901</ref> et seq.); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> section 1926–1 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002318">1</ref> of this title; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Water and waste facility programs and activities authorized by law, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> sections 1926, 1926a, 1926b,<sup>1</sup> and 1926c of this title, the provisions of sections 1929 and 1929a of this title relating to assets, terms, and conditions of water and sewer programs, <ref>section 1932(b) of this title</ref>, and <ref>section 1013a of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> section 2324 of the Food, Agriculture, Conservation, and Trade Act of 1990 <sup>1</sup> (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1926</ref> note).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–354, title II, § 232</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3219</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title VII, § 747(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1128</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–166, § 2(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2012-08-10">Aug. 10, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1283</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title XII, § 12408(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4976</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6943.</num>
<heading> Rural Housing and Community Development Service</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment authorized</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary is authorized to establish and maintain within the Department the Rural Housing and Community Development Service and to assign to the Service such functions as the Secretary considers appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Functions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">If the Secretary establishes the Rural Housing and Community Development Service under subsection (a), the Secretary is authorized to assign to the Service jurisdiction over the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Programs and activities under title V of the Housing Act of 1949 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 1471</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Programs and activities that relate to rural community lending programs, including programs authorized by <ref>section 2008d of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–354, title II, § 233</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3219</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title VII</ref>, §§ 747(b)(3), 753(b)(2), <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1128</ref>, 1131.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6944.</num>
<heading> Rural Business and Cooperative Development Service</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment authorized</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary is authorized to establish and maintain within the Department the Rural Business and Cooperative Development Service and to assign to the Service such functions as the Secretary considers appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Functions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">If the Secretary establishes the Rural Business and Cooperative Development Service under subsection (a), the Secretary is authorized to assign to the Service jurisdiction over the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Section 313 and title V of the Rural Electrification Act of 1936 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 940c</ref> and 950aa et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Subtitle G <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002319">1</ref> of title XVI of the Food, Agriculture, Conservation, and Trade Act of 1990.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Sections 306(a)(1) and 310B of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1926(a)(1)</ref> and 1932).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Section 1323 of the Food Security Act of 1985 (<ref>Public Law 99–198</ref>; <ref>7 U.S.C. 1932</ref> note).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The Act of <date date="1926-07-02">July 2, 1926</date> (<ref>44 Stat. 802</ref>, chapter 725; <ref>7 U.S.C. 451</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–354, title II, § 234</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3220</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6945.</num>
<heading> Rural Development Disaster Assistance Fund</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rural Development Disaster Assistance Fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On and after <date date="2008-09-30">September 30, 2008</date>, there is established in the Treasury a fund entitled the “Rural Development Disaster Assistance Fund”.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purpose and availability of Fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to subsection (d), amounts in the Rural Development Disaster Assistance Fund shall be available to the Secretary of Agriculture, until expended, to provide additional amounts, in the form of loans, grants, loan guarantees, or cooperative agreements, for any authorized activity of agencies of the Rural Development Mission Area in areas affected by a disaster declared by the President, the Secretary of Agriculture, or the Governor of a State or Territory. The cost of such direct and guaranteed loans, including the cost of modifying loans, shall be as defined in <ref>section 661a of title 2</ref>. Amounts so provided shall be in addition to any other amounts available to carry out the activity, but shall not be limited to the original form of assistance, if any. In carrying out this section, the Secretary may transfer funds into existing or new accounts as determined by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Waiver of activity or project limitations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For any activity or project for which amounts in the Rural Development Disaster Assistance Fund will be obligated under subsection (b)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Agriculture may waive any limits on population, income, age, and duplication with respect to replacement of damaged or destroyed utilities, or cost-sharing otherwise applicable, except that, if the amounts proposed to be obligated in connection with the disaster would exceed the amount specified in subsection (h), the notification required by that subsection shall include information and justification with regard to any waivers to be granted under this subsection;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Agriculture may use alternative sources of income data provided by local, regional, State, or Federal government sources to determine program eligibility; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> with respect to grants authorized by <ref>7 U.S.C. 1926(a)(19)</ref>,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002320">1</ref> the Secretary of Agriculture shall not require the applicant to demonstrate that it is unable to finance the proposed project from its own resources, or through commercial credit at reasonable rates and terms, or other funding sources without grant assistance.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment of certain amounts in Fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Amounts appropriated directly to the Rural Development Disaster Assistance Fund by this Act or any subsequent Act for a specific purpose shall be available only for that purpose until such time as the transfer authority provided by subsection (f) takes effect with regard to the amounts. Only subsection (c), including the notification requirements of such subsection, and subsections (g) and (i) apply to amounts described in this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer of prior appropriations to Fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture may transfer to the Rural Development Disaster Assistance Fund, and merge with other amounts generally appropriated to the Fund, the available unobligated balance of any amounts that were appropriated before <date date="2008-09-30">September 30, 2008</date>, for programs and activities of the Rural Development Mission Area to respond to a disaster and were designated by the Congress as an emergency requirement if, in advance of the transfer, the Secretary determines that the unobligated amounts are no longer needed to respond to the disaster for which the amounts were originally appropriated and the Secretary provides a certification of this determination to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer of other appropriations to Fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Unless otherwise specifically provided in an appropriations Act, the Secretary of Agriculture may transfer to or within the Rural Development Disaster Assistance Fund, and merge with other amounts generally appropriated to the Fund, the available unobligated balance of any amounts that are appropriated for fiscal year 2009 or any subsequent fiscal year for programs and activities of the Rural Development Mission Area to respond to a disaster and are designated by the Congress as an emergency requirement if, in advance of the transfer, the Secretary determines that the unobligated amounts are no longer needed to respond to the disaster for which the amounts were originally appropriated and the Secretary provides a certification of this determination to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate. A transfer of unobligated amounts with respect to a disaster may not be made under this subsection until after the end of the two-year period beginning on the date on which the amounts were originally appropriated for that disaster.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrative expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In addition to any other funds available to the Secretary of Agriculture to cover administrative costs, the Secretary may use up to 3 percent of the amounts allocated from the Rural Development Disaster Assistance Fund for a specific disaster to cover administrative costs of Rural Development’s State and local offices in the areas affected by the disaster to carry out disaster related activities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on per disaster obligations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Amounts in the Rural Development Disaster Assistance Fund, except for amounts described in subsection (d) that are appropriated to the Fund and obligated in accordance with that subsection, may not be obligated in excess of $1,000,000 for a disaster until at least 15 days after the date on which the Secretary of Agriculture notifies the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate of the Secretary’s determination to obligate additional amounts and the reasons for the determination. The Secretary may not obligate more than 50 percent of the funds contained in the Rural Development Disaster Assistance Fund for any one disaster unless the Secretary declares that there is a specific and extreme need that additional funds must be provided in response to such disaster at time of the obligation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Quarterly reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture shall submit, on a quarterly basis, to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate a report describing the status of the Rural Development Disaster Assistance Fund and any transactions that have affected the Fund since the previous report.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–329, div. B, title I, § 10101</ref>, <date date="2008-09-30">Sept. 30, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 3586</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–80, title VII, § 702</ref>, <date date="2009-10-21">Oct. 21, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2118</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–158, div. B, § 2101(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="2024-12-21">Dec. 21, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1730</ref>, 1731.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6946.</num>
<heading> Rural Health Liaison</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish in the Department the position of Rural Health Liaison.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Rural Health Liaison shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, coordinate the role of the Department with respect to rural health;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> integrate across the Department the strategic planning and activities relating to rural health;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> improve communication relating to rural health within the Department and between Federal agencies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> advocate on behalf of the health care and relevant infrastructure needs in rural areas;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> provide to stakeholders, potential grant applicants, Federal agencies, State agencies, Indian Tribes, private organizations, and academic institutions relevant data and information, including the eligibility requirements for, and availability and outcomes of, Department programs applicable to the advancement of rural health;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> maintain communication with public health, medical, occupational safety, and telecommunication associations, research entities, and other stakeholders to ensure that the Department is aware of current and upcoming issues relating to rural health;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> consult on programs, pilot projects, research, training, and other affairs relating to rural health at the Department and other Federal agencies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> provide expertise on rural health to support the activities of the Secretary as Chair of the Council on Rural Community Innovation and Economic Development; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> provide technical assistance and guidance with respect to activities relating to rural health to the outreach, extension, and county offices of the Department.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–354, title II, § 236</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title XII, § 12409</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4977</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>FOOD, NUTRITION, AND CONSUMER SERVICES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6951.</num>
<heading> Under Secretary of Agriculture for Food, Nutrition, and Consumer Services</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to establish in the Department the position of Under Secretary of Agriculture for Food, Nutrition, and Consumer Services.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Confirmation required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the Secretary establishes the position of Under Secretary of Agriculture for Food, Nutrition, and Consumer Services authorized under subsection (a), the Under Secretary shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Functions of Under Secretary</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Principal functions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Upon establishment, the Secretary shall delegate to the Under Secretary of Agriculture for Food, Nutrition, and Consumer Services those functions under the jurisdiction of the Department that are related to food, nutrition, and consumer services (except as provided in <ref>section 6981(b)(1) of this title</ref>).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional functions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Under Secretary of Agriculture for Food, Nutrition, and Consumer Services shall perform such other functions as may be required by law or prescribed by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Succession</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any official who is serving as Assistant Secretary of Agriculture for Food and Consumer Services on <date date="1994-10-13">October 13, 1994</date>, and who was appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, shall not be required to be reappointed under subsection (b) to the successor position authorized under subsection (a) if the Secretary establishes the position, and the official occupies the new position, within 180 days after <date date="1994-10-13">October 13, 1994</date> (or such later date set by the Secretary if litigation delays rapid succession).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–354, title II, § 241</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3222</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6952.</num>
<heading> Multiagency task force</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish, in the office of the Under Secretary for Food, Nutrition, and Consumer Services, a multiagency task force for the purpose of providing coordination and direction for commodity programs.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Composition</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Task Force shall be composed of at least 4 members, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> a representative from the Food Distribution Division of the Food and Nutrition Service, who shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> be appointed by the Under Secretary for Food, Nutrition, and Consumer Services; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> serve as Chairperson of the Task Force;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> at least 1 representative from the Agricultural Marketing Service, who shall be appointed by the Under Secretary for Marketing and Regulatory Programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> at least 1 representative from the Farm Services Agency, who shall be appointed by the Under Secretary of Agriculture for Farm Production and Conservation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> at least 1 representative from the Food Safety and Inspection Service, who shall be appointed by the Under Secretary for Food Safety.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Task Force shall be responsible for evaluation and monitoring of the commodity programs to ensure that the commodity programs meet the mission of the Department—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to support the United States farm sector; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to contribute to the health and well-being of individuals in the United States through the distribution of domestic agricultural products through commodity programs.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Specific duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In carrying out paragraph (1), the Task Force shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> review and make recommendations regarding the specifications used for the procurement of food commodities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> review and make recommendations regarding the efficient and effective distribution of food commodities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> review and make recommendations regarding the degree to which the quantity, quality, and specifications of procured food commodities align the needs of producers and the preferences of recipient agencies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2014-02-07">February 7, 2014</date>, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report that describes, for the period covered by the report—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the findings and recommendations of the Task Force; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> policies implemented for the improvement of commodity procurement programs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–354, title II, § 242</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 113–79, title IV, § 4205</ref>, <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 823</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title XII, § 12405(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4975</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6953.</num>
<heading> Healthy food financing initiative</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purpose</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The purpose of this section is to enhance the authorities of the Secretary to support efforts to provide access to healthy food by establishing an initiative to improve access to healthy foods in underserved areas, to create and preserve quality jobs, and to revitalize low-income communities by providing loans and grants to eligible fresh, healthy food retailers and enterprises to overcome the higher costs and initial barriers to entry in underserved areas.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Community development financial institution</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “community development financial institution” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 4702 of title 12</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initiative</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Initiative” means the Healthy Food Financing Initiative established under subsection (c)(1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National fund manager</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “national fund manager” means a community development financial institution that is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in existence on the date of enactment of this section; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> certified by the Community Development Financial Institution Fund of the Department of Treasury to manage the Initiative for purposes of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> raising private capital;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> providing financial and technical assistance to partnerships; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> funding eligible projects to attract fresh, healthy food retailers and enterprises to underserved areas, in accordance with this section.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Partnership</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “partnership” means a regional, State, or local public-private partnership that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is organized to improve access to fresh, healthy foods;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provides financial and technical assistance to eligible projects; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> meets such other criteria as the Secretary may establish.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Perishable food</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “perishable food” means a staple food that is fresh, refrigerated, or frozen.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Quality job</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “quality job” means a job that provides wages and other benefits comparable to, or better than, similar positions in existing businesses of similar size in similar local economies.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Staple food</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “staple food” means food that is a basic dietary item.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inclusions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “staple food” includes—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> bread or cereal;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> flour;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> fruits;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> vegetables;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> meat; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> dairy products.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initiative</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall establish an initiative to achieve the purpose described in subsection (a) in accordance with this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementation</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">In carrying out the Initiative, the Secretary shall provide funding to entities with eligible projects, as described in subparagraph (B), subject to the priorities described in subparagraph (C).</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">Funds provided to an entity pursuant to clause (i) shall be used—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> to create revolving loan pools of capital or other products to provide loans to finance eligible projects or partnerships;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> to provide grants for eligible projects or partnerships;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> to provide technical assistance to funded projects and entities seeking Initiative funding; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> to cover administrative expenses of the national fund manager in an amount not to exceed 10 percent of the Federal funds provided.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible projects</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Subject to the approval of the Secretary, the national fund manager shall establish eligibility criteria for projects under the Initiative, which shall include the existence or planned execution of agreements—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> to expand or preserve the availability of staple foods in underserved areas with moderate- and low-income populations by maintaining or increasing the number of retail outlets that offer an assortment of perishable food and staple food items, as determined by the Secretary, in those areas; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> as applicable, to accept benefits under the supplemental nutrition assistance program established under the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 2011</ref> et seq.).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Priorities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In carrying out the Initiative, priority shall be given to projects that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> are located in severely distressed low-income communities, as defined by the Community Development Financial Institutions Fund of the Department of Treasury; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> include 1 or more of the following characteristics:</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> The project will create or retain quality jobs for low-income residents in the community.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> The project supports regional food systems and locally grown foods, to the maximum extent practicable.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> In areas served by public transit, the project is accessible by public transit.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> The project involves women- or minority-owned businesses.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(V)</num>
<content> The project receives funding from other sources, including other Federal agencies.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(VI)</num>
<content> The project otherwise advances the purpose of this section, as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this section $125,000,000, to remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–354, title II, § 243</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 113–79, title IV, § 4206</ref>, <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 824</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title IV, § 4204</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4656</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER V—</num>
<heading>NATURAL RESOURCES AND ENVIRONMENT</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6961.</num>
<heading> Under Secretary of Agriculture for Natural Resources and Environment</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to establish in the Department the position of Under Secretary of Agriculture for Natural Resources and Environment.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Confirmation required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the Secretary establishes the position of Under Secretary of Agriculture for Natural Resources and Environment authorized under subsection (a), the Under Secretary shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Functions of Under Secretary</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Principal functions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Upon establishment, the Secretary shall delegate to the Under Secretary of Agriculture for Natural Resources and Environment those functions under the jurisdiction of the Department that are related to natural resources and environment (except to the extent those functions are delegated under <ref>section 6932 of this title</ref>).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional functions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Under Secretary of Agriculture for Natural Resources and Environment shall perform such other functions and duties as may be required by law or prescribed by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Succession</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any official who is serving as Assistant Secretary of Agriculture for Natural Resources and Environment on <date date="1994-10-13">October 13, 1994</date>, and who was appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, shall not be required to be reappointed under subsection (b) to the successor position authorized under subsection (a) if the Secretary establishes the position, and the official occupies the new position, within 180 days after <date date="1994-10-13">October 13, 1994</date> (or such later date set by the Secretary if litigation delays rapid succession).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–354, title II, § 245</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3223</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6962.</num>
<heading> Transferred</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6962a.</num>
<heading> Cooperative agreements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law (including provisions of law requiring competition), the Secretary of Agriculture may on and after <date date="2000-10-28">October 28, 2000</date>, enter into cooperative agreements (which may provide for the acquisition of goods or services, including personal services) with a State, political subdivision, or agency thereof, a public or private agency, organization, or any other person, if the Secretary determines that the objectives of the agreement will: (1) serve a mutual interest of the parties to the agreement in carrying out the programs administered by the Natural Resources Conservation Service; and (2) all parties will contribute resources to the accomplishment of these objectives: <i>Provided</i>, That Commodity Credit Corporation funds obligated for such purposes shall not exceed the level obligated by the Commodity Credit Corporation for such purposes in fiscal year 1998.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–387, § 1(a) [title VII, § 714]</ref>, <date date="2000-10-28">Oct. 28, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1549</ref>, 1549A–30.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6963.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title XII, § 12414(a)(5)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4981</ref></heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER VI—</num>
<heading>RESEARCH, EDUCATION, AND ECONOMICS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6971.</num>
<heading> Under Secretary of Agriculture for Research, Education, and Economics</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to establish in the Department the position of Under Secretary of Agriculture for Research, Education, and Economics (referred to in this section as the “Under Secretary”).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Confirmation required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Under Secretary shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, from among distinguished scientists with specialized training or significant experience in agricultural research, education, and economics.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Chief Scientist</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Under Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> hold the title of Chief Scientist of the Department; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> be responsible for the coordination of the research, education, and extension activities of the Department.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Functions of Under Secretary</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Principal function</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall delegate to the Under Secretary those functions and duties under the jurisdiction of the Department that relate to research, education, and economics.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Specific functions and duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Under Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> identify, address, and prioritize current and emerging agricultural research, education, and extension needs (including funding);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> ensure that agricultural research, education, and extension programs are effectively coordinated and integrated—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> across disciplines, agencies, and institutions; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> among applicable participants, grantees, and beneficiaries;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> promote the collaborative use of all agricultural research, education, and extension resources from the local, State, tribal, regional, national, and international levels to address priority needs; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> foster communication among agricultural research, education, and extension beneficiaries, including the public, to ensure the delivery of agricultural research, education, and extension knowledge.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional functions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Under Secretary shall perform such other functions and duties as may be required by law or prescribed by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Office of the Chief Scientist</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Under Secretary shall organize within the office of the Under Secretary 6 Divisions, to be known collectively as the “Office of the Chief Scientist”, which shall coordinate the research programs and activities of the Department.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Division designations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Divisions within the Office of the Chief Scientist shall be as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Renewable energy, natural resources, and environment.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Food safety, nutrition, and health.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Plant health and production and plant products.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Animal health and production and animal products.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Agricultural systems and technology.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Agricultural economics and rural communities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Division Chiefs</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Selection</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Under Secretary shall select a Division Chief for each Division using available personnel authority under title 5, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> by term, temporary, or other appointment, without regard to—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the provisions of title 5 governing appointments in the competitive service;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the provisions of subchapter I of chapter 35 of title 5 relating to retention preference; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5 relating to classification and General Schedule pay rates;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> by detail, notwithstanding any Act making appropriations for the Department of Agriculture, whether enacted before, on, or after the date of enactment of this paragraph, requiring reimbursement for those details unless the appropriation Act specifically refers to this subsection and specifically includes these details;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> by reassignment or transfer from any other civil service position; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> by an assignment under subchapter VI of chapter 33 of title 5.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Selection guidelines</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">To the maximum extent practicable, the Under Secretary shall select Division Chiefs under subparagraph (A) in a manner that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> promotes leadership and professional development;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> enables personnel to interact with other agencies of the Department; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> maximizes the ability of the Under Secretary to allow for rotations of Department personnel into the position of Division Chief.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Term of service</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Notwithstanding title 5, the maximum length of service for an individual selected as a Division Chief under clauses (i) and (iii) of subparagraph (A) shall be for not less than 3 years.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Qualifications</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">To be eligible for selection as a Division Chief, an individual shall have—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> conducted exemplary research, education, or extension in the field of agriculture or forestry; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> earned an advanced degree at an institution of higher education (as defined in <ref>section 1001 of title 20</ref>).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(E)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties of Division Chiefs</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Except as otherwise provided in this Act, each Division Chief shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> assist the Under Secretary in identifying and addressing emerging agricultural research, education, and extension needs;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> assist the Under Secretary in identifying and prioritizing Department-wide agricultural research, education, and extension needs, including funding;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> assess the strategic workforce needs of the research, education, and extension functions of the Department, and develop strategic workforce plans to ensure that existing and future workforce needs are met;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> communicate with research, education, and extension beneficiaries, including the public, and representatives of the research, education, and extension system, including the National Agricultural Research, Extension, Education, and Economics Advisory Board, to promote the benefits of agricultural research, education, and extension;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> assist the Under Secretary in preparing and implementing the roadmap for agricultural research, education, and extension, as described in <ref>section 7614a of this title</ref>; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> perform such other duties as the Under Secretary may determine.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional leadership duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In addition to selecting the Division Chiefs under paragraph (3), using available personnel authority under title 5, the Under Secretary shall select personnel—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to oversee implementation, training, and compliance with the scientific integrity policy of the Department;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> to integrate strategic program planning and evaluation functions across the programs of the Department; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> to help prepare the annual report to Congress on the relevance and adequacy of programs under the jurisdiction of the Under Secretary;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to assist the Chief Scientist in coordinating the international engagements of the Department with the Department of State and other international agencies and offices of the Federal Government; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> to oversee other duties as may be required by Federal law or Department policy.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General administration</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Funding</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">There is authorized to be appropriated such sums as are necessary to fund the costs of Division personnel.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional funding</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">In addition to amounts made available under clause (i), notwithstanding any Act making appropriations for the Department of Agriculture, whether enacted before, on, or after the date of enactment of this paragraph unless the appropriation Act specifically refers to this subsection and specifically includes the administration of funds under this section, the Secretary may transfer funds made available to an agency in the research, education, and economics mission area to fund the costs of Division personnel.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">To the maximum extent practicable—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Under Secretary shall minimize the number of full-time equivalent positions in the Divisions; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> at no time shall the aggregate number of staff for all Divisions exceed 30 full-time equivalent positions.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rotation of personnel</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">To the maximum extent practicable, and using the authority described in paragraph (3)(A), the Under Secretary shall rotate personnel among the Divisions, and between the Divisions and agencies of the Department, in a manner that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> promotes leadership and professional development;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> enables personnel to interact with other agencies of the Department; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> provides strong staff continuity to the Office of the Chief Scientist.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Organization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Under Secretary shall integrate leadership functions of the national program staff of the research agencies into the Office of the Chief Scientist in such form as is required to ensure that administrative duplication does not occur.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National Institute of Food and Agriculture</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In this subsection:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Advisory Board</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “Advisory Board” means the National Agricultural Research, Extension, Education, and Economics Advisory Board established under section 1408 of the National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act of 1977 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 3123</ref>).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applied research</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “applied research” means research that includes expansion of the findings of fundamental research to uncover practical ways in which new knowledge can be advanced to benefit individuals and society.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Capacity and infrastructure program</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “capacity and infrastructure program” means each of the following agricultural research, extension, education, and related programs for which the Secretary has administrative or other authority as of the day before the date of enactment of the Food, Conservation, and Energy Act of 2008:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Each program providing funding to any of the 1994 Institutions under sections 533, 534(a), and 535 of the Equity in Educational Land-Grant Status Act of 1994 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 301</ref> note; <ref>Public Law 103–382</ref>).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The program established under section 536 of the Equity in Educational Land-Grant Status Act of 1994 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 301</ref> note; <ref>Public Law 103–382</ref>) providing research grants for 1994 Institutions.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Each program established under subsections (b) and (c) of <ref>section 343 of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> Each program established under the Hatch Act of 1887 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 361a</ref> et seq.).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> Each program established under section 1417(b) of the National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act of 1977 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 3152(b)</ref>).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> The animal health and disease research program established under subtitle E of the National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act of 1977 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 3191</ref> et seq.) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002321">1</ref> except for the competitive grant program under section 1433(b) [<ref>7 U.S.C. 3195(b)</ref>].</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> Each extension program available to 1890 Institutions established under section 1444 of the National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act of 1977 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 3221</ref>).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> The program established under section 1445 of the National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act of 1977 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 3222</ref>).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ix)</num>
<content> The program providing grants to upgrade agricultural and food sciences facilities at 1890 Institutions established under section 1447 of the National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act of 1977 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 3222b</ref>).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(x)</num>
<content> The program providing distance education grants for insular areas established under section 1490 of the National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act of 1977 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 3362</ref>).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(xi)</num>
<content> The program providing resident instruction grants for insular areas established under section 1491 of the National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act of 1977 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 3363</ref>).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(xii)</num>
<content> Each research and development and related program established under <ref>Public Law 87–788</ref> (commonly known as the “McIntire-Stennis Cooperative Forestry Act”) (<ref>16 U.S.C. 582a</ref> et seq.).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(xiii)</num>
<content> Each program established under the Renewable Resources Extension Act of 1978 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 1671</ref> et seq.).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(xiv)</num>
<content> Each program providing funding to Hispanic-serving agricultural colleges and universities under section 1456 of the National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act of 1977 [<ref>7 U.S.C. 3243</ref>].</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(xv)</num>
<content> The program providing capacity grants to NLGCA Institutions under section 1473F of the National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act of 1977 [<ref>7 U.S.C. 3319i</ref>].</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(xvi)</num>
<content> Other programs that are capacity and infrastructure programs, as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Competitive program</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “competitive program” means each of the following agricultural research, extension, education, and related programs for which the Secretary has administrative or other authority as of the day before the date of enactment of the Food, Conservation, and Energy Act of 2008:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The Agriculture and Food Research Initiative established under <ref>section 3157(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The program providing competitive grants for risk management education established under <ref>section 1524(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> The program providing community food project competitive grants established under <ref>section 2034 of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> The beginning farmer and rancher development grant program established under subsection (d) of <ref>section 2279 of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> The program providing grants under section 1417(j) of the National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act of 1977 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 3152(j)</ref>).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> The program providing grants for Hispanic-serving institutions established under section 1455 of the National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act of 1977 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 3241</ref>).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> The program providing competitive grants for international agricultural science and education programs under section 1459A of the National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act of 1977 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 3292b</ref>).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> The research and extension projects carried out under <ref>section 5811 of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ix)</num>
<content> The organic agriculture research and extension initiative established under <ref>section 5925b of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(x)</num>
<content> The specialty crop research initiative under <ref>section 7632 of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(xi)</num>
<content> The research, extension, and education programs authorized by <ref>section 7627 of this title</ref> relating to the competitiveness, viability and sustainability of small- and medium-sized dairy, livestock, and poultry operations.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(xii)</num>
<content> Other programs that are competitive programs, as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(E)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Director</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “Director” means the Director of the Institute.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(F)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fundamental research</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “fundamental research” means research that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> increases knowledge or understanding of the fundamental aspects of phenomena and has the potential for broad application; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> has an effect on agriculture, food, nutrition, or the environment.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(G)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Institute</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “Institute” means the National Institute of Food and Agriculture established by paragraph (2)(A).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of National Institute of Food and Agriculture</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary shall establish within the Department an agency to be known as the “National Institute of Food and Agriculture”.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer of authorities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Secretary shall transfer to the Institute, effective not later than <date date="2009-10-01">October 1, 2009</date>, the authorities (including all budget authorities, available appropriations, and personnel), duties, obligations, and related legal and administrative functions prescribed by law or otherwise granted to the Secretary, the Department, or any other agency or official of the Department under—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the capacity and infrastructure programs;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the competitive programs;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the research, education, economic, cooperative State research programs, cooperative extension and education programs, international programs, and other functions and authorities delegated by the Under Secretary to the Administrator of the Cooperative State Research, Education, and Extension Service pursuant to section 2.66 of title 7, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> any and all other authorities administered by the Administrator of the Cooperative State Research, Education, and Extension Service.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Director</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Institute shall be headed by a Director, who shall be an individual who is—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a distinguished scientist; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> appointed by the President.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Supervision</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Director shall report directly to the Secretary, or the designee of the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Functions of the Director</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Director shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> serve for a 6-year term, subject to reappointment for an additional 6-year term;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> periodically report to the Secretary, or the designee of the Secretary, with respect to activities carried out by the Institute; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> consult regularly with the Secretary, or the designee of the Secretary, to ensure, to the maximum extent practicable, that—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> research of the Institute is relevant to agriculture in the United States and otherwise serves the national interest; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the research of the Institute supplements and enhances, and does not supplant, research conducted or funded by other Federal agencies.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Director shall receive basic pay at a rate not to exceed the maximum amount of compensation payable to a member of the Senior Executive Service under subsection (b) of <ref>section 5382 of title 5</ref>, except that the certification requirement in that subsection shall not apply to the compensation of the Director.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(E)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority and responsibilities of Director</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Except as otherwise specifically provided in this subsection, the Director shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> exercise all of the authority provided to the Institute by this subsection;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> formulate and administer programs in accordance with policies adopted by the Institute, in coordination with the Under Secretary;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> establish offices within the Institute;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> establish procedures for the provision and administration of grants by the Institute; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> consult regularly with the Advisory Board.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Institute shall have such authority as is necessary to carry out this subsection, including the authority to promulgate such regulations as the Institute considers to be necessary for governance of operations, organization, and personnel.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administration</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Director shall organize offices and functions within the Institute to administer fundamental and applied research and extension and education programs.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Research priorities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Director shall ensure the research priorities established by the Under Secretary through the Office of the Chief Scientist are carried out by the offices and functions of the Institute, where applicable.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fundamental and applied research</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Director shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> determine an appropriate balance between fundamental and applied research programs and functions to ensure future research needs are met; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> designate staff, as appropriate, to assist in carrying out this subparagraph.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Competitively funded awards</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Director shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> promote the use and growth of grants awarded through a competitive process; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> designate staff, as appropriate, to assist in carrying out this subparagraph.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(E)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Director shall ensure that the offices and functions established under subparagraph (A) are effectively coordinated for maximum efficiency.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Funding</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In addition to funds otherwise appropriated to carry out each program administered by the Institute, there are authorized to be appropriated such sums as are necessary to carry out this subsection for each fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Allocation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Funding made available under subparagraph (A) shall be allocated according to recommendations contained in the roadmap described in <ref>section 7614a of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–354, title II, § 251</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3226</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title VII, § 7511(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1259</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title VII, § 7511(a), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2021; <ref>Pub. L. 113–79, title VII</ref>, §§ 7111(b)(2), 7212(b), <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 874</ref>, 886; <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title XI, § 11125(b)</ref>, title XII, §§ 12301(a)(2)(B), 12411(a), (b)(1), <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4936</ref>, 4950, 4978, 4979.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6972.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title XII, § 12414(a)(6)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4981</ref></heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER VII—</num>
<heading>FOOD SAFETY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6981.</num>
<heading> Under Secretary of Agriculture for Food Safety</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established in the Department of Agriculture the position of Under Secretary of Agriculture for Food Safety. The Under Secretary shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, from among individuals with specialized training or significant experience in food safety or public health programs.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Functions of Under Secretary</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Principal functions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall delegate to the Under Secretary of Agriculture for Food Safety those functions and duties under the jurisdiction of the Department that are primarily related to food safety.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional functions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Under Secretary of Agriculture for Food Safety shall perform such other functions and duties as may be required by law or prescribed by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Technical and scientific review groups</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary, acting through the Under Secretary for Research, Education, and Economics, may, without regard to the provisions of title 5 governing appointment in the competitive service, and without regard to the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5 relating to classification and General Schedule pay rates—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> establish such technical and scientific review groups as are needed to carry out the functions of the Department; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> appoint and pay the members of the groups, except that officers and employees of the United States shall not receive additional compensation for service as a member of a group.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–354, title II, § 261</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3227</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6982.</num>
<heading> Conditions for implementation of alterations in the level of additives allowed in animal diets</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conditions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Food and Drug Administration shall not implement or enforce the final rule described in subsection (b) to alter the level of selenium allowed to be used as a supplement in animal diets unless the Commissioner of the Food and Drug Administration makes a determination that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> selenium additives are not essential, at levels authorized in the absence of such final rule, to maintain animal nutrition and protect animal health;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> selenium at such levels is not safe to the animals consuming the additive;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> selenium at such levels is not safe to individuals consuming edible portions of animals that receive the additive;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> selenium at such levels does not achieve its intended effect of promoting normal growth and reproduction of livestock and poultry; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the manufacture and use of selenium at such levels cannot reasonably be controlled by adherence to current good manufacturing practice requirements.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Final rule described</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The final rule referred to in subsection (a) is the final rule issued by the Food and Drug Administration and published in the Federal Register on <date date="1993-09-13">September 13, 1993</date> (58 Fed. Reg. 47962), in which the Administration stayed 1987 amendments to the selenium food additive regulations, and any modification of such rule issued after <date date="1994-10-13">October 13, 1994</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–354, title II, § 262</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3227</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER VIII—</num>
<heading>NATIONAL APPEALS DIVISION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6991.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this subchapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adverse decision</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “adverse decision” means an administrative decision made by an officer, employee, or committee of an agency that is adverse to a participant. The term includes a denial of equitable relief by an agency or the failure of an agency to issue a decision or otherwise act on the request or right of the participant. The term does not include a decision over which the Board of Contract Appeals has jurisdiction.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agency</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “agency” means any agency of the Department designated by the Secretary or a successor agency of the Department, except that the term shall include the following (and any successor to the following):</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Farm Service Agency (or other office, agency, or administrative unit of the Department assigned the functions authorized for the Farm Service Agency under <ref>section 6932 of this title</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Commodity Credit Corporation, with respect to domestic programs.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The Farmers Home Administration.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The Federal Crop Insurance Corporation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The Rural Development Administration.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> The Natural Resources Conservation Service (or other office, agency, or administrative unit of the Department assigned the functions authorized for the Natural Resources Conservation Service under <ref>section 6936(b) of this title</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> A State, county, or area committee established under <ref>section 590h(b)(5) of title 16</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appellant</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “appellant” means a participant who appeals an adverse decision in accordance with this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Case record</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “case record” means all the materials maintained by the Secretary related to an adverse decision.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Director</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Director” means the Director of the Division.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Division</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Division” means the National Appeals Division established by this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Hearing officer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “hearing officer” means an individual employed by the Division who hears and determines appeals of adverse decisions by any agency.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “implement” refers to those actions necessary to effectuate fully and promptly a final determination of the Division not later than 30 calendar days after the effective date of the final determination.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Participant</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “participant” shall have the meaning given that term by the Secretary by regulation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–354, title II, § 271</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3228</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title XII</ref>, §§ 12404(b)(2), 12410(c)(2)(B), <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4975</ref>, 4978.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6992.</num>
<heading> National Appeals Division and Director</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of Division</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish and maintain an independent National Appeals Division within the Department to carry out this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Director</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Division shall be headed by a Director, appointed by the Secretary from among persons who have substantial experience in practicing administrative law. In considering applicants for the position of Director, the Secretary shall consider persons currently employed outside Government as well as Government employees.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Term and removal</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Director shall serve for a 6-year term of office, and shall be eligible for reappointment. The Director shall not be subject to removal during the term of office, except for cause established in accordance with law.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Position classification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The position of the Director may not be a position in the excepted service or filled by a noncareer appointee.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Direction, control, and support</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Direction and control</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Except as provided in paragraph (2), the Director shall be free from the direction and control of any person other than the Secretary or the Deputy Secretary of Agriculture.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrative support</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Division shall not receive administrative support (except on a reimbursable basis) from any agency other than the Office of the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition on delegation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary may not delegate to any other officer or employee of the Department, other than the Deputy Secretary of Agriculture or the Director, the authority of the Secretary with respect to the Division.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Assistant Secretary for Administration is authorized to investigate, enforce, and implement the provisions in law, Executive order, or regulations that relate in general to competitive and excepted service positions and employment within the Division, including the position of Director, and such authority may be further delegated to subordinate officials.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determination of appealability of agency decisions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If an officer, employee, or committee of an agency determines that a decision is not appealable and a participant appeals the decision to the Director, the Director shall determine whether the decision is adverse to the individual participant and thus appealable or is a matter of general applicability and thus not subject to appeal. The determination of the Director as to whether a decision is appealable shall be administratively final.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Division personnel</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Director shall recommend to the Secretary persons for appointment as hearing officers as are necessary for the conduct of hearings under <ref>section 6997 of this title</ref>. The Director shall appoint such other employees as are necessary for the administration of the Division. A hearing officer or other employee of the Division shall have no duties other than those that are necessary to carry out this subchapter. Each position of the Division shall be filled by an individual who is not a political appointee.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Political appointee</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In this subsection, the term “political appointee” means an individual occupying—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a position described under sections 5312 through 5316 of title 5 (relating to the Executive Schedule);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a noncareer position in the Senior Executive Service, as described under section 3132(a)(7) of that title;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a position in the executive branch of the Government of a confidential or policy-determining character under schedule C of subpart C of part 213 of title 5, Code of Federal Regulations; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a position which has been excepted from the competitive service by reason of its confidential, policy-determining, policy-making, or policy-advocating character.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–354, title II, § 272</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3229</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–79, title I, § 1610(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 709</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title XII, § 12412</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4980</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6993.</num>
<heading> Transfer of functions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There are transferred to the Division all functions exercised and all administrative appeals pending before the effective date of this subchapter (including all related functions of any officer or employee) of or relating to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the National Appeals Division established by section 1433e(c) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002322">1</ref> of this title (as in effect on the day before <date date="1994-10-13">October 13, 1994</date>);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the National Appeals Division established by subsections (d) through (g) of section 1983b <sup>1</sup> of this title (as in effect on the day before <date date="1994-10-13">October 13, 1994</date>);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> appeals of decisions made by the Federal Crop Insurance Corporation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> appeals of decisions made by the Soil Conservation Service (as in effect on the day before <date date="1994-10-13">October 13, 1994</date>).</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–354, title II, § 273</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3230</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6994.</num>
<heading> Notice and opportunity for hearing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 10 working days after an adverse decision is made that affects the participant, the Secretary shall provide the participant with written notice of such adverse decision and the rights available to the participant under this subchapter or other law for the review of such adverse decision.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–354, title II, § 274</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3230</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6995.</num>
<heading> Informal hearings</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If an officer, employee, or committee of an agency makes an adverse decision, the agency shall hold, at the request of the participant, an informal hearing on the decision.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Farm Service Agency</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">With respect to programs carried out through the Farm Service Agency (or other office, agency, or administrative unit of the Department assigned to carry out the programs authorized for the Farm Service Agency under <ref>section 6932 of this title</ref>), the Secretary shall maintain the informal appeals process applicable to such programs, as in effect on <date date="1994-10-13">October 13, 1994</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Mediation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">If a mediation program is available under title V of the Agricultural Credit Act of 1987 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 5101</ref> et seq.) as a part of the informal hearing process, the participant shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> be offered the right to choose such mediation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to the maximum extent practicable, be allowed to use both informal agency review and mediation to resolve disputes under that title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–354, title II, § 275</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3230</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title XII, § 12032</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1391</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title XII, § 12032, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2153; <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title XII, § 12404(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4975</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6996.</num>
<heading> Right of participants to Division hearing</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appeal to Division for hearing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to subsection (b), a participant shall have the right to appeal an adverse decision to the Division for an evidentiary hearing by a hearing officer consistent with <ref>section 6997 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Time for appeal</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To be entitled to a hearing under <ref>section 6997 of this title</ref>, a participant shall request the hearing not later than 30 days after the date on which the participant first received notice of the adverse decision.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–354, title II, § 276</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3230</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6997.</num>
<heading> Division hearings</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General powers of Director and hearing officers</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Access to case record</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Director and hearing officer shall have access to the case record of any adverse decision appealed to the Division for a hearing.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrative procedures</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Director and hearing officer shall have the authority to require the attendance of witnesses, and the production of evidence, by subpoena and to administer oaths and affirmations. Except to the extent required for the disposition of ex parte matters as authorized by law—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an interested person outside the Division shall not make or knowingly cause to be made to the Director or a hearing officer who is or may reasonably be expected to be involved in the evidentiary hearing or review of an adverse decision, an ex parte communication (as defined in <ref>section 551(14) of title 5</ref>) relevant to the merits of the proceeding;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Director and such hearing officer shall not make or knowingly cause to be made to any interested person outside the Division an ex parte communication relevant to the merits of the proceeding.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Time for hearing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon a timely request for a hearing under <ref>section 6996(b) of this title</ref>, an appellant shall have the right to have a hearing by the Division on the adverse decision within 45 days after the date of the receipt of the request for the hearing.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Location and elements of hearing</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Location</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A hearing on an adverse decision shall be held in the State of residence of the appellant or at a location that is otherwise convenient to the appellant and the Division.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Evidentiary hearing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The evidentiary hearing before a hearing officer shall be in person, unless the appellant agrees to a hearing by telephone or by a review of the case record. The hearing officer shall not be bound by previous findings of fact by the agency in making a determination.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Information at hearing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The hearing officer shall consider information presented at the hearing without regard to whether the evidence was known to the agency officer, employee, or committee making the adverse decision at the time the adverse decision was made. The hearing officer shall leave the record open after the hearing for a reasonable period of time to allow the submission of information by the appellant or the agency after the hearing to the extent necessary to respond to new facts, information, arguments, or evidence presented or raised by the agency or appellant.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Burden of proof</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The appellant shall bear the burden of proving that the adverse decision of the agency was erroneous.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determination notice</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The hearing officer shall issue a notice of the determination on the appeal not later than 30 days after a hearing or after receipt of the request of the appellant to waive a hearing, except that the Director may establish an earlier or later deadline. If the determination is not appealed to the Director for review under <ref>section 6998 of this title</ref>, the notice provided by the hearing officer shall be considered to be a notice of an administratively final determination.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The final determination shall be effective as of the date of filing of an application, the date of the transaction or event in question, or the date of the original adverse decision, whichever is applicable.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–354, title II, § 277</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3230</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6998.</num>
<heading> Director review of determinations of hearing officers</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requests for Director review</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Time for request by appellant</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 30 days after the date on which an appellant receives the determination of a hearing officer under <ref>section 6997 of this title</ref>, the appellant shall submit a written request to the Director for review of the determination in order to be entitled to a review by the Director of the determination.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Time for request by agency head</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 15 business days after the date on which an agency receives the determination of a hearing officer under <ref>section 6997 of this title</ref>, the head of the agency may make a written request that the Director review the determination.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determination of Director</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Director shall conduct a review of the determination of the hearing officer using the case record, the record from the evidentiary hearing under <ref>section 6997 of this title</ref>, the request for review, and such other arguments or information as may be accepted by the Director. Based on such review, the Director shall issue a final determination notice that upholds, reverses, or modifies the determination of the hearing officer. However, if the Director determines that the hearing record is inadequate, the Director may remand all or a portion of the determination for further proceedings to complete the hearing record or, at the option of the Director, to hold a new hearing. The Director shall complete the review and either issue a final determination or remand the determination not later than—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> 10 business days after receipt of the request for review, in the case of a request by the head of an agency for review; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> 30 business days after receipt of the request for review, in the case of a request by an appellant for review.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Basis for determination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The determination of the hearing officer and the Director shall be based on information from the case record, laws applicable to the matter at issue, and applicable regulations published in the Federal Register and in effect on the date of the adverse decision or the date on which the acts that gave rise to the adverse decision occurred, whichever date is appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Equitable relief</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to regulations issued by the Secretary, the Director shall have the authority to grant equitable relief under this section in the same manner and to the same extent as such authority is provided to the Secretary under <ref>section 7996 of this title</ref> and other laws. Notwithstanding the administrative finality of a final determination of an appeal by the Division, the Secretary shall have the authority to grant equitable or other types of relief to the appellant after an administratively final determination is issued by the Division.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A final determination issued by the Director shall be effective as of the date of filing of an application, the date of the transaction or event in question, or the date of the original adverse decision, whichever is applicable.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–354, title II, § 278</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3232</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–171, title I, § 1613(j)(2)</ref>, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 221</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6999.</num>
<heading> Judicial review</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A final determination of the Division shall be reviewable and enforceable by any United States district court of competent jurisdiction in accordance with chapter 7 of title 5.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–354, title II, § 279</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3233</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7000.</num>
<heading> Implementation of final determinations of Division</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On the return of a case to an agency pursuant to the final determination of the Division, the head of the agency shall implement the final determination not later than 30 days after the effective date of the notice of the final determination.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this subsection, and every 180 days thereafter, the head of each agency shall submit to the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate, and publish on the website of the Department, a report that includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a description of all cases returned to the agency during the period covered by the report pursuant to a final determination of the Division;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the status of implementation of each final determination; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> if the final determination has not been implemented—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the reason that the final determination has not been implemented; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the projected date of implementation of the final determination.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Updates</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Each month, the head of each agency shall publish on the website of the Department any updates to the reports submitted under paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–354, title II, § 280</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3233</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title XIV, § 14009</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1446</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title XIV, § 14009, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2208.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7001.</num>
<heading> Conforming amendments relating to National Appeals Division</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Decisions of State, county, and area committees</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application of subsection</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), this subsection shall apply only with respect to functions of the Farm Service Agency or the Commodity Credit Corporation that are under the jurisdiction of a State, county, or area committee established under <ref>section 590h(b)(5) of title 16</ref> or an employee of such a committee.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonapplicability</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">This subsection does not apply to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a function performed under <ref>section 2008k of this title</ref>; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a function performed under a conservation program administered by the Natural Resources Conservation Service.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Finality</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Each decision of a State, county, or area committee (or an employee of such a committee) covered by paragraph (1) that is made in good faith in the absence of misrepresentation, false statement, fraud, or willful misconduct shall be final not later than 90 days after the date of filing of the application for benefits, unless the decision, before the end of the 90-day period, is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> appealed under this subchapter; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> modified by the Administrator of the Farm Service Agency or the Executive Vice President of the Commodity Credit Corporation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recovery of amounts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the decision of the State, county, or area committee has become final under paragraph (2), no action may be taken by the Farm Service Agency, the Commodity Credit Corporation, or a State, county, or area committee to recover amounts found to have been disbursed as a result of a decision in error unless the participant had reason to believe that the decision was erroneous.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Savings provision</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, a reference to the “Farm Service Agency” includes any other office, agency, or administrative unit of the Department assigned the functions authorized for the Farm Service Agency under <ref>section 6932 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold">, (c) Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–354, title II, § 281</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3233</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–171, title I, § 1613(i)</ref>, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 221</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7002.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out the activities of the Division.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–354, title II, § 283</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3235</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER VIII–A—</num>
<heading>MARKETING AND REGULATORY PROGRAMS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7005.</num>
<heading> Under Secretary of Agriculture for Marketing and Regulatory Programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to establish in the Department the position of Under Secretary of Agriculture for Marketing and Regulatory Programs.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Confirmation required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the Secretary establishes the position of Under Secretary of Agriculture for Marketing and Regulatory Programs authorized under subsection (a), the Under Secretary shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Functions of Under Secretary</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Principal functions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Upon establishment, the Secretary shall delegate to the Under Secretary of Agriculture for Marketing and Regulatory Programs those functions and duties under the jurisdiction of the Department that are related to agricultural marketing, animal and plant health inspection, grain inspection, and packers and stockyards.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional functions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Under Secretary of Agriculture for Marketing and Regulatory Programs shall perform such other functions and duties as may be required by law or prescribed by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Succession</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any official who is serving as Assistant Secretary of Agriculture for Marketing and Regulatory Programs on <date date="1998-10-21">October 21, 1998</date>, and who was appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, shall not be required to be reappointed under subsection (b) to the successor position authorized under subsection (a) if the Secretary establishes the position, and the official occupies the new position, within 180 days after <date date="1998-10-21">October 21, 1998</date> (or such later date set by the Secretary if litigation delays rapid succession).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–354, title II, § 285</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. A, § 101(a) [title X, § 1001(3)]</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681</ref>, 2681–41.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER VIII–B—</num>
<heading>TRADE AND FOREIGN AGRICULTURAL AFFAIRS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7007.</num>
<heading> Under Secretary of Agriculture for Trade and Foreign Agricultural Affairs</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established in the Department the position of Under Secretary of Agriculture for Trade and Foreign Agricultural Affairs.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Under Secretary of Agriculture for Trade and Foreign Agricultural Affairs shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Functions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Principal functions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall delegate to the Under Secretary of Agriculture for Trade and Foreign Agricultural Affairs those functions and duties under the jurisdiction of the Department that are related to trade and foreign agricultural affairs.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional functions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Under Secretary of Agriculture for Trade and Foreign Agricultural Affairs shall perform such other functions and duties as may be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> required by law; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> prescribed by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–354, title II, § 287</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title XII, § 12413(2)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4980</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IX—</num>
<heading>MISCELLANEOUS REORGANIZATION PROVISIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7011.</num>
<heading> Successorship provisions relating to bargaining units and exclusive representatives</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Voluntary agreement</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the exercise of the Secretary’s authority under this chapter results in changes to an existing bargaining unit that has been certified under chapter 71 of title 5, the affected parties shall attempt to reach a voluntary agreement on a new bargaining unit and an exclusive representative for such unit.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Criteria</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In carrying out the requirements of this subsection, the affected parties shall use criteria set forth in—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> sections 7103(a)(4), 7111(e), 7111(f)(1), and 7120 of title 5, relating to determining an exclusive representative; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content><ref>section 7112 of title 5</ref> (disregarding subsections (b)(5) and (d) thereof), relating to determining appropriate units.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect of an agreement</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the affected parties reach agreement on the appropriate unit and the exclusive representative for such unit under subsection (a), the Federal Labor Relations Authority shall certify the terms of such agreement, subject to paragraph (2)(A). Nothing in this subsection shall be considered to require the holding of any hearing or election as a condition for certification.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Restrictions</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conditions requiring noncertification</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Federal Labor Relations Authority may not certify the terms of an agreement under paragraph (1) if—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> it determines that any of the criteria referred to in subsection (a)(2) (disregarding <ref>section 7112(a) of title 5</ref>) have not been met; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> after the Secretary’s exercise of authority and before certification under this section, a valid election under <ref>section 7111(b) of title 5</ref> is held covering any employees who would be included in the unit proposed for certification.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Temporary waiver of provision that would bar an election after a collective bargaining agreement is reached</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Nothing in <ref>section 7111(f)(3) of title 5</ref> shall prevent the holding of an election under section 7111(b) of such title that covers employees within a unit certified under paragraph (1), or giving effect to the results of such an election (including a decision not to be represented by any labor organization), if the election is held before the end of the 12-month period beginning on the date such unit is so certified.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Clarification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The certification of a unit under paragraph (1) shall not, for purposes of the last sentence of <ref>section 7111(b) of title 5</ref> or section 7111(f)(4) of such title, be treated as if it had occurred pursuant to an election.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Delegation</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Federal Labor Relations Authority may delegate to any regional director (as referred to in <ref>section 7105(e) of title 5</ref>) its authority under the preceding provisions of this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Any action taken by a regional director under subparagraph (A) shall be subject to review under the provisions of <ref>section 7105(f) of title 5</ref> in the same manner as if such action had been taken under section 7105(e) of such title, except that in the case of a decision not to certify, such review shall be required if application therefor is filed by an affected party within the time specified in such provisions.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> “Affected party” defined</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the term “affected party” means—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> with respect to an exercise of authority by the Secretary under this chapter, any labor organization affected thereby; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Department of Agriculture.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–354, title II, § 291</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3235</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7012.</num>
<heading> Purchase of American-made equipment and products</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sense of Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is the sense of the Congress that, to the greatest extent practicable, all equipment and products purchased using funds made available pursuant to this chapter should be American-made.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In providing financial assistance to, or entering into any contract with, any entity using funds made available pursuant to this chapter, the Secretary, to the greatest extent practicable, shall provide to such entity a notice describing the statement made in subsection (a) by the Congress.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–354, title II, § 292</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3237</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7013.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title XII, § 12414(a)(7)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4981</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7014.</num>
<heading> Termination of authority</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to subsection (b), the authority delegated to the Secretary by this chapter to reorganize the Department shall terminate on the date that is 2 years after <date date="1994-10-13">October 13, 1994</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Functions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subsection (a) shall not affect:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The authority of the Secretary to continue to carry out a function that the Secretary performs on the date that is 2 years after <date date="1994-10-13">October 13, 1994</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The authority delegated to the Secretary under Reorganization Plan No. 2 of 1953 (5 U.S.C. App.; <ref>7 U.S.C. 2201</ref> note).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The authority of an agency, office, officer, or employee of the Department to continue to perform all functions delegated or assigned to the entity or person as of that termination date.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The authority of the Secretary to establish in the Department the position of Under Secretary of Agriculture for Marketing and Regulatory Programs under <ref>section 7005 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The authority of the Secretary to establish within the Department the position of Assistant Secretary of Agriculture for Civil Rights, and delegate duties to the Assistant Secretary, under <ref>section 6918 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> The authority of the Secretary to establish in the Department, under <ref>section 6971 of this title</ref>—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the position of Under Secretary of Agriculture for Research, Education, and Economics;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Office of the Chief Scientist; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the National Institute of Food and Agriculture.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The authority of the Secretary to establish in the Department the Office of Advocacy and Outreach in accordance with <ref>section 6934 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> The authority of the Secretary to carry out amendments made to this chapter by the Agricultural Act of 2014.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> The authority of the Secretary to carry out the amendments made to this chapter by section 772 of the Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2018.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> The authority of the Secretary to carry out the amendments made to this chapter by the Agriculture Improvement Act of 2018.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–354, title II, § 296</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3238</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. A, § 101(a) [title X, § 1001(4)]</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681</ref>, 2681–42; <ref>Pub. L. 107–171, title X, § 10704(c)</ref>, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 518</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title VII, § 7511(b)</ref>, title XIV, § 14013(b), <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1267</ref>, 1453; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title VII, § 7511(b), title XIV, § 14013(b), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2028, 2215; <ref>Pub. L. 113–79, title I, § 1610(b)</ref>, <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 710</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title XII</ref>, §§ 12411(b)(2), 12416, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4980</ref>, 4982.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER X—</num>
<heading>FREEDOM TO E-FILE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7031.</num>
<heading> Electronic filing and retrieval</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2000-06-20">June 20, 2000</date>, in accordance with subsection (c), the Secretary of Agriculture (referred to in this subchapter as the “Secretary”) shall, to the maximum extent practicable, establish an Internet-based system that enables agricultural producers to access all forms of the agencies of the Department of Agriculture (referred to in this subchapter as the “Department”) specified in subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The agencies referred to in subsection (a) are the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Farm Service Agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Natural Resources Conservation Service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The rural development components of the Department included in the Secretary’s service center initiative regarding State and field office collocation implemented pursuant to <ref>section 6915 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The agricultural producer programs component of the Commodity Credit Corporation administered by the Farm Service Agency and the Natural Resources Conservation Service.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> provide a method by which agricultural producers may—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> download from the Internet the forms of the agencies specified in subsection (b); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> submit completed forms via electronic facsimile, mail, or similar means;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> redesign the forms by incorporating into the forms user-friendly formats and self-help guidance materials; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> ensure that the agencies specified in subsection (b)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> use computer hardware and software that is compatible among the agencies and will operate in a common computing environment; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> develop common Internet user-interface locations and applications to consolidate the agencies’ news, information, and program materials.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Progress reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2000-06-20">June 20, 2000</date>, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report that describes the progress made toward implementing the Internet-based system required under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–222, § 2</ref>, <date date="2000-06-20">June 20, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 353</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7032.</num>
<heading> Accessing information and filing over the Internet</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 2 years after <date date="2000-06-20">June 20, 2000</date>, in accordance with subsection (b), the Secretary shall expand implementation of the Internet-based system established under <ref>section 7031 of this title</ref> by enabling agricultural producers to access and file all forms and, at the option of the Secretary, selected records and information of the agencies of the Department specified in <ref>section 7031(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary shall ensure that an agricultural producer is able—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to file electronically or in paper form, at the option of the agricultural producer, all forms required by agencies of the Department specified in <ref>section 7031(b) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to file electronically or in paper form, at the option of the agricultural producer, all documentation required by agencies of the Department specified in <ref>section 7031(b) of this title</ref> and determined appropriate by the Secretary; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to access information of the Department concerning farm programs, quarterly trade, economic, and production reports, and other similar production agriculture information that is readily available to the public in paper form.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–222, § 3</ref>, <date date="2000-06-20">June 20, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 354</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7033.</num>
<heading> Availability of agency information technology funds</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reservation of funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">From funds made available for agencies of the Department specified in <ref>section 7031(b) of this title</ref> for information technology or information resource management, the Secretary shall reserve from those agencies’ applicable accounts a total amount equal to not more than the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> For fiscal year 2001, $3,000,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> For each subsequent fiscal year, $2,000,000.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Time for reservation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall notify Congress of the amount to be reserved under subsection (a) for a fiscal year not later than December 1 of that fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of funds</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Funds reserved under subsection (a) shall be used to establish the Internet-based system required under <ref>section 7031 of this title</ref> and to expand the system as required by <ref>section 7032 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Maintenance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Once the system is established and operational, reserved amounts shall be used for maintenance and improvement of the system.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Return of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Funds reserved under subsection (a) and unobligated at the end of the fiscal year shall be returned to the agency from which the funds were reserved, to remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–222, § 4</ref>, <date date="2000-06-20">June 20, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 354</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7034.</num>
<heading> Federal Crop Insurance Corporation and Risk Management Agency</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than <date date="2000-12-01">December 1, 2000</date>, the Federal Crop Insurance Corporation and the Risk Management Agency shall submit to the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate a plan, that is consistent with this subchapter, to allow agricultural producers to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> obtain, over the Internet, from approved insurance providers all forms and other information concerning the program under the jurisdiction of the Corporation and Agency in which the agricultural producer is a participant; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> file electronically all paperwork required for participation in the program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administration</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The plan shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> conform to sections 7031(c) and 7032(b) of this title; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> prescribe—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the location and type of data to be made available to agricultural producers;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the location where agricultural producers can electronically file their paperwork; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the responsibilities of the applicable parties, including agricultural producers, the Risk Management Agency, the Federal Crop Insurance Corporation, approved insurance providers, crop insurance agents, and brokers.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than <date date="2001-12-01">December 1, 2001</date>, the Federal Crop Insurance Corporation and the Risk Management Agency shall complete implementation of the plan submitted under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–222, § 5</ref>, <date date="2000-06-20">June 20, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 355</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7035.</num>
<heading> Confidentiality</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In carrying out this subchapter, the Secretary—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> may not make available any information over the Internet that would otherwise not be available for release under section 552 or 552a of title 5; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall ensure, to the maximum extent practicable, that the confidentiality of persons is maintained.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–222, § 6</ref>, <date date="2000-06-20">June 20, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 355</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>