<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 14—</num>
<heading>AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATIONS</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 361.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Aug. 11, 1955, ch. 790, § 2</ref>, <ref>69 Stat. 674</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 361a.</num>
<heading> Congressional declaration of purpose; definitions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is the policy of Congress to continue the agricultural research at State agricultural experiment stations which has been encouraged and supported by the Hatch Act of 1887 [<ref>7 U.S.C. 361a</ref> et seq.], the Adams Act of 1906, the Purnell Act of 1925, the Bankhead-Jones Act of 1935, and title I, section 9, of that Act as added by the Act of <date date="1946-08-14">August 14, 1946</date>, and Acts amendatory and supplementary thereto, and to promote the efficiency of such research by a codification and simplification of such laws. As used in this Act [<ref>7 U.S.C. 361a</ref> et seq.], the terms “State” or “States” are defined to include the several States (including the District of Columbia), Puerto Rico, Guam and the Virgin Islands. As used in this Act [<ref>7 U.S.C. 361a</ref> et seq.], the term “State agricultural experiment station” means a department which shall have been established, under direction of the college or university or agricultural departments of the college or university in each State in accordance with an Act approved <date date="1862-07-02">July 2, 1862</date>, (<ref>12 Stat. 503</ref>), entitled “An Act donating public lands to the several States and Territo­ries which may provide colleges for the benefit of agriculture and the mechanic arts” [<ref>7 U.S.C. 301</ref> et seq.]; or such other substantially equivalent arrangements as any State shall determine.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 2, 1887, ch. 314, § 1</ref>, <ref>24 Stat. 440</ref>; <ref>Aug. 11, 1955, ch. 790, § 1</ref>, <ref>69 Stat. 671</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–318, title V, § 506(k)</ref>, <date date="1972-06-23">June 23, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 351</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–471, title II, § 208(e)</ref>, <date date="1974-10-26">Oct. 26, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1429</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–185, title II, § 203(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1998-06-23">June 23, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 534</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 361b.</num>
<heading> Congressional statement of policy; researches, investigations and experiments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is further the policy of the Congress to promote the efficient production, marketing, distribution, and utilization of products of the farm as essential to the health and welfare of our peoples and to promote a sound and prosperous agriculture and rural life as indispensable to the maintenance of maximum employment and national prosperity and security. It is also the intent of Congress to assure agriculture a position in research equal to that of industry, which will aid in maintaining an equitable balance between agriculture and other segments of our economy. It shall be the object and duty of the State agricultural experiment stations through the expenditure of the appropriations hereinafter authorized to conduct original and other researches, investigations, and experiments bearing directly on and contributing to the establishment and maintenance of a permanent and effective agricultural industry of the United States, including researches basic to the problems of agriculture in its broadest aspects, and such investigations as have for their purpose the development and improvement of the rural home and rural life and the maximum contribution by agriculture to the welfare of the consumer, as may be deemed advisable, having due regard to the varying conditions and needs of the respective States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 2, 1887, ch. 314, § 2</ref>, <ref>24 Stat. 440</ref>; <ref>Aug. 11, 1955, ch. 790, § 1</ref>, <ref>69 Stat. 671</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 361c.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations and allotments of grants</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated for the purposes of sections 361a to 361i of this title such sums as Congress may from time to time determine to be necessary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Allotments to States; authorization of appropriations for Virgin Islands and Guam; limitation</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Out of such sums each State shall be entitled to receive annually a sum of money equal to and subject to the same requirement as to use for marketing research projects as the sums received from Federal appropriations for State agricultural experiment stations for the fiscal year 1955, except that amounts heretofore made available from the fund known as the “Regional research fund, Office of Experiment Stations” shall continue to be available for the support of cooperative regional projects as defined in subsection (c)(3), and the said fund shall be designated “Regional research fund, State agricultural experiment stations,” and the Secretary of Agriculture shall be entitled to receive annually for the administration of sections 361a to 361i of this title, a sum not less than that available for this purpose for the fiscal year ending <date date="1955-06-30">June 30, 1955</date>: <i>Provided</i>, That if the appropriations hereunder available for distribution in any fiscal year are less than those for the fiscal year 1955 the allotment to each State and the amounts for Federal administration and the regional research fund shall be reduced in proportion to the amount of such reduction.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> There is authorized to be appropriated for the fiscal year ending <date date="1973-06-30">June 30, 1973</date>, and for each fiscal year thereafter, for payment to the Virgin Islands and Guam, $100,000 each, which sums shall be in addition to the sums appropriated for the several States of the United States and Puerto Rico under the provisions of this section. The amount paid by the Federal Government to the Virgin Islands and Guam pursuant to this paragraph shall not exceed during any fiscal year, except the fiscal years ending <date date="1971-06-30">June 30, 1971</date>, and <date date="1972-06-30">June 30, 1972</date>, when such amount may be used to pay the total cost of providing services pursuant to sections 361a to 361i of this title, the amount available and budgeted for expenditure by the Virgin Islands and Guam for the purposes of such sections.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Allotment of additional sums</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Any sums made available by the Congress in addition to those provided for in subsection (b) of this section for State agricultural experiment station work shall be distributed as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Twenty per centum shall be allotted equally to each State;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Not less than 52 per centum of such sums shall be allotted to each State, as follows: One-half in an amount which bears the same ratio to the total amount to be allotted as the rural population of the State bears to the total rural population of all the States as determined by the last preceding decennial census current at the time each such additional sum is first appropriated; and one-half in an amount which bears the same ratio to the total amount to be allotted as the farm population of the State bears to the total farm population of all the States as determined by the last preceding decennial census current at the time such additional sum is first appropriated;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Not less than 25 percent shall be allotted to the States for cooperative research employing multidisciplinary approaches in which a State agricultural experiment station, working with another State agricultural experiment station, the Agricultural Research Service, or a college or university, cooperates to solve problems that concern more than 1 State. The funds available under this paragraph, together with the funds available under subsection (b) for a similar purpose, shall be designated as the “Multistate Research Fund, State Agricultural Experiment Stations”.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Three per centum shall be available to the Secretary of Agriculture for administration of sections 361a to 361i of this title. These administrative funds may be used for transportation of scientists who are not officers or employees of the United States to research meetings convened for the purpose of assessing research opportunities or research planning.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Matching funds</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (4), no allotment shall be made to a State under subsection (b) or (c), and no payments from the allotment shall be made to a State, in excess of the amount that the State makes available out of non-Federal funds for agricultural research and for the establishment and maintenance of facilities for the performance of the research.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Failure to provide matching funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">If a State fails to comply with the requirement to provide matching funds for a fiscal year under paragraph (1), the Secretary of Agriculture shall withhold from payment to the State for that fiscal year an amount equal to the difference between—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the amount that would be allotted and paid to the State under subsections (b) and (c) (if the full amount of matching funds were provided by the State); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the amount of matching funds actually provided by the State.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reapportionment</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary of Agriculture shall reapportion amounts withheld under paragraph (2) for a fiscal year among the States satisfying the matching requirement for that fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Matching requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Any reapportionment of funds under this paragraph shall be subject to the matching requirement specified in paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception for insular areas and the District of Columbia</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Effective beginning for fiscal year 2003, in lieu of the matching funds requirement of paragraph (1), the insular areas of the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, and the Virgin Islands of the United States and the District of Columbia shall provide matching funds from non-Federal sources in an amount equal to not less than 50 percent of the formula funds distributed by the Secretary to each of the insular areas, respectively, and the District of Columbia under this section.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Waivers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary may waive the matching fund requirement of subparagraph (A) for any fiscal year if the Secretary determines that the government of the insular area or the District of Columbia will be unlikely to meet the matching requirement for the fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> “Administration” defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">“Administration” as used in this section shall include participation in planning and coordinating cooperative regional research as defined in subsection (c)(3).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adjustment of payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In making payments to States, the Secretary of Agriculture is authorized to adjust any such payment to the nearest dollar.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reductions and reapportionments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If in any year the amount made available by a State from its own funds (including any revenue-sharing funds) to a State agricultural experiment station is reduced because of an increase in the allotment made available under sections 361a to 361i of this title, the allotment to the State agricultural experiment station from the appropriation in the next succeeding fiscal year shall be reduced in an equivalent amount. The Secretary shall reapportion the amount of such reduction to other States for use by their agricultural experiment stations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Peer review</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Research carried out under subsection (c)(3) shall be subject to scientific peer review. The review of a project conducted under this subsection shall be considered to satisfy the merit review requirements of <ref>section 7613(e) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Integration of research and extension</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not less than the applicable percentage specified under paragraph (2) of the Federal formula funds that are paid under sections 361a to 361i of this title and subsections (b) and (c) of <ref>section 343 of this title</ref> to colleges and universities eligible to receive funds under the Act of <date date="1862-07-02">July 2, 1862</date> (<ref>12 Stat. 503</ref>, chapter 130; <ref>7 U.S.C. 301</ref> et seq.), during a fiscal year shall be expended for activities that integrate cooperative research and extension (referred to in this subsection as “integrated activities”).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicable percentages</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> 1997 expenditures on multistate activities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Of the Federal formula funds that were paid to each State for fiscal year 1997 under sections 361a to 361i of this title and subsections (b) and (c) of <ref>section 343 of this title</ref>, the Secretary of Agriculture shall determine the percentage that the State expended for integrated activities.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Required expenditures on multistate activities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Of the Federal formula funds that are paid to each State for fiscal year 2000 and each subsequent fiscal year under sections 361a to 361i of this title and subsections (b) and (c) of <ref>section 343 of this title</ref>, the State shall expend for the fiscal year for integrated activities a percentage that is at least equal to the lesser of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> 25 percent; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> twice the percentage for the State determined under subparagraph (A).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reduction by Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary of Agriculture may reduce the minimum percentage required to be expended by a State for integrated activities under subparagraph (B) in a case of hardship, infeasibility, or other similar circumstance beyond the control of the State, as determined by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">This subsection does not apply to funds provided—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> by a State or local government pursuant to a matching requirement;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to a 1994 Institution (as defined in section 532 of the Equity in Educational Land-Grant Status Act of 1994 (<ref>Public Law 103–382</ref>; <ref>7 U.S.C. 301</ref> note)); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, or Guam.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Relationship to other requirements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Federal formula funds described in paragraph (1) that are used by a State for a fiscal year for integrated activities in accordance with paragraph (2)(B) may also be used to satisfy the multistate activities requirements of subsection (c)(3) of this section and <ref>section 343(h) of this title</ref> for the same fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 2, 1887, ch. 314, § 3</ref>, <ref>24 Stat. 441</ref>; <ref>Aug. 11, 1955, ch. 790, § 1</ref>, <ref>69 Stat. 671</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–318, title V, § 506</ref>(<i>l</i>), <date date="1972-06-23">June 23, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 351</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–113, title XIV, § 1466</ref>, <date date="1977-09-29">Sept. 29, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 1018</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–98, title XIV, § 1442(a)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-22">Dec. 22, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1321</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XVI, § 1618(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3733</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title VIII, § 869</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1175</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–185, title I, § 104</ref>, title II, §§ 203(a), 204(a), <date date="1998-06-23">June 23, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 529</ref>, 533, 535; <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. A, § 101(a) [title VII, § 753(d)]</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681</ref>, 2681–33; <ref>Pub. L. 107–171, title VII, § 7213(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 448</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title VII, § 7404(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1246</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title VII, § 7404(a), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2008; <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title VII, § 7612(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4832</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 361d.</num>
<heading> Use of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Moneys appropriated pursuant to sections 361a to 361i of this title shall also be available, in addition to meeting expenses for research and investigations conducted under authority of <ref>section 361b of this title</ref>, for printing and disseminating the results of such research, retirement of employees subject to the provisions of <ref>section 331 of this title</ref>, administrative planning and direction, and for the purchase and rental of land and the construction, acquisition, alteration, or repair of buildings necessary for conducting research. The State agricultural experiment stations are authorized to plan and conduct any research authorized under <ref>section 361b of this title</ref> in cooperation with each other and such other agencies and individuals as may contribute to the solution of the agricultural problems involved, and moneys appropriated pursuant to sections 361a to 361i of this title shall be available for paying the necessary expenses of planning, coordinating, and conducting such cooperative research.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 2, 1887, ch. 314, § 4</ref>, <ref>24 Stat. 441</ref>; <ref>Aug. 11, 1955, ch. 790, § 1</ref>, <ref>69 Stat. 672</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 361e.</num>
<heading> Payment of allotments to State agricultural experiment stations; directors and treasurers or other officers; accounting; reports to Secretary; replacement by States of diminished, lost or misapplied allotments; subsequent allotments or payments contingent on such replacement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Sums available for allotment to the States under the terms of sections 361a to 361i of this title, excluding the Multistate Research Fund, State Agricultural Experiment Stations, shall be paid to each State agricultural experiment station in equal quarterly payments beginning on the first day of October of each fiscal year upon vouchers approved by the Secretary of Agriculture. Each such station authorized to receive allotted funds shall have a chief administrative officer known as a director, and a treasurer or other officer appointed by the governing board of the station. Such treasurer or other officer shall receive and account for all funds allotted to the State under the provisions of sections 361a to 361i of this title and shall report, with the approval of the director, to the Secretary of Agriculture on or before the first day of December of each year a detailed statement of the amount received under provisions of said sections during the preceding fiscal year, and of its disbursement on schedules prescribed by the Secretary of Agriculture. If any portion of the allotted moneys received by the authorized receiving officer of any State agricultural experiment station shall by any action or contingency be diminished, lost, or misapplied, it shall be replaced by the State concerned and until so replaced no subsequent appropriation shall be allotted or paid to such State.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 2, 1887, ch. 314, § 5</ref>, <ref>24 Stat. 441</ref>; <ref>Aug. 11, 1955, ch. 790, § 1</ref>, <ref>69 Stat. 673</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–273, § 9(2)</ref>, <date date="1976-04-21">Apr. 21, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 378</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–185, title II, § 203(c)(3)</ref>, <date date="1998-06-23">June 23, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 535</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 361f.</num>
<heading> Publications of experiment stations; free mailing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Bulletins, reports, periodicals, reprints of articles, and other publications necessary for the dissemination of results of the researches and experiments, including lists of publications available for distribution by the experiment stations, shall be transmitted in the mails of the United States. Such publications may be mailed from the principal place of business of the station or from an established subunit of said station.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 2, 1887, ch. 314, § 6</ref>, <ref>24 Stat. 441</ref>; <ref>Aug. 11, 1955, ch. 790, § 1</ref>, <ref>69 Stat. 673</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–375, § 4(a)</ref>, <date date="1970-08-12">Aug. 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 773</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title VII, § 7404(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1247</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title VII, § 7404(b)(1), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2008.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 361g.</num>
<heading> Duties of Secretary; ascertainment of entitlement of State to funds; plans of work</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties of Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture is charged with the responsibility for the proper administration of sections 361a to 361i of this title, and is authorized and directed to prescribe such rules and regulations as may be necessary to carry out its provisions. It shall be the duty of the Secretary to furnish such advice and assistance as will best promote the purposes of said sections, including participation in coordination of research initiated under said sections by the State agricultural experiment stations, from time to time to indicate such lines of inquiry as to him seem most important, and to encourage and assist in the establishment and maintenance of cooperation by and between the several State agricultural experiment stations, and between the stations and the United States Department of Agriculture.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Ascertainment of entitlement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On or before the first day of October in each year after the passage of sections 361a to 361i of this title, the Secretary of Agriculture shall ascertain as to each State whether it is entitled to receive its share of the annual appropriations for agricultural experiment stations under said sections and the amount which thereupon each is entitled, respectively, to receive.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Carryover</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The balance of any annual funds provided under sections 361a to 361i of this title to a State agricultural experiment station for a fiscal year that remains unexpended at the end of the fiscal year may be carried over for use during the following fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Failure to expend full allotment</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">If any unexpended balance carried over by a State is not expended by the end of the second fiscal year, an amount equal to the unexpended balance shall be deducted from the next succeeding annual allotment to the State.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Redistribution</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Federal funds that are deducted under subparagraph (A) for a fiscal year shall be redistributed by the Secretary in accordance with the formula set forth in <ref>section 361c(c) of this title</ref> to those States for which no deduction under subparagraph (A) has been taken for that fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Plan of work required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Before funds may be provided to a State under sections 361a to 361i of this title for any fiscal year, a plan of work to be carried out under sections 361a to 361i of this title shall be submitted by the proper officials of the State and shall be approved by the Secretary of Agriculture.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements related to plan of work</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each plan of work for a State required under subsection (d) shall contain descriptions of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A summary of planned projects or programs in the State using formula funds.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A description of the manner in which the State will meet the requirements of subsections (c)(3) and (i)(2) of <ref>section 361c of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A description of matching funds provided by the State with respect to the previous fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Research protocols</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Development</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary of Agriculture shall develop protocols to be used to evaluate the success of multistate, multi-institutional, and multidisciplinary research activities and joint research and extension activities in addressing critical agricultural issues identified in the plans of work submitted under subsection (d).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary of Agriculture shall develop the protocols in consultation with the National Agricultural Research, Extension, Education, and Economics Advisory Board established under <ref>section 3123 of this title</ref> and land-grant colleges and universities.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment of plans of work for other purposes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To the maximum extent practicable, the Secretary shall consider a plan of work submitted under subsection (d) to satisfy other appropriate Federal reporting requirements.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 2, 1887, ch. 314, § 7</ref>, <ref>24 Stat. 441</ref>; <ref>Aug. 11, 1955, ch. 790, § 1</ref>, <ref>69 Stat. 673</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–533, § 1(22)</ref>, <date date="1960-06-29">June 29, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 249</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–273, § 3(2)</ref>, <date date="1976-04-21">Apr. 21, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 376</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–185, title I, § 103(f)(2)</ref>, title II, § 202(b), <date date="1998-06-23">June 23, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 528</ref>, 532; <ref>Pub. L. 107–171, title VII, § 7202</ref>, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 437</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title VII, § 7612(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4832</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 361h.</num>
<heading> Relation of college or university to State unaffected; division of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in sections 361a to 361i of this title shall be construed to impair or modify the legal relation existing between any of the colleges or universities under whose direction State agricultural experiment stations have been established and the government of the States in which they are respectively located. States having agricultural experiment stations separate from such colleges or universities and established by law, shall be authorized to apply such benefits to research at stations so established by such States: <i>Provided</i>, That in any State in which more than one such college, university, or agricultural experiment station has been established the appropriations made pursuant to sections 361a to 361i of this title for such State shall be divided between such institutions as the legislature of such State shall direct.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 2, 1887, ch. 314, § 8</ref>, <ref>24 Stat. 441</ref>; <ref>Aug. 11, 1955, ch. 790, § 1</ref>, <ref>69 Stat. 674</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 361i.</num>
<heading> Power to amend, repeal, etc., reserved</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Congress may at any time, amend, suspend, or repeal any or all of the provisions of sections 361a to 361i of this title.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 2, 1887, ch. 314, § 9</ref>, <ref>24 Stat. 442</ref>; <ref>Aug. 11, 1955, ch. 790, § 1</ref>, <ref>69 Stat. 674</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 362, 363.</num>
<heading> Transferred</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 364.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Aug. 11, 1955, ch. 790, § 2</ref>, <ref>69 Stat. 675</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 365.</num>
<heading> Transferred</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 366.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Aug. 11, 1955, ch. 790, § 2</ref>, <ref>69 Stat. 674</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 367.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 368 to 368b.</num>
<heading> Transferred</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 368c.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 369 to 376.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Aug. 11, 1955, ch. 790, § 2</ref>, <ref>69 Stat. 674</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 377 to 379.</num>
<heading> Transferred</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 380.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Aug. 11, 1955, ch. 790, § 2</ref>, <ref>69 Stat. 674</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 381.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 382, 383.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Aug. 11, 1955, ch. 790, § 2</ref>, <ref>69 Stat. 674</ref>, 675</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 384.</num>
<heading> Card index of agricultural literature; copies to be furnished by Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture may furnish to such institutions or individuals as may care to buy them copies of the card index of agricultural literature prepared by the Department of Agriculture in connection with its administration of the Act of March second, eighteen hundred and eighty-seven [<ref>7 U.S.C. 361a</ref> et seq.], and the Act of March sixteenth, nineteen hundred and six, and the Acts amendatory of and supplementary thereto, and charge for the same a price covering the additional expenses involved in the preparation of these copies, the money received from such sales to be deposited in the Treasury of the United States as miscellaneous receipts.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 4, 1915, ch. 144</ref>, <ref>38 Stat. 1109</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 385.</num>
<heading> South Carolina Experiment Station; cooperation by Secretary of Agriculture; lump sum appropriation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated the sum of $50,000 to enable the Secretary of Agriculture to cooperate with the South Carolina Agricultural Experiment Station and/or other agencies in making investigations and experiments in dairying and livestock industries and of the problems pertaining to the establishment and development of such industries, including cropping systems, soil improvement, and farm organization studies of such industries, and for demonstration, assistance, and service in developing the agriculture of the Sand Hill region of the Southeast.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 3, 1927, ch. 367, § 1</ref>, <ref>44 Stat. 1397</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 385a.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated each fiscal year necessary appropriations to enable the Secretary of Agriculture to carry on the cooperative experiments contemplated by <ref>section 385 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 3, 1927, ch. 367, § 2</ref>, as added <ref>Feb. 4, 1928, ch. 24</ref>, <ref>45 Stat. 57</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 386 to 386f.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Aug. 11, 1955, ch. 790, § 2</ref>, <ref>69 Stat. 674</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 386g.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Oct. 31, 1951, ch. 654, § 1(10)</ref>, <ref>65 Stat. 701</ref></heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>EXPERIMENT STATIONS FOR PROPAGATION OF TREES, SHRUBS, VINES, AND VEGETABLES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 387.</num>
<heading> Station for semi-arid or dry-land regions; establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture is authorized and directed to cause such shade, ornamental, fruit, and shelter-belt trees, shrubs, vines, and vegetables as are adapted to the conditions and needs of the semi-arid or dry-land regions of the United States, to be propagated at an experiment station of the Department of Agriculture to be established at or near Cheyenne, Wyoming, and seedlings and cuttings and seeds of such trees, shrubs, vines, and vegetables to be distributed free of charge under such regulations as he may prescribe for experimental and demonstration purposes within the semi-arid or dry-land regions of the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 19, 1928, ch. 228, § 1</ref>, <ref>45 Stat. 323</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 387a.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated each fiscal year necessary appropriations to enable the Secretary of Agriculture to carry on the experiments contemplated by <ref>section 387 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 19, 1928, ch. 228, § 3</ref>, <ref>45 Stat. 323</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 388.</num>
<heading> Station for southern Great Plains area; establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture is authorized and directed to cause such shade, ornamental, fruit, and shelter-belt trees, shrubs, and vines as are adapted to the conditions and needs of the southern Great Plains area, comprised of those parts of the States of Colorado, Nebraska, Kansas, Texas, Oklahoma, and New Mexico lying west of the ninety-eighth meridian and east of the five thousand-foot contour line, to be propagated at one of the existing field stations of the Department of Agriculture in such area, and seedlings and cuttings and seeds of such trees, shrubs, and vines to be distributed free of charge under such regulations as he may prescribe for experimental and demonstration purposes within such area.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Apr. 16, 1928, ch. 377, § 1</ref>, <ref>45 Stat. 430</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 388a.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated each fiscal year necessary appropriations to enable the Secretary of Agriculture to carry on the experiments contemplated by <ref>section 388 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Apr. 16, 1928, ch. 377, § 3</ref>, <ref>45 Stat. 431</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 389.</num>
<heading> Transfer of certain dry land and irrigation field stations to States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture is authorized, at such times as he deems appropriate, to convey by appropriate conveyances, without consideration, the interest of the United States in the lands, including water rights, buildings, and improvements presently comprising or appurtenant to the following dry land and irrigation field stations, to the States in which such stations are located, when, in the opinion of the Secretary of Agriculture, the transfer of any such station will result in establishing a more effective program in the cooperative agricultural experimental work of the Department of Agriculture and the respective State and the furtherance of agricultural experimental work on a national or regional basis will be better served by such transfer: Huntley, Montana; Mitchell, Nebraska; Fallon, Nevada; Tucumcari, New Mexico; Hermiston, Oregon; Sheridan, Wyoming: <i>Provided</i>, That when any or all of the land, including water rights, comprising any such station is public-domain land, only the Secretary of the Interior may by patent or other appropriate conveyance transfer such lands to the respective States: <i>Provided further</i>, That when any easement necessary to a station conveyed or patented hereunder is on public-domain lands, only the Secretary of the Interior may grant such easements to the State to which the station has been conveyed.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Sept. 23, 1950, ch. 1005, § 1</ref>, <ref>64 Stat. 981</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 389a.</num>
<heading> Conditions of transfer of dry land and irrigation field stations; reservation of mineral rights</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Conveyances or patents under this section and <ref>section 389 of this title</ref> shall be upon such conditions as in the opinion of the Secretary of Agriculture will assure the use of such station in the cooperative agricultural experimental work of the Department of Agriculture and the respective State. Any such conveyances of the land shall contain a reservation to the United States of all the minerals in the land together with the right to prospect for, mine, and remove the same under such regulations as the Secretary of the Interior may prescribe.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Sept. 23, 1950, ch. 1005, § 2</ref>, <ref>64 Stat. 982</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>RESEARCH FACILITIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 390.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this subchapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agricultural research facility</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “agricultural research facility” means a proposed facility for research in food and agricultural sciences for which Federal funds are requested by an entity eligible to receive funds under a capacity and infrastructure program (as defined in <ref>section 6971(f)(1)(C) of this title</ref>) to assist in the construction, alteration, acquisition, modernization, renovation, or remodeling of the facility.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Congressional agriculture committees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “congressional agriculture committees” means the Committee on Appropriations and the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Appropriations and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Food and agricultural sciences</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “food and agricultural sciences” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 3103 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Agriculture.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 88–74, § 2</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title VIII, § 884(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1176</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–171, title VII</ref>, §§ 7214, 7308(b), <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 448</ref>, 455; <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title VII, § 7101(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1213</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title VII, § 7101(b)(1), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1974; <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title VII, § 7503(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4821</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 390a.</num>
<heading> Review process</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Submission to Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each proposal for an agricultural research facility shall be submitted to the Secretary for review. The Secretary shall review the proposals in the order in which the proposals are received.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application process</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In consultation with the congressional agriculture committees, the Secretary shall establish an application process for the submission of proposals for agricultural research facilities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Criteria for approval</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determination by Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">With respect to each proposal for an agricultural research facility submitted under subsection (a), the Secretary shall determine whether the proposal meets the criteria set forth in paragraph (2).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Criteria</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A proposal for an agricultural research facility shall meet the following criteria:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Non-Federal share</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The proposal shall certify the availability of at least a 50 percent non-Federal share of the cost of the facility. The non-Federal share shall be paid in cash and may include funding from private sources or from units of State or local government.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonduplication of facilities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The proposal shall demonstrate how the agricultural research facility would be complementary to, and not duplicative of, facilities of colleges, universities, and nonprofit institutions, and facilities of the Agricultural Research Service, within the State and region.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National research priorities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The proposal shall demonstrate how the agricultural research facility would serve—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> 1 or more of the national research policies and priorities set forth in <ref>section 3101 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> national or multistate needs.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Long-term support</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The proposal shall demonstrate that the recipient entity has the ability and commitment to support the long-term, ongoing operating and maintenance costs of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the agricultural research facility after the facility is completed; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> each program to be based at the facility.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Evaluation of proposals</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 90 days after receiving a proposal under subsection (a), the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> evaluate and assess the merits of the proposal, including the extent to which the proposal meets the criteria set forth in subsection (c); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> report to the congressional agriculture committees on the results of the evaluation and assessment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National or multistate needs served by ARS facilities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall ensure that each research activity conducted by a facility of the Agricultural Research Service serves a national or multistate need.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 88–74, § 3</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title VIII, § 884(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1177</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–185, title I, § 106(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1998-06-23">June 23, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 530</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title VII, § 7503(a)(2)</ref>, (b), <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4821</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 390b.</num>
<heading> Competitive grant program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish a program to make competitive grants to assist in the construction, alteration, acquisition, modernization, renovation, or remodeling of agricultural research facilities.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 88–74, § 4</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title VII, § 7503(c)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4821</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 390c.</num>
<heading> Applicability of chapter 10 of title 5</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Chapter 10 of title 5 and title XVIII of the Food and Agriculture Act of 1977 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 2281</ref> et seq.) shall not apply to a panel or board created solely for the purpose of reviewing applications or proposals submitted under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 88–74, § 5</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title VIII, § 884(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1179</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(a)(22)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4307</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 390d.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to subsections (b), (c), and (d), there are authorized to be appropriated such sums as are necessary for each of fiscal years 1996 through 2023 for the study, plan, design, structure, and related costs of agricultural research facilities under this subchapter. Funds appropriated pursuant to the preceding sentence shall be available until expended.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Allowable administrative costs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not more than 3 percent of the funds made available for any project for an agricultural research facility shall be available for administration of the project.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Maximum amount</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not more than 25 percent of the funds made available pursuant to subsection (a) for any fiscal year shall be used for any single agricultural research facility project.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Project limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An entity eligible to receive funds under this subchapter may receive funds for only one project at a time.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 88–74, § 6</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title VIII, § 884(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1179</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–185, title III, § 301(d)</ref>, <date date="1998-06-23">June 23, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 563</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–171, title VII, § 7135</ref>, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 436</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title VII, § 7405</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1247</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title VII, § 7405, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2008; <ref>Pub. L. 113–79, title VII, § 7403</ref>, <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 895</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title VII, § 7503(d)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4821</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>