<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 113—</num>
<heading>AGRICULTURAL COMMODITY SUPPORT PROGRAMS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 8701.</num>
<heading> Definition of Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this Act, the term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Agriculture.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–234, § 2</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 936</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246</ref>, §§ 2, 4(a), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8702.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter (other than subchapter III):</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Average crop revenue election payment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “average crop revenue election payment” means a payment made to producers on a farm under section 8715 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002369">1</ref> of this title.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Base acres</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “base acres”, with respect to a covered commodity on a farm, means the number of acres established under <ref>section 7911 of this title</ref> as in effect on <date date="2007-09-30">September 30, 2007</date>, subject to any adjustment under <ref>section 8711 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Peanuts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “base acres for peanuts” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 8751 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Counter-cyclical payment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “counter-cyclical payment” means a payment made to producers on a farm under section 8714 <sup>1</sup> of this title.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Covered commodity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “covered commodity” means wheat, corn, grain sorghum, barley, oats, upland cotton, long grain rice, medium grain rice, pulse crops, soybeans, and other oilseeds.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Direct payment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “direct payment” means a payment made to producers on a farm under section 8713 <sup>1</sup> of this title.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective price</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “effective price”, with respect to a covered commodity for a crop year, means the price calculated by the Secretary under section 8714 <sup>1</sup> of this title to determine whether counter-cyclical payments are required to be made for that crop year.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Extra long staple cotton</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “extra long staple cotton” means cotton that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is produced from pure strain varieties of the Barbadense species or any hybrid of the species, or other similar types of extra long staple cotton, designated by the Secretary, having characteristics needed for various end uses for which United States upland cotton is not suitable and grown in irrigated cotton-growing regions of the United States designated by the Secretary or other areas designated by the Secretary as suitable for the production of the varieties or types; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is ginned on a roller-type gin or, if authorized by the Secretary, ginned on another type gin for experimental purposes.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Loan commodity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “loan commodity” means wheat, corn, grain sorghum, barley, oats, upland cotton, extra long staple cotton, long grain rice, medium grain rice, soybeans, other oilseeds, graded wool, nongraded wool, mohair, honey, dry peas, lentils, small chickpeas, and large chickpeas.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Medium grain rice</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “medium grain rice” includes short grain rice.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(10)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other oilseed</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “other oilseed” means a crop of sunflower seed, rapeseed, canola, safflower, flaxseed, mustard seed, crambe, sesame seed, or any oilseed designated by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(11)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payment acres</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “payment acres” means, in the case of direct payments and counter-cyclical payments—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> except as provided in subparagraph (B), 85 percent of the base acres of a covered commodity on a farm on which direct payments or counter-cyclical payments are made; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of direct payments for each of the 2009 through 2011 crop years, 83.3 percent of the base acres for the covered commodity on a farm on which direct payments are made.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(12)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payment yield</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “payment yield” means the yield established for direct payments and the yield established for counter-cyclical payments under <ref>section 7912 of this title</ref> as in effect on <date date="2007-09-30">September 30, 2007</date>, or under <ref>section 8712 of this title</ref>, for a farm for a covered commodity.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(13)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Producer</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “producer” means an owner, operator, landlord, tenant, or sharecropper that shares in the risk of producing a crop and is entitled to share in the crop available for marketing from the farm, or would have shared had the crop been produced.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Hybrid seed</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In determining whether a grower of hybrid seed is a producer, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> not take into consideration the existence of a hybrid seed contract; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> ensure that program requirements do not adversely affect the ability of the grower to receive a payment under this chapter.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(14)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Pulse crop</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “pulse crop” means dry peas, lentils, small chickpeas, and large chickpeas.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(15)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “State” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a State;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the District of Columbia;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> any other territory or possession of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(16)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Target price</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “target price” means the price per bushel, pound, or hundredweight (or other appropriate unit) of a covered commodity used to determine the payment rate for counter-cyclical payments.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(17)</num>
<heading class="bold"> United States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “United States”, when used in a geographical sense, means all of the States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(18)</num>
<heading class="bold"> United States Premium Factor</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “United States Premium Factor” means the percentage by which the difference in the United States loan schedule premiums for Strict Middling (SM) 1⅛-inch upland cotton and for Middling (M) 1<sup>3</sup>⁄<sub>32</sub>-inch upland cotton exceeds the difference in the applicable premiums for comparable international qualities.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title I, § 1001</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 936</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title I, § 1001, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>DIRECT PAYMENTS AND COUNTER-CYCLICAL PAYMENTS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 8711.</num>
<heading> Base acres</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adjustment of base acres</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary shall provide for an adjustment, as appropriate, in the base acres for covered commodities for a farm whenever any of the following circumstances occurs:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A conservation reserve contract entered into under section 1231 of the Food Security Act of 1985 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 3831</ref>) with respect to the farm expires or is voluntarily terminated, or was terminated or expired during the period beginning on <date date="2007-10-01">October 1, 2007</date>, and ending on the date of enactment of this Act.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Cropland is released from coverage under a conservation reserve contract by the Secretary, or was released during the period beginning on <date date="2007-10-01">October 1, 2007</date>, and ending on the date of enactment of this Act.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The producer has eligible pulse crop acreage, which shall be determined in the same manner as eligible oilseed acreage under <ref>section 7911(a)(2) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The producer has eligible oilseed acreage as the result of the Secretary designating additional oilseeds, which shall be determined in the same manner as eligible oilseed acreage under <ref>section 7911(a)(2) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special conservation reserve acreage payment rules</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For the crop year in which a base acres adjustment under subparagraph (A) or (B) of paragraph (1) is first made, the owner of the farm shall elect to receive either direct payments and counter-cyclical payments with respect to the acreage added to the farm under this subsection or a prorated payment under the conservation reserve contract, but not both.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prevention of excess base acres</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Required reduction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the sum of the base acres for a farm, together with the acreage described in paragraph (2) exceeds the actual cropland acreage of the farm, the Secretary shall reduce the base acres for 1 or more covered commodities for the farm or the base acres for peanuts for the farm so that the sum of the base acres and acreage described in paragraph (2) does not exceed the actual cropland acreage of the farm.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other acreage</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of paragraph (1), the Secretary shall include the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Any base acres for peanuts for the farm.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Any acreage on the farm enrolled in the conservation reserve program or wetlands reserve program under chapter 1 of subtitle D of title XII of the Food Security Act of 1985 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 3830</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Any other acreage on the farm enrolled in a Federal conservation program for which payments are made in exchange for not producing an agricultural commodity on the acreage.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Any eligible pulse crop acreage, which shall be determined in the same manner as eligible oilseed acreage under <ref>section 7911(a)(2) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> If the Secretary designates additional oilseeds, any eligible oilseed acreage, which shall be determined in the same manner as eligible oilseed acreage under <ref>section 7911(a)(2) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Selection of acres</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall give the owner of the farm the opportunity to select the base acres for a covered commodity or the base acres for peanuts for the farm against which the reduction required by paragraph (1) will be made.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception for double-cropped acreage</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In applying paragraph (1), the Secretary shall make an exception in the case of double cropping, as determined by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordinated application of requirements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall take into account <ref>section 8752(b) of this title</ref> when applying the requirements of this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reduction in base acres</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reduction at option of owner</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The owner of a farm may reduce, at any time, the base acres for any covered commodity for the farm.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect of reduction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A reduction under subparagraph (A) shall be permanent and made in a manner prescribed by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Required action by Secretary</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Secretary shall proportionately reduce base acres on a farm for covered commodities for land that has been subdivided and developed for multiple residential units or other nonfarming uses if the size of the tracts and the density of the subdivision is such that the land is unlikely to return to the previous agricultural use, unless the producers on the farm demonstrate that the land—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> remains devoted to commercial agricultural production; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> is likely to be returned to the previous agricultural use.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary shall establish procedures to identify land described in subparagraph (A).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review and report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Each year, to ensure, to the maximum extent practicable, that payments are received only by producers, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report that describes the results of the actions taken under paragraph (2).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment of farms with limited base acres</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition on payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (2) and notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, a producer on a farm may not receive direct payments, counter-cyclical payments, or average crop revenue election payments if the sum of the base acres of the farm is 10 acres or less, as determined by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Paragraph (1) shall not apply to a farm owned by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a socially disadvantaged farmer or rancher (as defined in <ref>section 2003(e) of this title</ref>; <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002370">1</ref> or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a limited resource farmer or rancher, as defined by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Data collection and publication</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> collect and publish segregated data and survey information about the farm profiles, utilization of land, and crop production; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> perform an evaluation on the supply and price of fruits and vegetables based on the effects of suspension of base acres under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Suspension of prohibition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Paragraphs (1) through (3) shall not apply during the 2008 crop year.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title I, § 1101</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 938</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title I, § 1101, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1666; <ref>Pub. L. 110–398, § 1(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2008-10-13">Oct. 13, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4213</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8712.</num>
<heading> Payment yields</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment and purpose</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purpose of making direct payments and counter-cyclical payments under this subchapter, the Secretary shall provide for the establishment of a yield for each farm for any designated oilseed or eligible pulse crop for which a payment yield was not established under <ref>section 7912 of this title</ref> in accordance with this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payment yields for designated oilseeds and eligible pulse crops</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determination of average yield</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In the case of designated oilseeds and eligible pulse crops, the Secretary shall determine the average yield per planted acre for the designated oilseed or pulse crop on a farm for the 1998 through 2001 crop years, excluding any crop year in which the acreage planted to the designated oilseed or pulse crop was zero.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adjustment for payment yield</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The payment yield for a farm for a designated oilseed or eligible pulse crop shall be equal to the product of the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The average yield for the designated oilseed or pulse crop determined under paragraph (1).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The ratio resulting from dividing the national average yield for the designated oilseed or pulse crop for the 1981 through 1985 crops by the national average yield for the designated oilseed or pulse crop for the 1998 through 2001 crops.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> No national average yield information available</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">To the extent that national average yield information for a designated oilseed or pulse crop is not available, the Secretary shall use such information as the Secretary determines to be fair and equitable to establish a national average yield under this section.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of partial county average yield</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the yield per planted acre for a crop of a designated oilseed or pulse crop for a farm for any of the 1998 through 2001 crop years was less than 75 percent of the county yield for that designated oilseed or pulse crop, the Secretary shall assign a yield for that crop year equal to 75 percent of the county yield for the purpose of determining the average under paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> No historic yield data available</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In the case of establishing yields for designated oilseeds and eligible pulse crops, if historic yield data is not available, the Secretary shall use the ratio for dry peas calculated under paragraph (2)(A)(ii) in determining the yields for designated oilseeds and eligible pulse crops, as determined to be fair and equitable by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title I, § 1102</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 940</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title I, § 1102, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1669.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8713.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 113–79, title I, § 1101</ref>, <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 658</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8714.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 113–79, title I, § 1102(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 658</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8715.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 113–79, title I, § 1103(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 658</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8716.</num>
<heading> Producer agreement required as condition of provision of payments</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compliance with certain requirements</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Before the producers on a farm may receive direct payments, counter-cyclical payments, or average crop revenue election payments with respect to the farm, the producers shall agree, during the crop year for which the payments are made and in exchange for the payments—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to comply with applicable conservation requirements under subtitle B of title XII of the Food Security Act of 1985 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 3811</ref> et seq.);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to comply with applicable wetland protection requirements under subtitle C of title XII of that Act (<ref>16 U.S.C. 3821</ref> et seq.);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to comply with the planting flexibility requirements of <ref>section 8717 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> to use the land on the farm, in a quantity equal to the attributable base acres for the farm and any base acres for peanuts for the farm under subchapter III, for an agricultural or conserving use, and not for a nonagricultural commercial, industrial, or residential use, as determined by the Secretary; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> to effectively control noxious weeds and otherwise maintain the land in accordance with sound agricultural practices, as determined by the Secretary, if the agricultural or conserving use involves the noncultivation of any portion of the land referred to in subparagraph (D).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compliance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may issue such rules as the Secretary considers necessary to ensure producer compliance with the requirements of paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Modification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">At the request of the transferee or owner, the Secretary may modify the requirements of this subsection if the modifications are consistent with the objectives of this subsection, as determined by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer or change of interest in farm</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Except as provided in paragraph (2), a transfer of (or change in) the interest of the producers on a farm in base acres for which direct payments or counter-cyclical payments are made, or on which average crop revenue election payments are based, shall result in the termination of the direct payments, counter-cyclical payments, or average crop revenue election payments to the extent the payments are made or based on the base acres, unless the transferee or owner of the acreage agrees to assume all obligations under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The termination shall take effect on the date determined by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If a producer entitled to a direct payment, counter-cyclical payment, or average crop revenue election payment dies, becomes incompetent, or is otherwise unable to receive the payment, the Secretary shall make the payment, in accordance with rules issued by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Acreage reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">As a condition on the receipt of any benefits under this subchapter or subchapter II, the Secretary shall require producers on a farm to submit to the Secretary annual acreage reports with respect to all cropland on the farm.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Production reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">As a condition on the receipt of any benefits under this subchapter or subchapter II, the Secretary shall require producers on a farm that receive payments under section 8715 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002371">1</ref> of this title to submit to the Secretary annual production reports with respect to all covered commodities and peanuts produced on the farm.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Penalties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">No penalty with respect to benefits under this subchapter or subchapter II shall be assessed against the producers on a farm for an inaccurate acreage or production report unless the producers on the farm knowingly and willfully falsified the acreage or production report.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tenants and sharecroppers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In carrying out this subchapter, the Secretary shall provide adequate safeguards to protect the interests of tenants and sharecroppers.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sharing of payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall provide for the sharing of direct payments, counter-cyclical payments, or average crop revenue election payments among the producers on a farm on a fair and equitable basis.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Extension of 2008 signup</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary shall extend the 2008 crop year deadline for the signup for benefits under this subchapter by producers on a farm with base acres of 10 acres or less until the later of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content><date date="2008-11-14">November 14, 2008</date>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the end of the 45-day period beginning on <date date="2008-10-13">October 13, 2008</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Penalties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall ensure that no penalty with respect to benefits under this subchapter or subchapter II is assessed against producers on a farm described in paragraph (1) for failure to submit reports under this section or timely comply with other program requirements as a result of compliance with the extended signup deadline under that paragraph.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title I, § 1106</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 949</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title I, § 1106, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1677; <ref>Pub. L. 110–398, § 1(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2008-10-13">Oct. 13, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4213</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8717.</num>
<heading> Planting flexibility</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Permitted crops</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to subsection (b), any commodity or crop may be planted on base acres on a farm.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations regarding certain commodities</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The planting of an agricultural commodity specified in paragraph (3) shall be prohibited on base acres unless the commodity, if planted, is destroyed before harvest.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment of trees and other perennials</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The planting of an agricultural commodity specified in paragraph (3) that is produced on a tree or other perennial plant shall be prohibited on base acres.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Covered agricultural commodities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Paragraphs (1) and (2) apply to the following agricultural commodities:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Fruits.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Vegetables (other than mung beans and pulse crops).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Wild rice.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (b) shall not limit the planting of an agricultural commodity specified in paragraph (3) of that subsection—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in any region in which there is a history of double-cropping of covered commodities with agricultural commodities specified in subsection (b)(3), as determined by the Secretary, in which case the double-cropping shall be permitted;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> on a farm that the Secretary determines has a history of planting agricultural commodities specified in subsection (b)(3) on base acres, except that direct payments and counter-cyclical payments shall be reduced by an acre for each acre planted to such an agricultural commodity; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> by the producers on a farm that the Secretary determines has an established planting history of a specific agricultural commodity specified in subsection (b)(3), except that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the quantity planted may not exceed the average annual planting history of such agricultural commodity by the producers on the farm in the 1991 through 1995 or 1998 through 2001 crop years (excluding any crop year in which no plantings were made), as determined by the Secretary; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> direct payments and counter-cyclical payments shall be reduced by an acre for each acre planted to such agricultural commodity.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Planting transferability pilot project</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Pilot project authorized</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (b) and in addition to the exceptions provided in subsection (c), the Secretary shall carry out a pilot project to permit the planting of cucumbers, green peas, lima beans, pumpkins, snap beans, sweet corn, and tomatoes grown for processing on base acres during each of the 2009 through 2012 crop years.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Pilot project States and acres</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The number of base acres eligible during each crop year for the pilot project under paragraph (1) shall be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> 9,000 acres in the State of Illinois;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> 9,000 acres in the State of Indiana;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> 1,000 acres in the State of Iowa;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> 9,000 acres in the State of Michigan;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> 34,000 acres in the State of Minnesota;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> 4,000 acres in the State of Ohio; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> 9,000 acres in the State of Wisconsin.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contract and management requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">To be eligible for selection to participate in the pilot project, the producers on a farm shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> demonstrate to the Secretary that the producers on the farm have entered into a contract to produce a crop of a commodity specified in paragraph (1) for processing;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> agree to produce the crop as part of a program of crop rotation on the farm to achieve agronomic and pest and disease management benefits; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> provide evidence of the disposition of the crop.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Temporary reduction in base acres</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The base acres on a farm for a crop year shall be reduced by an acre for each acre planted under the pilot program.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duration of reductions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The reduction in the base acres of a farm for a crop year under paragraph (4) shall expire at the end of the crop year.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recalculation of base acres</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">If the Secretary recalculates base acres for a farm while the farm is included in the pilot project, the planting and production of a crop of a commodity specified in paragraph (1) on base acres for which a temporary reduction was made under this section shall be considered to be the same as the planting and production of a covered commodity.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Nothing in this paragraph provides authority for the Secretary to recalculate base acres for a farm.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Pilot impact evaluation</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Secretary shall periodically evaluate the pilot project conducted under this subsection to determine the effects of the pilot project on the supply and price of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> fresh fruits and vegetables; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> fruits and vegetables for processing.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determination</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">An evaluation under subparagraph (A) shall include a determination as to whether—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> producers of fresh fruits and vegetables are being negatively impacted; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> existing production capacities are being supplanted.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">As soon as practicable after conducting an evaluation under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate a report that describes the results of the evaluation.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title I, § 1107</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 950</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title I, § 1107, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1679.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8718.</num>
<heading> Special rule for long grain and medium grain rice</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Calculation method</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to subsections (b) and (c), for the purposes of determining the amount of the counter-cyclical payments to be paid to the producers on a farm for long grain rice and medium grain rice under section 8714 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002372">1</ref> of this title, the base acres of rice on the farm shall be apportioned using the 4-year average of the percentages of acreage planted in the applicable State to long grain rice and medium grain rice during the 2003 through 2006 crop years, as determined by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Producer election</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As an alternative to the calculation method described in subsection (a), the Secretary shall provide producers on a farm the opportunity to elect to apportion rice base acres on the farm using the 4-year average of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the percentages of acreage planted on the farm to long grain rice and medium grain rice during the 2003 through 2006 crop years;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the percentages of any acreage on the farm that the producers were prevented from planting to long grain rice and medium grain rice during the 2003 through 2006 crop years because of drought, flood, other natural disaster, or other condition beyond the control of the producers, as determined by the Secretary; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> in the case of a crop year for which a producer on a farm elected not to plant to long grain and medium grain rice during the 2003 through 2006 crop years, the percentages of acreage planted in the applicable State to long grain rice and medium grain rice, as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall use the same total base acres, payment acres, and payment yields established with respect to rice under sections 7911 and 7912 of this title, as in effect on <date date="2007-09-30">September 30, 2007</date>, subject to any adjustment under <ref>section 8711 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title I, § 1108</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 952</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title I, § 1108, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1681.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8719.</num>
<heading> Period of effectiveness</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This subchapter shall be effective beginning with the 2008 crop year of each covered commodity through the 2012 crop year.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title I, § 1109</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 953</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title I, § 1109, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1681.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>MARKETING ASSISTANCE LOANS AND LOAN DEFICIENCY PAYMENTS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 8731.</num>
<heading> Availability of nonrecourse marketing assistance loans for loan commodities</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonrecourse loans available</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For each of the 2008 through 2012 crops of each loan commodity, the Secretary shall make available to producers on a farm nonrecourse marketing assistance loans for loan commodities produced on the farm.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Terms and conditions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The marketing assistance loans shall be made under terms and conditions that are prescribed by the Secretary and at the loan rate established under <ref>section 8732 of this title</ref> for the loan commodity.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible production</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The producers on a farm shall be eligible for a marketing assistance loan under subsection (a) for any quantity of a loan commodity produced on the farm.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compliance with conservation and wetlands requirements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As a condition of the receipt of a marketing assistance loan under subsection (a), the producer shall comply with applicable conservation requirements under subtitle B of title XII of the Food Security Act of 1985 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 3811</ref> et seq.) and applicable wetland protection requirements under subtitle C of title XII of that Act (<ref>16 U.S.C. 3821</ref> et seq.) during the term of the loan.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title I, § 1201</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 953</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title I, § 1201, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1681.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8732.</num>
<heading> Loan rates for nonrecourse marketing assistance loans</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> 2008 crop year</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of the 2008 crop year, the loan rate for a marketing assistance loan under <ref>section 8731 of this title</ref> for a loan commodity shall be equal to the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In the case of wheat, $2.75 per bushel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In the case of corn, $1.95 per bushel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> In the case of grain sorghum, $1.95 per bushel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> In the case of barley, $1.85 per bushel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> In the case of oats, $1.33 per bushel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> In the case of base quality of upland cotton, $0.52 per pound.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> In the case of extra long staple cotton, $0.7977 per pound.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> In the case of long grain rice, $6.50 per hundredweight.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> In the case of medium grain rice, $6.50 per hundredweight.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> In the case of soybeans, $5.00 per bushel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<chapeau> In the case of other oilseeds, $9.30 per hundredweight for each of the following kinds of oilseeds:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Sunflower seed.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Rapeseed.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Canola.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Safflower.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Flaxseed.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Mustard seed.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> Crambe.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> Sesame seed.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> Other oilseeds designated by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> In the case of dry peas, $6.22 per hundredweight.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> In the case of lentils, $11.72 per hundredweight.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> In the case of small chickpeas, $7.43 per hundredweight.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<content> In the case of graded wool, $1.00 per pound.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(16)</num>
<content> In the case of nongraded wool, $0.40 per pound.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(17)</num>
<content> In the case of mohair, $4.20 per pound.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(18)</num>
<content> In the case of honey, $0.60 per pound.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> 2009 crop year</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except as provided in section 8715 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002373">1</ref> of this title, for purposes of the 2009 crop year, the loan rate for a marketing assistance loan under <ref>section 8731 of this title</ref> for a loan commodity shall be equal to the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In the case of wheat, $2.75 per bushel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In the case of corn, $1.95 per bushel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> In the case of grain sorghum, $1.95 per bushel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> In the case of barley, $1.85 per bushel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> In the case of oats, $1.33 per bushel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> In the case of base quality of upland cotton, $0.52 per pound.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> In the case of extra long staple cotton, $0.7977 per pound.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> In the case of long grain rice, $6.50 per hundredweight.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> In the case of medium grain rice, $6.50 per hundredweight.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> In the case of soybeans, $5.00 per bushel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<chapeau> In the case of other oilseeds, $9.30 per hundredweight for each of the following kinds of oilseeds:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Sunflower seed.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Rapeseed.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Canola.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Safflower.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Flaxseed.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Mustard seed.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> Crambe.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> Sesame seed.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> Other oilseeds designated by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> In the case of dry peas, $5.40 per hundredweight.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> In the case of lentils, $11.28 per hundredweight.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> In the case of small chickpeas, $7.43 per hundredweight.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<content> In the case of large chickpeas, $11.28 per hundredweight.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(16)</num>
<content> In the case of graded wool, $1.00 per pound.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(17)</num>
<content> In the case of nongraded wool, $0.40 per pound.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(18)</num>
<content> In the case of mohair, $4.20 per pound.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(19)</num>
<content> In the case of honey, $0.60 per pound.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> 2010 through 2012 crop years</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except as provided in section 8715 <sup>1</sup> of this title, for purposes of each of the 2010 through 2012 crop years, the loan rate for a marketing assistance loan under <ref>section 8731 of this title</ref> for a loan commodity shall be equal to the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In the case of wheat, $2.94 per bushel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In the case of corn, $1.95 per bushel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> In the case of grain sorghum, $1.95 per bushel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> In the case of barley, $1.95 per bushel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> In the case of oats, $1.39 per bushel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> In the case of base quality of upland cotton, $0.52 per pound.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> In the case of extra long staple cotton, $0.7977 per pound.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> In the case of long grain rice, $6.50 per hundredweight.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> In the case of medium grain rice, $6.50 per hundredweight.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> In the case of soybeans, $5.00 per bushel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<chapeau> In the case of other oilseeds, $10.09 per hundredweight for each of the following kinds of oilseeds:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Sunflower seed.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Rapeseed.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Canola.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Safflower.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Flaxseed.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Mustard seed.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> Crambe.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> Sesame seed.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> Other oilseeds designated by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> In the case of dry peas, $5.40 per hundredweight.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> In the case of lentils, $11.28 per hundredweight.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> In the case of small chickpeas, $7.43 per hundredweight.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<content> In the case of large chickpeas, $11.28 per hundredweight.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(16)</num>
<content> In the case of graded wool, $1.15 per pound.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(17)</num>
<content> In the case of nongraded wool, $0.40 per pound.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(18)</num>
<content> In the case of mohair, $4.20 per pound.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(19)</num>
<content> In the case of honey, $0.69 per pound.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Single county loan rate for other oilseeds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish a single loan rate in each county for each kind of other oilseeds described in subsections (a)(11), (b)(11), and (c)(11).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title I, § 1202</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 954</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title I, § 1202, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1682.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8733.</num>
<heading> Term of loans</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Term of loan</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the case of each loan commodity, a marketing assistance loan under <ref>section 8731 of this title</ref> shall have a term of 9 months beginning on the first day of the first month after the month in which the loan is made.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Extensions prohibited</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may not extend the term of a marketing assistance loan for any loan commodity.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title I, § 1203</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 956</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title I, § 1203, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1684.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8734.</num>
<heading> Repayment of loans</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General rule</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall permit the producers on a farm to repay a marketing assistance loan under <ref>section 8731 of this title</ref> for a loan commodity (other than upland cotton, long grain rice, medium grain rice, extra long staple cotton, and confectionery and each other kind of sunflower seed (other than oil sunflower seed)) at a rate that is the lesser of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the loan rate established for the commodity under <ref>section 8732 of this title</ref>, plus interest (determined in accordance with <ref>section 7283 of this title</ref>);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> a rate (as determined by the Secretary) that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is calculated based on average market prices for the loan commodity during the preceding 30-day period; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> will minimize discrepancies in marketing loan benefits across State boundaries and across county boundaries; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> a rate that the Secretary may develop using alternative methods for calculating a repayment rate for a loan commodity that the Secretary determines will—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> minimize potential loan forfeitures;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> minimize the accumulation of stocks of the commodity by the Federal Government;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> minimize the cost incurred by the Federal Government in storing the commodity;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> allow the commodity produced in the United States to be marketed freely and competitively, both domestically and internationally; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> minimize discrepancies in marketing loan benefits across State boundaries and across county boundaries.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Repayment rates for upland cotton, long grain rice, and medium grain rice</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall permit producers to repay a marketing assistance loan under <ref>section 8731 of this title</ref> for upland cotton, long grain rice, and medium grain rice at a rate that is the lesser of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the loan rate established for the commodity under <ref>section 8732 of this title</ref>, plus interest (determined in accordance with <ref>section 7283 of this title</ref>); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the prevailing world market price for the commodity, as determined and adjusted by the Secretary in accordance with this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Repayment rates for extra long staple cotton</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Repayment of a marketing assistance loan for extra long staple cotton shall be at the loan rate established for the commodity under <ref>section 8732 of this title</ref>, plus interest (determined in accordance with <ref>section 7283 of this title</ref>).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prevailing world market price</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section and <ref>section 8737 of this title</ref>, the Secretary shall prescribe by regulation—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a formula to determine the prevailing world market price for each of upland cotton, long grain rice, and medium grain rice; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a mechanism by which the Secretary shall announce periodically those prevailing world market prices.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adjustment of prevailing world market price for upland cotton, long grain rice, and medium grain rice</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rice</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The prevailing world market price for long grain rice and medium grain rice determined under subsection (d) shall be adjusted to United States quality and location.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cotton</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The prevailing world market price for upland cotton determined under subsection (d)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> shall be adjusted to United States quality and location, with the adjustment to include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a reduction equal to any United States Premium Factor for upland cotton of a quality higher than Middling (M) 1<sup>3</sup>⁄<sub>32</sub>-inch; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the average costs to market the commodity, including average transportation costs, as determined by the Secretary; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> may be further adjusted, during the period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act and ending on <date date="2013-07-31">July 31, 2013</date>, if the Secretary determines the adjustment is necessary to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> minimize potential loan forfeitures;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> minimize the accumulation of stocks of upland cotton by the Federal Government;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> ensure that upland cotton produced in the United States can be marketed freely and competitively, both domestically and internationally; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<chapeau> ensure an appropriate transition between current-crop and forward-crop price quotations, except that the Secretary may use forward-crop price quotations prior to July 31 of a marketing year only if—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> there are insufficient current-crop price quotations; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the forward-crop price quotation is the lowest such quotation available.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Guidelines for additional adjustments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In making adjustments under this subsection, the Secretary shall establish a mechanism for determining and announcing the adjustments in order to avoid undue disruption in the United States market.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Repayment rates for confectionery and other kinds of sunflower seeds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall permit the producers on a farm to repay a marketing assistance loan under <ref>section 8731 of this title</ref> for confectionery and each other kind of sunflower seed (other than oil sunflower seed) at a rate that is the lesser of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the loan rate established for the commodity under <ref>section 8732 of this title</ref>, plus interest (determined in accordance with <ref>section 7283 of this title</ref>); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the repayment rate established for oil sunflower seed.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payment of cotton storage costs</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> 2008 through 2011 crop years</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Effective for each of the 2008 through 2011 crop years, the Secretary shall provide cotton storage payments in the same manner, and at the same rates as the Secretary provided storage payments for the 2006 crop of cotton, except that the rates shall be reduced by 10 percent.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Subsequent crop years</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Beginning with the 2012 crop year, the Secretary shall provide cotton storage payments in the same manner, and at the same rates as the Secretary provided storage payments for the 2006 crop of cotton, except that the rates shall be reduced by 20 percent.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority to temporarily adjust repayment rates</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adjustment authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In the event of a severe disruption to marketing, transportation, or related infrastructure, the Secretary may modify the repayment rate otherwise applicable under this section for marketing assistance loans under <ref>section 8731 of this title</ref> for a loan commodity.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any adjustment made under paragraph (1) in the repayment rate for marketing assistance loans for a loan commodity shall be in effect on a short-term and temporary basis, as determined by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title I, § 1204</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 956</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title I, § 1204, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1684.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8735.</num>
<heading> Loan deficiency payments</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability of loan deficiency payments</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in subsection (d), the Secretary may make loan deficiency payments available to producers on a farm that, although eligible to obtain a marketing assistance loan under <ref>section 8731 of this title</ref> with respect to a loan commodity, agree to forgo obtaining the loan for the commodity in return for loan deficiency payments under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Unshorn pelts, hay, and silage</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Marketing assistance loans</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Subject to subparagraph (B), nongraded wool in the form of unshorn pelts and hay and silage derived from a loan commodity are not eligible for a marketing assistance loan under <ref>section 8731 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Loan deficiency payment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Effective for the 2008 through 2012 crop years, the Secretary may make loan deficiency payments available under this section to producers on a farm that produce unshorn pelts or hay and silage derived from a loan commodity.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Computation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A loan deficiency payment for a loan commodity or commodity referred to in subsection (a)(2) shall be computed by multiplying—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the payment rate determined under subsection (c) for the commodity; by</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the quantity of the commodity produced by the eligible producers, excluding any quantity for which the producers obtain a marketing assistance loan under <ref>section 8731 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payment rate</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In the case of a loan commodity, the payment rate shall be the amount by which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the loan rate established under <ref>section 8732 of this title</ref> for the loan commodity; exceeds</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the rate at which a marketing assistance loan for the loan commodity may be repaid under <ref>section 8734 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Unshorn pelts</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In the case of unshorn pelts, the payment rate shall be the amount by which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the loan rate established under <ref>section 8732 of this title</ref> for ungraded wool; exceeds</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the rate at which a marketing assistance loan for ungraded wool may be repaid under <ref>section 8734 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Hay and silage</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In the case of hay or silage derived from a loan commodity, the payment rate shall be the amount by which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the loan rate established under <ref>section 8732 of this title</ref> for the loan commodity from which the hay or silage is derived; exceeds</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the rate at which a marketing assistance loan for the loan commodity may be repaid under <ref>section 8734 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception for extra long staple cotton</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall not apply with respect to extra long staple cotton.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date for payment rate determination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall determine the amount of the loan deficiency payment to be made under this section to the producers on a farm with respect to a quantity of a loan commodity or commodity referred to in subsection (a)(2) using the payment rate in effect under subsection (c) as of the date the producers request the payment.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title I, § 1205</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 958</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title I, § 1205, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1686.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8736.</num>
<heading> Payments in lieu of loan deficiency payments for grazed acreage</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible producers</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Effective for the 2008 through 2012 crop years, in the case of a producer that would be eligible for a loan deficiency payment under <ref>section 8735 of this title</ref> for wheat, barley, or oats, but that elects to use acreage planted to the wheat, barley, or oats for the grazing of livestock, the Secretary shall make a payment to the producer under this section if the producer enters into an agreement with the Secretary to forgo any other harvesting of the wheat, barley, or oats on that acreage.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grazing of triticale acreage</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Effective for the 2008 through 2012 crop years, with respect to a producer on a farm that uses acreage planted to triticale for the grazing of livestock, the Secretary shall make a payment to the producer under this section if the producer enters into an agreement with the Secretary to forgo any other harvesting of triticale on that acreage.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payment amount</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The amount of a payment made under this section to a producer on a farm described in subsection (a)(1) shall be equal to the amount determined by multiplying—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the loan deficiency payment rate determined under <ref>section 8735(c) of this title</ref> in effect, as of the date of the agreement, for the county in which the farm is located; by</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> the payment quantity determined by multiplying—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the quantity of the grazed acreage on the farm with respect to which the producer elects to forgo harvesting of wheat, barley, or oats; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the payment yield in effect for the calculation of direct payments under subchapter I with respect to that loan commodity on the farm or, in the case of a farm without a payment yield for that loan commodity, an appropriate yield established by the Secretary in a manner consistent with <ref>section 7912 of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grazing of triticale acreage</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The amount of a payment made under this section to a producer on a farm described in subsection (a)(2) shall be equal to the amount determined by multiplying—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the loan deficiency payment rate determined under <ref>section 8735(c) of this title</ref> in effect for wheat, as of the date of the agreement, for the county in which the farm is located; by</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> the payment quantity determined by multiplying—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the quantity of the grazed acreage on the farm with respect to which the producer elects to forgo harvesting of triticale; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the payment yield in effect for the calculation of direct payments under subchapter I with respect to wheat on the farm or, in the case of a farm without a payment yield for wheat, an appropriate yield established by the Secretary in a manner consistent with <ref>section 7912 of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Time, manner, and availability of payment</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Time and manner</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A payment under this section shall be made at the same time and in the same manner as loan deficiency payments are made under <ref>section 8735 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary shall establish an availability period for the payments authorized by this section.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certain commodities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In the case of wheat, barley, and oats, the availability period shall be consistent with the availability period for the commodity established by the Secretary for marketing assistance loans authorized by this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition on crop insurance indemnity or noninsured crop assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A 2008 through 2012 crop of wheat, barley, oats, or triticale planted on acreage that a producer elects, in the agreement required by subsection (a), to use for the grazing of livestock in lieu of any other harvesting of the crop shall not be eligible for an indemnity under a policy or plan of insurance authorized under the Federal Crop Insurance Act (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1501</ref> et seq.) or noninsured crop assistance under <ref>section 7333 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title I, § 1206</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 959</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title I, § 1206, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1687.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8737.</num>
<heading> Special marketing loan provisions for upland cotton</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special import quota</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition of special import quota</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In this subsection, the term “special import quota” means a quantity of imports that is not subject to the over-quota tariff rate of a tariff-rate quota.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The President shall carry out an import quota program during the period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act through <date date="2013-07-31">July 31, 2013</date>, as provided in this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program requirements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Whenever the Secretary determines and announces that for any consecutive 4-week period, the Friday through Thursday average price quotation for the lowest-priced United States growth, as quoted for Middling (M) 1<sup>3</sup>⁄<sub>32</sub>-inch cotton, delivered to a definable and significant international market, as determined by the Secretary, exceeds the prevailing world market price, there shall immediately be in effect a special import quota.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Quantity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The quota shall be equal to 1 week’s consumption of cotton by domestic mills at the seasonally adjusted average rate of the most recent 3 months for which data are available.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The quota shall apply to upland cotton purchased not later than 90 days after the date of the Secretary’s announcement under paragraph (2) and entered into the United States not later than 180 days after that date.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Overlap</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A special quota period may be established that overlaps any existing quota period if required by paragraph (2), except that a special quota period may not be established under this subsection if a quota period has been established under subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Preferential tariff treatment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The quantity under a special import quota shall be considered to be an in-quota quantity for purposes of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content><ref>section 2703(d) of title 19</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content><ref>section 3203 of title 19</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content><ref>section 2463(d) of title 19</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> General Note 3(a)(iv) to the Harmonized Tariff Schedule.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The quantity of cotton entered into the United States during any marketing year under the special import quota established under this subsection may not exceed the equivalent of 10 week’s consumption of upland cotton by domestic mills at the seasonally adjusted average rate of the 3 months immediately preceding the first special import quota established in any marketing year.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limited global import quota for upland cotton</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In this subsection:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Supply</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “supply” means, using the latest official data of the Bureau of the Census, the Department of Agriculture, and the Department of the Treasury—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the carry-over of upland cotton at the beginning of the marketing year (adjusted to 480-pound bales) in which the quota is established;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> production of the current crop; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> imports to the latest date available during the marketing year.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Demand</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “demand” means—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the average seasonally adjusted annual rate of domestic mill consumption of cotton during the most recent 3 months for which data are available; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> the larger of—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> average exports of upland cotton during the preceding 6 marketing years; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> cumulative exports of upland cotton plus outstanding export sales for the marketing year in which the quota is established.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limited global import quota</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “limited global import quota” means a quantity of imports that is not subject to the over-quota tariff rate of a tariff-rate quota.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The President shall carry out an import quota program that provides that whenever the Secretary determines and announces that the average price of the base quality of upland cotton, as determined by the Secretary, in the designated spot markets for a month exceeded 130 percent of the average price of the quality of cotton in the markets for the preceding 36 months, notwithstanding any other provision of law, there shall immediately be in effect a limited global import quota subject to the following conditions:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Quantity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The quantity of the quota shall be equal to 21 days of domestic mill consumption of upland cotton at the seasonally adjusted average rate of the most recent 3 months for which data are available or as estimated by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Quantity if prior quota</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">If a quota has been established under this subsection during the preceding 12 months, the quantity of the quota next established under this subsection shall be the smaller of 21 days of domestic mill consumption calculated under subparagraph (A) or the quantity required to increase the supply to 130 percent of the demand.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Preferential tariff treatment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The quantity under a limited global import quota shall be considered to be an in-quota quantity for purposes of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content><ref>section 2703(d) of title 19</ref>;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content><ref>section 3203 of title 19</ref>;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content><ref>section 2463(d) of title 19</ref>; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> General Note 3(a)(iv) to the Harmonized Tariff Schedule.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Quota entry period</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">When a quota is established under this subsection, cotton may be entered under the quota during the 90-day period beginning on the date the quota is established by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> No overlap</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding paragraph (2), a quota period may not be established that overlaps an existing quota period or a special quota period established under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title I, § 1207</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 960</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title I, § 1207, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1689; <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title I, § 1203(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4510</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8738.</num>
<heading> Special competitive provisions for extra long staple cotton</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Competitiveness program</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, during the period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act through <date date="2013-07-31">July 31, 2013</date>, the Secretary shall carry out a program—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to maintain and expand the domestic use of extra long staple cotton produced in the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to increase exports of extra long staple cotton produced in the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to ensure that extra long staple cotton produced in the United States remains competitive in world markets.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payments under program; trigger</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Under the program, the Secretary shall make payments available under this section whenever—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> for a consecutive 4-week period, the world market price for the lowest priced competing growth of extra long staple cotton (adjusted to United States quality and location and for other factors affecting the competitiveness of such cotton), as determined by the Secretary, is below the prevailing United States price for a competing growth of extra long staple cotton; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the lowest priced competing growth of extra long staple cotton (adjusted to United States quality and location and for other factors affecting the competitiveness of such cotton), as determined by the Secretary, is less than 134 percent of the loan rate for extra long staple cotton.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible recipients</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall make payments available under this section to domestic users of extra long staple cotton produced in the United States and exporters of extra long staple cotton produced in the United States that enter into an agreement with the Commodity Credit Corporation to participate in the program under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payment amount</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Payments under this section shall be based on the amount of the difference in the prices referred to in subsection (b)(1) during the fourth week of the consecutive 4-week period multiplied by the amount of documented purchases by domestic users and sales for export by exporters made in the week following such a consecutive 4-week period.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title I, § 1208</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 963</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title I, § 1208, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1692.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8739.</num>
<heading> Availability of recourse loans for high moisture feed grains and seed cotton</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> High moisture feed grains</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition of high moisture state</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In this subsection, the term “high moisture state” means corn or grain sorghum having a moisture content in excess of Commodity Credit Corporation standards for marketing assistance loans made by the Secretary under <ref>section 8731 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recourse loans available</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For each of the 2008 through 2012 crops of corn and grain sorghum, the Secretary shall make available recourse loans, as determined by the Secretary, to producers on a farm that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> normally harvest all or a portion of their crop of corn or grain sorghum in a high moisture state;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> present—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> certified scale tickets from an inspected, certified commercial scale, including a licensed warehouse, feedlot, feed mill, distillery, or other similar entity approved by the Secretary, pursuant to regulations issued by the Secretary; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> field or other physical measurements of the standing or stored crop in regions of the United States, as determined by the Secretary, that do not have certified commercial scales from which certified scale tickets may be obtained within reasonable proximity of harvest operation;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> certify that they were the owners of the feed grain at the time of delivery to, and that the quantity to be placed under loan under this subsection was in fact harvested on the farm and delivered to, a feedlot, feed mill, or commercial or on-farm high-moisture storage facility, or to a facility maintained by the users of corn and grain sorghum in a high moisture state; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> comply with deadlines established by the Secretary for harvesting the corn or grain sorghum and submit applications for loans under this subsection within deadlines established by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility of acquired feed grains</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A loan under this subsection shall be made on a quantity of corn or grain sorghum of the same crop acquired by the producer equivalent to a quantity determined by multiplying—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the acreage of the corn or grain sorghum in a high moisture state harvested on the producer’s farm; by</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the lower of the farm program payment yield used to make counter-cyclical payments under subchapter I or the actual yield on a field, as determined by the Secretary, that is similar to the field from which the corn or grain sorghum was obtained.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recourse loans available for seed cotton</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For each of the 2008 through 2012 crops of upland cotton and extra long staple cotton, the Secretary shall make available recourse seed cotton loans, as determined by the Secretary, on any production.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Repayment rates</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Repayment of a recourse loan made under this section shall be at the loan rate established for the commodity by the Secretary, plus interest (determined in accordance with <ref>section 7283 of this title</ref>).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title I, § 1209</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 964</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title I, § 1209, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1692.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8740.</num>
<heading> Adjustments of loans</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adjustment authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to subsection (e), the Secretary may make appropriate adjustments in the loan rates for any loan commodity (other than cotton) for differences in grade, type, quality, location, and other factors.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Manner of adjustment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The adjustments under subsection (a) shall, to the maximum extent practicable, be made in such a manner that the average loan level for the commodity will, on the basis of the anticipated incidence of the factors, be equal to the level of support determined in accordance with this subtitle and subtitles B through E.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002374">1</ref></p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adjustment on county basis</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may establish loan rates for a crop for producers in individual counties in a manner that results in the lowest loan rate being 95 percent of the national average loan rate, if those loan rates do not result in an increase in outlays.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Adjustments under this subsection shall not result in an increase in the national average loan rate for any year.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adjustment in loan rate for cotton</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may make appropriate adjustments in the loan rate for cotton for differences in quality factors.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Revisions to quality adjustments for upland cotton</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall implement revisions in the administration of the marketing assistance loan program for upland cotton to more accurately and efficiently reflect market values for upland cotton.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Mandatory revisions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Revisions under subparagraph (A) shall include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the elimination of warehouse location differentials;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the establishment of differentials for the various quality factors and staple lengths of cotton based on a 3-year, weighted moving average of the weighted designated spot market regions, as determined by regional production;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the elimination of any artificial split in the premium or discount between upland cotton with a 32 or 33 staple length due to micronaire; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> a mechanism to ensure that no premium or discount is established that exceeds the premium or discount associated with a leaf grade that is 1 better than the applicable color grade.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Discretionary revisions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Revisions under subparagraph (A) may include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the use of non-spot market price data, in addition to spot market price data, that would enhance the accuracy of the price information used in determining quality adjustments under this subsection;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> adjustments in the premiums or discounts associated with upland cotton with a staple length of 33 or above due to micronaire with the goal of eliminating any unnecessary artificial splits in the calculations of the premiums or discounts; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> such other adjustments as the Secretary determines appropriate, after consultations conducted in accordance with paragraph (3).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation with private sector</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prior to revision</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In making adjustments to the loan rate for cotton (including any review of the adjustments) as provided in this subsection, the Secretary shall consult with representatives of the United States cotton industry.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inapplicability of chapter 10 of title 5</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Chapter 10 of title 5 shall not apply to consultations under this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review of adjustments</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary may review the operation of the upland cotton quality adjustments implemented pursuant to this subsection and may make further revisions to the administration of the loan program for upland cotton, by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> revoking or revising any actions taken under paragraph (2)(B); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> revoking or revising any actions taken or authorized to be taken under paragraph (2)(C).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rice</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall not make adjustments in the loan rates for long grain rice and medium grain rice, except for differences in grade and quality (including milling yields).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title I, § 1210</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 965</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title I, § 1210, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1693; <ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(a)(42)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4310</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>PEANUTS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 8751.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this subchapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Base acres for peanuts</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “base acres for peanuts” means the number of acres assigned to a farm pursuant to <ref>section 7952 of this title</ref>, as in effect on <date date="2007-09-30">September 30, 2007</date>, subject to any adjustment under <ref>section 8752 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Covered commodities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “base acres”, with respect to a covered commodity, has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 8711 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Counter-cyclical payment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “counter-cyclical payment” means a payment made to producers on a farm under section 8754 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002375">1</ref> of this title.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Direct payment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “direct payment” means a direct payment made to producers on a farm under section 8753 <sup>1</sup> of this title.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective price</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “effective price” means the price calculated by the Secretary under section 8754 <sup>1</sup> of this title for peanuts to determine whether counter-cyclical payments are required to be made under that section for a crop year.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payment acres</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “payment acres” means, in the case of direct payments and counter-cyclical payments—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> except as provided in subparagraph (B), 85 percent of the base acres of peanuts on a farm on which direct payments or counter-cyclical payments are made; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of direct payments for each of the 2009 through 2011 crop years, 83.3 percent of the base acres for peanuts on a farm on which direct payments are made.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payment yield</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “payment yield” means the yield established for direct payments and the yield established for counter-cyclical payments under <ref>section 7952 of this title</ref>, as in effect on <date date="2007-09-30">September 30, 2007</date>, for a farm for peanuts.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Producer</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “producer” means an owner, operator, landlord, tenant, or sharecropper that shares in the risk of producing a crop on a farm and is entitled to share in the crop available for marketing from the farm, or would have shared had the crop been produced.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Hybrid seed</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In determining whether a grower of hybrid seed is a producer, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> not take into consideration the existence of a hybrid seed contract; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> ensure that program requirements do not adversely affect the ability of the grower to receive a payment under this subchapter.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “State” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a State;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the District of Columbia;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> any other territory or possession of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Target price</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “target price” means the price per ton of peanuts used to determine the payment rate for counter-cyclical payments.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(10)</num>
<heading class="bold"> United States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “United States”, when used in a geographical sense, means all of the States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title I, § 1301</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 966</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title I, § 1301, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1695.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8752.</num>
<heading> Base acres for peanuts for a farm</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adjustment of base acreage for peanuts</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary shall provide for an adjustment, as appropriate, in the base acres for peanuts for a farm whenever any of the following circumstances occur:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A conservation reserve contract entered into under section 1231 of the Food Security Act of 1985 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 3831</ref>) with respect to the farm expires or is voluntarily terminated, or was terminated or expired during the period beginning on <date date="2007-10-01">October 1, 2007</date>, and ending on the date of enactment of this Act.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Cropland is released from coverage under a conservation reserve contract by the Secretary, or was released during the period beginning on <date date="2007-10-01">October 1, 2007</date>, and ending on the date of enactment of this Act.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The producer has eligible pulse crop acreage, which shall be determined in the same manner as eligible oilseed acreage under <ref>section 7911(a)(2) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The producer has eligible oilseed acreage as the result of the Secretary designating additional oilseeds, which shall be determined in the same manner as eligible oilseed acreage under <ref>section 7911(a)(2) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special conservation reserve acreage payment rules</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For the crop year in which a base acres for peanuts adjustment under subparagraph (A) or (B) of paragraph (1) is first made, the owner of the farm shall elect to receive either direct payments and counter-cyclical payments with respect to the acreage added to the farm under this subsection or a prorated payment under the conservation reserve contract, but not both.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prevention of excess base acres for peanuts</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Required reduction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the sum of the base acres for peanuts for a farm, together with the acreage described in paragraph (2), exceeds the actual cropland acreage of the farm, the Secretary shall reduce the base acres for peanuts for the farm or the base acres for 1 or more covered commodities for the farm so that the sum of the base acres for peanuts and acreage described in paragraph (2) does not exceed the actual cropland acreage of the farm.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other acreage</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of paragraph (1), the Secretary shall include the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Any base acres for the farm for a covered commodity.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Any acreage on the farm enrolled in the conservation reserve program or wetlands reserve program under chapter 1 of subtitle D of title XII of the Food Security Act of 1985 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 3830</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Any other acreage on the farm enrolled in a Federal conservation program for which payments are made in exchange for not producing an agricultural commodity on the acreage.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Any eligible pulse crop acreage, which shall be determined in the same manner as eligible oilseed acreage under <ref>section 7911(a)(2) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> If the Secretary designates additional oilseeds, any eligible oilseed acreage, which shall be determined in the same manner as eligible oilseed acreage under <ref>section 7911(a)(2) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Selection of acres</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall give the owner of the farm the opportunity to select the base acres for peanuts or the base acres for covered commodities against which the reduction required by paragraph (1) will be made.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception for double-cropped acreage</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In applying paragraph (1), the Secretary shall make an exception in the case of double cropping, as determined by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordinated application of requirements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall take into account <ref>section 8711(b) of this title</ref> when applying the requirements of this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reduction in base acres</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reduction at option of owner</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The owner of a farm may reduce, at any time, the base acres for peanuts for the farm.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect of reduction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A reduction under subparagraph (A) shall be permanent and made in a manner prescribed by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Required action by Secretary</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Secretary shall proportionately reduce base acres on a farm for peanuts for land that has been subdivided and developed for multiple residential units or other nonfarming uses if the size of the tracts and the density of the subdivision is such that the land is unlikely to return to the previous agricultural use, unless the producers on the farm demonstrate that the land—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> remains devoted to commercial agricultural production; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> is likely to be returned to the previous agricultural use.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary shall establish procedures to identify land described in subparagraph (A).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review and report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Each year, to ensure, to the maximum extent practicable, that payments are received only by producers, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report that describes the results of the actions taken under paragraph (2).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment of farms with limited base acres</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition on payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (2) and notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, a producer on a farm may not receive direct payments, counter-cyclical payments, or average crop revenue election payments if the sum of the base acres of the farm is 10 acres or less, as determined by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Paragraph (1) shall not apply to a farm owned by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a socially disadvantaged farmer or rancher (as defined in <ref>section 2003(e) of this title</ref>; <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002376">1</ref> or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a limited resource farmer or rancher, as defined by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Suspension of prohibition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Paragraphs (1) and (2) shall not apply during the 2008 crop year.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title I, § 1302</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 968</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title I, § 1302, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1696; <ref>Pub. L. 110–398, § 1(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2008-10-13">Oct. 13, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4213</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–188, title I, § 101(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-11-26">Nov. 26, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 2017</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8753.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 113–79, title I, § 1101</ref>, <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 658</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8754.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 113–79, title I, § 1102(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 658</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8755.</num>
<heading> Producer agreement required as condition on provision of payments</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compliance with certain requirements</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Before the producers on a farm may receive direct payments or counter-cyclical payments under this subchapter, or average crop revenue election payments under section 8715 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002377">1</ref> of this title, with respect to the farm, the producers shall agree, during the crop year for which the payments are made and in exchange for the payments—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to comply with applicable conservation requirements under subtitle B of title XII of the Food Security Act of 1985 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 3811</ref> et seq.);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to comply with applicable wetland protection requirements under subtitle C of title XII of that Act (<ref>16 U.S.C. 3821</ref> et seq.);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to comply with the planting flexibility requirements of <ref>section 8756 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> to use the land on the farm, in a quantity equal to the attributable base acres for peanuts and any base acres for the farm under subchapter I, for an agricultural or conserving use, and not for a nonagricultural commercial, industrial, or residential use, as determined by the Secretary; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> to effectively control noxious weeds and otherwise maintain the land in accordance with sound agricultural practices, as determined by the Secretary, if the agricultural or conserving use involves the noncultivation of any portion of the land referred to in subparagraph (D).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compliance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may issue such rules as the Secretary considers necessary to ensure producer compliance with the requirements of paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Modification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">At the request of the transferee or owner, the Secretary may modify the requirements of this subsection if the modifications are consistent with the objectives of this subsection, as determined by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer or change of interest in farm</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Except as provided in paragraph (2), a transfer of (or change in) the interest of the producers on a farm in the base acres for peanuts for which direct payments or counter-cyclical payments are made, or on which average crop revenue election payments are based, shall result in the termination of the direct payments, counter-cyclical payments, or average crop revenue election payments to the extent the payments are made or based on the base acres, unless the transferee or owner of the acreage agrees to assume all obligations under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The termination shall take effect on the date determined by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If a producer entitled to a direct payment, counter-cyclical payment, or average crop revenue election payment dies, becomes incompetent, or is otherwise unable to receive the payment, the Secretary shall make the payment, in accordance with rules issued by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Acreage reports</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">As a condition on the receipt of any benefits under this subchapter, the Secretary shall require producers on a farm to submit to the Secretary annual acreage reports with respect to all cropland on the farm.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Penalties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">No penalty with respect to benefits under this subchapter shall be assessed against the producers on a farm for an inaccurate acreage report unless the producers on the farm knowingly and willfully falsified the acreage report.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tenants and sharecroppers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In carrying out this subchapter, the Secretary shall provide adequate safeguards to protect the interests of tenants and sharecroppers.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sharing of payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall provide for the sharing of direct payments, counter-cyclical payments, or average crop revenue election payments under section 8715 <sup>1</sup> of this title among the producers on a farm on a fair and equitable basis.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Extension of 2008 signup</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary shall extend the 2008 crop year deadline for the signup for benefits under this subchapter by producers on a farm with base acres of 10 acres or less until the later of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content><date date="2008-11-14">November 14, 2008</date>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the end of the 45-day period beginning on <date date="2008-10-13">October 13, 2008</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Penalties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall ensure that no penalty with respect to benefits under this subchapter is assessed against producers on a farm described in paragraph (1) for failure to submit reports under this section or timely comply with other program requirements as a result of compliance with the extended signup deadline under that paragraph.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title I, § 1305</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 972</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title I, § 1305, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1701; <ref>Pub. L. 110–398, § 1(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2008-10-13">Oct. 13, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4213</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8756.</num>
<heading> Planting flexibility</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Permitted crops</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to subsection (b), any commodity or crop may be planted on the base acres for peanuts on a farm.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations regarding certain commodities</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The planting of an agricultural commodity specified in paragraph (3) shall be prohibited on base acres for peanuts unless the commodity, if planted, is destroyed before harvest.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment of trees and other perennials</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The planting of an agricultural commodity specified in paragraph (3) that is produced on a tree or other perennial plant shall be prohibited on base acres for peanuts.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Covered agricultural commodities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Paragraphs (1) and (2) apply to the following agricultural commodities:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Fruits.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Vegetables (other than mung beans and pulse crops).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Wild rice.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (b) shall not limit the planting of an agricultural commodity specified in paragraph (3) of that subsection—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in any region in which there is a history of double-cropping of peanuts with agricultural commodities specified in subsection (b)(3), as determined by the Secretary, in which case the double-cropping shall be permitted;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> on a farm that the Secretary determines has a history of planting agricultural commodities specified in subsection (b)(3) on the base acres for peanuts, except that direct payments and counter-cyclical payments shall be reduced by an acre for each acre planted to such an agricultural commodity; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> by the producers on a farm that the Secretary determines has an established planting history of a specific agricultural commodity specified in subsection (b)(3), except that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the quantity planted may not exceed the average annual planting history of such agricultural commodity by the producers on the farm in the 1991 through 1995 or 1998 through 2001 crop years (excluding any crop year in which no plantings were made), as determined by the Secretary; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> direct payments and counter-cyclical payments shall be reduced by an acre for each acre planted to such agricultural commodity.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title I, § 1306</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 973</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title I, § 1306, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1702.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8757.</num>
<heading> Marketing assistance loans and loan deficiency payments for peanuts</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonrecourse loans available</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For each of the 2008 through 2012 crops of peanuts, the Secretary shall make available to producers on a farm nonrecourse marketing assistance loans for peanuts produced on the farm.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Terms and conditions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The loans shall be made under terms and conditions that are prescribed by the Secretary and at the loan rate established under subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible production</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The producers on a farm shall be eligible for a marketing assistance loan under this subsection for any quantity of peanuts produced on the farm.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Options for obtaining loan</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A marketing assistance loan under this subsection, and loan deficiency payments under subsection (e), may be obtained at the option of the producers on a farm through—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a designated marketing association or marketing cooperative of producers that is approved by the Secretary; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Farm Service Agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Storage of loan peanuts</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">As a condition on the Secretary’s approval of an individual or entity to provide storage for peanuts for which a marketing assistance loan is made under this section, the individual or entity shall agree—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to provide such storage on a nondiscriminatory basis; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to comply with such additional requirements as the Secretary considers appropriate to accomplish the purposes of this section and promote fairness in the administration of the benefits of this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Storage, handling, and associated costs</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Beginning with the 2008 crop of peanuts, to ensure proper storage of peanuts for which a loan is made under this section, the Secretary shall pay handling and other associated costs (other than storage costs) incurred at the time at which the peanuts are placed under loan, as determined by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Redemption and forfeiture</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> require the repayment of handling and other associated costs paid under subparagraph (A) for all peanuts pledged as collateral for a loan that is redeemed under this section; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> pay storage, handling, and other associated costs for all peanuts pledged as collateral that are forfeited under this section.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Marketing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A marketing association or cooperative may market peanuts for which a loan is made under this section in any manner that conforms to consumer needs, including the separation of peanuts by type and quality.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Loan rate</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as provided in section 8715 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002378">1</ref> of this title, the loan rate for a marketing assistance loan for peanuts under subsection (a) shall be equal to $355 per ton.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Term of loan</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A marketing assistance loan for peanuts under subsection (a) shall have a term of 9 months beginning on the first day of the first month after the month in which the loan is made.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Extensions prohibited</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may not extend the term of a marketing assistance loan for peanuts under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Repayment rate</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary shall permit producers on a farm to repay a marketing assistance loan for peanuts under subsection (a) at a rate that is the lesser of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the loan rate established for peanuts under subsection (b), plus interest (determined in accordance with <ref>section 7283 of this title</ref>); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> a rate that the Secretary determines will—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> minimize potential loan forfeitures;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> minimize the accumulation of stocks of peanuts by the Federal Government;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> minimize the cost incurred by the Federal Government in storing peanuts; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> allow peanuts produced in the United States to be marketed freely and competitively, both domestically and internationally.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority to temporarily adjust repayment rates</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adjustment authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In the event of a severe disruption to marketing, transportation, or related infrastructure, the Secretary may modify the repayment rate otherwise applicable under this subsection for marketing assistance loans for peanuts under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">An adjustment made under subparagraph (A) in the repayment rate for marketing assistance loans for peanuts shall be in effect on a short-term and temporary basis, as determined by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Loan deficiency payments</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may make loan deficiency payments available to producers on a farm that, although eligible to obtain a marketing assistance loan for peanuts under subsection (a), agree to forgo obtaining the loan for the peanuts in return for loan deficiency payments under this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Computation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A loan deficiency payment under this subsection shall be computed by multiplying—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the payment rate determined under paragraph (3) for peanuts; by</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the quantity of the peanuts produced by the producers, excluding any quantity for which the producers obtain a marketing assistance loan under subsection (a).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payment rate</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, the payment rate shall be the amount by which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the loan rate established under subsection (b); exceeds</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the rate at which a loan may be repaid under subsection (d).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date for payment rate determination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall determine the amount of the loan deficiency payment to be made under this subsection to the producers on a farm with respect to a quantity of peanuts using the payment rate in effect under paragraph (3) as of the date the producers request the payment.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compliance with conservation and wetlands requirements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As a condition of the receipt of a marketing assistance loan under subsection (a), the producer shall comply with applicable conservation requirements under subtitle B of title XII of the Food Security Act of 1985 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 3811</ref> et seq.) and applicable wetland protection requirements under subtitle C of title XII of that Act (<ref>16 U.S.C. 3821</ref> et seq.) during the term of the loan.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reimbursable agreements and payment of administrative expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may implement any reimbursable agreements or provide for the payment of administrative expenses under this subchapter only in a manner that is consistent with such activities in regard to other commodities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title I, § 1307</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 974</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title I, § 1307, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1703.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8758.</num>
<heading> Adjustments of loans</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adjustment authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may make appropriate adjustments in the loan rates for peanuts for differences in grade, type, quality, location, and other factors.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Manner of adjustment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The adjustments under subsection (a) shall, to the maximum extent practicable, be made in such a manner that the average loan level for peanuts will, on the basis of the anticipated incidence of the factors, be equal to the level of support determined in accordance with this subchapter and subtitles B, D, and E.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adjustment on county basis</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subject to paragraph (2), the Secretary may establish loan rates for a crop of peanuts for producers in individual counties in a manner that results in the lowest loan rate being 95 percent of the national average loan rate, if those loan rates do not result in an increase in outlays.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Adjustments under this subsection shall not result in an increase in the national average loan rate for any year.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title I, § 1308</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 977</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title I, § 1308, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1705.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>DAIRY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 8771.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 113–79, title I, § 1421</ref>, <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 694</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8772.</num>
<heading> Dairy forward pricing program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish a program under which milk producers and cooperative associations of producers are authorized to voluntarily enter into forward price contracts with milk handlers.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Minimum milk price requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Payments made by milk handlers to milk producers and cooperative associations of producers, and prices received by milk producers and cooperative associations, in accordance with the terms of a forward price contract authorized by subsection (a), shall be treated as satisfying—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> all uniform and minimum milk price requirements of subparagraphs (B) and (F) of paragraph (5) of <ref>section 608c of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the total payment requirement of subparagraph (C) of that paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Milk covered by program</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Covered milk</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The program shall apply only with respect to the marketing of federally regulated milk that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is not classified as Class I milk or otherwise intended for fluid use; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is in the current of interstate or foreign commerce or directly burdens, obstructs, or affects interstate or foreign commerce in federally regulated milk.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Relation to Class I milk</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To assist milk handlers in complying with paragraph (1)(A) without having to segregate or otherwise individually track the source and disposition of milk, a milk handler may allocate milk receipts from producers, cooperatives, and other sources that are not subject to a forward contract to satisfy the obligations of the handler with regard to Class I milk usage.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Voluntary program</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A milk handler may not require participation in a forward pricing contract as a condition of the handler receiving milk from a producer or cooperative association of producers.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Pricing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A producer or cooperative association described in paragraph (1) may continue to have their <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002379">1</ref> milk priced in accordance with the minimum payment provisions of the Federal milk marketing order.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Complaints</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary shall investigate complaints made by producers or cooperative associations of coercion by handlers to enter into forward contracts.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Action</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">If the Secretary finds evidence of coercion, the Secretary shall take appropriate action.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duration</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> New contracts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">No forward price contract may be entered into under the program established under this section after <date date="2023-09-30">September 30, 2023</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">No forward contract entered into under the program may extend beyond <date date="2028-09-30">September 30, 2028</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title I, § 1502</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 991</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title I, § 1502, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1720; <ref>Pub. L. 113–79, title I, § 1424</ref>, <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 695</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title I, § 1402(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4518</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–22, div. B, title I, § 102(c)(2)(C)</ref>, <date date="2023-11-17">Nov. 17, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 116</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–158, div. D, § 4101(c)(4)(B)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-21">Dec. 21, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1769</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8773.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 113–79, title I, § 1422(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 695</ref></heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER V—</num>
<heading>ADMINISTRATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 8781.</num>
<heading> Administration generally</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of Commodity Credit Corporation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided in this chapter, the Secretary shall use the funds, facilities, and authorities of the Commodity Credit Corporation to carry out this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determinations by Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A determination made by the Secretary under this chapter shall be final and conclusive.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary and the Commodity Credit Corporation, as appropriate, shall promulgate such regulations as are necessary to implement this chapter and the amendments made by this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Procedure</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The promulgation of the regulations and administration of this chapter and the amendments made by this chapter shall be made without regard to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> chapter 35 of title 44 (commonly known as the “Paperwork Reduction Act”);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Statement of Policy of the Secretary of Agriculture effective <date date="1971-07-24">July 24, 1971</date> (36 Fed. Reg. 13804), relating to notices of proposed rulemaking and public participation in rulemaking; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the notice and comment provisions of <ref>section 553 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Congressional review of agency rulemaking</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In carrying out this subsection, the Secretary shall use the authority provided under <ref>section 808 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interim regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding paragraphs (1) and (2), the Secretary shall implement the amendments made by sections 1603 and 1604 for the 2009 crop, fiscal, or program year, as appropriate, through the promulgation of an interim rule.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adjustment authority related to trade agreements compliance</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Required determination; adjustment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the Secretary determines that expenditures under this chapter that are subject to the total allowable domestic support levels under the Uruguay Round Agreements (as defined in <ref>section 3501 of title 19</ref>) will exceed such allowable levels for any applicable reporting period, the Secretary shall, to the maximum extent practicable, make adjustments in the amount of such expenditures during that period to ensure that such expenditures do not exceed such allowable levels.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Congressional notification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Before making any adjustment under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives or the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate a report describing the determination made under that paragraph and the extent of the adjustment to be made.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title I, § 1601</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1000</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title I, § 1601, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1728.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8782.</num>
<heading> Suspension of permanent price support authority</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agricultural Adjustment Act of 1938</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The following provisions of the Agricultural Adjustment Act of 1938 [<ref>7 U.S.C. 1281</ref> et seq.] shall not be applicable to the 2008 through 2012 crops of covered commodities, peanuts, and sugar and shall not be applicable to milk during the period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act through <date date="2012-12-31">December 31, 2012</date>:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Parts II through V of subtitle B of title III (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1326</ref> et seq.) [<ref>7 U.S.C. 1321</ref> et seq., 1331 et seq., 1341 et seq., 1351].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In the case of upland cotton, section 377 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1377</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Subtitle D of title III (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1379a</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Title IV (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1401</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agricultural Act of 1949</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The following provisions of the Agricultural Act of 1949 [<ref>7 U.S.C. 1421</ref> et seq.] shall not be applicable to the 2008 through 2012 crops of covered commodities, peanuts, and sugar and shall not be applicable to milk during the period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act and through <date date="2012-12-31">December 31, 2012</date>:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Section 101 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1441</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Section 103(a) (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1444(a)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Section 105 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1444b</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Section 107 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1445a</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Section 110 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1445e</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Section 112 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1445g</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Section 115 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1445k</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Section 201 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1446</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> Title III (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1447</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> Title IV (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1421</ref> et seq.), other than sections 404, 412, and 416 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1424</ref>, 1429, and 1431).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> Title V (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1461</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> Title VI (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1471</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Suspension of certain quota provisions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The joint resolution entitled “A joint resolution relating to corn and wheat marketing quotas under the Agricultural Adjustment Act of 1938, as amended”, approved <date date="1941-05-26">May 26, 1941</date> (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1330</ref> and 1340), shall not be applicable to the crops of wheat planted for harvest in the calendar years 2008 through 2012.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title I, § 1602</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1001</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title I, § 1602, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1729.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8783.</num>
<heading> Availability of quality incentive payments for covered oilseed producers</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Incentive payments required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to subsection (b) and the availability of appropriations under subsection (h), the Secretary shall use funds made available under subsection (h) to provide quality incentive payments for the production of oilseeds with specialized traits that enhance human health, as determined by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Covered oilseeds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall make payments under this section only for the production of an oilseed variety that has, as determined by the Secretary—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> been demonstrated to improve the health profile of the oilseed for use in human consumption by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> reducing or eliminating the need to partially hydrogenate the oil derived from the oilseed for use in human consumption; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> adopting new technology traits; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> 1 or more impediments to commercialization.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Request for proposals</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Issuance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If funds are made available to carry out this section for a crop year, the Secretary shall issue a request for proposals for payments under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Multiyear proposals</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A proponent may submit a multiyear proposal for payments under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Content of proposals</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A proposal for payments under this section shall include a description of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> how use of the oilseed enhances human health;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the impediments to commercial use of the oilseed;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> each oilseed variety described in subsection (b) and the value of the oilseed variety as a matter of public policy;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a range for the base price and premiums per bushel or hundredweight to be paid to producers;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> a per bushel or hundredweight amount of incentive payments requested for each year under this section that does not exceed ⅓ of the total premium offered for any year;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the period of time, not to exceed 4 years, during which incentive payments are to be provided to producers; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> the targeted total quantity of production and estimated acres needed to produce the targeted quantity for each year under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contracts for production</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall approve successful proposals submitted under subsection (c) on a timely basis.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Timing of payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall make payments to producers under this section after the Secretary receives documentation that the premium required under a contract has been paid to covered producers.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administration</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If funding provided for a crop year is not fully allocated under the initial request for proposals under subsection (c), the Secretary shall issue additional requests for proposals for subsequent crop years under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prorated payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If funding provided for a crop year is less than the amount otherwise approved by the Secretary or for which approval is sought, the Secretary shall prorate the payments or approvals in a manner determined by the Secretary so that the total payments do not exceed the funding level.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Proprietary information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall protect proprietary information provided to the Secretary for the purpose of administering this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program compliance and penalties</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Guarantee</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The proponent, if approved, shall be required to guarantee that the oilseed on which a payment is made by the Secretary under this section is used for human consumption as described in the proposal, as approved by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Noncompliance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">If oilseeds on which a payment is made by the Secretary under this section are not actually used for the purpose the payment is made, the proponent shall be required to pay to the Secretary an amount equal to, as determined by the Secretary—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the case of an inadvertent failure, twice the amount of the payment made by the Secretary under this section to the producer of the oilseeds; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in any other case, up to twice the full value of the oilseeds involved.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Documentation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may require such assurances and documentation as may be needed to enforce the guarantee.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional penalties</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In addition to payments required under paragraph (2), the Secretary may impose penalties on additional persons that use oilseeds the use of which is restricted under this section for a purpose other than the intended use.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amount</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The amount of a penalty under this paragraph shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> be in an amount determined appropriated by the Secretary; but</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> not to exceed twice the full value of the oilseeds.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as are necessary to carry out this section for each of fiscal years 2009 through 2012.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title I, § 1605</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1016</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title I, § 1605, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1744.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8784.</num>
<heading> Assignment of payments</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The provisions of <ref>section 590h(g) of title 16</ref>, relating to assignment of payments, shall apply to payments made under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The producer making the assignment, or the assignee, shall provide the Secretary with notice, in such manner as the Secretary may require, of any assignment made under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title I, § 1608</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1018</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title I, § 1608, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1746.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8785.</num>
<heading> Tracking of benefits</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary may track the benefits provided, directly or indirectly, to individuals and entities under titles I and II and the amendments made by those titles.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title I, § 1609</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1018</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title I, § 1609, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1746.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8786.</num>
<heading> Prevention of deceased individuals receiving payments under farm commodity programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall promulgate regulations that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> describe the circumstances under which, in order to allow for the settlement of estates and for related purposes, payments may be issued in the name of a deceased individual; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> preclude the issuance of payments to, and on behalf of, deceased individuals that were not eligible for the payments.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">At least twice each year, the Secretary shall reconcile the social security numbers of all individuals who receive payments under this chapter, whether directly or indirectly, with the Social Security Administration to determine if the individuals are alive.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title I, § 1611</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1018</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title I, § 1611, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1746.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8787.</num>
<heading> Hard white wheat development program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible hard white wheat seed</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “eligible hard white wheat seed” means hard white wheat seed that, as determined by the Secretary, is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> certified;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> of a variety that is suitable for the State in which the seed will be planted;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> rated at least superior with respect to quality; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> specifically approved under a seed establishment program established by the State Department of Agriculture and the State Wheat Commission of the 1 or more States in which the seed will be planted.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “program” means the hard white wheat development program established under subsection (b)(1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Agriculture, in consultation with the State Departments of Agriculture and the State Wheat Commissions of the States in regions in which hard white wheat is produced, as determined by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subject to the availability of appropriations, the Secretary shall establish a hard white wheat development program in accordance with paragraph (2) to promote the establishment of hard white wheat as a viable market class of wheat in the United States by encouraging production of at least 240,000,000 bushels of hard white wheat by 2012.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payments</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Subject to subparagraphs (B) and (C) and subsection (c), if funds are made available for any of the 2009 through 2012 crops of hard white wheat, the Secretary shall make available incentive payments to producers of those crops.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Acreage limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary shall carry out subparagraph (A) subject to a regional limitation determined by the Secretary on the number of acres for which payments may be received that takes into account planting history and potential planting, but does not exceed a total of 2,900,000 acres or the equivalent volume of production based on a yield of 50 bushels per acre.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payment limitations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Payments to producers on a farm described in subparagraph (A) shall be—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> in an amount that is not less than $0.20 per bushel; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in an amount that is not less than $2.00 per acre for planting eligible hard white wheat seed.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $35,000,000 for the period of fiscal years 2009 through 2012.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title I, § 1612</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1019</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title I, § 1612, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1747.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8788.</num>
<heading> Durum wheat quality program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to the availability of funds under subsection (c), the Secretary shall provide compensation to producers of durum wheat in an amount not to exceed 50 percent of the actual cost of fungicides applied to a crop of durum wheat of the producers to control Fusarium head blight (wheat scab) on acres certified to have been planted to Durum wheat in a crop year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Insufficient funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the total amount of funds appropriated for a fiscal year under subsection (c) are insufficient to fulfill all eligible requests for compensation under this section, the Secretary shall prorate the compensation payments in a manner determined by the Secretary to be equitable.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2009 through 2012.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title I, § 1613</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1019</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title I, § 1613, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1748.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8789.</num>
<heading> Storage facility loans</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall establish a storage facility loan program to provide funds for producers of grains, oilseeds, pulse crops, hay, renewable biomass, and other storable commodities (other than sugar), as determined by the Secretary, to construct or upgrade storage and handling facilities for the commodities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible producers</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A storage facility loan under this section shall be made available to any producer described in subsection (a) that, as determined by the Secretary—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> has a satisfactory credit history;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> has a need for increased storage capacity; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> demonstrates an ability to repay the loan.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Term of loans</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A storage facility loan under this section shall have a maximum term of 12 years.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Loan amount</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The maximum principal amount of a storage facility loan under this section shall be $500,000.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Loan disbursements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall provide for 1 partial disbursement of loan principal and 1 final disbursement of loan principal, as determined to be appropriate and subject to acceptable documentation, to facilitate the purchase and construction of eligible facilities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Loan security</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Approval of a storage facility loan under this section shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> require the borrower to provide loan security to the Secretary, in the form of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a lien on the real estate parcel on which the storage facility is located; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> such other security as is acceptable to the Secretary;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> under such rules and regulations as the Secretary may prescribe, not require a severance agreement from the holder of any prior lien on the real estate parcel on which the storage facility is located, if the borrower—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> agrees to increase the down payment on the storage facility by an amount determined appropriate by the Secretary; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provides other security acceptable to the Secretary; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> allow a borrower, upon the approval of the Secretary, to define a subparcel of real estate as security for the storage facility loan if the subparcel is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> of adequate size and value to adequately secure the loan; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> not subject to any other liens or mortgages that are superior to the lien interest of the Commodity Credit Corporation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title I, § 1614</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1020</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title I, § 1614, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1748.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8790.</num>
<heading> Signature authority</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In carrying out this title and title II and amendments made by those titles, if the Secretary approves a document, the Secretary shall not subsequently determine the document is inadequate or invalid because of the lack of authority of any person signing the document on behalf of the applicant or any other individual, entity, general partnership, or joint venture, or the documents relied upon were determined inadequate or invalid, unless the person signing the program document knowingly and willfully falsified the evidence of signature authority or a signature.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Affirmation</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Nothing in this section prohibits the Secretary from asking a proper party to affirm any document that otherwise would be considered approved under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> No retroactive effect</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A denial of benefits based on a lack of affirmation under paragraph (1) shall not be retroactive with respect to third-party producers who were not the subject of the erroneous representation of authority, if the third-party producers—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> relied on the prior approval by the Secretary of the documents in good faith; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> substantively complied with all program requirements <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002380">1</ref></content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title I, § 1617</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1021</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title I, § 1617, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1750.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8791.</num>
<heading> Information gathering</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Geospatial systems</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall ensure that all the geospatial data of the agencies of the Department of Agriculture are portable and standardized.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on disclosures</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition of agricultural operation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In this subsection, the term “agricultural operation” includes the production and marketing of agricultural commodities and livestock.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraphs (3) and (4), the Secretary, any officer or employee of the Department of Agriculture, or any contractor or cooperator of the Department, shall not disclose—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> information provided by an agricultural producer or owner of agricultural land concerning the agricultural operation, farming or conservation practices, or the land itself, in order to participate in programs of the Department; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> geospatial information otherwise maintained by the Secretary about agricultural land or operations for which information described in subparagraph (A) is provided.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorized disclosures</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limited release of information</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">If the Secretary determines that the information described in paragraph (2) will not be subsequently disclosed except in accordance with paragraph (4), the Secretary may release or disclose the information to a person or Federal, State, local, or tribal agency working in cooperation with the Secretary in any Department program—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> when providing technical or financial assistance with respect to the agricultural operation, agricultural land, or farming or conservation practices; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> when responding to a disease or pest threat to agricultural operations, if the Secretary determines that a threat to agricultural operations exists and the disclosure of information to a person or cooperating government entity is necessary to assist the Secretary in responding to the disease or pest threat as authorized by law.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Nothing in this subsection affects—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the disclosure of payment information (including payment information and the names and addresses of recipients of payments) under any Department program that is otherwise authorized by law;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> the disclosure of information described in paragraph (2) if the information has been transformed into a statistical or aggregate form without naming any—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> individual owner, operator, or producer; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> specific data gathering site; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the disclosure of information described in paragraph (2) pursuant to the consent of the agricultural producer or owner of agricultural land.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Condition of other programs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The participation of the agricultural producer or owner of agricultural land in, or receipt of any benefit under, any program administered by the Secretary may not be conditioned on the consent of the agricultural producer or owner of agricultural land under paragraph (4)(C).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Waiver of privilege or protection</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The disclosure of information under paragraph (2) shall not constitute a waiver of any applicable privilege or protection under Federal law, including trade secret protection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title I, § 1619</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1022</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title I, § 1619, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1750.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8792.</num>
<heading> Geographically disadvantaged farmers and ranchers</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agricultural commodity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “agricultural commodity” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 5602 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Geographically disadvantaged farmer or rancher</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “geographically disadvantaged farmer or rancher” has the meaning given the term in section 10906(a) of the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 2204</ref> note; <ref>Public Law 107–171</ref>).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to the availability of funds under subsection (d), the Secretary may provide geographically disadvantaged farmers or ranchers direct reimbursement payments for activities described in subsection (c).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transportation</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subject to paragraphs (2) and (3), the Secretary may provide direct reimbursement payments to a geographically disadvantaged farmer or rancher to transport an agricultural commodity, or inputs used to produce an agricultural commodity, during a fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Proof of eligibility</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To be eligible to receive assistance under paragraph (1), a geographically disadvantaged farmer or rancher shall demonstrate to the Secretary that transportation of the agricultural commodity or inputs occurred over a distance of more than 30 miles, as determined by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amount</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Subject to paragraph (2), the amount of direct reimbursement payments made to a geographically disadvantaged farmer or rancher under this section for a fiscal year shall equal the product obtained by multiplying—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the amount of costs incurred by the geographically disadvantaged farmer or rancher for transportation of the agricultural commodity or inputs during the fiscal year; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the percentage of the allowance for that fiscal year under <ref>section 5941 of title 5</ref> for Federal employees stationed in Alaska and Hawaii; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> in the case of an insular area (as defined in <ref>section 3103 of this title</ref>), a comparable percentage of the allowance for the fiscal year, as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The total amount of direct reimbursement payments provided by the Secretary under this section shall not exceed $15,000,000 for a fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as are necessary to carry out this section for fiscal year 2009 and each succeeding fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title I, § 1621</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1024</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title I, § 1621, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1752; <ref>Pub. L. 113–79, title I, § 1606</ref>, <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 708</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8793.</num>
<heading> Implementation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall make available to the Farm Service Agency to carry out this chapter $50,000,000.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title I, § 1622</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1025</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title I, § 1622, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1753.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>