<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 109A—</num>
<heading>CONTROL OF WILD ANIMALS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 8351.</num>
<heading> Predatory and other wild animals</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture may conduct a program of wildlife services with respect to injurious animal species and take any action the Secretary considers necessary in conducting the program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall administer the program in a manner consistent with all of the wildlife services authorities in effect on the day before <date date="2000-10-28">October 28, 2000</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Action by FWS</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service shall use the most expeditious procedure practicable to process and administer permits for take of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a depredating eagle under the Act of <date date="1940-06-08">June 8, 1940</date> (commonly known as the “Bald Eagle Protection Act”) (<ref>54 Stat. 250</ref>, chapter 278; <ref>16 U.S.C. 668</ref> et seq.), or sections 22.11 through 22.32 of title 50, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations) (including depredation of livestock, wildlife, and species protected under the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 1531</ref> et seq.) or any other Federal management program); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a migratory bird included on the list under section 10.13 of title 50, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations) that is posing a conflict.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 2, 1931, ch. 370, § 1</ref>, <ref>46 Stat. 1468</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–237, title X, § 1013(d)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-13">Dec. 13, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1901</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–387, § 1(a) [title VII, § 767]</ref>, <date date="2000-10-28">Oct. 28, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1549</ref>, 1549A–44; <ref>Pub. L. 115–270, title IV, § 4307</ref>, <date date="2018-10-23">Oct. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 3886</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8352.</num>
<heading> Authorization of expenditures for the eradication and control of predatory and other wild animals</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture is authorized to make such expenditures for equipment, supplies, and materials, including the employment of persons and means in the District of Columbia and elsewhere, and to employ such means as may be necessary to execute the functions imposed upon him by <ref>section 8351 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 2, 1931, ch. 370, § 3</ref>, <ref>46 Stat. 1469</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8353.</num>
<heading> Control of nuisance mammals and birds and those constituting reservoirs of zoonotic diseases; exception</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On and after <date date="1987-12-22">December 22, 1987</date>, the Secretary of Agriculture is authorized, except for urban rodent control, to conduct activities and to enter into agreements with States, local jurisdictions, individuals, and public and private agencies, organizations, and institutions in the control of nuisance mammals and birds and those mammal and bird species that are reservoirs for zoonotic diseases, and to deposit any money collected under any such agreement into the appropriation accounts that incur the costs to be available immediately and to remain available until expended for Animal Damage Control activities.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–202, § 101(k) [title I]</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1329–322</ref>, 1329–331.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8354.</num>
<heading> Expenditures for cooperative agreements to lease aircraft</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On and after <date date="2005-11-10">November 10, 2005</date>, notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of Agriculture may use appropriations available to the Secretary for activities authorized under sections 8351 to 8353 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002361">1</ref> of this title, under this or any other Act, to enter into cooperative agreements, with a State, political subdivision, or agency thereof, a public or private agency, organization, or any other person, to lease aircraft if the Secretary determines that the objectives of the agreement will: (1) serve a mutual interest of the parties to the agreement in carrying out the programs administered by the Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service, Wildlife Services; and (2) all parties will contribute resources to the accomplishment of these objectives; award of a cooperative agreement authorized by the Secretary may be made for an initial term not to exceed 5 years.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–97, title VII, § 749</ref>, <date date="2005-11-10">Nov. 10, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 2156</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8355.</num>
<heading> Losses of livestock due to depredation by federally protected species</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Depredation</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “depredation” means actual death, injury, or destruction of livestock that is caused by a federally protected species.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exclusions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “depredation” does not include damage to real or personal property other than livestock, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> damage to—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> other animals;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> vegetation;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> motor vehicles; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> structures;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> diseases;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> lost profits; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> consequential damages.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federally protected species</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “federally protected species” means a species that is or previously was protected under—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Act of <date date="1940-06-08">June 8, 1940</date> (commonly known as the “Bald and Golden Eagle Protection Act”) (<ref>54 Stat. 250</ref>, chapter 278; <ref>16 U.S.C. 668</ref> et seq.);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 1531</ref> et seq.); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Migratory Bird Treaty Act (<ref>16 U.S.C. 703</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Indian Tribe</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Indian Tribe” has the meaning given to the term “Indian tribe” in <ref>section 5304 of title 25</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Livestock</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “livestock” means horses, mules and asses, rabbits, llamas, cattle, bison, swine, sheep, goats, poultry, bees, honey and beehives, or any other animal generally used for food or in the production of food or fiber.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inclusion</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “livestock” includes guard animals actively engaged in the protection of livestock described in subparagraph (A).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “program” means the grant program established under subsection (b)(1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretaries</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “Secretaries” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Administrator of the Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grant program for losses of livestock due to depredation by federally protected species</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretaries shall establish a program to provide grants to States and Indian Tribes to supplement amounts provided by States, Indian Tribes, or State agencies under 1 or more programs established by the States and Indian Tribes (including programs established after <date date="2020-10-30">October 30, 2020</date>)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> to assist livestock producers in carrying out—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> proactive and nonlethal activities to reduce the risk of livestock loss due to depredation by federally protected species occurring on—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> Federal, State, or private land within the applicable State; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> land owned by, or held in trust for the benefit of, the applicable Indian Tribe; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> research relating to the activities described in clause (i); and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> to compensate livestock producers for livestock losses due to depredation by federally protected species occurring on—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Federal, State, or private land within the applicable State; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> land owned by, or held in trust for the benefit of, the applicable Indian Tribe.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Allocation of funding</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports to the secretaries</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Not later than September 30 of each year, a State or Indian Tribe desiring to receive a grant under the program shall submit to the Secretaries a report describing, for the 1-year period ending on that September 30, the losses of livestock due to depredation by federally protected species occurring on—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Federal, State, or private land within the applicable State; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> land owned by, or held in trust for the benefit of, the applicable Indian Tribe.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Allocation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretaries shall allocate available funding to carry out this Act among States and Indian Tribes for a 1-year period ending on September 30 based on the losses described in the reports submitted for the previous 1-year period ending on September 30 under subparagraph (A).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">To be eligible to receive a grant under paragraph (1), a State or Indian Tribe shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> designate an appropriate agency of the State or Indian Tribe to administer the 1 or more programs supplemented by the grant funds;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> establish 1 or more accounts to receive grant funds;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> maintain files of all claims received and paid under grant-funded programs, including supporting documentation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> submit to the Secretaries—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> annual reports that include—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> a summary of claims and expenditures under the program during the year; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> a description of any action taken on the claims; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> such other reports as the Secretaries may require to assist the Secretaries in determining the effectiveness of assisted activities under this section.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sense of Congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the sense of Congress that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> no State or Indian Tribe is required to participate in the program; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the program supplements, and does not replace or supplant, any State compensation programs for depredation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $15,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2021 through 2030, of which—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> $5,000,000 shall be used to provide grants for the purposes described in subsection (b)(1)(A); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> $10,000,000 shall be used to provide grants for the purpose described in subsection (b)(1)(B).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–188, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="2020-10-30">Oct. 30, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 908</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–198, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2678</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8356.</num>
<heading> Depredation permits for black vultures and common ravens; black vulture livestock protection program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Depredation permits for black vultures and common ravens</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service (referred to in this section as the “Secretary”), may issue depredation permits to livestock producers authorizing takings of black vultures or common ravens otherwise prohibited by Federal law to prevent those vultures or common ravens from taking livestock during the calving season or lambing season.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limited to affected States or regions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may issue permits under paragraph (1) only to livestock producers in States and regions in which livestock producers are affected or have been affected in the previous year by black vultures or common ravens, as determined by Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reporting</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall require, as a condition of a permit under paragraph (1), that the permit holder shall report to the appropriate enforcement agencies the takings of black vultures or common ravens pursuant to the permit.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Black vulture livestock protection program</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary, in coordination with States, shall carry out, through fiscal year 2030, a black vulture livestock protection program (referred to in this subsection as the “program”) that allows 1 public entity or Farm Bureau organization per State to hold a statewide depredation permit to protect commercial agriculture livestock from black vulture predation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Each public entity or Farm Bureau organization that holds a depredation permit under the program—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> demonstrate sufficient experience and capacity to provide government regulated services to the public, as determined by the Secretary;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> submit a complete depredation permit application, as determined by the Secretary, for review and approval according to procedures of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> be responsible for complying with, and ensuring subpermittee compliance with, as applicable, all permit conditions; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> be responsible for collecting, managing, and reporting required information under the permit; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> may subpermit to livestock producers to take black vultures for the purposes of livestock protection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Study</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Administrator of the Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service, shall carry out a study on whether prescribed take levels of black vultures may be increased for subpermittees within a biologically sustainable take level for the population.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2024-12-23">December 23, 2024</date>, the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Administrator of the Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service, shall submit to the Chair and Ranking Member of the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate and the Chair and Ranking Member of the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives a report on the status of the program, including the results of the study required under paragraph (3).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–188, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="2020-10-30">Oct. 30, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 911</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–198, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2678</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>