<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 87—</num>
<heading>EXPORT PROMOTION</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5601.</num>
<heading> Purpose</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the purpose of this chapter to increase the profitability of farming and to increase opportunities for United States farms and agricultural enterprises by—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> increasing the effectiveness of the Department of Agriculture in agricultural export policy formulation and implementation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> improving the competitiveness of United States agricultural commodities and products in the world market; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> providing for the coordination and efficient implementation of all agricultural export programs.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–501, title I, § 101</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XV, § 1531</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3669</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5602.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agricultural commodity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “agricultural commodity” means any agricultural commodity, food, feed, fiber, or livestock (including livestock as it is defined in <ref>section 1471(2) of this title</ref> and insects), and any product thereof.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Developing country</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “developing country” means a country that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> has a shortage of foreign exchange earnings and has difficulty accessing sufficient commercial credit to meet all of its food needs, as determined by the Secretary; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> has the potential to become a commercial market for agricultural commodities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Agriculture.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Service</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Service” means the Foreign Agricultural Service of the Department of Agriculture.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Unfair trade practice</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Subject to subparagraph (B), the term “unfair trade practice” means any act, policy, or practice of a foreign country that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> violates, or is inconsistent with, the provisions of, or otherwise denies benefits to the United States under, any trade agreement to which the United States is a party;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in the case of a monopolistic state trading enterprise engaged in the export sale of an agricultural commodity, implements a pricing practice that is inconsistent with sound commercial practice;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> provides a subsidy that—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> decreases market opportunities for United States exports; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> unfairly distorts an agricultural market to the detriment of United States exporters;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<chapeau> imposes an unfair technical barrier to trade, including—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> a trade restriction or commercial requirement (such as a labeling requirement) that adversely affects a new technology (including biotechnology); and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> an unjustified sanitary or phytosanitary restriction (including any restriction that, in violation of the Uruguay Round Agreements, is not based on scientific principles; <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002301">1</ref></content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> imposes a rule that unfairly restricts imports of United States agricultural commodities in the administration of tariff rate quotas; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> fails to adhere to, or circumvents any obligation under, any provision of a trade agreement with the United States.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consistency with 1974 Trade Act</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Nothing in this chapter may be construed to authorize the Secretary to make any determination regarding an unfair trade practice that is inconsistent with <ref>section 2411 of title 19</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> United States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “United States” includes each of the States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, and the territories and possessions of the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> United States agricultural commodity</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “United States agricultural commodity” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an agricultural commodity or product entirely produced in the United States; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> a product of an agricultural commodity—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> 90 percent or more of the agricultural components of which by weight, excluding packaging and added water, is entirely produced in the United States; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> that the Secretary determines to be a high value agricultural product.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">For purposes of this paragraph, fish entirely produced in the United States include fish harvested by a documented fishing vessel as defined in title 46 in waters that are not waters (including the territorial sea) of a foreign country.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Independent states of the former Soviet Union</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “independent states of the former Soviet Union” means the following: Armenia, Azerbaijan, Belarus, Georgia, Kazakhstan, Kyrgyzstan, Moldova, Russia, Tajikistan, Turkmenistan, Ukraine, and Uzbekistan.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–501, title I, § 102</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XV, § 1531</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3669</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–511, title VII, § 702</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 3349</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title II, § 243(c)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 967</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–171, title III, § 3104(b)</ref>, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 290</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5603.</num>
<heading> Agricultural export promotion strategy</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall develop a strategy for implementing Federal agricultural export promotion programs that takes into account the new market opportunities for agricultural products, including opportunities that result from—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the North American Free Trade Agreement and the Uruguay Round Agreements;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any accession to membership in the World Trade Organization;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the continued economic growth in the Pacific Rim; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> other developments.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purpose of strategy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The strategy developed under subsection (a) shall encourage the maintenance, development, and expansion of export markets for United States agricultural commodities and related products, including high-value and value-added products.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Goals of strategy</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The strategy developed under subsection (a) shall have the following goals:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Increase the value of United States agricultural exports each year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Increase the value of United States agricultural exports each year at a faster rate than the rate of increase in the value of overall world export trade in agricultural products.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Increase the value of United States high-value and value-added agricultural exports each year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Increase the value of United States high-value and value-added agricultural exports each year at a faster rate than the rate of increase in the value of overall world export trade in high-value and value-added agricultural products.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> Ensure that to the extent practicable—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> all obligations undertaken in the Uruguay Round Agreement on Agriculture that significantly increase access for United States agricultural commodities are implemented to the extent required by the Uruguay Round Agreements; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> applicable United States laws are used to secure United States rights under the Uruguay Round Agreement on Agriculture.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Priority markets</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Identification of markets</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In developing the strategy required under subsection (a), the Secretary shall annually identify as priority markets—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> those markets in which imports of agricultural products show the greatest potential for increase; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> those markets in which, with the assistance of Federal export promotion programs, exports of United States agricultural products show the greatest potential for increase.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Identification of supporting offices</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The President shall identify annually in the budget of the United States Government submitted under <ref>section 1105 of title 31</ref> each overseas office of the Foreign Agricultural Service that provides assistance to United States exporters in each of the priority markets identified under paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–501, title I, § 103</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XV, § 1531</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3670</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–237, title III, § 308</ref>, <date date="1991-12-13">Dec. 13, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1856</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title II, § 241(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 963</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5603a.</num>
<heading> Global market strategy</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, and biennially thereafter, the Secretary of Agriculture shall consult with the Committee on Agriculture, and the Committee on International Relations, of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate on the formulation and implementation of a global market strategy for the Department of Agriculture that, to the maximum extent practicable—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> identifies opportunities for the growth of agricultural exports to overseas markets;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> ensures that the resources, programs, and policies of the Department are coordinated with those of other agencies; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> remove <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002302">1</ref> barriers to agricultural trade in overseas markets.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The consultations under subsection (a) shall include a review of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the strategic goals of the Department; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the progress of the Department in implementing the strategic goals through the global market strategy.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–171, title III, § 3206</ref>, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 301</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5604.</num>
<heading> Preservation of traditional markets</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall, in implementing programs of the Department of Agriculture intended to encourage or assist exports of agricultural commodities, seek to preserve traditional markets for United States agricultural commodities.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–501, title I, § 104</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XV, § 1531</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3672</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5605.</num>
<heading> Independence of authorities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each authority granted under this chapter shall be in addition to, and not in lieu of, any authority granted to the Secretary or the Commodity Credit Corporation under any other provision of law.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–501, title I, § 105</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XV, § 1531</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3672</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5606.</num>
<heading> Implementation of commitments under Uruguay Round Agreements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than September 30 of each year, the Secretary shall evaluate whether the obligations undertaken by foreign countries under the Uruguay Round Agreement on Agriculture are being fully implemented. If the Secretary has reason to believe (based on the evaluation) that any foreign country, by not implementing the obligations of the country, may be significantly constraining an opportunity for United States agricultural exports, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> submit the evaluation to the United States Trade Representative; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> transmit a copy of the evaluation to the Committee on Agriculture, and the Committee on Ways and Means, of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry, and the Committee on Finance, of the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–501, title I, § 106</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title II, § 242(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 964</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5607.</num>
<heading> Exporter assistance initiative</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To provide a comprehensive source of information to facilitate exports of United States agricultural commodities, the Secretary shall maintain on a website on the Internet information to assist exporters and potential exporters of United States agricultural commodities.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–501, title I, § 107</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 107–171, title III, § 3101</ref>, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 288</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5608.</num>
<heading> Foreign trade missions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tribal representation on trade missions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary, in consultation with the Tribal Advisory Committee established under subsection (b)(2) of <ref>section 6921 of this title</ref> (referred to in this section as the “Advisory Committee”), shall seek—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to support the greater inclusion of Tribal agricultural and food products in Federal trade-related activities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to increase the collaboration between Federal trade promotion efforts and other Federal trade-related activities in support of the greater inclusion sought under subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interdepartmental coordination</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In carrying out activities to increase the collaboration described in paragraph (1)(B), the Secretary shall coordinate with—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Commerce;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Secretary of State;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Secretary of the Interior; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the heads of any other relevant Federal agencies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report; goals</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 2 years after <date date="2018-12-20">December 20, 2018</date>, the Secretary shall submit a report describing the efforts of the Department of Agriculture and other Federal agencies under this section to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Advisory Committee;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the Committee on Indian Affairs of the Senate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Goals</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 90 days after <date date="2018-12-20">December 20, 2018</date>, the Secretary shall establish goals for measuring, in an objective and quantifiable format, the extent to which Indian Tribes and Tribal agricultural and food products are included in the trade-related activities of the Department of Agriculture.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title III, § 3312</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4623</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>AGRICULTURAL EXPORT PROGRAMS</heading>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part A—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Programs</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5621.</num>
<heading> Direct credit sales program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Short-term program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To promote the sale of agricultural commodities, the Commodity Credit Corporation may finance the commercial export sale of such commodities from privately owned stocks on credit terms for not to exceed a 3-year period.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Intermediate-term program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to subsection (c), to promote the sale of agricultural commodities the Commodity Credit Corporation may finance the commercial export sales of agricultural commodities from privately owned stocks on credit terms for a period of not less than 3 years nor in excess of 10 years in a manner that will directly benefit United States agricultural producers.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determinations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Commodity Credit Corporation shall not finance an export sale under subsection (b) unless the Secretary determines that such sale will—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> develop, expand, or maintain the importing country as a foreign market, on a long-term basis, for the commercial sale and export of United States agricultural commodities, without displacing normal commercial sales;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> improve the capability of the importing country to purchase and use, on a long-term basis, United States agricultural commodities; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> otherwise promote the export of United States agricultural commodities.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">The reference in paragraphs (1) and (2) to “on a long-term basis” shall not apply in the case of determinations with respect to sales to the independent states of the former Soviet Union.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of program</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General uses</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Commodity Credit Corporation may use export sales financing authorized under this section—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to increase exports of agricultural commodities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to compete against foreign agricultural exports;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> to assist countries in meeting their food and fiber needs, particularly—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> developing countries; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> countries that are emerging markets that have committed to carry out, or are carrying out, policies that promote economic freedom, private domestic production of food commodities for domestic consumption, and the creation and expansion of efficient domestic markets for the purchase and sale of agricultural commodities; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> for such other purposes as the Secretary determines appropriate consistent with the provisions of subsection (c).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General restrictions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Export sales financing authorized under this section shall not be used for foreign aid, foreign policy, or debt rescheduling purposes. The provisions of the cargo preference laws shall not apply to export sales financed under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Terms of credit assistance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Any contract for the financing of exports by the Commodity Credit Corporation under this section shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a requirement that repayment shall be made in dollars with interest accruing thereon as determined appropriate by the Secretary; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a requirement, if the Secretary determines such requirement appropriate to protect the interests of the United States, that an initial payment be made by the purchaser at the time of sale or shipment of the agricultural commodity that is subject to the contract.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Restrictions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commodity Credit Corporation may not make export sales financing authorized under this section available in connection with sales of an agricultural commodity to any country that the Secretary determines cannot adequately service the debt associated with such sale.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–501, title II, § 201</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XV, § 1531</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3672</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–511, title VII, § 707(a)</ref>–(c), <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 3350</ref>, 3351; <ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title II, § 277(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 979</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5622.</num>
<heading> Export credit guarantee program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Short-term credit guarantees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commodity Credit Corporation may guarantee the repayment of credit made available to finance commercial export sales of agricultural commodities, including processed agricultural products and high-value agricultural products, from privately owned stocks on credit terms that do not exceed a 24-month period.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purpose of program</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Commodity Credit Corporation may use export credit guarantees authorized under this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to increase exports of agricultural commodities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to compete against foreign agricultural exports;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> to assist countries in meeting their food and fiber needs, particularly—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> developing countries; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> countries that are emerging markets that have committed to carry out, or are carrying out, policies that promote economic freedom, private domestic production of food commodities for domestic consumption, and the creation and expansion of efficient domestic markets for the purchase and sale of agricultural commodities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> for such other purposes as the Secretary determines appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Restrictions on use of credit guarantees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Export credit guarantees authorized by this section shall not be used for foreign aid, foreign policy, or debt rescheduling purposes. The provisions of the cargo preference laws shall not apply to export sales with respect to which credit is guaranteed under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Restrictions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commodity Credit Corporation shall not make credit guarantees available in connection with sales of agricultural commodities to any obligor that the Secretary determines cannot adequately service the debt associated with such sale.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Terms</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Export credit guarantees issued pursuant to this section shall contain such terms and conditions as the Commodity Credit Corporation determines to be necessary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> United States agricultural commodities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commodity Credit Corporation shall finance or guarantee under this section only United States agricultural commodities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Ineligibility of financial institutions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A financial institution shall be ineligible to receive an assignment of a credit guarantee issued by the Commodity Credit Corporation under this section if it is determined by the Corporation, at the time of the assignment, that such financial institution—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is the financial institution issuing the letter of credit or a subsidiary of such institution; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is owned or controlled by an entity that owns or controls that financial institution issuing the letter of credit.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Third country banks</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Commodity Credit Corporation may guarantee under subsection (a) the repayment of credit made available to finance an export sale irrespective of whether the obligor is located in the country to which the export sale is destined.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conditions for fish and processed fish products</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In making available any guarantees of credit under this section in connection with sales of fish and processed fish products, the Secretary shall make such guarantees available under terms and conditions that are comparable to the terms and conditions that apply to guarantees provided with respect to sales of other agricultural commodities under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation on agricultural export credit programs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary and the United States Trade Representative shall consult on a regular basis with the Committee on Agriculture, and the Committee on International Relations, of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate on the status of multilateral negotiations regarding agricultural export credit programs.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administration</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition of long term</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In this subsection, the term “long term” means a period of 10 or more years.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Guarantees</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In administering the export credit guarantees authorized under this section, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> develop an approach to risk evaluation that facilitates accurate country risk designations and timely adjustments to the designations (on an ongoing basis) in response to material changes in country risk conditions, with ongoing opportunity for input and evaluation from the private sector;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> adjust risk-based guarantees as necessary to ensure program effectiveness and United States competitiveness;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> work with industry to ensure, to the maximum extent practicable, that risk-based fees associated with the guarantees cover the operating costs and losses over the long term; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> notwithstanding any other provision of this section, administer and carry out (only after consulting with the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition and Forestry of the Senate) the program pursuant to such terms as may be agreed between the parties to address the World Trade Organization dispute WTO/DS267 to the extent not superseded by any applicable international undertakings on officially supported export credits to which the United States is a party.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–501, title II, § 202</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XV, § 1531</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3673</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–237, title III, § 334</ref>, <date date="1991-12-13">Dec. 13, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1859</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–511, title VII</ref>, §§ 708, 709(a), <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 3351</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title II</ref>, §§ 243(a), 277(c)(3), <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 965</ref>, 979; <ref>Pub. L. 107–171, title III, § 3102(a)</ref>–(c), <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 289</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, title III, § 3101(a)</ref>, (c), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1831</ref>, 1832; <ref>Pub. L. 113–79, title III, § 3101(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 778</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5623.</num>
<heading> Agricultural trade promotion and facilitation</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall carry out activities under this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to access, develop, maintain, and expand markets for United States agricultural commodities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to promote cooperation and the exchange of information.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Market Access Program</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition of eligible trade organization</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In this subsection, the term “eligible trade organization” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a United States agricultural trade organization or regional State-related organization that promotes the export and sale of United States agricultural commodities and that does not stand to profit directly from specific sales of United States agricultural commodities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a cooperative organization or State agency that promotes the sale of United States agricultural commodities; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a private organization that promotes the export and sale of United States agricultural commodities if the Secretary determines that such organization would significantly contribute to United States export market development.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Commodity Credit Corporation shall establish and carry out a program, to be known as the “Market Access Program”, to encourage the development, maintenance, and expansion of commercial export markets for United States agricultural commodities (including commodities that are organically produced (as defined in <ref>section 6502 of this title</ref>)) through cost-share assistance to eligible trade organizations that implement a foreign market development program.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Participation requirements</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Marketing plan and other requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">To be eligible for cost-share assistance under this subsection, an eligible trade organization shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> prepare and submit a marketing plan to the Secretary that meets the guidelines governing such a marketing plan specified in this paragraph or otherwise established by the Secretary;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> meet any other requirements established by the Secretary; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> enter into an agreement with the Secretary.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purpose of marketing plan</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A marketing plan submitted under this paragraph shall describe the advertising or other market oriented export promotion activities to be carried out by the eligible trade organization with respect to which assistance under this subsection is being requested.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Specific elements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">To be approved by the Secretary, a marketing plan submitted under this paragraph shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> specifically describe the manner in which assistance received by the eligible trade organization, in conjunction with funds and services provided by the eligible trade organization, will be expended in implementing the marketing plan;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> establish specific market goals to be achieved under the marketing plan; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> contain whatever additional requirements are determined by the Secretary to be necessary.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Branded promotion</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A marketing plan approved by the Secretary may provide for the use of branded advertising to promote the sale of United States agricultural commodities in a foreign country under such terms and conditions as may be established by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(E)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amendments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">An approved marketing plan may be amended by the eligible trade organization at any time, subject to the approval of the amendment by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Level of assistance and cost-share requirements</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary shall justify in writing the level of assistance to be provided to an eligible trade organization under this subsection and the level of cost sharing required of the organization.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on branded promotion</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Assistance provided under this subsection for activities described in paragraph (3)(D) shall not exceed 50 percent of the cost of implementing the marketing plan, except that the Secretary may determine not to apply such limitation in the case of United States agricultural commodities with respect to which there has been a favorable decision by the United States Trade Representative under <ref>section 2411 of title 19</ref>. Criteria used by the Secretary for determining that the limitation shall not apply shall be consistent and documented.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other terms and conditions</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Multiyear basis</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary may provide assistance under this subsection on a multiyear basis, subject to annual review by the Secretary for compliance with the approved marketing plan.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination of assistance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Secretary may terminate any assistance made, or to be made, available under this subsection if the Secretary determines that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the eligible trade organization is not adhering to the terms and conditions applicable to the provision of the assistance;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the eligible trade organization is not implementing the approved marketing plan or is not adequately meeting the established goals of the plan;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the eligible trade organization is not adequately contributing its own resources to the implementation of the plan; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the Secretary determines that termination of assistance in a particular instance is in the best interests of the Market Access Program.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Evaluations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Beginning not later than 15 months after the initial provision of assistance under this subsection to an eligible trade organization, the Secretary shall monitor the expenditures by the eligible trade organization of such assistance, including the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> An evaluation of the effectiveness of the marketing plan of the eligible trade organization in developing or maintaining markets for United States agricultural commodities.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> An evaluation of whether assistance provided under this subsection is necessary to maintain such markets.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> A thorough accounting of the expenditure by the eligible trade organization of the assistance provided under this subsection.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Restrictions on use of funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Assistance provided under this subsection to an eligible trade organization may not be used—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to provide direct assistance to any foreign for-profit corporation for the corporation’s use in promoting foreign-produced products; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> to provide direct assistance to any for-profit corporation that is not recognized as a small business concern (as described in <ref>section 632(a) of title 15</ref>), excluding—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a cooperative;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> an association described in <ref>section 291 of this title</ref>; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a nonprofit trade association.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Permissive use of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Assistance provided under this subsection to a United States agricultural trade association, cooperative, or small business may be used for individual branded promotional activity related to a United States branded product, if the beneficiaries of the activity have provided funds for the activity in an amount that is at least equivalent to the amount of such assistance.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Priority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In providing assistance for branded promotion, the Secretary should give priority to small-sized entities.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contribution level</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary should require a minimum contribution level of 10 percent from an eligible trade organization that receives assistance for nonbranded promotion.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Increases in contribution level</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary may increase the contribution level in any subsequent year that an eligible trade organization receives assistance for nonbranded promotion.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(10)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additionality</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary should require each participant in the Market Access Program to certify that any Federal funds received supplement, but do not supplant, private or third party participant funds or other contributions to Program activities.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(11)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Independent audits</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If as a result of an evaluation or audit of activities of a participant under the Market Access Program, the Secretary determines that a further review is justified in order to ensure compliance with the requirements of the Program, the Secretary should require the participant to contract for an independent audit of the Program activities, including activities of any subcontractor.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(12)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tobacco</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">No funds made available under the Market Access Program may be used for activities to develop, maintain, or expand foreign markets for tobacco.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Foreign Market Development Cooperator Program</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition of eligible trade organization</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In this subsection, the term “eligible trade organization” means a United States trade organization that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> promotes the export of 1 or more United States agricultural commodities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> does not have a business interest in or receive remuneration from specific sales of agricultural commodities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall establish and, in cooperation with eligible trade organizations, carry out a program to be known as the “Foreign Market Development Cooperator Program” to maintain and develop foreign markets for United States agricultural commodities.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Funds made available to carry out this subsection shall be used only to provide—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> cost-share assistance to an eligible trade organization under a contract or agreement with the eligible trade organization; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> assistance for other costs that are appropriate to carry out the Foreign Market Development Cooperator Program, including contingent liabilities that are not otherwise funded.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> E (Kika) de la Garza Emerging Markets Program</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition of emerging market</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In this subsection, the term “emerging market” means any country, foreign territory, customs union, or other economic market that the Secretary determines—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is taking steps toward a market-oriented economy through the food, agriculture, or rural business sectors of its economy; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> has the potential to provide a viable and significant market for United States agricultural commodities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary shall establish and carry out a program, to be known as the “E (Kika) de la Garza Emerging Markets Program”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to develop agricultural markets in emerging markets; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to promote cooperation and exchange of information between agricultural institutions and agribusinesses in the United States and emerging markets.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Development of agricultural systems</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">To develop, maintain, or expand markets for exports of United States agricultural commodities, the Secretary shall make available to emerging markets the expertise of the United States—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> to make assessments of food and rural business systems needs;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> to make recommendations on measures necessary to enhance the effectiveness of the food and rural business systems described in subclause (I), including potential reductions in trade barriers; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> to identify and carry out specific opportunities and projects to enhance the effectiveness of the food and rural business systems described in subclause (I).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Extent of program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The Secretary shall implement this subparagraph with respect to at least 3 emerging markets in each fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Experts from the United States</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Secretary may implement subparagraph (A) by providing—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> assistance to teams (consisting primarily of agricultural consultants, agricultural producers, other persons from the private sector, and government officials expert in assessing the food and rural business systems of other countries) to enable those teams to conduct the assessments, make the recommendations, and identify the opportunities and projects described in subparagraph (A)(i) in emerging markets;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> for necessary subsistence and transportation expenses of—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> United States food and rural business system experts, including United States agricultural producers and other United States individuals knowledgeable in agricultural and agribusiness matters, to enable such United States food and rural business system experts to assist in transferring knowledge and expertise to entities from emerging markets; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> individuals designated by emerging markets to enable such designated individuals to consult with such United States experts to enhance food and rural business systems of such emerging markets and to transfer knowledge and expertise to such emerging markets.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cost-sharing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary shall encourage the nongovernmental experts described in subparagraph (B) to share the costs of, and otherwise assist in, the participation of those experts in the E (Kika) de la Garza Emerging Markets Program.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Technical assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary is authorized to provide, or pay the necessary costs for, technical assistance (including the establishment of extension services) to enable individuals or other entities to carry out recommendations, projects, and opportunities in emerging markets, including recommendations, projects, and opportunities described in subclauses (II) and (III) of subparagraph (A)(i).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(E)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports to Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A team that receives assistance under subparagraph (B)(i) shall prepare and submit to the Secretary such reports as the Secretary may require.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(F)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Advisory committee</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">To provide the Secretary with information that may be useful to the Secretary in carrying out this subsection, the Secretary may establish an advisory committee composed of representatives of the various sectors of the food and rural business systems of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(G)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The authority provided under this subsection shall be in addition to and not in place of any other authority of the Secretary or the Commodity Credit Corporation.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Technical assistance for specialty crops</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary of Agriculture shall establish an export assistance program, in this subsection referred to as the “program”, to address existing or potential unique barriers that prohibit or threaten the export of United States specialty crops.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purpose</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The program shall provide direct assistance through public and private sector projects and technical assistance, including through the program under <ref>section 3157(e) of this title</ref>, to remove, resolve, or mitigate existing or potential sanitary, phytosanitary, and technical barriers to trade.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Priority</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The program shall address time sensitive and strategic market access projects based on—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> trade effect on market retention, market access, and market expansion; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> trade impact.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Multiyear projects</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may provide assistance under the program to a project for longer than a 5-year period if the Secretary determines that further assistance would effectively support the purpose described in paragraph (2).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Outreach and technical assistance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> conduct outreach to inform eligible organizations of the requirements of the program and the process by which such organizations may submit proposals for funding;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provide technical assistance to eligible organizations to assist in developing proposals and complying with the requirements of the program; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> solicit input from eligible organizations on improvements to streamline and facilitate the provision of assistance under this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations and procedures</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2018-12-20">December 20, 2018</date>, the Secretary shall review program regulations, procedures, and guidelines for assistance under this subsection and make revisions to streamline, improve, and clarify the application, approval and compliance processes for such assistance, including revisions to implement the requirements of paragraph (5).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Considerations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In reviewing and making revisions under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall consider—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> establishing accountability standards that are appropriate for the size and scope of a project; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> establishing streamlined application and approval processes, including for smaller-scale projects or projects to address time-sensitive trade barriers.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Each year, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report that contains, for the period covered by the report, a description of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> each factor that affects the export of specialty crops, including each factor relating to any—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> significant sanitary or phytosanitary issue;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> trade barrier; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> emerging sanitary or phytosanitary issue or trade barrier; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any funds provided under subsection (f)(3)(A)(iv) that were not obligated in a fiscal year; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the reason such funds were not obligated.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Funding and administration</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Commodity Credit Corporation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall use the funds, facilities, and authorities of the Commodity Credit Corporation to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Funding amount</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For each of fiscal years 2019 through 2023, of the funds of, or an equal value of commodities owned by, the Commodity Credit Corporation, the Secretary shall use to carry out this section $255,000,000, to remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Allocation</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">For each of fiscal years 2019 through 2023, the Secretary shall allocate funds to carry out this section in accordance with the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Market access program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">For market access activities authorized under subsection (b), of the funds of, or an equal value of commodities owned by, the Commodity Credit Corporation, not less than $200,000,000 for each fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Foreign market development cooperator program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">To carry out subsection (c), of the funds of, or an equal value of commodities owned by, the Commodity Credit Corporation, not less than $34,500,000 for each fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> E (Kika) de la Garza Emerging Markets Program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">To provide assistance under subsection (d), of the funds of, or an equal value of commodities owned by, the Commodity Credit Corporation, not more than $8,000,000 for each fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iv)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Technical assistance for specialty crops</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">To carry out subsection (e), of the funds of, or an equal value of the commodities owned by, the Commodity Credit Corporation, $9,000,000 for each fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(v)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Priority trade fund</heading>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(I)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent4">In addition to the amounts allocated under clauses (i) through (iv), and notwithstanding any limitations in those clauses, as determined by the Secretary, for 1 or more programs under this section for authorized activities to access, develop, maintain, and expand markets for United States agricultural commodities, $3,500,000 for each fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(II)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Considerations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent4">In allocating funds made available under subclause (I), the Secretary may consider providing a greater allocation to 1 or more programs under this section for which the amounts requested under applications exceed available funding for the 1 or more programs.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reallocation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Any funds allocated under clauses (i) through (iv) of subparagraph (A) that remain unobligated one year after the end of the fiscal year in which they are first made available shall be reallocated to the priority trade fund under subparagraph (A)(v). To the maximum extent practicable, the Secretary shall allocate such reallocated funds to support exports of those types of United States agricultural commodities eligible for assistance under the program for which the funds were originally allocated under subparagraph (A).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cuba</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding <ref>section 7207 of title 22</ref> or any other provision of law, funds made available under this section may be used to carry out the programs authorized under subsections (b) and (c) in Cuba. Funds may not be used as described in the previous sentence in contravention with directives set forth under the National Security Presidential Memorandum entitled “Strengthening the Policy of the United States Toward Cuba” issued by the President on <date date="2017-06-16">June 16, 2017</date>, during the period in which that memorandum is in effect.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In addition to any other amounts provided under this subsection, there are authorized to be appropriated such sums as are necessary to carry out the programs and authorities under paragraph (3)(A)(v) and subsections (b) through (e).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–501, title II, § 203</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XV, § 1531</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3674</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–237, title III, § 309</ref>, <date date="1991-12-13">Dec. 13, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1856</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–66, title I, § 1302(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1993-08-10">Aug. 10, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 330</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–465, title IV, § 411(d)</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4963</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title II, § 244(a)(1)</ref>, (b), <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 967</ref>, 968; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, title III, § 3102(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1832</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title III, § 3201(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4608</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5624.</num>
<heading> Barter of agricultural commodities</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary or the Commodity Credit Corporation may provide eligible commodities in barter for foreign products under such terms and conditions as the Secretary or the Corporation shall prescribe.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible commodities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Unless otherwise specified, eligible commodities shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> agricultural commodities acquired by the Commodity Credit Corporation through price support operations; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> agricultural commodities acquired by the Secretary or the Commodity Credit Corporation in the normal course of business and available for disposition.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Barter by exporters of agricultural commodities</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purpose</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary or the Commodity Credit Corporation shall encourage exporters of agricultural commodities to barter such commodities for foreign products—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to acquire such foreign products needed by such exporters; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to develop, maintain, or expand foreign markets for United States agricultural exports.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible activities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary or the Commodity Credit Corporation may provide eligible commodities to exporters to assist such exporters in barter transactions.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Technical assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary or the Commodity Credit Corporation shall provide technical advice and assistance relating to the barter of agricultural commodities to any United States exporter who requests such advice or assistance.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer of foreign products to other Government agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary or the Commodity Credit Corporation may transfer any foreign products that the Secretary or such Corporation obtains through barter activities to other Government agencies if the Corporation receives assurances that it will receive full reimbursement from the agency within the same fiscal year in which such transfer occurs.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Corporation authority not limited</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing contained in this section shall limit the authority of the Commodity Credit Corporation to acquire, hold, or dispose of such foreign materials as such Corporation determines appropriate in carrying out the functions and protecting the assets of the Corporation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibited activities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary or the Commodity Credit Corporation shall take reasonable precautions to prevent the misuse of eligible commodities in a barter or exchange program, including activities that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> displace or interfere with commercial sales of United States agricultural commodities that otherwise might be made;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> unduly disrupt world prices of agricultural commodities or the normal patterns of commercial trade with recipient countries; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> permit the resale or transshipment of eligible commodities to countries other than the intended recipient country.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–501, title II, § 204</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XV, § 1531</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3676</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–237, title III, § 320</ref>, <date date="1991-12-13">Dec. 13, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1857</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5625.</num>
<heading> Combination of programs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commodity Credit Corporation may carry out a program under which commercial export credit guarantees available under <ref>section 5622 of this title</ref> are combined with direct credits from the Commodity Credit Corporation under <ref>section 5621 of this title</ref> to reduce the effective rate of interest on export sales of agricultural commodities.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–501, title II, § 205</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XV, § 1531</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3677</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part B—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Implementation</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5641.</num>
<heading> Funding levels</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Direct credit programs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commodity Credit Corporation may make available for each fiscal year such funds of the Commodity Credit Corporation as it determines necessary to carry out any direct credit program established under <ref>section 5621 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Export credit guarantee program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commodity Credit Corporation shall make available for each fiscal year $5,500,000,000 of credit guarantees under <ref>section 5622(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–501, title II, § 211</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XV, § 1531</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3677</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–66, title I, § 1302(a)</ref>, <date date="1993-08-10">Aug. 10, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 330</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title II</ref>, §§ 243(b), 244(a)(2)(B), (c), <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 967</ref>, 968; <ref>Pub. L. 107–171, title III</ref>, §§ 3102(d), 3103, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 289</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, title III</ref>, §§ 3101(b), 3102(b), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1831</ref>, 1832; <ref>Pub. L. 113–79, title III</ref>, §§ 3101(b), 3102, <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 779</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title III, § 3201(b)(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4616</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>BARRIERS TO EXPORTS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5651.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, title III, § 3103(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1832</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5652.</num>
<heading> Relief from unfair trade practices</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of programs</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may, for each article described in paragraph (2), make available some or all of the commercial export promotion programs of the Department of Agriculture and the Commodity Credit Corporation to help mitigate or offset the effects of the unfair trade practice serving as the basis for the proceeding described in paragraph (2).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Commodities specified</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Paragraph (1) shall apply in the case of articles for which the United States has instituted, under any international trade agreement, any dispute settlement proceeding based on an unfair trade practice if such proceeding has been prevented from progressing to a decision by the refusal of the party maintaining the unfair trade practice to permit the proceeding to progress.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultations required</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For any article described in subsection (a)(2), the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> promptly consult with representatives of the industry producing such articles and other allied groups or individuals regarding specific actions or the development of an integrated marketing strategy utilizing some or all of the commercial export programs of the Department of Agriculture and the Commodity Credit Corporation to help mitigate or offset the effects of the unfair trade practice identified in subsection (a)(2); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> ascertain and take into account the industry preference for the practical use of available commercial export promotion programs in implementing subsection (a)(1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–501, title III, § 301</ref>, formerly § 302, as added <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XV, § 1531</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3680</ref>; renumbered § 301, <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, title III, § 3103(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1832</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5653.</num>
<heading> Equitable treatment of high-value and value-added United States agricultural commodities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the case of any program operated by the Secretary or the Commodity Credit Corporation during the fiscal years 1991 through 1995, for the purpose of discouraging unfair trade practices, the Secretary shall establish as an objective to expend annually at least 25 percent of the total funds available (or 25 percent of the value of any commodities employed) for program activities involving the export sales of high-value agricultural commodities and value-added products of United States agricultural commodities.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–501, title III, § 302</ref>, formerly § 303, as added <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XV, § 1531</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3680</ref>; renumbered § 302 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, title III, § 3103(b)(2)</ref>, (3), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1832</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS</heading>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part A—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Program Controls</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5661.</num>
<heading> Program controls for export programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Arrival certification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">With respect to a commodity provided, or for which financing or a credit guarantee or other assistance is made available, under a program authorized in section 5621 or 5622 of this title, the Commodity Credit Corporation shall require the exporter of the commodity to maintain records of an official or customary commercial nature or other documents as the Secretary may require, and shall allow representatives of the Commodity Credit Corporation access to the records or documents as needed, to verify the arrival of the commodity in the country that is the intended destination of the commodity.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Diversion</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The unauthorized diversion of commodities under the programs authorized in sections 5621 and 5622 of this title is prohibited. The Commodity Credit Corporation shall establish procedures providing for the annual audit of a sufficient number of export transactions under such programs to ensure that the agricultural commodities that were the subject of such transactions arrived in the country of destination as provided in the sales agreement.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Good faith</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The failure of an exporter, seller or other person to comply with the provisions of this section shall not affect the validity of any credit guarantee or other obligation of the Commodity Credit Corporation under the programs under this chapter with respect to any exporter, seller, or person who had no knowledge of such failure to comply at the time such exporter, seller, or person was assigned the credit guarantee or at the time the Corporation entered into such obligation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–501, title IV, § 401</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XV, § 1531</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3680</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title II, § 246</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 969</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, title III, § 3103(b)(4)</ref>, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1832</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5662.</num>
<heading> Compliance provisions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Records</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In the administration of the programs established under sections 5621, 5622, and 5623(b) of this title the Secretary shall require by regulation each exporter or other participant under the program to maintain all records concerning a program transaction for a period of not to exceed 5 years after completion of the program transaction, and to permit the Secretary to have full and complete access, for such 5-year period, to such records.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Confidentiality</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The personally identifiable information contained in reports under subsection (a) may be withheld in accordance with <ref>section 552(b)(4) of title 5</ref>. Any officer or employee of the Department of Agriculture who knowingly discloses confidential information as defined by <ref>section 1905 of title 18</ref> shall be subject to <ref>section 1905 of title 18</ref>. Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to authorize the withholding of information from Congress.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Violation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">If any exporter, assignee, or other participant has engaged in fraud with respect to the programs authorized under this chapter, or has otherwise violated program requirements under this chapter, the Commodity Credit Corporation may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> hold such exporter, assignee, or participant liable for any and all losses to the Corporation resulting from such fraud or violation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> require a refund of any assistance provided to such exporter, assignee, or participant plus interest, as determined by the Secretary; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> collect liquidated damages from such exporter, assignee, or participant in an amount determined appropriate by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">The provisions of this subsection shall be without prejudice to any other remedy that is available under any other provision of law.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Suspension and debarment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commodity Credit Corporation may suspend or debar for 1 or more years any exporter, assignee, or other participant from participation in one or more of the programs authorized by this chapter if the Corporation determines, after opportunity for a hearing, that such exporter, assignee, or other participant has violated the terms and conditions of the program or of this chapter and that the violation is of such a nature as to warrant suspension or debarment.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> False certifications</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The provisions of <ref>section 1001 of title 18</ref> shall apply to any false certifications issued under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–501, title IV, § 402</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XV, § 1531</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3681</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title II, § 247</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 969</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, title III, § 3103(b)(5)</ref>, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1833</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title III, § 3201(b)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4616</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5663.</num>
<heading> Departmental administration system</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">With respect to each commercial export promotion program of the Department of Agriculture or the Commodity Credit Corporation, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> specify by regulation the criteria used to evaluate and approve proposals for that program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> establish a centralized system to permit the Foreign Agricultural Service to provide the history and current status of any proposal;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> provide for regular audits of program transactions to determine compliance with program objectives and requirements; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> establish criteria to evaluate loans eligible for guarantees by the Commodity Credit Corporation, so as to ensure that the Corporation does not assume undue risk in providing such guarantees.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Accessibility of information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Information pertaining to the status of a particular proposal shall be retrievable within the central system by appropriate categories, as determined appropriate by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–501, title IV, § 403</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XV, § 1531</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3682</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5664.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title II, § 248</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 969</ref></heading>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part B—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Miscellaneous Provisions</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5671.</num>
<heading> Agricultural embargo protection</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prerequisites; scope of compensation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the President or other member of the executive branch of the Federal Government causes the export of any agricultural commodity to any country or area of the world to be suspended or restricted for reasons of national security or foreign policy under the Export Administration Act of 1979 (50 U.S.C. App. 2401 et seq.) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002303">1</ref> or under any other provision of law;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> such suspension or restriction of the export of such agricultural commodity is imposed other than in connection with a suspension or restriction of all exports from the United States to such country or area of the world; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> sales of such agricultural commodity for export from the United States to such country or area of the world during the year preceding the year in which the suspension or restriction is imposed exceeds 3 percent of the total sales of such commodity for export from the United States to all foreign countries during the year preceding the year in which the suspension or restriction is in effect;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">the Secretary shall compensate producers of the commodity involved by making payments available to such producers, as provided in subsection (b) of this section.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amount of payments</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">If the Secretary makes payments available to producers under subsection (a), the amount of such payment shall be determined—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> in the case of an agricultural commodity for which payments are authorized to be made to producers under Title I of the Agricultural Act of 1949 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1441</ref> et seq.), by multiplying—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the farm program payment yield for the producer or the yield established for the farm for the commodity involved; by</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the crop acreage base established for the commodity; by</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the amount by which the average market price per unit of such commodity received by producers during the 60-day period immediately following the date of the imposition of the suspension or restriction is less than 100 percent of the parity price for such commodity, as determined by the Secretary on the date of the imposition of the suspension or restriction; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in the case of other agricultural commodities for which price support is authorized for producers under the Agricultural Act of 1949 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1421</ref> et seq.), by multiplying the amount by which the average market price per unit of such commodity received by the producers during the 60-day period immediately following the date of the imposition of the suspension or restriction is less than 100 percent of the parity price for such commodity, as determined by the Secretary on the date of the imposition of the suspension or restriction, by the quantity of such commodity sold by the producer during the period that the suspension or restriction is in effect.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Time for payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Payments under paragraph (1) of subsection (b) shall be made for each marketing year or part thereof during which the suspension or restriction is in effect and shall be made in equal amounts at 90-day intervals, beginning 90 days after the date of the imposition of the suspension or restriction.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Commodity Credit Corporation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall use the Commodity Credit Corporation in carrying out the provisions of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may issue such regulations as are determined necessary to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–501, title IV, § 411</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XV, § 1531</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3682</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5672.</num>
<heading> Development of plans to alleviate adverse impact of embargoes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">To alleviate, to the maximum extent possible, the adverse impact on farmers, elevator operators, common carriers, and exporters of agricultural commodities of the President or other member of the executive branch of the Federal Government causing the export of any agricultural commodity to any country or area of the world to be suspended or restricted, the Secretary of Agriculture shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> develop a comprehensive contingency plan that shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an assessment of existing farm programs with a view to determining whether such programs are sufficiently flexible to enable the Secretary to efficiently and effectively offset the adverse impact of such a suspension or restriction on farmers, elevator operators, common carriers, and exporters of commodities provided for under such programs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an evaluation of the kinds and availability of information needed to determine, on an emergency basis, the extent and severity of the impact of such a suspension or restriction on producers, elevator operators, common carriers, and exporters; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the development of criteria for determining the extent, if any, to which the impact of such a suspension or restriction should be offset in the case of each of the sectors referred to in paragraph (1)(B);</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> for any suspension or restriction for which compensation is not provided under <ref>section 5671 of this title</ref>, prepare and submit to the appropriate Committees of Congress such recommendations for changes in existing agricultural programs, or for new programs, as the Secretary considers necessary to handle effectively, efficiently, economically, and fairly the impact of any such suspension or restriction;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> for any suspension or restriction for which compensation is provided under <ref>section 5671 of this title</ref>, prepare and submit to the appropriate Committees of Congress a plan for implementing and administering <ref>section 5671 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> require the Commodity Credit Corporation, prior to such Corporation purchasing any contracts for the purpose of offsetting the impact of a commodity suspension or restriction, to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> prepare an economic justification for each commodity involved in the suspension or restriction to determine if such a purchase is necessary;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> estimate any suspension- or restriction-related benefits and detrimental effects to the exporters, and use both estimates in determining the extent, if any, Federal assistance is needed; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> limit its purchases to only those types and grades of commodities suspended or restricted from shipment and make such purchases at prices at or near the current market prices.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–501, title IV, § 412</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XV, § 1531</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3684</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5673.</num>
<heading> Contracting authority to expand agricultural export markets</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may contract with individuals for services to be performed outside the United States as the Secretary determines necessary or appropriate for carrying out programs and activities to maintain, develop, or enhance export markets for United States agricultural commodities and products.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Not employees of United States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Individuals referred to in subsection (a) shall not be regarded as officers or employees of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–501, title IV, § 413</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XV, § 1531</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3685</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5674.</num>
<heading> Trade consultations concerning imports</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation between agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall require consultation between the Administrator of the Service and the heads of other appropriate agencies and offices of the Department of Agriculture, including the Administrator of the Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service, prior to relaxing or removing any restriction on the importation of any agricultural commodity into the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation with Trade Representative</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall consult with the United States Trade Representative prior to relaxing or removing any restriction on the importation of any agricultural commodity or a product thereof into the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Monitoring compliance with sanitary and phytosanitary measures</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall monitor the compliance of World Trade Organization member countries with the sanitary and phytosanitary measures of the Agreement on Agriculture of the Uruguay Round of Multilateral Trade Negotiations of the General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade. If the Secretary has reason to believe that any country may have failed to meet the commitment on sanitary and phytosanitary measures under the Agreement in a manner that adversely impacts the exports of a United States agricultural commodity, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provide such information to the United States Trade Representative of the circumstances surrounding the matter arising under this subsection; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> with respect to any such circumstances that the Secretary considers to have a continuing adverse effect on United States agricultural exports, report to the Committee on Agriculture, and the Committee on Ways and Means, of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry, and the Committee on Finance, of the Senate—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> that a country may have failed to meet the sanitary and phytosanitary commitments; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any notice given by the Secretary to the United States Trade Representative.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–501, title IV, § 414</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XV, § 1531</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3685</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title II, § 242(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 965</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5675.</num>
<heading> Technical assistance in trade negotiations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall provide technical services to the United States Trade Representative on matters pertaining to agricultural trade and with respect to international negotiations on issues related to agricultural trade.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–501, title IV, § 415</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XV, § 1531</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3685</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5676.</num>
<heading> Limitation on use of certain export promotion programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may provide that a person shall be ineligible for participation in an export program established under title I of the Food for Peace Act [<ref>7 U.S.C. 1701</ref> et seq.], or in any other export credit, credit guarantee, bonus, or other export program carried out through, or administered by, the Commodity Credit Corporation or carried out with funds made available pursuant to <ref>section 612c of this title</ref> with respect to the export of any agricultural commodity or product that has been or will be used as the basis for a claim of a refund, as drawback, pursuant to <ref>section 1313(j)(2) of title 19</ref>, of any duty, tax, or fee imposed under Federal law on an imported commodity or product.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Vegetable oil</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A person shall be ineligible for participation in any of the export programs referred to in subsection (a) with respect to the export of vegetable oil or a vegetable oil product that has been or will be used as the basis for a claim of a refund, as a drawback, pursuant to <ref>section 1313 of title 19</ref>, of any duty, tax, or fee imposed under Federal law on an imported commodity or product.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the Secretary takes action under the authority granted under subsection (a), a person applying to export any agricultural commodity under the export programs referred to in subsection (a) shall certify that none of the commodity has been or will be used as the basis of a claim for any refund specified in subsection (a), except that regardless of whether the Secretary takes action under the authority granted under subsection (a), a person applying to export any vegetable oil or vegetable oil product under such programs shall certify that none of the vegetable oil or vegetable oil product has been or will be used as the basis of a claim for any refund specified in subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall promulgate regulations to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall not apply to quantities of agricultural commodities and products with respect to which an exporter has entered into a contract, prior to <date date="1990-11-28">November 28, 1990</date>, for an export sale.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–501, title IV, § 416</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XV, § 1531</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3685</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–237, title III, § 313</ref>, <date date="1991-12-13">Dec. 13, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1856</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, title III, § 3001(b)(1)(A)</ref>, (2)(K), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1820</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5677.</num>
<heading> Trade compensation and assistance programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as provided in subsection (f), notwithstanding any other provision of law, if, after <date date="1996-04-04">April 4, 1996</date>, the President or any other member of the executive branch causes exports from the United States to any country to be unilaterally suspended for reasons of national security or foreign policy, and if within 90 days after the date on which the suspension is imposed on United States exports no other country with an agricultural economic interest agrees to participate in the suspension, the Secretary shall carry out a trade compensation assistance program in accordance with this section (referred to in this section as a “program”).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation or provision of funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Under a program, the Secretary shall, based on an evaluation by the Secretary of the method most likely to produce the greatest compensatory benefit for producers of the commodity involved in the suspension—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> compensate producers of the commodity by making payments available to producers, as provided by subsection (c)(1); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> make available an amount of funds calculated under subsection (c)(2), to promote agricultural exports or provide agricultural commodities to developing countries under any authorities available to the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determination of amount of compensation or funds</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the Secretary makes payments available to producers under subsection (b)(1), the amount of the payment shall be determined by the Secretary based on the Secretary’s estimate of the loss suffered by producers of the commodity involved due to any decrease in the price of the commodity as a result of the suspension.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determination of amount of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For each fiscal year of a program, the amount of funds made available under subsection (b)(2) shall be equal to 90 percent of the average annual value of United States agricultural exports to the country with respect to which exports are suspended during the most recent 3 years prior to the suspension for which data are available.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duration of program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For each suspension of exports for which a program is implemented under this section, funds shall be made available under subsection (b) for each fiscal year or part of a fiscal year for which the suspension is in effect, but not to exceed 3 fiscal years.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Commodity Credit Corporation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall use funds of the Commodity Credit Corporation to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception to carrying out program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall not apply to any suspension of trade due to a war or armed hostility.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Partial year embargoes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the Secretary makes funds available under subsection (b)(2), regardless of whether an embargo is in effect for only part of a fiscal year, the full amount of funds as calculated under subsection (c)(2) shall be made available under a program for the fiscal year. If the Secretary determines that making the required amount of funds available in a partial fiscal year is impracticable, the Secretary may make all or part of the funds required to be made available in the following fiscal year (in addition to any funds otherwise required under a program to be made available in the following fiscal year).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Short supply embargoes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the President or any other member of the executive branch causes exports to be suspended based on a determination of short supply, the Secretary shall carry out <ref>section 1310 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–501, title IV, § 417</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title II, § 249</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 969</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5678.</num>
<heading> Edward R. Madigan United States Agricultural Export Excellence Award</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Congress finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> United States producers of agricultural products are some of the most productive and efficient producers of agricultural products in the world;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> continued growth and expansion of markets for United States agricultural exports is crucial to the continued development and economic well-being of rural areas of the United States and the agricultural sector of the United States economy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> in recent years, United States agricultural exports have steadily increased, surpassing $54,000,000,000 in value in 1995;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> as United States agricultural producers move toward a market-oriented system in which planting and other decisions by producers are driven by national and international market signals, developing new and expanding agricultural export markets is vital to maintaining a vibrant and healthy agricultural sector and rural economy; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> a United States agricultural export excellence award will increase United States agricultural exports by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> identifying efforts of United States entities to develop and expand markets for United States agricultural exports through the development of new products and services and through the use of innovative marketing techniques;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> recognizing achievements of those who have exhibited or supported entrepreneurial efforts to expand and create new markets for United States agricultural exports or increase the volume or value of United States agricultural exports; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> disseminating information on successful methods used to develop and expand markets for United States agricultural exports.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established the Edward R. Madigan United States Agricultural Export Excellence Award, which shall be evidenced by a medal bearing the inscription “Edward R. Madigan United States Agricultural Export Excellence Award”. The medal shall be of such design and materials and bear such additional inscriptions as the Secretary of Agriculture (referred to in this section as the “Secretary”) may prescribe.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Selection of recipient</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President or the Secretary (on the basis of recommendations received from the board established under subsection (h)) shall periodically provide the award to companies and other entities that in the judgment of the President or the Secretary substantially encourage entrepreneurial efforts in the food and agriculture sector for advancing United States agricultural exports.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Presentation of award</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The presentation of the award shall be made by the President or the Secretary with such ceremonies as the President or the Secretary considers proper.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Publication of award</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An entity to which an award is made under this section may publicize the receipt of the award by the entity and use the award in advertising of the entity.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Categories for which award may be given</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Separate awards shall be made to qualifying entities in each of the following categories:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Development of new products or services for agricultural export markets.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Development of new agricultural export markets.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Creative marketing of products or services in agricultural export markets.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Criteria for qualification</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">An entity may qualify for an award under this section only if the entity—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> applies to the board established under subsection (h) in writing for the award; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is recommended for the award by a Governor of a State;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> has exhibited significant entrepreneurial effort to create new markets for United States agricultural exports or increase United States agricultural exports; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> has provided significant assistance to others in an effort to create new markets for United States agricultural exports or increase United States agricultural exports;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> has not received another award in the same category under subsection (f) during the preceding 5-year period; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> meets such other requirements and specifications as the Secretary determines are appropriate to achieve the objectives of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Board</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Selection</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall appoint a board of evaluators, consisting of at least 5 individuals from the private sector selected for their knowledge and experience in exporting United States agricultural products.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Meetings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The board shall meet at least once annually to review and evaluate all applicants and entities recommended by States under subsection (g)(1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recommendations of board</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The board shall report its recommendations concerning the making of the award to the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Term</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Each member of the board may serve a term of not to exceed 3 years.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Funding</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may seek and accept gifts from public and private sources to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title II, § 261</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 972</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5679.</num>
<heading> Biotechnology and agricultural trade program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established in the Department the biotechnology and agricultural trade program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purpose</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purpose of the program shall be to remove, resolve, or mitigate significant regulatory nontariff barriers to the export of United States agricultural commodities (as defined in <ref>section 5602 of this title</ref>) into foreign markets through public and private sector projects funded by grants that address—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> quick response intervention regarding nontariff barriers to United States exports involving—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> United States agricultural commodities produced through biotechnology or new agricultural production technologies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> food safety;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> disease; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> other sanitary or phytosanitary concerns; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> developing protocols as part of bilateral negotiations with other countries on issues such as animal health, grain quality, and genetically modified commodities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible programs</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Depending on need, as determined by the Secretary, activities authorized under this section may be carried out through—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the emerging markets program under section 1542 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002304">1</ref> and <ref>section 5623(d) of this title</ref>; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the Cochran Fellowship Program under <ref>section 3293 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Funding</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated $2,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2019 through 2023.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XV, § 1543A</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 107–171, title III, § 3204</ref>, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 300</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title III</ref>, §§ 3201(b)(3)(C), 3301, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4617</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5680.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title III, § 3201(b)(4)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4617</ref></heading>
</section>
</part>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER V—</num>
<heading>FOREIGN AGRICULTURAL SERVICE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5691.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 103–354, title II, § 225(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3214</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5692.</num>
<heading> Administrator of Foreign Agricultural Service</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is hereby established in the Department of Agriculture the position of Administrator of the Foreign Agricultural Service.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator of the Foreign Agricultural Service is authorized to exercise such functions and perform such duties related to foreign agriculture, and shall perform such other duties, as may be required by law or prescribed by the Secretary of Agriculture.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of Service</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In carrying out the duties under this section, the Administrator shall oversee the operations of the Foreign Agricultural Service, the General Sales Manager, and the Agricultural Attaché Service.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–501, title V, § 502</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XV, § 1531</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3686</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5693.</num>
<heading> Duties of Foreign Agricultural Service</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Service shall assist the Secretary in carrying out the agricultural trade policy and international cooperation policy of the United States by—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> acquiring information pertaining to agricultural trade;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> carrying out market promotion and development activities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> providing agricultural technical assistance and training; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> carrying out the programs authorized under this chapter, the Food for Peace Act (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1691</ref> et seq.), and other Acts.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–501, title V, § 503</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XV, § 1531</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3686</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title II, § 250</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 971</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, title III, § 3001(b)(1)(A)</ref>, (2)(K), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1820</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5694.</num>
<heading> Staff of Foreign Agricultural Service</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Personnel of Service</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To ensure that the agricultural export programs of the United States are carried out in an effective manner, the authorized number of personnel for the Service shall not be less than 900 staff years each fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rank of Foreign Agricultural Service officers in foreign missions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of State shall, on the request of the Secretary of Agriculture, accord the diplomatic title of Minister-Counselor to the senior Service officer assigned to any United States mission abroad. The number of Service officers holding such diplomatic title at any time may not exceed twelve.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–501, title V, § 504</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XV, § 1531</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3686</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5695.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are hereby authorized to be appropriated for the Service such sums as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–501, title V, § 505</ref>, formerly § 506, as added <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XV, § 1531</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3687</ref>; renumbered § 505, <ref>Pub. L. 102–237, title III, § 314</ref>, <date date="1991-12-13">Dec. 13, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1856</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER VI—</num>
<heading>REPORTS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5711.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title II, § 241(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 964</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5712.</num>
<heading> Export reporting and contract sanctity</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Export sales reports</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">All exporters of wheat and wheat flour, feed grains, oil seeds, cotton, pork, beef, and products thereof, and other commodities that the Secretary may designate produced in the United States shall report to the Secretary of Agriculture, on a weekly basis, the following information regarding any contract for export sales entered into or subsequently modified in any manner during the reporting period:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> type, class, and quantity of the commodity sought to be exported;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the marketing year of shipment; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> destination, if known.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Confidentiality and compilation of reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Individual reports shall remain confidential but shall be compiled by the Secretary and published in compilation form each week following the week of reporting.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Immediate reporting</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">All exporters of agricultural commodities produced in the United States shall, upon request of the Secretary, immediately report to the Secretary any information with respect to export sales of agricultural commodities and at such times as the Secretary may request. When the Secretary requires that such information be reported by exporters on a daily basis, the information compiled from individual reports shall be made available to the public daily.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Monthly reporting permitted</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary may, with respect to any commodity or type or class thereof during any period in which the Secretary determines that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> there is a domestic supply of such commodity substantially in excess of the quantity needed to meet domestic requirements,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> total supplies of such commodity in the exporting countries are estimated to be in surplus,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> anticipated exports will not result in excessive drain on domestic supplies, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> to require the reports to be made will unduly hamper export sales,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">provide for such reports by exporters and publishing of such data to be on a monthly basis rather than on a weekly basis.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Failure to report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any person who knowingly fails to make any report required under this section shall be fined not more than $25,000 or imprisoned for not more than 1 year, or both.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contract sanctity</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the President shall not prohibit or curtail the export of any agricultural commodity under an export sales contract—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> that is entered into before the President announces an action that would otherwise prohibit or curtail the export of the commodity, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the terms of which require delivery of the commodity within 270 days after the date of the suspension of trade is imposed,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">except that the President may prohibit or curtail the export of any agricultural commodity during a period for which the President has declared a national emergency or for which the Congress has declared war.</continuation>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–501, title VI, § 602</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XV, § 1531</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3688</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–237, title III, § 327</ref>, <date date="1991-12-13">Dec. 13, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1858</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–78, title IX, § 921</ref>, <date date="1999-10-22">Oct. 22, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1206</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–239, § 2(c)</ref>, <date date="2010-09-27">Sept. 27, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2502</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5713.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 113–188, title I, § 101(d)</ref>, <date date="2014-11-26">Nov. 26, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 2017</ref></heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER VII—</num>
<heading>FOREIGN MARKET DEVELOPMENT COOPERATOR PROGRAM</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 5721 to 5723.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title III, § 3201(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4616</ref></heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>