<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 95—</num>
<heading>RURAL REVITALIZATION THROUGH FORESTRY</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>FORESTRY RURAL REVITALIZATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6601.</num>
<heading> Forestry rural revitalization</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of economic development and global marketing program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the National Institute of Food and Agriculture and the Cooperative Extension System, and in consultation with the Forest Service, shall establish and implement educational programs and provide technical assistance to assist businesses, industries, and policymakers to create jobs, raise incomes, and increase public revenues in manners consistent with environmental concerns.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Activities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each program established under subsection (a) shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> transfer technologies to natural resource-based industries in the United States to make such industries more efficient, productive, and competitive;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> assist businesses to identify global marketing opportunities, conduct business on an international basis, and market themselves more effectively; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> train local leaders in strategic community economic development.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Types of programs</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture shall establish specific programs under subsection (a) to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> deliver educational services focused on community economic analysis, economic diversification, economic impact analysis, retention and expansion of existing commodity and noncommodity industries, amenity resource and tourism development, and entrepreneurship focusing on forest lands and rural communities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> use Cooperative Extension System databases and analytical tools to help communities diversify their economic bases, add value locally to raw forest product materials, and retain revenues by helping to develop local businesses and industries to supply forest products locally; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> use the full resources of the Cooperative Extension System, including land-grant universities and county offices, to promote economic development that is sustainable and environmentally sound.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rural revitalization technologies</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Chief of the Forest Service, in consultation with the State and Private Forestry Technology Marketing Unit at the Forest Products Laboratory, and in collaboration with eligible institutions, may carry out a program—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to accelerate adoption of technologies using biomass and small-diameter materials;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to create community-based enterprises through marketing activities and demonstration projects; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to establish small-scale business enterprises to make use of biomass and small-diameter materials.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this subsection $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2008 through 2023.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XXIII, § 2371</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4045</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–148, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="2003-12-03">Dec. 3, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1902</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title VII, § 7511(c)(25)</ref>, title VIII, § 8201, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1269</ref>, 1290; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title VII, § 7511(c)(25), title VIII, § 8201, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2031, 2051; <ref>Pub. L. 113–79, title VIII, § 8201</ref>, <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 914</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title VIII, § 8701</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4875</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>NATIONAL FOREST-DEPENDENT RURAL COMMUNITIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6611.</num>
<heading> Findings and purposes</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the economic well-being of rural America is vital to our national growth and prosperity;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the economic well-being of many rural communities depends upon the goods and services that are derived from National Forest System land;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the economies of many of these communities suffer from a lack of industrial and business diversity;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> this lack of diversity is particularly serious in communities whose economies are predominantly dependent on timber and recreation resources and where management decisions made on National Forest System land by Federal and private organizations may disrupt the supply of those resources;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the Forest Service has expertise and resources that could be directed to promote modernization and economic diversification of existing industries and services based on natural resources;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the Forest Service has the technical expertise to provide leadership, in cooperation with other governmental agencies and the private sector, to assist rural communities dependent upon National Forest System land resources to upgrade existing industries and diversify by developing new economic activity in non-forest-related industries; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> technical assistance, training, education, and other assistance provided by the Department of Agriculture can be targeted to provide immediate help to those rural communities in greatest need.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes of this subchapter are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to provide assistance to rural communities that are located in or near National Forest System land and that are economically dependent upon natural resources or are likely to be economically disadvantaged by Federal or private sector land management practices;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to aid in diversifying such communities’ economic bases; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to improve the economic, social, and environmental well-being of rural America.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XXIII, § 2373</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4046</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(3) [title III, § 345(a)]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1535</ref>, 1501A–203.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6612.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this subchapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “action team” means a rural natural resources and economic diversification action team established by the Secretary pursuant to <ref>section 6613(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “economically disadvantaged” means economic hardship due to the loss of jobs or income (labor or proprietor) derived from forestry, the wood products industry, or related commercial enterprises such as recreation and tourism in the national forest.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The term “rural community” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any town, township, municipality, or other similar unit of general purpose local government, or any area represented by a not-for-profit corporation or institution organized under State or Federal law to promote broad based economic development, or unit of general purpose local government, as approved by the Secretary, that has a population of not more than 10,000 individuals, is located within a county in which at least 15 percent of the total primary and secondary labor and proprietor income is derived from forestry, wood products, and forest-related industries such as recreation, forage production, and tourism and that is located within the boundary, or within 100 miles of the boundary, of a national forest; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any county that is not contained within a Metropolitan Statistical Area as defined by the United States Office of Management and Budget, in which at least 15 percent of the total primary and secondary labor and proprietor income is derived from forestry, wood products, and forest-related industries such as recreation, forage production, and tourism and that is located within the boundary, or within 100 miles of the boundary, of a national forest.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Agriculture.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XXIII, § 2374</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4046</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–115</ref>, <date date="1993-10-26">Oct. 26, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1117</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(3) [title III, § 345(b)]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1535</ref>, 1501A–203.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6613.</num>
<heading> Rural natural resources and economic diversification action teams</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requests for assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Economically disadvantaged rural communities may request assistance from the Secretary in identifying opportunities that will promote economic improvement and diversification and revitalization.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon request, the Secretary may establish rural natural resources and economic diversification action teams to prepare an action plan to provide technical assistance to economically disadvantaged communities. The action plan shall identify opportunities to promote economic diversification and enhance local economies now dependent upon National Forest System land resources. The action team may also identify opportunities to use value-added products and services derived from National Forest System land resources.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Organization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall design and organize any action team established pursuant to subsection (b) to meet the unique needs of the requesting rural community. Each action team shall be directed by an employee of the Forest Service and may include personnel from other agencies within the Department of Agriculture, from other Federal and State departments and agencies, and from the private sector.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cooperation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In preparing action plans, the Secretary may cooperate with State and local governments, universities, private companies, individuals, and nonprofit organizations for procurement of services determined necessary or desirable.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall ensure that no substantially similar geographical or defined local area in a State receives a grant for technical assistance to an economically disadvantaged community under this subchapter and a grant for assistance under a designated rural development program during any continuous five-year period.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Approval</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">After reviewing requests under this section for financial and economic feasibility and viability, the Secretary shall approve and implement in accordance with <ref>section 6614 of this title</ref> those action plans that will achieve the purposes of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> “Designated rural development program” defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this section, the term “designated rural development program” means a program carried out under section 1924(b), 1926(a), or 1932(e) of this title for which funds are available at any time during the fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XXIII, § 2375</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4047</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title VII, § 753(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1131</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(3) [title III, § 345(c)]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1535</ref>, 1501A–204.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6614.</num>
<heading> Action plan implementation</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Action plans shall be implemented, insofar as practicable, to upgrade existing industries to use natural resources more efficiently and to expand the economic base of rural communities so as to alleviate or reduce their dependence on National Forest System land resources.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To implement action plans, the Secretary may make grants and enter into cooperative agreements and contracts to provide necessary technical and related assistance. Such grants, cooperative agreements, and contracts may be with the affected rural community, State and local governments, universities, corporations, and other persons.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Federal contribution to the overall implementation of an action plan shall not exceed 80 percent of the total cost of the plan, including administrative and other costs. In calculating the Federal contribution, the Secretary shall take into account the fair market value of equipment, personnel, and services provided.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Available authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may use the Secretary’s authority under the Cooperative Forestry Assistance Act of 1978 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 2101</ref> et seq.) and other Federal, State, and local governmental authorities in implementing action plans.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consistency with forest plans</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The implementation of action plans shall be consistent with land and resource management plans.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XXIII, § 2376</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4048</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(3) [title III, § 345(d)]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1535</ref>, 1501A–204.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6615.</num>
<heading> Training and education</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Programs</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In furtherance of an action plan, the Secretary may use the National Institute of Food and Agriculture and other appropriate agencies of the Department of Agriculture to develop and conduct education programs that assist businesses, elected or appointed officials, and individuals in rural communities to deal with the effects of a transition from being economically disadvantaged to economic diversification. These programs may include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> community economic analysis and strategic planning;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> methods for improving and retooling enterprises now dependent on National Forest System land resources;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> methods for expanding enterprises and creating new economic opportunities by emphasizing economic opportunities in other industries or services not dependent on National Forest System land resources; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> assistance in the evaluation, counseling, and enhancement of vocational skills, training in basic and remedial literacy skills, assistance in job seeking skills, and training in starting or operating a business enterprise.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Existing educational and training programs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Insofar as practicable, the Secretary shall use existing Federal, State, and private education resources in carrying out these programs.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XXIII, § 2377</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4048</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(3) [title III, § 345(e)]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1535</ref>, 1501A–204; <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title VII, § 7511(c)(26)</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1270</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title VII, § 7511(c)(26), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2031.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6616.</num>
<heading> Loans to economically disadvantaged rural communities</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary, under such terms and conditions as the Secretary shall establish, may make loans to economically disadvantaged rural communities for the purposes of securing technical assistance and services to aid in the development and implementation of action plans, including planning for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> improving existing facilities in the community that may generate employment or revenue;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> expanding existing infrastructure, facilities, and services to capitalize on opportunities to diversify economies now dependent on National Forest System land resources; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> supporting the development of new industries or commercial ventures unrelated to National Forest System land resources.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interest rates</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The interest rates on a loan made pursuant to this section shall be as determined by the Secretary, but not in excess of the current average market yield on outstanding marketable obligations of the United States with remaining periods to maturity comparable to the maturity of such loan, plus not to exceed 1 percent, as determined by the Secretary, and rounded to the nearest one-eighth of 1 percent.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XXIII, § 2378</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4048</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(3) [title III, § 345(f)]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1535</ref>, 1501A–204.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6617.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations and spending authority</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except as provided in subsection (b), there are authorized to be appropriated—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> an amount not to exceed 5 percent of the sum of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the sums received by the Secretary from sales of timber and other products of the forests; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> user fees paid in connection with the use of forest lands; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> such additional sums as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on authorization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subsection (a) shall not in any way affect payments to the States pursuant to <ref>section 500 of title 16</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Spending authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any spending authority (as defined in <ref>section 651 of title 2</ref>) provided in this subchapter shall be effective for any fiscal year only to such extent or in such amounts as are provided in appropriation Acts.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XXIII, § 2379</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4049</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>