<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 13—</num>
<heading>AGRICULTURAL AND MECHANICAL COLLEGES</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>COLLEGE-AID LAND APPROPRIATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 301.</num>
<heading> Land grant aid of colleges</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is granted to the several States, for the purposes hereinafter mentioned in this subchapter, an amount of public land, to be apportioned to each State a quantity equal to thirty thousand acres for each Senator and Representative in Congress to which the States are respectively entitled by the apportionment under the census of 1860: <i>Provided</i>, That no mineral lands shall be selected or purchased under the provisions of said sections.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 2, 1862, ch. 130, § 1</ref>, <ref>12 Stat. 503</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 302.</num>
<heading> Method of apportionment and selection; issuance of land scrip</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The land aforesaid, after being surveyed, shall be apportioned to the several States in sections or subdivisions of sections, not less than one-quarter of a section; and whenever there are public lands in a State subject to sale at private entry at $1.25 per acre, the quantity to which said State shall be entitled shall be selected from such lands within the limits of such State, and the Secretary of the Interior is directed to issue to each of the States in which there is not the quantity of public lands subject to sale at private entry at $1.25 per acre, to which said State may be entitled under the provisions of this subchapter, land scrip to the amount in acres for the deficiency of its distributive share; said scrip to be sold by said States and the proceeds thereof applied to the uses and purposes prescribed in said sections, and for no other use or purpose whatsoever: <i>Provided</i>, That in no case shall any State to which land scrip may thus be issued be allowed to locate the same within the limits of any other State, or of any Territory of the United States, but their assignees may thus locate said land scrip upon any of the unappropriated lands of the United States subject to sale at private entry at $1.25, or less, per acre: <i>And provided further</i>, That not more than one million acres shall be located by such assignees in any one of the States: <i>And provided further</i>, That no such location shall be made before <date date="1863-07-02">July 2, 1863</date>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 2, 1862, ch. 130, § 2</ref>, <ref>12 Stat. 503</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 303.</num>
<heading> Management expenses paid by State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All the expenses of management, superintendence, and taxes from date of selection of said lands, previous to their sales, and all expenses incurred in the management and disbursement of the moneys which may be received therefrom, shall be paid by the States to which they may belong, out of the treasury of said States, so that the entire proceeds of the sale of said lands shall be applied without any diminution whatever to the purposes in sections 304, 305, 307 and 308 of this title mentioned.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 2, 1862, ch. 130, § 3</ref>, <ref>12 Stat. 504</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 304.</num>
<heading> Investment of proceeds of sale of land or scrip</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All moneys derived from the sale of lands as provided in <ref>section 302 of this title</ref> by the States to which lands are apportioned and from the sales of land scrip provided for in said section shall be invested in bonds of the United States or of the States or some other safe bonds; or the same may be invested by the States having no State bonds, in any manner after the legislatures of such States shall have assented thereto and engaged that such funds shall yield a fair and reasonable rate of return, to be fixed by the State legislatures, and that the principal thereof shall forever remain unimpaired: <i>Provided</i>, That the moneys so invested or loaned shall constitute a perpetual fund, the capital of which shall remain forever undiminished (except so far as may be provided in <ref>section 305 of this title</ref>), and the interest of which shall be inviolably appropriated, by each State which may take and claim the benefit of this subchapter, to the endowment, support, and maintenance of at least one college where the leading object shall be, without excluding other scientific and classical studies and including military tactics, to teach such branches of learning as are related to agriculture and the mechanic arts, in such manner as the legislatures of the States may respectively prescribe, in order to promote the liberal and practical education of the industrial classes in the several pursuits and professions in life.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 2, 1862, ch. 130, § 4</ref>, <ref>12 Stat. 504</ref>; <ref>Mar. 3, 1883, ch. 102</ref>, <ref>22 Stat. 484</ref>; <ref>Apr. 13, 1926, ch. 130</ref>, <ref>44 Stat. 247</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 305.</num>
<heading> Conditions of grant</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The grant of land and land scrip hereby authorized shall be made on the following conditions, to which, as well as to the provisions contained in said sections, the previous assent of the several States shall be signified by legislative acts:</p>
<p class="indent0">First. If any portion of the fund invested, as provided by <ref>section 304 of this title</ref>, or any portion of the interest thereon, shall, by any action or contingency, be diminished or lost, it shall be replaced by the State to which it belongs, so that the capital of the fund shall remain forever undiminished; and the annual interest shall be regularly applied without diminution to the purposes mentioned in <ref>section 304 of this title</ref>, except that a sum, not exceeding 10 per centum upon the amount received by any State under the provisions of this subchapter, may be expended for the purchase of lands for sites or experimental farms, whenever authorized by the respective legislatures of said States.</p>
<p class="indent0">Second. No portion of said fund, nor the interest thereon, shall be applied, directly or indirectly, under any pretense whatever, to the purchase, erection, preservation, or repair of any building or buildings.</p>
<p class="indent0">Third. Any State which may take and claim the benefit of the provisions of this subchapter shall provide, within five years from the time of its acceptance as provided in subdivision seven of this section, at least not less than one college, as described in <ref>section 304 of this title</ref>, or the grant to such State shall cease; and said State shall be bound to pay the United States the amount received of any lands previously sold, and the title to purchasers under the State shall be valid.</p>
<p class="indent0">Fourth. An annual report shall be made regarding the progress of each college, recording any improvements and experiments made, with their cost and results, and such other matters, including State industrial and economical statistics, as may be supposed useful; one copy of which shall be transmitted by mail, by each, to all the other colleges which may be endowed under the provisions of this subchapter, and also one copy to the Secretary of the Interior.</p>
<p class="indent0">Fifth. When lands shall be selected from those which have been raised to double the minimum price, in consequence of railroad grants, they shall be computed to the States at the maximum price, and the number of acres proportionally diminished.</p>
<p class="indent0">Sixth. No State while in a condition of rebellion or insurrection against the Government of the United States shall be entitled to the benefit of the provisions of this subchapter.</p>
<p class="indent0">Seventh. No State shall be entitled to the benefits of the provisions of this subchapter unless it shall express its acceptance thereof by its legislature within three years from <date date="1866-07-23">July 23, 1866</date>: <i>Provided</i>, That when any Territory shall become a State and be admitted into the Union, such new State shall be entitled to the benefits of the provisions of said sections, by expressing the acceptance therein required within three years from the date of its admission into the Union, and providing the college or colleges within five years after such acceptance, as heretofore prescribed in this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 2, 1862, ch. 130, § 5</ref>, <ref>12 Stat. 504</ref>; <ref>July 23, 1866, ch. 209</ref>, <ref>14 Stat. 208</ref>; <ref>Mar. 3, 1873, ch. 231, § 3</ref>, <ref>17 Stat. 559</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 306.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Dec. 16, 1930, ch. 14, § 1</ref>, <ref>46 Stat. 1028</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 307.</num>
<heading> Fees for locating land scrip</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The land officers shall receive the same fees for locating land scrip issued under the provisions of this subchapter as was on <date date="1862-07-02">July 2, 1862</date>, allowed for the location of military bounty land warrants under laws existing at that time: <i>Provided</i>, That their maximum compensation shall not be thereby increased.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 2, 1862, ch. 130, § 7</ref>, <ref>12 Stat. 505</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 308.</num>
<heading> Reports by State governors of sale of scrip</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The governors of the several States to which scrip shall be issued under the provisions of this subchapter shall be required to report annually to Congress all sales made of such scrip until the whole shall be disposed of, the amount received for the same, and what appropriation has been made of the proceeds.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 2, 1862, ch. 130, § 8</ref>, <ref>12 Stat. 505</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 309.</num>
<heading> Land grants in the State of North Dakota</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding <ref>section 303 of this title</ref>, the State of North Dakota shall manage the land granted to the State under <ref>section 301 of this title</ref>, including any proceeds from the land, in accordance with this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disposition of proceeds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Notwithstanding <ref>section 304 of this title</ref>, the State of North Dakota shall, with respect to any trust fund in which proceeds from the sale of land under this subchapter are deposited (referred to in this section as the “trust fund”)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> deposit all revenues earned by a trust fund into the trust fund;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> deduct the costs of administering a trust fund from each trust fund; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> manage each trust fund to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> preserve the purchasing power of the trust fund; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> maintain stable distributions to trust fund beneficiaries.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Distributions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding <ref>section 304 of this title</ref>, any distributions from trust funds in the State of North Dakota shall be made in accordance with section 2 of article IX of the Constitution of the State of North Dakota.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Management</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding <ref>section 305 of this title</ref>, the State of North Dakota shall manage the land granted under <ref>section 301 of this title</ref>, including any proceeds from the land, in accordance with this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 2, 1862, ch. 130, § 9</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 111–11, title XIII, § 13001(b)</ref>, <date date="2009-03-30">Mar. 30, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1446</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>COLLEGE-AID ANNUAL APPROPRIATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 321.</num>
<heading> Secretary of Agriculture to administer annual college-aid appropriation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture is charged with the proper administration of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 30, 1890, ch. 841, § 4</ref>, <ref>26 Stat. 419</ref>; 1939 Reorg. Plan No. 1, §§ 201, 204, eff. <date date="1939-07-01">July 1, 1939</date>, 4 F.R. 2728, <ref>53 Stat. 1424</ref>; 1953 Reorg. Plan No. 1, §§ 5, 8, eff. <date date="1953-04-11">Apr. 11, 1953</date>, 18 F.R. 2053, <ref>67 Stat. 631</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title III, § 301(a)(2)(E)</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 677</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–98, title XIV, § 1419</ref>, <date date="1981-12-22">Dec. 22, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1306</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 322.</num>
<heading> Annual appropriation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is annually appropriated, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, to be paid as provided in <ref>section 324 of this title</ref>, to each State and Territory for the more complete endowment and maintenance of colleges for the benefit of agriculture and the mechanic arts established in accordance with the provisions of subchapter I of this chapter, $50,000 to be applied only to instruction in food and agricultural sciences, and to the facilities for such instruction: <i>Provided</i>, That said colleges may use a portion of this money for providing courses for the special preparation of instructors for teaching the elements of food and agricultural sciences.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 30, 1890, ch. 841, § 1</ref>, <ref>26 Stat. 417</ref>; <ref>Mar. 4, 1907, ch. 2907</ref>, <ref>34 Stat. 1281</ref>, 1282; <ref>Pub. L. 97–98, title XIV, § 1421</ref>, <date date="1981-12-22">Dec. 22, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1306</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 323.</num>
<heading> Racial discrimination by colleges restricted</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No money shall be paid out under this subchapter to any State or Territory for the support or maintenance of a college where a distinction of race or color is made in the admission of students, but the establishment and maintenance of such colleges separately for white and colored students shall be held to be a compliance with the provisions of said sections if the funds received in such State or Territory be equitably divided as hereinafter set forth: <i>Provided</i>, That in any State in which there has been one college established in pursuance of subchapter I of this chapter, and also in which an educational institution of like character has been established, or may be hereafter established, and is on <date date="1890-08-30">August 30, 1890</date>, aided by such State from its own revenue, for the education of colored students in agriculture and the mechanic arts, however named or styled, or whether or not it has received money prior to <date date="1890-08-30">August 30, 1890</date>, under said subchapter I, the legislature of such State may propose and report to the Secretary of Agriculture a just and equitable division of the fund to be received under this subchapter between one college for white students and one institution for colored students established as aforesaid, which shall be divided into two parts and paid accordingly, and thereupon such institution for colored students shall be entitled to the benefits of said sections and subject to their provisions, as much as it would have been if it had been included under subchapter I of this chapter, and the fulfillment of the foregoing provisions shall be taken as a compliance with the provision in reference to separate colleges for white and colored students.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 30, 1890, ch. 841, § 1</ref>, <ref>26 Stat. 417</ref>; 1939 Reorg. Plan No. 1, §§ 201, 204, eff. <date date="1939-07-01">July 1, 1939</date>, 4 F.R. 2728, <ref>53 Stat. 1424</ref>; 1953 Reorg. Plan No. 1, §§ 5, 8, eff. <date date="1953-04-11">Apr. 11, 1953</date>, 18 F.R. 2053, <ref>67 Stat. 631</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title III, § 301(a)(2)(E)</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 677</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–98, title XIV, § 1419</ref>, <date date="1981-12-22">Dec. 22, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1306</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 324.</num>
<heading> Time, manner, etc., of annual payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The sums appropriated by this subchapter to the States and Territories for the further endowment and support of colleges shall be annually paid on or before the 31st day of October of each year, by the Secretary of the Treasury, upon the warrant of the Secretary of Agriculture, out of the Treasury of the United States, to the State or Territorial treasurer, or to such officer as shall be designated by the laws of such State or Territory to receive the same, who shall, upon the order of the trustees of the college, or the institution for colored students, immediately pay over said sums to the treasurers of the respective colleges or other institutions entitled to receive the same, and such treasurers shall be required to report to the Secretary of Agriculture, on or before the 1st day of December of each year, a detailed statement of the amount so received and of its disbursement. The grants of moneys authorized by this subchapter are made subject to the legislative assent of the several States and Territories to the purpose of said grants.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 30, 1890, ch. 841, § 2</ref>, <ref>26 Stat. 418</ref>; 1939 Reorg. Plan No. I, §§ 201, 204, eff. <date date="1939-07-01">July 1, 1939</date>, 4 F.R. 2728, <ref>53 Stat. 1424</ref>; 1953 Reorg. Plan No. 1, §§ 5, 8, eff. <date date="1953-04-11">Apr. 11, 1953</date>, 18 F.R. 2053, <ref>67 Stat. 631</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–273, § 9(1)</ref>, <date date="1976-04-21">Apr. 21, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 378</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title III, § 301(a)(2)(E)</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 677</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–98, title XIV, § 1419</ref>, <date date="1981-12-22">Dec. 22, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1306</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 325.</num>
<heading> State to replace funds misapplied, etc.; restrictions on use of funds; reports by colleges</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If any portion of the moneys received by the designated officer of the State or Territory for the further and more complete endowment, support, and maintenance of colleges, or of institutions for colored students, as provided in this subchapter, shall, by any action or contingency, be diminished or lost, or be misapplied, it shall be replaced by the State or Territory to which it belongs, and until so replaced no subsequent appropriation shall be apportioned or paid to such State or Territory; and no portion of said moneys shall be applied, directly or indirectly, under any pretense whatever, to the purchase, erection, preservation, or repair of any building or buildings. An annual report by the president of each of said colleges shall be made to the Secretary of Agriculture, regarding the condition and progress of each college, including statistical information in relation to its receipts and expenditures, its library, the number of its students and professors, and also as to any improvements and experiments made under the direction of any experiment stations attached to said colleges, with their cost and results, and such other industrial and economical statistics as may be regarded as useful, one copy of which shall be transmitted by mail free to all other colleges further endowed under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 30, 1890, ch. 841, § 3</ref>, <ref>26 Stat. 418</ref>; 1939 Reorg. Plan No. I, §§ 201, 204, eff. <date date="1939-07-01">July 1, 1939</date>, 4 F.R. 2728, <ref>53 Stat. 1424</ref>; 1953 Reorg. Plan No. 1, §§ 5, 8, eff. <date date="1953-04-11">Apr. 11, 1953</date>, 18 F.R. 2053, <ref>67 Stat. 631</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title III, § 301(a)(2)(E)</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 677</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–98, title XIV, § 1419</ref>, <date date="1981-12-22">Dec. 22, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1306</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 326.</num>
<heading> Ascertainment and certification of amounts due States; certificates withheld from States; appeal to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On or before the 1st day of October in each year, the Secretary of Agriculture shall ascertain and certify to the Secretary of the Treasury as to each State and Territory whether it is entitled to receive its share of the annual appropriation for colleges, or of institutions for colored students, under this subchapter, and the amount which thereupon each is entitled, respectively, to receive. If the Secretary of Agriculture shall withhold a certificate from any State or Territory of its appropriation the facts and reasons therefor shall be reported to the President, and the amount involved shall be kept separate in the Treasury until the close of the next Congress, in order that the State or Territory may, if it should so desire, appeal to Congress from the determination of the Secretary of Agriculture. If the next Congress shall not direct such sum to be paid it shall be covered into the Treasury.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 30, 1890, ch. 841, § 4</ref>, <ref>26 Stat. 419</ref>; 1939 Reorg. Plan No. I, §§ 201, 204, eff. <date date="1939-07-01">July 1, 1939</date>, 4 F.R. 2728, <ref>53 Stat. 1424</ref>; 1953 Reorg. Plan No. 1, §§ 5, 8, eff. <date date="1953-04-11">Apr. 11, 1953</date>, 18 F.R. 2053, <ref>67 Stat. 631</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–273, § 3(1)</ref>, <date date="1976-04-21">Apr. 21, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 376</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title III, § 301(a)(2)(E)</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 677</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–97, title XIV, § 1419</ref>, <date date="1981-12-22">Dec. 22, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1306</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 326a.</num>
<heading> Annual appropriations for Puerto Rico, Virgin Islands, American Samoa, Guam, Northern Mariana Islands, Federated States of Micronesia, Republic of the Marshall Islands, and Republic of Palau</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is appropriated annually, out of funds in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, for payment to the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands of the United States, Guam, American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, the Federated States of Micronesia, the Republic of the Marshall Islands, and the Republic of Palau the amount they would be entitled to receive under this subchapter if they were States. Sums appropriated under this section shall be treated in the same manner and be subject to the same provisions of law, as would be the case if they had been appropriated by the first sentence of <ref>section 322 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 30, 1890, ch. 841, § 5</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 92–318, title V, § 506(c)</ref>, <date date="1972-06-23">June 23, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 350</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 96–374, title XIII, § 1361(b)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-03">Oct. 3, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1502</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–396, § 9(b)</ref>, <date date="1986-08-27">Aug. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 840</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–339, § 2</ref>, <date date="1988-06-17">June 17, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 620</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title III, § 352</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3966</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 327.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>May 29, 1928, ch. 901, § 1(74)</ref>, <ref>45 Stat. 991</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 328.</num>
<heading> Power to amend, repeal, etc., reserved</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Congress may at any time amend, suspend, or repeal any or all of the provisions of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 30, 1890, ch. 841, § 6</ref>, <ref>26 Stat. 419</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 329.</num>
<heading> Additional appropriation for agricultural colleges</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In order to provide for the more complete endowment and support of the colleges in the several States, Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, and the Northern Mariana Islands entitled to the benefits of the Act entitled “An Act donating public lands to the several States and Territories which may provide colleges for the benefit of agriculture and the mechanic arts,” approved <date date="1862-07-02">July 2, 1862</date>, as amended and supplemented (<ref>7 U.S.C. 301–328</ref>), there are authorized to be appropriated annually, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, the following amounts:</chapeau>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> For the first fiscal year beginning after the date of enactment of this Act, and for each fiscal year thereafter, $8,250,000; and</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> For the first fiscal year beginning after the date of enactment of this Act, and for each fiscal year thereafter, $4,380,000.<p class="indent0">The sums appropriated in pursuance of paragraph (a) shall be paid annually to the several States, Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, and the Northern Mariana Islands in equal shares. The sums appropriated in pursuance of paragraph (b) shall be in addition to sums appropriated in pursuance of paragraph (a) and shall be allotted and paid annually to each of the several States, Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, and the Northern Mariana Islands in the proportion to which the total population of each State, Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, and the Northern Mariana Islands bears to the total population of all the States, Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, and the Northern Mariana Islands as determined by the last preceding decennial census. Sums appropriated in pursuance of this section shall be in addition to sums appropriated or authorized under such Act of <date date="1862-07-02">July 2, 1862</date>, as amended and supplemented, and shall be applied only for the purposes of the colleges defined in such Act, as amended and supplemented. The provisions of law applicable to the use and payment of sums under the Act entitled “An Act to apply a portion of the proceeds of the public lands to the more complete endowment and support of the colleges for the benefit of agriculture and the mechanic arts established under the provisions of an Act of Congress approved <date date="1862-07-02">July 2, 1862</date>,” approved <date date="1890-08-30">August 30, 1890</date>, as amended and supplemented, shall apply to the use and payment of sums appropriated in pursuance of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 29, 1935, ch. 338</ref>, title II, § 22, <ref>49 Stat. 439</ref>; <ref>June 12, 1952, ch. 419</ref>, §§ 1–4, <ref>66 Stat. 135</ref>, 136; <ref>Pub. L. 86–658</ref>, <date date="1960-07-14">July 14, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 525</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–791, title I, § 108(a)</ref>, <date date="1966-11-07">Nov. 7, 1966</date>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 90–354, § 1</ref>, <date date="1968-06-20">June 20, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 241</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–318, title V, § 506(d)</ref>, <date date="1972-06-23">June 23, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 350</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–396, § 9(d)</ref>, <date date="1986-08-27">Aug. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 840</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>RETIREMENT OF EMPLOYEES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 331.</num>
<heading> Retirement of land-grant college employees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Pursuant to the recognized obligations of governments to guarantee the social security of their employees and in order to provide for the retirement on an annuity, or otherwise, of all persons being paid salaries in whole or in part from grants of Federal funds to the several States, Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, and Guam pursuant to the terms of the Act approved <date date="1862-07-02">July 2, 1862</date>, for the endowment and support of colleges of agriculture and mechanic arts [<ref>7 U.S.C. 301</ref> et seq.], and Acts supplementary thereto providing for instruction in agriculture and mechanic arts, for the establishment of agricultural experiment stations, and for cooperative extension work in agriculture and home economics, all States, Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, and Guam are after <date date="1940-03-04">March 4, 1940</date>, authorized, notwithstanding any contrary provisions in said Acts, to withhold from expenditure, from Federal funds advanced under the terms of said Acts, amounts designated as employer contributions to be made by the States, Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, or Guam to retirement systems established in accordance with the laws of such States, Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, or Guam, or established by the governing boards of colleges of agriculture and mechanic arts in accordance with the authority vested in them, and to deposit such amounts to the credit of such retirement systems for subsequent disbursement in accordance with the terms of the retirement systems in effect in the respective States, Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, and Guam: <i>Provided</i>, That there shall not be deducted from Federal funds and deposited to the credit of retirement accounts as employer contributions, amounts in excess of 5 per centum of that portion of the salaries of employees paid from such Federal funds: <i>Provided further</i>, That, for the purpose of making deposits and contributions in retirement systems in favor of any employee, in no event shall the deductions from any Federal fund advanced pursuant to the foregoing Acts be in greater proportion to the total deductions for such employee than the salary received under such Federal funds bears to the total salary from Federal sources: <i>Provided further</i>, That the deposits and contributions from funds of Federal origin to any retirement system established by a State, Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, or Guam or a land-grant college must be at least equaled by the total contributions thereto on the part of the individuals concerned, the State, Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, or Guam, and the counties: <i>And provided further</i>, That no deductions for the foregoing purposes shall be made from Federal funds in support of employees appointed pursuant to the terms of the foregoing Acts, whose salaries are paid wholly by the States, Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, or Guam: <i>Provided further</i>, That the provisions of this section shall not apply to any employee paid in whole or in part from Federal funds who may be subject to subchapter III of chapter 83 of title 5.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 4, 1940, ch. 38</ref>, <ref>54 Stat. 39</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–318, title V, § 506(e)</ref>, <date date="1972-06-23">June 23, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 351</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>AGRICULTURAL EXTENSION WORK APPROPRIATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 341.</num>
<heading> Cooperative extension work by colleges</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In order to aid in diffusing among the people of the United States useful and practical information on subjects relating to agriculture, uses of solar energy with respect to agriculture, home economics, and rural energy, and to encourage the application of the same, there may be continued or inaugurated in connection with the college or colleges in each State, Territory, or possession, now receiving, or which may hereafter receive, the benefits of subchapters I and II of this chapter, agricultural extension work which shall be carried on in cooperation with the United States Department of Agriculture: <i>Provided</i>, That in any State, Territory, or possession in which two or more such colleges have been or hereafter may be established, the appropriations hereinafter made to such State, Territory, or possession shall be administered by such college or colleges as the legislature of such State, Territory, or possession may direct. For the purposes of this subchapter, the term “solar energy” means energy derived from sources (other than fossil fuels) and technologies included in the Federal Non-Nuclear <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002086">1</ref> Energy Research and Development Act of 1974, as amended [<ref>42 U.S.C. 5901</ref> et seq.].</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 8, 1914, ch. 79, § 1</ref>, <ref>38 Stat. 372</ref>; <ref>June 26, 1953, ch. 157, § 1</ref>, <ref>67 Stat. 83</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–113, title XIV, § 1447(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="1977-09-29">Sept. 29, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 1011</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–294, title II, § 256(1)</ref>, <date date="1980-06-30">June 30, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 708</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 342.</num>
<heading> Cooperative agricultural extension work; cooperation with Secretary of Agriculture</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Cooperative agricultural extension work shall consist of the development of practical applications of research knowledge and giving of instruction and practical demonstrations of existing or improved practices or technologies in agriculture, uses of solar energy with respect to agriculture, home economics, and rural energy and subjects relating thereto to persons not attending or resident in said colleges in the several communities, and imparting information on said subjects through demonstrations, publications, and otherwise and for the necessary printing and distribution of information in connection with the foregoing; and this work shall be carried on in such manner as may be mutually agreed upon by the Secretary of Agriculture and the State agricultural college or colleges or Territory or possession receiving the benefits of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 8, 1914, ch. 79, § 2</ref>, <ref>38 Stat. 373</ref>; <ref>June 26, 1953, ch. 157, § 1</ref>, <ref>67 Stat. 84</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–749, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1962-10-05">Oct. 5, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 745</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–113, title XIV, § 1447(3)</ref>, <date date="1977-09-29">Sept. 29, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 1011</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–294, title II, § 256(2)</ref>, <date date="1980-06-30">June 30, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 708</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–198, title XIV, § 1435(a)</ref>, <date date="1985-12-23">Dec. 23, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 1557</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 343.</num>
<heading> Appropriations; distribution; allotment and apportionment; Secretary of Agriculture; matching funds; cooperative extension activities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> There are authorized to be appropriated for the purposes of this subchapter such sums as Congress may from time to time determine to be necessary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Out of such sums, each State and the Secretary of Agriculture shall be entitled to receive annually a sum of money equal to the sums available from Federal cooperative extension funds for the fiscal year 1962, and subject to the same requirements as to furnishing of equivalent sums by the State, except that amounts heretofore made available to the Secretary for allotment on the basis of special needs shall continue available for use on the same basis.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> There is authorized to be appropriated for the fiscal year ending <date date="1971-06-30">June 30, 1971</date>, and for each fiscal year thereafter, for payment to the Virgin Islands, Guam, and the Northern Mariana Islands, $100,000 each, which sums shall be in addition to the sums appropriated for the several States of the United States and Puerto Rico under the provisions of this section. The amount paid by the Federal Government to the Virgin Islands and Guam pursuant to this paragraph shall not exceed during any fiscal year, except the fiscal years ending <date date="1971-06-30">June 30, 1971</date>, and <date date="1972-06-30">June 30, 1972</date>, when such amount may be used to pay the total cost of providing services pursuant to this subchapter, the amount available and budgeted for expenditure by the Virgin Islands and Guam for the purposes of this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> There are authorized to be appropriated for the fiscal year ending <date date="1996-06-30">June 30, 1996</date>, and for each fiscal year thereafter, for payment on behalf of the 1994 Institutions (as defined in section 532 of the Equity in Educational Land-Grant Status Act of 1994), such sums as are necessary for the purposes set forth in <ref>section 342 of this title</ref>. The balance of any annual funds provided under the preceding sentence for a fiscal year that remains unexpended at the end of that fiscal year shall remain available without fiscal year limitation. Such sums shall be in addition to the sums appropriated for the several States and Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, and Guam under the provisions of this section. Such sums shall be distributed on the basis of a competitive application process to be developed and implemented by the Secretary and paid by the Secretary to 1994 Institutions (in accordance with regulations that the Secretary may promulgate) and may be administered by the 1994 Institutions through cooperative agreements with colleges and universities eligible to receive funds under subchapters I and II of this chapter, including Tuskegee University, located in any State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Annual appropriation for hispanic-serving agricultural colleges and universities.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authorization of appropriations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary for payments to Hispanic-serving agricultural colleges and universities (as defined in <ref>section 3103 of this title</ref>) such sums as are necessary to carry out this paragraph for fiscal year 2008 and each fiscal year thereafter, to remain available until expended.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Additional amount</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Amounts made available under this paragraph shall be in addition to any other amounts made available under this section to States, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, or the United States Virgin Islands.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Administration</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Amounts made available under this paragraph shall be—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> distributed on the basis of a competitive application process to be developed and implemented by the Secretary;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> paid by the Secretary to the State institutions established in accordance with the Act of <date date="1862-07-02">July 2, 1862</date> (commonly known as the “First Morrill Act”) (<ref>7 U.S.C. 301</ref> et seq.); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> administered by State institutions through cooperative agreements with the Hispanic-serving agricultural colleges and universities in the State in accordance with regulations promulgated by the Secretary.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> Any sums made available by the Congress for further development of cooperative extension work in addition to those referred to in subsection (b) of this section shall be distributed as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Four per centum of the sum so appropriated for each fiscal year shall be allotted to the Secretary of Agriculture for administrative, technical, and other services, and for coordinating the extension work of the Department and the several States, Territories, and possessions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Of the remainder so appropriated for each fiscal year 20 per centum shall be paid to the several States in equal proportions, 40 per centum shall be paid to the several States in the proportion that the rural population of each bears to the total rural population of the several States as determined by the census, and the balance shall be paid to the several States in the proportion that the farm population of each bears to the total farm population of the several States as determined by the census. Any appropriation made hereunder shall be allotted in the first and succeeding years on the basis of the decennial census current at the time such appropriation is first made, and as to any increase, on the basis of decennial census current at the time such increase is first appropriated.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Agriculture shall receive such additional amounts as Congress shall determine for administration, technical, and other services and for coordinating the extension work of the Department and the several States, Territories, and possessions. A college or university eligible to receive funds under subchapter II of this chapter, including Tuskegee University, may compete for and receive funds directly from the Secretary of Agriculture. A 1994 Institution (as defined in section 532 of the Equity in Educational Land-Grant Status Act of 1994 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 301</ref> note; <ref>Public Law 103–382</ref>)) may compete for and receive funds directly from the Secretary of Agriculture for the Children, Youth, and Families at Risk funding program and the Federally Recognized Tribes Extension Program.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Matching Funds.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in paragraph (4) and subsection (f), no allotment shall be made to a State under subsection (b) or (c), and no payments from the allotment shall be made to a State, in excess of the amount that the State makes available out of non-Federal funds for cooperative extension work.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Failure to provide matching funds</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>If a State fails to comply with the requirement to provide matching funds for a fiscal year under paragraph (1), the Secretary of Agriculture shall withhold from payment to the State for that fiscal year an amount equal to the difference between—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the amount that would be allotted and paid to the State under subsections (b) and (c) (if the full amount of matching funds were provided by the State); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the amount of matching funds actually provided by the State.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Reapportionment.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Agriculture shall reapportion amounts withheld under paragraph (2) for a fiscal year among the States satisfying the matching requirement for that fiscal year.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Matching requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any reapportionment of funds under this paragraph shall be subject to the matching requirement specified in paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Exception for insular areas.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Effective beginning for fiscal year 2003, in lieu of the matching funds requirement of paragraph (1), the insular areas of the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, and the Virgin Islands of the United States shall provide matching funds from non-Federal sources in an amount equal to not less than 50 percent of the formula funds distributed by the Secretary to each of the insular areas, respectively, under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Waivers</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may waive the matching fund requirement of subparagraph (A) for any fiscal year if the Secretary determines that the government of the insular area will be unlikely to meet the matching requirement for the fiscal year.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Matching Funds Exception for</inline> 1994 <inline class="small-caps">Institutions and Hispanic-Serving Agricultural Colleges and Universities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There shall be no matching requirement for funds made available to a 1994 Institution or Hispanic-serving agricultural colleges and universities in accordance with paragraphs (3) and (4) of subsection (b).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Agriculture may conduct educational, instructional, demonstration, and publication distribution programs and enter into cooperative agreements with private nonprofit and profit organizations and individuals to share the cost of such programs through contributions from private sources as provided in this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary may receive contributions under this subsection from private sources for the purposes described in paragraph (1) and provide matching funds in an amount not greater than 50 percent of such contributions.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Multistate Cooperative Extension Activities.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not less than the applicable percentage specified under paragraph (2) of the amounts that are paid to a State under subsections (b) and (c) during a fiscal year shall be expended by States for cooperative extension activities in which 2 or more States cooperate to solve problems that concern more than 1 State (referred to in this subsection as “multistate activities”).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Applicable percentages.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading> 1997 <inline class="small-caps">expenditures on multistate activities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Of the Federal formula funds that were paid to each State for fiscal year 1997 under subsections (b) and (c), the Secretary of Agriculture shall determine the percentage that the State expended for multistate activities.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Required expenditures on multistate activities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Of the Federal formula funds that are paid to each State for fiscal year 2000 and each subsequent fiscal year under subsections (b) and (c), the State shall expend for the fiscal year for multistate activities a percentage that is at least equal to the lesser of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> 25 percent; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> twice the percentage for the State determined under subparagraph (A).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reduction by secretary</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may reduce the minimum percentage required to be expended for multistate activities under subparagraph (B) by a State in a case of hardship, infeasibility, or other similar circumstance beyond the control of the State, as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Applicability</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>This subsection does not apply to funds provided—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> by a State or local government pursuant to a matching requirement;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to a 1994 Institution (as defined in section 532 of the Equity in Educational Land-Grant Status Act of 1994 (<ref>Public Law 103–382</ref>; <ref>7 U.S.C. 301</ref> note)); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, or Guam.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Merit Review.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Review required</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Effective <date date="1999-10-01">October 1, 1999</date>, extension activity carried out under subsection (h) shall be subject to merit review.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Other requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An extension activity for which merit review is conducted under paragraph (1) shall be considered to have satisfied the requirements for review under <ref>section 7613(e) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Integration of Research and Extension</inline>.—</heading>
<content><ref>Section 361c(i) of this title</ref> shall apply to amounts made available to carry out this subchapter.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 8, 1914, ch. 79, § 3</ref>, <ref>38 Stat. 373</ref>; <ref>June 26, 1953, ch. 157, § 1</ref>, <ref>67 Stat. 84</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–749, § 1(b)</ref>–(e), <date date="1962-10-05">Oct. 5, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 745</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–318, title V, § 506(g)</ref>, <date date="1972-06-23">June 23, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 351</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–113, title XIV, § 1465</ref>, <date date="1977-09-29">Sept. 29, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 1018</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–198, title XIV, § 1435(b)</ref>, <date date="1985-12-23">Dec. 23, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 1557</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–396, § 9(e)</ref>, <date date="1986-08-27">Aug. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 840</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title V, § 534(b)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4050</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title VIII, § 883(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1176</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–185, title I, § 105</ref>, title II, §§ 201, 203(b), (c)(2), 204(b), <date date="1998-06-23">June 23, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 529</ref>, 531, 534, 536; <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. A, § 101(a) [title VII, § 753(e)]</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681</ref>, 2681–33; <ref>Pub. L. 107–171, title VII</ref>, §§ 7213(b), 7215, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 448</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title VII</ref>, §§ 7129(b), 7403(a), <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1226</ref>, 1246; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title VII, §§ 7129(b), 7403(a), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1987, 2007; <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title VII</ref>, §§ 7609(a), 7612(a)(1), <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4830</ref>, 4831.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 343a to 343c–1.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>June 26, 1953, ch. 157, § 2</ref>, <ref>67 Stat. 85</ref>, 86</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 343d.</num>
<heading> Transferred</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 343d–1 to 343d–5.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>June 26, 1953, ch. 157, § 2</ref>, <ref>67 Stat. 86</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 343e.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Oct. 27, 1949, ch. 768, § 3</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 940</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 343f, 343g.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>June 26, 1953, ch. 157, § 2</ref>, <ref>67 Stat. 86</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 344.</num>
<heading> Ascertainment of entitlement of State to funds; time and manner of payment; State reporting requirements; plans of work</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Ascertainment of entitlement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On or about the first day of October in each year after <date date="1953-06-26">June 26, 1953</date>, the Secretary of Agriculture shall ascertain as to each State whether it is entitled to receive its share of the annual appropriation for cooperative agricultural extension work under this subchapter and the amount which it is entitled to receive. Before the funds herein provided shall become available to any college for any fiscal year, plans for the work to be carried on under this subchapter shall be submitted by the proper officials of each college and approved by the Secretary of Agriculture. The Secretary shall ensure that each college seeking to receive funds under this subchapter has in place appropriate guidelines, as determined by the Secretary, to minimize actual or potential conflicts of interest among employees of such college whose salaries are funded in whole or in part with such funds.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Time and manner of payment; related reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The amount to which a State is entitled shall be paid in equal quarterly payments in or about July, October, January, and April of each year to the treasurer or other officer of the State duly authorized by the laws of the State to receive the same, and such officer shall be required to report to the Secretary of Agriculture on or about the first day of April of each year, a detailed statement of the amount so received during the previous fiscal year and its disbursement, on forms prescribed by the Secretary of Agriculture.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements related to plan of work</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each extension plan of work for a State required under subsection (a) shall contain descriptions of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A summary of planned projects or programs in the State using formula funds.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A description of the manner in which the State will meet the requirements of <ref>section 343(h) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A description of the manner in which the State will meet the requirements of <ref>section 361c(i)(2) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> A description of matching funds provided by the State with respect to the previous fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Extension protocols</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Development</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary of Agriculture shall develop protocols to be used to evaluate the success of multistate, multi-institutional, and multidisciplinary extension activities and joint research and extension activities in addressing critical agricultural issues identified in the plans of work submitted under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary of Agriculture shall develop the protocols in consultation with the National Agricultural Research, Extension, Education, and Economics Advisory Board established under <ref>section 3123 of this title</ref> and land-grant colleges and universities.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment of plans of work for other purposes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To the maximum extent practicable, the Secretary shall consider a plan of work submitted under subsection (a) to satisfy other appropriate Federal reporting requirements.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 8, 1914, ch. 79, § 4</ref>, <ref>38 Stat. 374</ref>; <ref>June 26, 1953, ch. 157, § 1</ref>, <ref>67 Stat. 85</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–749, § 1(f)</ref>, <date date="1962-10-05">Oct. 5, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 745</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–273, § 15</ref>, <date date="1976-04-21">Apr. 21, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 379</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XVI, § 1617</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3732</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–185, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-06-23">June 23, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 531</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title VII, § 7612(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4831</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 345.</num>
<heading> Replacement of diminished, lost or misapplied funds; restrictions on use; reports of colleges</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If any portion of the moneys received by the designated officer of any State for the support and maintenance of cooperative agricultural extension work, as provided in this subchapter, shall by any action or contingency be diminished or lost or be misapplied, it shall be replaced by said State and until so replaced no subsequent appropriation shall be apportioned or paid to said State. No portion of said moneys shall be applied, directly or indirectly, to the purchase, erection, preservation, or repair of any building or buildings, or the purchase or rental of land, or in college-course teaching, lectures in college, or any other purpose not specified in this subchapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 8, 1914, ch. 79, § 5</ref>, <ref>38 Stat. 374</ref>; <ref>June 26, 1953, ch. 157, § 1</ref>, <ref>67 Stat. 85</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–749, § 1(g)</ref>, <date date="1962-10-05">Oct. 5, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 745</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title VII, § 7403(b)</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1246</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title VII, § 7403(b), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2007.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 346.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 105–185, title I, § 103(f)(1)</ref>, <date date="1998-06-23">June 23, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 528</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 347.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 86–533, § 1(21)</ref>, <date date="1960-06-29">June 29, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 249</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 347a.</num>
<heading> Disadvantaged agricultural areas</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Congressional findings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Congress finds that there exists special circumstances in certain agricultural areas which cause such areas to be at a disadvantage insofar as agricultural development is concerned, which circumstances include the following: (1) There is concentration of farm families on farms either too small or too unproductive or both; (2) such farm operators because of limited productivity are unable to make adjustments and investments required to establish profitable operations; (3) the productive capacity of the existing farm unit does not permit profitable employment of available labor; (4) because of limited resources, many of these farm families are not able to make full use of current extension programs designed for families operating economic units nor are extension facilities adequate to provide the assistance needed to produce desirable results.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appropriation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In order to further the purposes of <ref>section 342 of this title</ref> in such areas and to encourage complementary development essential to the welfare of such areas, there are authorized to be appropriated such sums as the Congress from time to time shall determine to be necessary for payments to the States on the basis of special needs in such areas as determined by the Secretary of Agriculture.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In determining that the area has such special need, the Secretary shall find that it has a substantial number of disadvantaged farms or farm families for one or more of the reasons heretofore enumerated. The Secretary shall make provisions for the assistance to be extended to include one or more of the following: (1) Intensive on-the-farm educational assistance to the farm family in appraising and resolving its problems; (2) assistance and counseling to local groups in appraising resources for capability of improvement in agriculture or introduction of industry designed to supplement farm income; (3) cooperation with other agencies and groups in furnishing all possible information as to existing employment opportunities, particularly to farm families having under-employed workers; and (4) in cases where the farm family, after analysis of its opportunities and existing resources, finds it advisable to seek a new farming venture, the providing of information, advice, and counsel in connection with making such change.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Allocation of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No more than 10 per centum of the sums available under this section shall be allotted to any one State. The Secretary shall use project proposals and plans of work submitted by the State Extension directors as a basis for determining the allocation of funds appropriated pursuant to this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appropriation as additional; limitation on amount</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Sums appropriated pursuant to this section shall be in addition to, and not in substitution for, appropriations otherwise available under this subchapter. The amounts authorized to be appropriated pursuant to this section shall not exceed a sum in any year equal to 10 per centum of sums otherwise appropriated pursuant to this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 8, 1914, ch. 79, § 8</ref>, as added <ref>Aug. 11, 1955, ch. 798, § 1(a)</ref>, <ref>69 Stat. 683</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 87–749, § 1(h)</ref>, <date date="1962-10-05">Oct. 5, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 745</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 348.</num>
<heading> Rules and regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture is authorized to make such rules and regulations as may be necessary for carrying out the provisions of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 8, 1914, ch. 79, § 9</ref>, formerly § 8, <ref>38 Stat. 374</ref>; <ref>June 26, 1953, ch. 157, § 1</ref>, <ref>67 Stat. 85</ref>; renumbered § 9, <ref>Aug. 11, 1955, ch. 798, § 1(b)</ref>, <ref>69 Stat. 684</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 349.</num>
<heading> “State” defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The term “State” means the States of the Union, Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam and the Northern Mariana Islands.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 8, 1914, ch. 79, § 10</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 87–749, § 1(i)</ref>, <date date="1962-10-05">Oct. 5, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 745</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 92–318, title V, § 506(h)</ref>, <date date="1972-06-23">June 23, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 351</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–396, § 9(f)</ref>, <date date="1986-08-27">Aug. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 840</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>