<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 15—</num>
<heading>BUREAU OF ANIMAL INDUSTRY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 391.</num>
<heading> Establishment of bureau; appointment of chief; duties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There shall be in the Department of Agriculture a Bureau of Animal Industry. The Secretary of Agriculture is authorized to appoint a chief thereof, who shall be a competent veterinary surgeon, and whose duty it shall be to investigate and report upon the condition of the domestic animals and live poultry of the United States, their protection and use, and also inquire into and report the causes of contagious, infectious, and communicable diseases among them, and the means for the prevention and cure of the same, and to collect such information on these subjects as shall be valuable to the agricultural and commercial interests of the country.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 29, 1884, ch. 60, § 1</ref>, <ref>23 Stat. 31</ref>; <ref>July 14, 1890, ch. 707</ref>, <ref>26 Stat. 288</ref>; <ref>Feb. 7, 1928, ch. 30</ref>, <ref>45 Stat. 59</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 392.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Oct. 31, 1951, ch. 654, § 1(11)</ref>, <ref>65 Stat. 701</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 393.</num>
<heading> Sale of pathological and zoological specimens; disposition of moneys</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture is authorized to prepare and sell at cost such pathological and zoological specimens as he may deem of scientific or educational value to scientists or others engaged in the work of hygiene and sanitation: <i>Provided</i>, That all moneys received from the sale of such specimens shall be deposited in the Treasury as miscellaneous receipts.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 4, 1913, ch. 145, § 1</ref> [part], <ref>37 Stat. 833</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 394.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 107–171, title X, § 10703(c)(3)</ref>, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 518</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 394a.</num>
<heading> Overtime of employees working at establishments which prepare virus, serum, toxin, and analogous products</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture is authorized to pay employees of the Bureau of Animal Industry employed in establishments subject to the provisions of <ref>section 157 of title 21</ref>, for all overtime, night, or holiday work performed at such establishments, at such rates as he may determine, and to accept from such establishments wherein such overtime work is performed reimbursement for any sums paid out by him for such overtime work.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 392</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 495</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 395.</num>
<heading> Fees for rabies diagnoses; disposition of moneys</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Fees shall be charged for all diagnoses in connection with rabies, except those performed for agencies of the United States Government, in such amounts as the Secretary shall prescribe, and such fees shall be covered into the Treasury as miscellaneous receipts.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Sept. 21, 1944, ch. 412</ref>, title I, § 101(e), <ref>58 Stat. 734</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 396.</num>
<heading> Inspection of livestock, hides, animal products, etc.; place; charges; disposition of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture upon application of any exporter, importer, packer, or owner of, or the agent thereof, or dealer in, livestock, hides, skins, meat, or other animal products may, in his discretion, cause to be made inspections and examinations at places other than the headquarters of inspectors for the convenience of said applicants, who may be charged for the expenses of travel and subsistence incurred for such inspections and examinations, the funds derived from such charges to be deposited in the Treasury of the United States to the credit of the appropriation from which the expenses are paid.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Sept. 21, 1944, ch. 412</ref>, title I, § 101(c), <ref>58 Stat. 734</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 397.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 398.</num>
<heading> Purchase and testing of serums or analogous products; dissemination of test results</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture may purchase in the open market from applicable appropriations samples of all tuberculin, serums, antitoxins, or analogous products, of foreign or domestic manufacture, which are sold in the United States, for the detection, prevention, treatment, or cure of diseases of domestic animals, test the same, and disseminate the results of said tests in such manner as he may deem best.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Sept. 21, 1944, ch. 412</ref>, title I, § 101(d), <ref>58 Stat. 734</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 399.</num>
<heading> Domestic raising of fur-bearing animals; classification</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For the purposes of all classification and administration of Acts of Congress, Executive orders, administrative orders, and regulations pertaining to—</chapeau>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> fox, rabbit, mink, chinchilla, marten, fisher, muskrat, karakul and all other fur-bearing animals, raised in captivity for breeding or other useful purposes shall be deemed domestic animals;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> such animals and the products thereof shall be deemed agricultural products; and</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> the breeding, raising, producing, or marketing of such animals or their products by the producer shall be deemed an agricultural pursuit.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Apr. 30, 1946, ch. 242, § 1</ref>, <ref>60 Stat. 127</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>