<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 68—</num>
<heading>AGRICULTURAL SUBTERMINAL FACILITIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3701.</num>
<heading> Congressional findings and declarations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Congress finds and declares that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an adequate system for the efficient transient storage and movement of bulk agricultural commodities is essential to the overall success of the agricultural industry of the Nation, the development of rural areas of the Nation, and the economic stability of the Nation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the movement and storage of bulk agricultural commodities has been seriously and repeatedly impeded by shortages of transient storage facilities, adequate rail rolling stock, and the deterioration of many railroad track beds and rural highways throughout the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the efficient movement and storage of bulk agricultural commodities may be achieved and facilitated by the joint location at strategic points throughout the United States of transient storage facilities and multimodal terminal facilities constructed especially for the efficient shipment and receipt of agricultural commodities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the location of such facilities must be carefully planned to assure maximum benefits to producers of agricultural commodities and unprocessed agricultural products and utilization of the most efficient means of transporting bulk agricultural commodities for domestic and export markets.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–358, § 2</ref>, <date date="1980-09-25">Sept. 25, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1184</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3702.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this chapter, the term—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “bulk agricultural commodity” means any agricultural commodity that can be transported in bulk and can be temporarily stored in bulk quantities without undergoing processing or packaging. Such term also includes any commodity or product that is used by producers in the production of agricultural commodities and that can be stored or shipped in bulk, such as fertilizer and fuel;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> “unprocessed agricultural products” means food, fiber, and other agricultural products that have not been packaged or otherwise prepared for retail sale, including animal products and unfinished cotton, wool, leather, or any other unfinished natural material;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> “Secretary” means Secretary of Agriculture;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> “subterminal facility” means any facility that is located in the area of production or consumption of agricultural commodities or any major storage or major export point for such commodities and is located at a place that conveniently serves the needs of producers, purchasers, and consumers of bulk agricultural commodities, and is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> used for the transient storage of bulk agricultural commodities and may include equipment or structures necessary for the transportation, upgrading, receiving, drying, or loading out of such commodities; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any rail siding, loading, or unloading facility that can accommodate unit railroad trains or multiple car trains and other appropriate transportation modes designed for the transport of bulk agricultural commodities and production materials; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> “region” means two or more States acting together to develop a coordinated regional subterminal facilities plan.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–358, § 3</ref>, <date date="1980-09-25">Sept. 25, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1184</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3703.</num>
<heading> State and regional plans</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grants; requisite provisions of plans</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall, beginning not more than one hundred and eighty days after <date date="1980-10-01">October 1, 1980</date>, make financial assistance available to any State that makes application therefor, and that otherwise meets the requirements of this section, for the purpose of assisting such State in the development of a subterminal facilities plan (hereinafter in this chapter referred to as the “State plan”) for such State. Assistance under this section shall be made available in the form of a grant. No grant may be made to any State unless the Governor of such State or the appropriate agency of such State makes an application therefor as provided in this section. To the maximum extent practicable, the personnel and resources of the colleges or universities in the State which are eligible to receive funds under the Act of <date date="1862-07-02">July 2, 1862</date> (<ref>7 U.S.C. 301–305</ref>, 307, and 308), or the Act of <date date="1890-08-30">August 30, 1890</date> (<ref>7 U.S.C. 321–326</ref> and 328), including Tuskegee Institute, shall be utilized in developing the subterminal facilities plan for that State pursuant to this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary may also make grants under this section available to two or more States acting together to develop a coordinated regional subterminal facilities plan (hereinafter in this chapter referred to as the “regional plan”) for such region.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Grants made under this section to any State or region may not exceed 80 per centum of the cost of preparing the State or regional plan.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The State or regional plan shall prescribe in detail the actions such State or region proposes to take in order to (A) facilitate the efficient and competitive movement of bulk agricultural commodities from the points of production within such State or region to major market or export points, (B) provide adequate storage facilities for such commodities between points of production and market, (C) provide adequate receiving, storage, and loading facilities for any bulk agricultural commodity, and (D) assure that such facilities will be located at sites that will result in maximum benefits to local producers.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> Each State or regional plan shall include the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an analysis of the marketing, shipping, storage, and production of bulk agricultural commodities produced in that State or region and the short- and long-range projections with respect to the marketing, shipping, storage, and production of such commodities in that State or region;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a determination, on the basis of the analysis and projections required under clause (A) of this paragraph, of the needs of the State or region for subterminal facilities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> an assessment of the use of existing on-farm storage facilities located within the State or region and an assessment of the ways in which subterminal facilities can benefit the continued use of on-farm storage facilities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> an evaluation of the effect of the development of new subterminal facilities on small capacity rural shipping and storage facilities within the State or region;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> an evaluation of ways to ensure adequate rail service for subterminal facilities described in clause (D) of this paragraph, including an evaluation of the use and feasibility of contract rates;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> an assessment of the ways that subterminal facilities can enhance the operation of small capacity shipping and storage facilities within the State or region;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> an assessment of other actions being taken or considered in such State or region for the improvement of agricultural transportation, including an evaluation of the use being made of shuttle or collector trains and combinations of rail and barge service;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> an evaluation of the potential benefits of subterminal ownership and leasing arrangements for rail rolling stock (including locomotive power), motor trucks, barge equipment, and other bulk agricultural commodity transport equipment that may help achieve maximum benefits from the operation of subterminal facilities within the State or region;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> an assessment of the overall transportation system in the State or region and future plans for that overall system, including the adequacy of highways and bridges; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> consideration of the feasibility and advisability of the ownership and operation of rail branch lines by farmer-owned cooperatives, and the role that such cooperatives might play in any overall planning for the restructuring and rehabilitation of rail service and marketing facilities within the State or region.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Plan review commissions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Funds made available to a State or region under this chapter for the purposes of assisting such State or region to develop a plan shall be subject to the condition that the State or region establish a plan review commission composed of local producers, local elevator operators, representatives of affected motor and rail carriers, other interested individuals, and, when appropriate in the judgment of the Secretary, consumers of bulk agricultural commodities used in the production of unproc­essed agricultural products. A majority of the members of any plan review commission must be local producers or, when appropriate in the judgment of the Secretary, consumers of bulk agricultural commodities used in the production of unproc­essed agricultural products. The plan review commission shall consider the information and analyses developed by the State or region in the development of a State or regional plan and make appropriate recommendations regarding the State or regional plan. The plan review commission shall also make recommendations, based on information developed in the plan, for the most beneficial location of subterminal facilities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recommendations of need</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No application for planning assistance authorized pursuant to this section may be submitted by a State or region until the appropriate plan review commission established in accordance with this chapter has had the opportunity to make recommendations to the Governor or Governors that a need exists for the development of a State or regional plan, and a majority of the members of such plan review commission concur that such application should be submitted.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prerequisites for receipt of grant</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">No State or region may receive a grant under this section unless—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an application therefor has been submitted that complies with the provisions of this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the average annual production of bulk agricultural commodities produced within such State or region, or shipments of such commodities transported into such State or region, meets minimum levels established by the Secretary for a period the Secretary considers appropriate preceding the year in which application for such grant is made;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the Governor of such State or the Governors of the States in such region certify to the Secretary that producers of agricultural commodities have experienced serious storage and transportation problems within such State or region during the three years preceding the year in which application for such grant is made; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> such State or each State within such region has established an adequate plan, as described in <ref>section 22102 of title 49</ref>, for rail service in such State or States, or such State or each State in such region is actively developing such a plan.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Approved State plans; approved regional plans</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever any State or region has submitted a State or regional plan under this section, the Secretary shall approve such plan only if it has been approved by a majority of the members of the appropriate plan review commission established pursuant to this chapter, and it meets the other conditions specified in this chapter and those prescribed in regulations issued by the Secretary to carry out this chapter. When a plan is approved by the Secretary, such plan shall be known as an “approved State plan” or an “approved regional plan”, as appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To carry out the purposes of this section, there are authorized to be appropriated not to exceed $3,300,000 for each of the fiscal years ending <date date="1981-09-30">September 30, 1981</date>, <date date="1982-09-30">September 30, 1982</date>, and <date date="1983-09-30">September 30, 1983</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–358, § 4</ref>, <date date="1980-09-25">Sept. 25, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1185</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>