<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 100—</num>
<heading>AGRICULTURAL MARKET TRANSITION</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>SHORT TITLE, PURPOSE, AND DEFINITIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7201.</num>
<heading> Short title and purpose</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Short title</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This chapter may be cited as the “Agricultural Market Transition Act”.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purpose</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the purpose of this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to authorize the use of binding production flexibility contracts between the United States and agricultural producers to support farming certainty and flexibility while ensuring continued compliance with farm conservation and wetland protection requirements;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to make nonrecourse marketing assistance loans and loan deficiency payments available for certain crops;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to improve the operation of farm programs for milk, peanuts, and sugar; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to establish a commission to undertake a comprehensive review of past and future production agriculture in the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 896</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7202.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agricultural Act of 1949</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except in <ref>section 7301 of this title</ref>, the term “Agricultural Act of 1949” means the Agricultural Act of 1949 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1421</ref> et seq.), as in effect prior to the suspensions under <ref>section 7301(b)(1) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Considered planted</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “considered planted” means acreage that is considered planted under title V of the Agricultural Act of 1949 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1461</ref> et seq.) and such other acreage as the Secretary considers fair and equitable.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contract</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The terms “contract” and “production flexibility contract” mean a production flexibility contract entered into under <ref>section 7211 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contract acreage</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “contract acreage” means 1 or more crop acreage bases established for contract commodities under title V of the Agricultural Act of 1949 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1461</ref> et seq.) that would have been in effect for the 1996 crop (but for suspension under <ref>section 7301(b)(1) of this title</ref>).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contract commodity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “contract commodity” means wheat, corn, grain sorghum, barley, oats, upland cotton, and rice.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contract payment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “contract payment” means a payment made under this subchapter <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002324">1</ref> pursuant to a contract.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Department</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Department” means the Department of Agriculture.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Extra long staple cotton</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “extra long staple cotton” means cotton that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is produced from pure strain varieties of the Barbadense species or any hybrid thereof, or other similar types of extra long staple cotton, designated by the Secretary, having characteristics needed for various end uses for which United States upland cotton is not suitable and grown in irrigated cotton-growing regions of the United States designated by the Secretary or other areas designated by the Secretary as suitable for the production of the varieties or types; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is ginned on a roller-type gin or, if authorized by the Secretary, ginned on another type gin for experimental purposes.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Farm program payment yield</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “farm program payment yield” means the farm program payment yield established for the 1995 crop of a contract commodity under section 505 of the Agricultural Act of 1949 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1465</ref>). The Secretary shall adjust the farm program payment yield for the 1995 crop of a contract commodity to account for any additional yield payments made with respect to that crop under subsection (b)(2) of the section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(10)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Loan commodity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “loan commodity” means each contract commodity, extra long staple cotton, and oilseed.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(11)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Oilseed</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “oilseed” means a crop of soybeans, sunflower seed, rapeseed, canola, safflower, flaxseed, mustard seed, or, if designated by the Secretary, other oilseeds.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(12)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Producer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “producer” means an owner, operator, landlord, tenant, or sharecropper who shares in the risk of producing a crop and who is entitled to share in the crop available for marketing from the farm, or would have shared had the crop been produced. In determining whether a grower of hybrid seed is a producer, the Secretary shall not take into consideration the existence of a hybrid seed contract.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(13)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Agriculture.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(14)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “State” means each of the several States of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and any other territory or possession of the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(15)</num>
<heading class="bold"> United States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “United States”, when used in a geographical sense, means all of the States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 897</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>PRODUCTION FLEXIBILITY CONTRACTS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7211.</num>
<heading> Authorization for use of production flexibility contracts</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Offer and terms</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall offer to enter into a production flexibility contract with an eligible owner or producer described in subsection (b) on a farm containing eligible cropland. Under the terms of a contract, the owner or producer shall agree, in exchange for annual contract payments, to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> comply with applicable conservation requirements under subtitle B of title XII of the Food Security Act of 1985 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 3811</ref> et seq.);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> comply with applicable wetland protection requirements under subtitle C of title XII of the Act (<ref>16 U.S.C. 3821</ref> et seq.);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> comply with the planting flexibility requirements of <ref>section 7218 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> use the land subject to the contract for an agricultural or related activity, but not for a nonagricultural commercial or industrial use, as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible owners and producers described</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The following producers and owners shall be eligible to enter into a contract:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> An owner of eligible cropland who assumes all or a part of the risk of producing a crop.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A producer (other than an owner) on eligible cropland with a share-rent lease of the eligible cropland, regardless of the length of the lease, if the owner enters into the same contract.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A producer (other than an owner) on eligible cropland who cash rents the eligible cropland under a lease expiring on or after <date date="2002-09-30">September 30, 2002</date>, in which case the owner is not required to enter into the contract.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> A producer (other than an owner) on eligible cropland who cash rents the eligible cropland under a lease expiring before <date date="2002-09-30">September 30, 2002</date>. The owner of the eligible cropland may also enter into the same contract. If the producer elects to enroll less than 100 percent of the eligible cropland in the contract, the consent of the owner is required.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> An owner of eligible cropland who cash rents the eligible cropland and the lease term expires before <date date="2002-09-30">September 30, 2002</date>, if the tenant declines to enter into a contract. In the case of an owner covered by this paragraph, contract payments shall not begin under a contract until the lease held by the tenant ends.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> An owner or producer described in any preceding paragraph regardless of whether the owner or producer purchased catastrophic risk protection for a 1996 crop under <ref>section 1508(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tenants and sharecroppers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In carrying out this subchapter, the Secretary shall provide adequate safeguards to protect the interests of tenants and sharecroppers.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible cropland described</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Land shall be considered to be cropland eligible for coverage under a contract only if the land has contract acreage attributable to the land and—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> for at least 1 of the 1991 through 1995 crops, at least a portion of the land was enrolled in the acreage reduction program authorized for a crop of a contract commodity under section 101B, 103B, 105B, or 107B of the Agricultural Act of 1949 or was considered planted;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> was subject to a conservation reserve contract under section 1231 of the Food Security Act of 1985 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 3831</ref>) whose term expired, or was voluntarily terminated, on or after <date date="1995-01-01">January 1, 1995</date>; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> is released from coverage under a conservation reserve contract by the Secretary during the period beginning on <date date="1995-01-01">January 1, 1995</date>, and ending on the date specified in <ref>section 7212(a)(2) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Quantity of eligible cropland covered by contract</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to subsection (b)(4), an owner or producer may enroll as contract acreage all or a portion of the eligible cropland on the farm.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Voluntary reduction in contract acreage</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to subsection (b)(4), an owner or producer who enters into a contract may subsequently reduce the quantity of contract acreage covered by the contract.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title I, § 111</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 898</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7212.</num>
<heading> Elements of contracts</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Time for contracting</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Commencement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To the extent practicable, the Secretary shall commence entering into contracts not later than 45 days after <date date="1996-04-04">April 4, 1996</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deadline</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (3), the Secretary may not enter into a contract after <date date="1996-08-01">August 1, 1996</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conservation reserve lands</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">At the beginning of each fiscal year, the Secretary shall allow an eligible owner or producer on a farm covered by a conservation reserve contract entered into under <ref>section 3831 of title 16</ref> that terminates after the date specified in paragraph (2) to enter into or expand a production flexibility contract to cover the contract acreage of the farm that was subject to the former conservation reserve contract.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amount</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Contract payments made for contract acreage under this paragraph shall be made at the rate and amount applicable to the annual contract payment level for the applicable crop. For the fiscal year in which the conservation reserve contract is terminated, the owner or producer subject to the production flexibility contract may elect to receive either contract payments or a prorated payment under the conservation reserve contract, but not both.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duration of contract</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Beginning date</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term of a contract shall begin with—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the 1996 crop of a contract commodity; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of acreage that was subject to a conservation reserve contract described in subsection (a)(3), the date the production flexibility contract was entered into or expanded to cover the acreage.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Ending date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term of a contract shall extend through the 2002 crop, unless earlier terminated by the owner or producer.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Estimation of contract payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">At the time the Secretary enters into a contract, the Secretary shall provide an estimate of the minimum contract payments anticipated to be made during at least the first fiscal year for which contract payments will be made.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Time for payment</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">An annual contract payment shall be made not later than September 30 of each of fiscal years 1996 through 2002.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Advance payments</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fiscal year 1996</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">At the option of the owner or producer, 50 percent of the contract payment for fiscal year 1996 shall be made not later than 30 days after the date on which the contract is entered into and approved by the Secretary and the owner or producer.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Subsequent fiscal years</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">At the option of the owner or producer for fiscal year 1997 and each subsequent fiscal year, 50 percent of the annual contract payment shall be made on December 15 or January 15 of the fiscal year. The owner or producer may change the date selected under this subparagraph for a subsequent fiscal year by providing advance notice to the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rule</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding the requirements for making an annual contract payment specified in paragraphs (1) and (2), at the option of the owner or producer, the Secretary shall pay the full amount (or such portion as the owner or producer may specify) of the contract payment required to be paid for any of fiscal years 1999 through 2002 at such time or times during that fiscal year as the owner or producer may specify.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title I, § 112</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 899</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–228, § 2</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1516</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–78, title VIII, § 811</ref>, <date date="1999-10-22">Oct. 22, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1181</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7213.</num>
<heading> Amounts available for contract payments</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fiscal year amounts</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall, to the maximum extent practicable, expend the following amounts to satisfy the obligations of the Secretary under all contracts:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> For fiscal year 1996, $5,570,000,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> For fiscal year 1997, $5,385,000,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> For fiscal year 1998, $5,800,000,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> For fiscal year 1999, $5,603,000,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> For fiscal year 2000, $5,130,000,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> For fiscal year 2001, $4,130,000,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> For fiscal year 2002, $4,008,000,000.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Allocation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The amount made available for a fiscal year under subsection (a) shall be allocated as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> For wheat, 26.26 percent.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> For corn, 46.22 percent.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> For grain sorghum, 5.11 percent.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> For barley, 2.16 percent.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> For oats, 0.15 percent.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> For upland cotton, 11.63 percent.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> For rice, 8.47 percent.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adjustment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall adjust the amounts allocated for each contract commodity under subsection (b) for a particular fiscal year by—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> adding an amount equal to the sum of all repayments of deficiency payments required under section 114(a)(2) of the Agricultural Act of 1949 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1445j(a)(2)</ref>) for the commodity;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> adding an amount equal to the sum of all refunds of contract payments received during the preceding fiscal year under <ref>section 7216 of this title</ref> for the commodity; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> subtracting an amount equal to the amount, if any, necessary during that fiscal year to satisfy payment requirements for the commodity under sections 103B, 105B, or 107B of the Agricultural Act of 1949 for the 1994 and 1995 crop years.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional rice allocation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In addition to the adjustments required under subsection (c), the amount allocated under subsection (b) for rice contract payments shall be increased by $8,500,000 for each of fiscal years 1997 through 2002.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exclusion of certain amounts from contract payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any amount added pursuant to paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (c) to the amount available under subsection (a) for a fiscal year and paid to owners and producers under a contract shall not be treated as a contract payment for purposes of <ref>section 7215 of this title</ref> or section 1308(1) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002325">1</ref> of this title. However, the amount of a payment covered by this subsection may not exceed $50,000 per person.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect of payment limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The amount available under subsection (a) for a fiscal year shall be reduced by an amount equal to the total amount of contract payments for the fiscal year that owners and producers forgo as a result of operation of the payment limitation under section 1308(1) <sup>1</sup> of this title.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title I, § 113</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 900</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7214.</num>
<heading> Determination of contract payments under contracts</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Individual payment quantity of contract commodities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For each contract, the payment quantity of a contract commodity for each fiscal year shall be equal to the product of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> 85 percent of the contract acreage; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the farm program payment yield.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual payment quantity of contract commodities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The payment quantity of each contract commodity covered by all contracts for each fiscal year shall be equal to the sum of the amounts calculated under subsection (a) for each individual contract.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual payment rate</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The payment rate for a contract commodity for each fiscal year shall be equal to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the amount made available under <ref>section 7213 of this title</ref> for the contract commodity for the fiscal year; divided by</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the amount determined under subsection (b) for the fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual payment amount</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The amount to be paid under a contract in effect for each fiscal year with respect to all contract commodities covered by the contract shall be equal to the sum of the products of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the payment quantity determined under subsection (a) for each of the contract commodities covered by the contract; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the corresponding payment rate for the contract commodity in effect under subsection (c).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reduction in payment amount</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The contract payment determined under subsection (d) for an owner or producer for a fiscal year shall be immediately reduced by the amount of any repayment of deficiency payments that is required under section 114(a)(2) of the Agricultural Act of 1949 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1445j(a)(2)</ref>) and is not repaid as of the date the contract payment is determined. The Secretary shall be required to collect the required repayment, or any claim based on the required repayment, as soon as the contract payment is determined.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assignment of contract payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The provisions of <ref>section 590h(g) of title 16</ref> (relating to assignment of payments) shall apply to contract payments under this section. The owner or producer making the assignment, or the assignee, shall provide the Secretary with notice, in such manner as the Secretary may require in the contract, of any assignment made under this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sharing of contract payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall provide for the sharing of contract payments among the owners and producers subject to the contract on a fair and equitable basis.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title I, § 114</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 901</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7215.</num>
<heading> Applicability of payment limitations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Sections 1308 through 1308–3 of this title shall be applicable to contract payments made under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title I, § 115(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 902</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7216.</num>
<heading> Violations of contract</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination of contract for violation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as provided in subsection (b), if an owner or producer subject to a contract violates a requirement of the contract specified in <ref>section 7211(a) of this title</ref>, the Secretary shall terminate the contract with respect to the owner or producer on each farm in which the owner or producer has an interest. On the termination, the owner or producer shall forfeit all rights to receive future contract payments on each farm in which the owner or producer has an interest and shall refund to the Secretary all contract payments received by the owner or producer during the period of the violation, together with interest on the contract payments as determined by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Refund or adjustment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">If the Secretary determines that a violation does not warrant termination of the contract under subsection (a), the Secretary may require the owner or producer subject to the contract—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to refund to the Secretary that part of the contract payments received by the owner or producer during the period of the violation, together with interest on the contract payments as determined by the Secretary; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to accept a reduction in the amount of future contract payments that is proportionate to the severity of the violation, as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Foreclosure</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect of foreclosure</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">An owner or producer subject to a contract may not be required to make repayments to the Secretary of amounts received under the contract if the contract acreage has been foreclosed on and the Secretary determines that forgiving the repayments is appropriate to provide fair and equitable treatment.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Resumption of operation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">This subsection shall not void the responsibilities of the owner or producer under the contract if the owner or producer continues or resumes operation, or control, of the contract acreage. On the resumption of operation or control over the contract acreage by the owner or producer, the provisions of the contract in effect on the date of the foreclosure shall apply.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A determination of the Secretary under this section shall be considered to be an adverse decision for purposes of the availability of administrative review of the determination.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title I, § 116</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 903</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7217.</num>
<heading> Transfer or change of interest in lands subject to contract</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as provided in subsection (c), a transfer of (or change in) the interest of an owner or producer subject to a contract in the contract acreage covered by the contract shall result in the termination of the contract with respect to the acreage, unless the transferee or owner of the acreage agrees to assume all obligations under the contract. The termination shall be effective on the date of the transfer or change.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Modification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">At the request of the transferee or owner, the Secretary may modify the contract if the modifications are consistent with the objectives of this subchapter, as determined by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If an owner or producer who is entitled to a contract payment dies, becomes incompetent, or is otherwise unable to receive the contract payment, the Secretary shall make the payment, in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title I, § 117</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 904</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7218.</num>
<heading> Planting flexibility</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Permitted crops</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to subsection (b), any commodity or crop may be planted on contract acreage on a farm.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations and exceptions regarding fruits and vegetables</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The planting of fruits and vegetables (other than lentils, mung beans, and dry peas) shall be prohibited on contract acreage.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Paragraph (1) shall not limit the planting of a fruit or vegetable—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in any region in which there is a history of double-cropping of contract commodities with fruits or vegetables, as determined by the Secretary, in which case the double-cropping shall be permitted;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> on a farm that the Secretary determines has a history of planting fruits or vegetables on contract acreage, except that a contract payment shall be reduced by an acre for each acre planted to the fruit or vegetable; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> by a producer who the Secretary determines has an established planting history of a specific fruit or vegetable, except that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the quantity planted may not exceed the producer’s average annual planting history of the fruit or vegetable in the 1991 through 1995 crop years (excluding any crop year in which no plantings were made), as determined by the Secretary; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a contract payment shall be reduced by an acre for each acre planted to the fruit or vegetable.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title I, § 118</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 904</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>NONRECOURSE MARKETING ASSISTANCE LOANS AND LOAN DEFICIENCY PAYMENTS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7231.</num>
<heading> Availability of nonrecourse marketing assistance loans</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonrecourse loans available</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For each of the 1996 through 2002 crops of each loan commodity, the Secretary shall make available to producers on a farm nonrecourse marketing assistance loans for loan commodities produced on the farm. The loans shall be made under terms and conditions that are prescribed by the Secretary and at the loan rate established under <ref>section 7232 of this title</ref> for the loan commodity.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible production</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The following production shall be eligible for a marketing assistance loan under subsection (a):</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In the case of a marketing assistance loan for a contract commodity, any production by a producer on a farm containing eligible cropland covered by a production flexibility contract.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In the case of a marketing assistance loan for extra long staple cotton and oilseeds, any production.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compliance with conservation and wetlands requirements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As a condition of the receipt of a marketing assistance loan under subsection (a), the producer shall comply with applicable conservation requirements under subtitle B of title XII of the Food Security Act of 1985 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 3811</ref> et seq.) and applicable wetland protection requirements under subtitle C of title XII of the Act (<ref>16 U.S.C. 3821</ref> et seq.) during the term of the loan.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional outlays prohibited</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall carry out this subchapter in such a manner that there are no additional outlays under this subchapter as a result of the reconstitution of a farm that occurs as a result of the combination of another farm that does not contain eligible cropland covered by a production flexibility contract.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title I, § 131</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 905</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7232.</num>
<heading> Loan rates for marketing assistance loans</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Wheat</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Loan rate</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Subject to paragraph (2), the loan rate for a marketing assistance loan under <ref>section 7231 of this title</ref> for wheat shall be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> not less than 85 percent of the simple average price received by producers of wheat, as determined by the Secretary, during the marketing years for the immediately preceding 5 crops of wheat, excluding the year in which the average price was the highest and the year in which the average price was the lowest in the period; but</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> not more than $2.58 per bushel.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Stocks to use ratio adjustment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">If the Secretary estimates for any marketing year that the ratio of ending stocks of wheat to total use for the marketing year will be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> equal to or greater than 30 percent, the Secretary may reduce the loan rate for wheat for the corresponding crop by an amount not to exceed 10 percent in any year;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> less than 30 percent but not less than 15 percent, the Secretary may reduce the loan rate for wheat for the corresponding crop by an amount not to exceed 5 percent in any year; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> less than 15 percent, the Secretary may not reduce the loan rate for wheat for the corresponding crop.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Feed grains</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Loan rate for corn</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Subject to paragraph (2), the loan rate for a marketing assistance loan under <ref>section 7231 of this title</ref> for corn shall be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> not less than 85 percent of the simple average price received by producers of corn, as determined by the Secretary, during the marketing years for the immediately preceding 5 crops of corn, excluding the year in which the average price was the highest and the year in which the average price was the lowest in the period; but</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> not more than $1.89 per bushel.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Stocks to use ratio adjustment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">If the Secretary estimates for any marketing year that the ratio of ending stocks of corn to total use for the marketing year will be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> equal to or greater than 25 percent, the Secretary may reduce the loan rate for corn for the corresponding crop by an amount not to exceed 10 percent in any year;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> less than 25 percent but not less than 12.5 percent, the Secretary may reduce the loan rate for corn for the corresponding crop by an amount not to exceed 5 percent in any year; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> less than 12.5 percent, the Secretary may not reduce the loan rate for corn for the corresponding crop.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other feed grains</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The loan rate for a marketing assistance loan under <ref>section 7231 of this title</ref> for grain sorghum, barley, and oats, respectively, shall be established at such level as the Secretary determines is fair and reasonable in relation to the rate that loans are made available for corn, taking into consideration the feeding value of the commodity in relation to corn.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Upland cotton</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Loan rate</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Subject to paragraph (2), the loan rate for a marketing assistance loan under <ref>section 7231 of this title</ref> for upland cotton shall be established by the Secretary at such loan rate, per pound, as will reflect for the base quality of upland cotton, as determined by the Secretary, at average locations in the United States a rate that is not less than the smaller of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> 85 percent of the average price (weighted by market and month) of the base quality of cotton as quoted in the designated United States spot markets during 3 years of the 5-year period ending July 31 of the year preceding the year in which the crop is planted, excluding the year in which the average price was the highest and the year in which the average price was the lowest in the period; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> 90 percent of the average, for the 15-week period beginning July 1 of the year preceding the year in which the crop is planted, of the 5 lowest-priced growths of the growths quoted for Middling 1<sup>3</sup>⁄<sub>32</sub>-inch cotton C.I.F. Northern Europe (adjusted downward by the average difference during the period April 15 through October 15 of the year preceding the year in which the crop is planted between the average Northern European price quotation of such quality of cotton and the market quotations in the designated United States spot markets for the base quality of upland cotton), as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The loan rate for a marketing assistance loan for upland cotton shall not be less than $0.50 per pound or more than $0.5192 per pound.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Extra long staple cotton</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The loan rate for a marketing assistance loan under <ref>section 7231 of this title</ref> for extra long staple cotton shall be—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> not less than 85 percent of the simple average price received by producers of extra long staple cotton, as determined by the Secretary, during 3 years of the 5-year period ending July 31 of the year preceding the year in which the crop is planted, excluding the year in which the average price was the highest and the year in which the average price was the lowest in the period; but</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> not more than $0.7965 per pound.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rice</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The loan rate for a marketing assistance loan under <ref>section 7231 of this title</ref> for rice shall be $6.50 per hundredweight.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Oilseeds</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Soybeans</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The loan rate for a marketing assistance loan under <ref>section 7231 of this title</ref> for soybeans shall be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> not less than 85 percent of the simple average price received by producers of soybeans, as determined by the Secretary, during the marketing years for the immediately preceding 5 crops of soybeans, excluding the year in which the average price was the highest and the year in which the average price was the lowest in the period; but</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> not less than $4.92 or more than $5.26 per bushel.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sunflower seed, canola, rapeseed, safflower, mustard seed, and flaxseed</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The loan rate for a marketing assistance loan under <ref>section 7231 of this title</ref> for sunflower seed, canola, rapeseed, safflower, mustard seed, and flaxseed, individually, shall be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> not less than 85 percent of the simple average price received by producers of sunflower seed, individually, as determined by the Secretary, during the marketing years for the immediately preceding 5 crops of sunflower seed, individually, excluding the year in which the average price was the highest and the year in which the average price was the lowest in the period; but</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> not less than $0.087 or more than $0.093 per pound.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other oilseeds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The loan rates for a marketing assistance loan under <ref>section 7231 of this title</ref> for other oilseeds shall be established at such level as the Secretary determines is fair and reasonable in relation to the loan rate available for soybeans, except in no event shall the rate for the oilseeds (other than cottonseed) be less than the rate established for soybeans on a per-pound basis for the same crop.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title I, § 132</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 905</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7233.</num>
<heading> Term of loans</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Term of loan</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the case of each loan commodity (other than upland cotton or extra long staple cotton), a marketing assistance loan under <ref>section 7231 of this title</ref> shall have a term of 9 months beginning on the first day of the first month after the month in which the loan is made.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rule for cotton</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A marketing assistance loan for upland cotton or extra long staple cotton shall have a term of 10 months beginning on the first day of the month in which the loan is made.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Extensions prohibited</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may not extend the term of a marketing assistance loan for any loan commodity.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title I, § 133</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 907</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7234.</num>
<heading> Repayment of loans</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Repayment rates for wheat, feed grains, and oilseeds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall permit a producer to repay a marketing assistance loan under <ref>section 7231 of this title</ref> for wheat, corn, grain sorghum, barley, oats, and oilseeds at a rate that is the lesser of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the loan rate established for the commodity under <ref>section 7232 of this title</ref>, plus interest (as determined by the Secretary); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> a rate that the Secretary determines will—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> minimize potential loan forfeitures;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> minimize the accumulation of stocks of the commodity by the Federal Government;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> minimize the cost incurred by the Federal Government in storing the commodity; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> allow the commodity produced in the United States to be marketed freely and competitively, both domestically and internationally.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Repayment rates for upland cotton and rice</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall permit producers to repay a marketing assistance loan under <ref>section 7231 of this title</ref> for upland cotton and rice at a rate that is the lesser of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the loan rate established for the commodity under <ref>section 7232 of this title</ref>, plus interest (as determined by the Secretary); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the prevailing world market price for the commodity (adjusted to United States quality and location), as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Repayment rates for extra long staple cotton</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Repayment of a marketing assistance loan for extra long staple cotton shall be at the loan rate established for the commodity under <ref>section 7232 of this title</ref>, plus interest (as determined by the Secretary).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prevailing world market price</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section and <ref>section 7236 of this title</ref>, the Secretary shall prescribe by regulation—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a formula to determine the prevailing world market price for each loan commodity, adjusted to United States quality and location; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a mechanism by which the Secretary shall announce periodically the prevailing world market price for each loan commodity.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adjustment of prevailing world market price for upland cotton</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">During the period ending <date date="2003-07-31">July 31, 2003</date>, the prevailing world market price for upland cotton (adjusted to United States quality and location) established under subsection (d) shall be further adjusted if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the adjusted prevailing world market price is less than 115 percent of the loan rate for upland cotton established under <ref>section 7232 of this title</ref>, as determined by the Secretary; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Friday through Thursday average price quotation for the lowest-priced United States growth as quoted for Middling (M) 1<sup>3</sup>⁄<sub>32</sub>-inch cotton delivered C.I.F. Northern Europe is greater than the Friday through Thursday average price of the 5 lowest-priced growths of upland cotton, as quoted for Middling (M) 1<sup>3</sup>⁄<sub>32</sub>-inch cotton, delivered C.I.F. Northern Europe (referred to in this section as the “Northern Europe price”).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Further adjustment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (3), the adjusted prevailing world market price for upland cotton shall be further adjusted on the basis of some or all of the following data, as available:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The United States share of world exports.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The current level of cotton export sales and cotton export shipments.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Other data determined by the Secretary to be relevant in establishing an accurate prevailing world market price for upland cotton (adjusted to United States quality and location).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on further adjustment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The adjustment under paragraph (2) may not exceed the difference between—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Friday through Thursday average price for the lowest-priced United States growth as quoted for Middling 1<sup>3</sup>⁄<sub>32</sub>-inch cotton delivered C.I.F. Northern Europe; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Northern Europe price.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title I, § 134</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 908</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7235.</num>
<heading> Loan deficiency payments</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability of loan deficiency payments</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except as provided in subsection (d), the Secretary may make loan deficiency payments available to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> producers who, although eligible to obtain a marketing assistance loan under <ref>section 7231 of this title</ref> with respect to a loan commodity, agree to forgo obtaining the loan for the commodity in return for payments under this section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> effective only for the 2000 and 2001 crop years, producers that, although not eligible to obtain such a marketing assistance loan under <ref>section 7231 of this title</ref>, produce a contract commodity.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Computation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A loan deficiency payment under this section shall be computed by multiplying—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the loan payment rate determined under subsection (c) for the loan commodity; by</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the quantity of the loan commodity produced by the eligible producers, excluding any quantity for which the producers obtain a loan under <ref>section 7231 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Loan payment rate</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the loan payment rate shall be the amount by which—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the loan rate established under <ref>section 7232 of this title</ref> for the loan commodity; exceeds</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the rate at which a loan for the commodity may be repaid under <ref>section 7234 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception for extra long staple cotton</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall not apply with respect to extra long staple cotton.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A payment to a producer eligible for a payment under subsection (a)(2) that harvested a commodity on or before the date that is 30 days after the promulgation of the regulations implementing subsection (a)(2) shall be determined as the date the producer lost beneficial interest in the commodity, as determined by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Beneficial interest</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to subsection (e), a producer shall be eligible for a payment under this section only if the producer has a beneficial interest in the commodity, as determined by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date for payment rate determination</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For the 2001 crop year, the Secretary shall determine the amount of the loan deficiency payment to be made under this section to the producers on a farm with respect to a quantity of a loan commodity using the payment rate in effect under subsection (c) as of the earlier of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The date on which the producers marketed or otherwise lost beneficial interest in the crop of the loan commodity, as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The date the producers requested the payment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title I, § 135</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 909</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–224, title II, § 206</ref>, <date date="2000-06-20">June 20, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 405</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–171, title I, § 1205(f)(2)</ref>, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 159</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7236.</num>
<heading> Special marketing loan provisions for upland cotton</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cotton user marketing certificates</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Issuance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">During the period ending <date date="2003-07-31">July 31, 2003</date>, the Secretary shall issue marketing certificates or cash payments, at the option of the recipient, to domestic users and exporters for documented purchases by domestic users and sales for export by exporters made in the week following a consecutive 4-week period in which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Friday through Thursday average price quotation for the lowest-priced United States growth, as quoted for Middling (M) 1<sup>3</sup>⁄<sub>32</sub>-inch cotton, delivered C.I.F. Northern Europe exceeds the Northern Europe price by more than 1.25 cents per pound; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the prevailing world market price for upland cotton (adjusted to United States quality and location) does not exceed 134 percent of the loan rate for upland cotton established under <ref>section 7232 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Value of certificates or payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The value of the marketing certificates or cash payments shall be based on the amount of the difference (reduced by 1.25 cents per pound) in the prices during the 4th week of the consecutive 4-week period multiplied by the quantity of upland cotton included in the documented sales.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administration of marketing certificates</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Redemption, marketing, or exchange</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary shall establish procedures for redeeming marketing certificates for cash or marketing or exchange of the certificates for agricultural commodities owned by the Commodity Credit Corporation or pledged to the Commodity Credit Corporation as collateral for a loan in such manner, and at such price levels, as the Secretary determines will best effectuate the purposes of cotton user marketing certificates, including enhancing the competitiveness and marketability of United States cotton. Any price restrictions that would otherwise apply to the disposition of agricultural commodities by the Commodity Credit Corporation shall not apply to the redemption of certificates under this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Designation of commodities and products</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">To the extent practicable, the Secretary shall permit owners of certificates to designate the commodities and products, including storage sites, the owners would prefer to receive in exchange for certificates.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Marketing certificates issued to domestic users and exporters of upland cotton may be transferred to other persons in accordance with regulations issued by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special import quota</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The President shall carry out an import quota program during the period ending <date date="2003-07-31">July 31, 2003</date>, as provided in this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program requirements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Except as provided in subparagraph (C), whenever the Secretary determines and announces that for any consecutive 4-week period, the Friday through Thursday average price quotation for the lowest-priced United States growth, as quoted for Middling (M) 1<sup>3</sup>⁄<sub>32</sub>-inch cotton, delivered C.I.F. Northern Europe, adjusted for the value of any certificate issued under subsection (a), exceeds the Northern Europe price by more than 1.25 cents per pound, there shall immediately be in effect a special import quota.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tight domestic supply</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">During any month for which the Secretary estimates the season-ending United States upland cotton stocks-to-use ratio, as determined under subparagraph (D), to be below 16 percent, the Secretary, in making the determination under subparagraph (B), shall not adjust the Friday through Thursday average price quotation for the lowest-priced United States growth, as quoted for Middling (M) 1<sup>3</sup>⁄<sub>32</sub>-inch cotton, delivered C.I.F. Northern Europe, for the value of any certificates issued under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Season-ending United States stocks-to-use ratio</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">For the purposes of making estimates under subparagraph (C), the Secretary shall, on a monthly basis, estimate and report the season-ending United States upland cotton stocks-to-use ratio, excluding projected raw cotton imports but including the quantity of raw cotton that has been imported into the United States during the marketing year.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Quantity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The quota shall be equal to 1 week’s consumption of upland cotton by domestic mills at the seasonally adjusted average rate of the most recent 3 months for which data are available.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The quota shall apply to upland cotton purchased not later than 90 days after the date of the Secretary’s announcement under paragraph (1) and entered into the United States not later than 180 days after the date.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Overlap</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A special quota period may be established that overlaps any existing quota period if required by paragraph (1), except that a special quota period may not be established under this subsection if a quota period has been established under subsection (c).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Preferential tariff treatment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The quantity under a special import quota shall be considered to be an in-quota quantity for purposes of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content><ref>section 2703(d) of title 19</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content><ref>section 3203 of title 19</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content><ref>section 2463(d) of title 19</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> General Note 3(a)(iv) to the Harmonized Tariff Schedule.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> “Special import quota” defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In this subsection, the term “special import quota” means a quantity of imports that is not subject to the over-quota tariff rate of a tariff-rate quota.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The quantity of cotton entered into the United States during any marketing year under the special import quota established under this subsection may not exceed the equivalent of 5 week’s consumption of upland cotton by domestic mills at the seasonally adjusted average rate of the 3 months immediately preceding the first special import quota established in any marketing year.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limited global import quota for upland cotton</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The President shall carry out an import quota program that provides that whenever the Secretary determines and announces that the average price of the base quality of upland cotton, as determined by the Secretary, in the designated spot markets for a month exceeded 130 percent of the average price of such quality of cotton in the markets for the preceding 36 months, notwithstanding any other provision of law, there shall immediately be in effect a limited global import quota subject to the following conditions:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Quantity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The quantity of the quota shall be equal to 21 days of domestic mill consumption of upland cotton at the seasonally adjusted average rate of the most recent 3 months for which data are available.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Quantity if prior quota</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">If a quota has been established under this subsection during the preceding 12 months, the quantity of the quota next established under this subsection shall be the smaller of 21 days of domestic mill consumption calculated under subparagraph (A) or the quantity required to increase the supply to 130 percent of the demand.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Preferential tariff treatment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The quantity under a limited global import quota shall be considered to be an in-quota quantity for purposes of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content><ref>section 2703(d) of title 19</ref>;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content><ref>section 3203 of title 19</ref>;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content><ref>section 2463(d) of title 19</ref>; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> General Note 3(a)(iv) to the Harmonized Tariff Schedule.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In this subsection:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Supply</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">The term “supply” means, using the latest official data of the Bureau of the Census, the Department of Agriculture, and the Department of the Treasury—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the carry-over of upland cotton at the beginning of the marketing year (adjusted to 480-pound bales) in which the quota is established;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> production of the current crop; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> imports to the latest date available during the marketing year.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Demand</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">The term “demand” means—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the average seasonally adjusted annual rate of domestic mill consumption during the most recent 3 months for which data are available; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<chapeau> the larger of—</chapeau>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> average exports of upland cotton during the preceding 6 marketing years; or</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> cumulative exports of upland cotton plus outstanding export sales for the marketing year in which the quota is established.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limited global import quota</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The term “limited global import quota” means a quantity of imports that is not subject to the over-quota tariff rate of a tariff-rate quota.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(E)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Quota entry period</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">When a quota is established under this subsection, cotton may be entered under the quota during the 90-day period beginning on the date the quota is established by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> No overlap</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding paragraph (1), a quota period may not be established that overlaps an existing quota period or a special quota period established under subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title I, § 136</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 909</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–86, title VII, § 731</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 2108</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. A, § 101(a) [title VII, § 762]</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681</ref>, 2681–36; <ref>Pub. L. 106–78, title VIII, § 806</ref>, <date date="1999-10-22">Oct. 22, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1179</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7236a.</num>
<heading> Special competitive provisions for extra long staple cotton</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Competitiveness program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, during the period beginning on <date date="1999-10-01">October 1, 1999</date>, and ending on <date date="2003-07-31">July 31, 2003</date>, the Secretary shall carry out a program to maintain and expand the domestic use of extra long staple cotton produced in the United States, to increase exports of extra long staple cotton produced in the United States, and to ensure that extra long staple cotton produced in the United States remains competitive in world markets.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payments under program; trigger</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Under the program, the Secretary shall make payments available under this section whenever—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> for a consecutive 4-week period, the world market price for the lowest priced competing growth of extra long staple cotton (adjusted to United States quality and location and for other factors affecting the competitiveness of such cotton), as determined by the Secretary, is below the prevailing United States price for a competing growth of extra long staple cotton; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the lowest priced competing growth of extra long staple cotton (adjusted to United States quality and location and for other factors affecting the competitiveness of such cotton), as determined by the Secretary, is less than 134 percent of the loan rate for extra long staple cotton.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible recipients</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall make payments available under this section to domestic users of extra long staple cotton produced in the United States and exporters of extra long staple cotton produced in the United States who enter into an agreement with the Commodity Credit Corporation to participate in the program under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payment amount</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Payments under this section shall be based on the amount of the difference in the prices referred to in subsection (b)(1) during the fourth week of the consecutive 4-week period multiplied by the amount of documented purchases by domestic users and sales for export by exporters made in the week following such a consecutive 4-week period.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Form of payment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Payments under this section shall be made through the issuance of cash or marketing certificates, at the option of eligible recipients of the payments.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title I, § 136A</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(5) [title I, § 104(c)]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–291.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7237.</num>
<heading> Availability of recourse loans for high moisture feed grains and seed cotton and other fibers</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> High moisture feed grains</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recourse loans available</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For each of the 1996 through 2002 crops of corn and grain sorghum, the Secretary shall make available recourse loans, as determined by the Secretary, to producers on a farm containing eligible cropland covered by a production flexibility contract who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> normally harvest all or a portion of their crop of corn or grain sorghum in a high moisture state;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> present—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> certified scale tickets from an inspected, certified commercial scale, including a licensed warehouse, feedlot, feed mill, distillery, or other similar entity approved by the Secretary, pursuant to regulations issued by the Secretary; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> field or other physical measurements of the standing or stored crop in regions of the United States, as determined by the Secretary, that do not have certified commercial scales from which certified scale tickets may be obtained within reasonable proximity of harvest operation;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> certify that they were the owners of the feed grain at the time of delivery to, and that the quantity to be placed under loan under this subsection was in fact harvested on the farm and delivered to, a feedlot, feed mill, or commercial or on-farm high-moisture storage facility, or to a facility maintained by the users of corn and grain sorghum in a high moisture state; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> comply with deadlines established by the Secretary for harvesting the corn or grain sorghum and submit applications for loans under this subsection within deadlines established by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility of acquired feed grains</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A loan under this subsection shall be made on a quantity of corn or grain sorghum of the same crop acquired by the producer equivalent to a quantity determined by multiplying—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the acreage of the corn or grain sorghum in a high moisture state harvested on the producer’s farm; by</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the lower of the farm program payment yield or the actual yield on a field, as determined by the Secretary, that is similar to the field from which the corn or grain sorghum was obtained.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> “High moisture state” defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In this subsection, the term “high moisture state” means corn or grain sorghum having a moisture content in excess of Commodity Credit Corporation standards for marketing assistance loans made by the Secretary under <ref>section 7231 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recourse loans available for seed cotton</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Upland cotton</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For each of the 1996 through 2002 crops of upland cotton, the Secretary shall make available recourse seed cotton loans, as determined by the Secretary, to producers on a farm containing eligible cropland covered by a production flexibility contract.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Extra long staple cotton</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For each of the 1996 through 2002 crops of extra long staple cotton, the Secretary shall make available recourse seed cotton loans, as determined by the Secretary, on any production.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recourse loans available for mohair</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recourse loans available</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, during fiscal year 1999, the Secretary shall make available recourse loans, as determined by the Secretary, to producers of mohair produced during or before that fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Loan rate</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The loan rate for a loan under paragraph (1) shall be equal to $2.00 per pound.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Term of loan</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A loan under paragraph (1) shall have a term of 1 year beginning on the first day of the first month after the month in which the loan is made.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Waiver of interest</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding subsection (d), the Secretary shall not charge interest on a loan made under paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Repayment rates</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Repayment of a recourse loan made under this section shall be at the loan rate established for the commodity by the Secretary, plus interest (as determined by the Secretary).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title I, § 137</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 912</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. A, § 101(a) [title XI, § 1126]</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681</ref>, 2681–46.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>OTHER COMMODITIES</heading>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part A—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Dairy</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7251.</num>
<heading> Milk price support program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Support activities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture shall support the price of milk produced in the 48 contiguous States through the purchase of cheese, butter, and nonfat dry milk produced from the milk.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rate</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The price of milk shall be supported at the following rates per hundredweight for milk containing 3.67 percent butterfat:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> During calendar year 1996, $10.35.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> During calendar year 1997, $10.20.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> During calendar year 1998, $10.05.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> During each of calendar years 1999 through 2001, $9.90.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> During the period beginning on <date date="2002-01-01">January 1, 2002</date>, and ending on <date date="2002-05-31">May 31, 2002</date>, $9.90.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purchase prices</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The support purchase prices under this section for each of the products of milk (butter, cheese, and nonfat dry milk) announced by the Secretary shall be the same for all of that product sold by persons offering to sell the product to the Secretary. The purchase prices shall be sufficient to enable plants of average efficiency to pay producers, on average, a price that is not less than the rate of price support for milk in effect under subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rule for butter and nonfat dry milk purchase prices</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Allocation of purchase prices</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may allocate the rate of price support between the purchase prices for nonfat dry milk and butter in a manner that will result in the lowest level of expenditures by the Commodity Credit Corporation or achieve such other objectives as the Secretary considers appropriate. Not later than 10 days after making or changing an allocation, the Secretary shall notify the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate of the allocation. <ref>Section 553 of title 5</ref> shall not apply with respect to the implementation of this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Timing of purchase price adjustments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may make any such adjustments in the purchase prices for nonfat dry milk and butter the Secretary considers to be necessary not more than twice in each calendar year.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Refunds of 1995 and 1996 assessments</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Refund required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall provide for a refund of the entire reduction required under section 204(h)(2) of the Agricultural Act of 1949 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1446e(h)(2)</ref>), as in effect on the day before the amendment made by subsection (g), in the price of milk received by a producer during calendar year 1995 or 1996, if the producer provides evidence that the producer did not increase marketings in calendar year 1995 or 1996 when compared to calendar year 1994 or 1995, respectively.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">This subsection shall not apply with respect to a producer for a particular calendar year if the producer has already received a refund under section 204(h) of the Agricultural Act of 1949 for the same fiscal year before the effective date of this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment of refund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A refund under this subsection shall not be considered as any type of price support or payment for purposes of sections 3811 and 3821 of title 16.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Commodity Credit Corporation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall carry out the program authorized by this section through the Commodity Credit Corporation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Period of effectiveness</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section (other than subsection (g)) shall be effective only during the period beginning on the first day of the first month beginning after <date date="1996-04-04">April 4, 1996</date>, and ending on <date date="2002-05-31">May 31, 2002</date>. The program authorized by this section shall terminate on <date date="2002-05-31">May 31, 2002</date>, and shall be considered to have expired notwithstanding <ref>section 907 of title 2</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title I, § 141</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 914</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–78, title VIII, § 807(a)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-22">Oct. 22, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1181</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–387, § 1(a) [title VII, § 742(a)]</ref>, <date date="2000-10-28">Oct. 28, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1549</ref>, 1549A–35; <ref>Pub. L. 107–76, title VII, § 772(a)</ref>, <date date="2001-11-28">Nov. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 745</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7252.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 107–76, title VII, § 772(b)</ref>, <date date="2001-11-28">Nov. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 745</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7253.</num>
<heading> Consolidation and reform of Federal milk marketing orders</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amendment of orders</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Required consolidation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall amend Federal milk marketing orders issued under <ref>section 608c of this title</ref> to limit the number of Federal milk marketing orders to not less than 10 and not more than 14 orders.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inclusion of California as separate order</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Upon the petition and approval of California dairy producers in the manner provided in <ref>section 608c of this title</ref>, the Secretary shall designate the State of California as a separate Federal milk marketing order. The order covering California shall have the right to reblend and distribute order receipts to recognize quota value. Subsection (b) does not apply to the authority of the Secretary under this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Related issues addressed in consolidation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Among the issues the Secretary is authorized to implement as part of the consolidation of Federal milk marketing orders are the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The use of utilization rates and multiple basing points for the pricing of fluid milk.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The use of uniform multiple component pricing when developing 1 or more basic formula prices for manufacturing milk.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect of existing law</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In implementing the consolidation of Federal milk marketing orders and related reforms under this subsection, the Secretary may not consider, or base any decision on, the table contained in <ref>section 608c(5)(A) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Expedited process</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of informal rulemaking</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To implement the consolidation of Federal milk marketing orders and related reforms under subsection (a), the Secretary shall use the notice and comment procedures provided in <ref>section 553 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Time limitations</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Proposed amendments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary shall announce the proposed amendments to be made under subsection (a) not later than 2 years after <date date="1996-04-04">April 4, 1996</date>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Final amendments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary shall implement the amendments not later than 3 years after <date date="1996-04-04">April 4, 1996</date>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect of court order</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The actions authorized by this subsection are intended to ensure the timely publication and implementation of new and amended Federal milk marketing orders. In the event that the Secretary is enjoined or otherwise restrained by a court order from publishing or implementing the consolidation and related reforms under subsection (a), the length of time for which that injunction or other restraining order is effective shall be added to the time limitations specified in paragraph (2) thereby extending those time limitations by a period of time equal to the period of time for which the injunction or other restraining order is effective.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Failure to timely consolidate orders</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the Secretary fails to implement the consolidation required under subsection (a)(1) within the time period required under subsection (b)(2)(B) (plus any additional period provided under subsection (b)(3)), the Secretary may not assess or collect assessments from milk producers or handlers under such <ref>section 608c of this title</ref> for marketing order administration and services provided under such section after the end of that period until the consolidation is completed. The Secretary may not reduce the level of services provided under the section on account of the prohibition against assessments, but shall rather cover the cost of marketing order administration and services through funds available for the Agricultural Marketing Service of the Department.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report regarding further reforms</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report required</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than <date date="1997-04-01">April 1, 1997</date>, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> reviewing the Federal milk marketing order system established pursuant to <ref>section 608c of this title</ref> in light of the reforms required by subsection (a);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> describing the efforts underway and the progress made in implementing the reforms required by subsection (a); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> containing such recommendations as the Secretary considers appropriate for further improvements and reforms to the Federal milk marketing order system.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect of other laws</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any limitation imposed by Act of Congress on the conduct or completion of reports to Congress shall not apply to the report required under this section, unless the limitation specifically refers to this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title I, § 143</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 915</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–79, title I, § 1410(d)</ref>, <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 693</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7254.</num>
<heading> Effect on fluid milk standards in State of California</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Nothing in this Act or any other provision of law shall be construed to preempt, prohibit, or otherwise limit the authority of the State of California, directly or indirectly, to establish or continue to effect any law, regulation, or requirement regarding—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the percentage of milk solids or solids not fat in fluid milk products sold at retail or marketed in the State of California; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the labeling of such fluid milk products with regard to milk solids or solids not fat.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title I, § 144</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 917</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7255.</num>
<heading> Milk manufacturing marketing adjustment</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Maximum allowances established</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">No State shall provide for a manufacturing allowance for the processing of milk in excess of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> $1.65 per hundredweight of milk for milk manufactured into butter and nonfat dry milk; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> $1.80 per hundredweight of milk for milk manufactured into cheese.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> “Manufacturing allowance” defined</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section, the term “manufacturing allowance” means—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the amount by which the product price value of butter and nonfat dry milk manufactured from a hundred pounds of milk containing 3.5 pounds of butterfat and 8.7 pounds of milk solids not fat resulting from a State’s yield and product price formulas exceeds the class price for the milk used to produce those products; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the amount by which the product price value of cheese manufactured from a hundred pounds of milk containing 3.5 pounds of butterfat and 8.7 pounds of milk solids not fat resulting from a State’s yield and product price formulas exceeds the class price for the milk used to produce cheese.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect of violation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the Secretary determines following a hearing that a State has in effect a manufacturing allowance that exceeds the manufacturing allowance authorized in subsection (a), the Secretary shall suspend purchases of cheddar cheese, butter, and nonfat dry milk produced in that State until such time as the State complies with such subsection.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date; implementation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section (other than subsection (e) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002326">1</ref>) shall be effective during the period beginning on the first day of the first month beginning after <date date="1996-04-04">April 4, 1996</date>, and ending on <date date="1999-12-31">December 31, 1999</date>. During that period, the Secretary may exercise the authority provided to the Secretary under this section without regard to the issuance of regulations intended to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title I, § 145</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 917</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7256.</num>
<heading> Northeast Interstate Dairy Compact</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Congress hereby consents to the Northeast Interstate Dairy Compact entered into among the States of Connecticut, Maine, Massachusetts, New Hampshire, Rhode Island and Vermont as specified in section 1(b) Senate <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002327">1</ref> Joint Resolution 28 of the 104th Congress, as placed on the calendar of the Senate, subject to the following conditions:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Finding of compelling public interest</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Based upon a finding by the Secretary of a compelling public interest in the Compact region, the Secretary may grant the States that have ratified the Northeast Interstate Dairy Compact, as of <date date="1996-04-04">April 4, 1996</date>, the authority to implement the Northeast Interstate Dairy Compact.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on manufacturing price</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Northeast Interstate Dairy Compact Commission shall not regulate Class II, Class III, or Class III–A milk used for manufacturing purposes or any other milk, other than Class I (fluid) milk, as defined by a Federal milk marketing order issued under <ref>section 608c of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Consent for the Northeast Interstate Dairy Compact shall terminate on <date date="2001-09-30">September 30, 2001</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Delaware, New Jersey, New York, Pennsylvania, Maryland, and Virginia are the only additional States that may join the Northeast Interstate Dairy Compact, individually or otherwise, if upon entry the State is contiguous to a participating State and if Congress consents to the entry of the State into the Compact after <date date="1996-04-04">April 4, 1996</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation of Commodity Credit Corporation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Before the end of each fiscal year that a Compact price regulation is in effect, the Northeast Interstate Dairy Compact Commission shall compensate the Commodity Credit Corporation for the cost of any purchases of milk and milk products by the Corporation that result from the projected rate of increase in milk production for the fiscal year within the Compact region in excess of the projected national average rate of the increase in milk production, as determined by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Milk marketing order Administrator</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">At the request of the Northeast Interstate Dairy Compact Commission, the Administrator of the applicable Federal milk marketing order issued under section 608c(5) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002328">2</ref> of this title shall provide technical assistance to the Compact Commission and be compensated for that assistance.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Further conditions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Northeast Interstate Dairy Compact Commission shall not prohibit or in any way limit the marketing in the Compact region of any milk or milk product produced in any other production area in the United States. The Compact Commission shall respect and abide by the ongoing procedures between Federal milk marketing orders with respect to the sharing of proceeds from sales within the Compact region of bulk milk, packaged milk, or producer milk originating from outside of the Compact region. The Compact Commission shall not use compensatory payments under section 10(6) of the Compact as a barrier to the entry of milk into the Compact region or for any other purpose. Establishment of a Compact over-order price, in itself, shall not be considered a compensatory payment or a limitation or prohibition on the marketing of milk.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title I, § 147</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 919</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(8) [§ 4]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–520.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7257.</num>
<heading> Authority to assist in establishment and maintenance of one or more export trading companies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture shall, consistent with the obligations of the United States as a member of the World Trade Organization, provide such advice and assistance to the United States dairy industry as may be necessary to enable that industry to establish and maintain one or more export trading companies under the Export Trading Company Act of 1982 (<ref>15 U.S.C. 4001</ref> et seq.) for the purpose of facilitating the international market development for and exportation of dairy products produced in the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title I, § 149</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 921</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7258.</num>
<heading> Standby authority to indicate entity best suited to provide international market development and export services</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Indication of entity best suited to assist international market development for and export of United States dairy products</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture shall indicate which entity or entities autonomous of the Government of the United States, which seeks such a designation, is best suited to facilitate the international market development for and exportation of United States dairy products, if the Secretary determines that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the United States dairy industry has not established an export trading company under the Export Trading Company Act of 1982 (<ref>15 U.S.C. 4001</ref> et seq.) for the purpose of facilitating the international market development for an exportation of dairy products produced in the United States on or before <date date="1997-06-30">June 30, 1997</date>; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the quantity of exports of United States dairy products during the 12-month period preceding <date date="1998-07-01">July 1, 1998</date> does not exceed the quantity of exports of United States dairy products during the 12-month period preceding <date date="1997-07-01">July 1, 1997</date> by 1.5 billion pounds (milk equivalent, total solids basis).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Funding of export activities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall assist the entity or entities identified under subsection (a) in identifying sources of funding for the activities specified in subsection (a) from within the dairy industry and elsewhere.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application of section</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall apply only during the period beginning on <date date="1997-07-01">July 1, 1997</date> and ending on <date date="2000-09-30">September 30, 2000</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title I, § 150</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 921</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7259.</num>
<heading> Study and report regarding potential impact of Uruguay Round on prices, income, and government purchases</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Study</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture shall conduct a study, on a variety by variety of cheese basis, to determine the potential impact on milk prices in the United States, dairy producer income, and Federal dairy program costs, of the allocation of additional cheese granted access to the United States as a result of the obligations of the United States as a member of the World Trade Organization.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than <date date="1997-06-30">June 30, 1997</date>, the Secretary shall report to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate and the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives the results of the study conducted under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any limitation imposed by Act of Congress on the conduct or completion of studies or reports to Congress shall not apply to the study and report required under this section, unless the limitation specifically refers to this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title I, § 151</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 922</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part B—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Sugar</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7271.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 107–171, title I, § 1310(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 182</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7272.</num>
<heading> Sugar program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sugarcane</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall make loans available to processors of domestically grown sugarcane at a rate equal to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> 18.00 cents per pound for raw cane sugar for the 2008 crop year;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> 18.25 cents per pound for raw cane sugar for the 2009 crop year;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> 18.50 cents per pound for raw cane sugar for the 2010 crop year;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> 18.75 cents per pound for raw cane sugar for each of the 2011 through 2018 crop years; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> 19.75 cents per pound for raw cane sugar for each of the 2019 through 2023 crop years.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sugar beets</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall make loans available to processors of domestically grown sugar beets at a rate equal to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> 22.9 cents per pound for refined beet sugar for the 2008 crop year; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a rate that is equal to 128.5 percent of the loan rate per pound of raw cane sugar for the applicable crop year under subsection (a) for each of the 2009 through 2023 crop years.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Term of loans</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A loan under this section during any fiscal year shall be made available not earlier than the beginning of the fiscal year and shall mature at the earlier of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the end of the 9-month period beginning on the first day of the first month after the month in which the loan is made; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the end of the fiscal year in which the loan is made.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Supplemental loans</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In the case of a loan made under this section in the last 3 months of a fiscal year, the processor may repledge the sugar as collateral for a second loan in the subsequent fiscal year, except that the second loan shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> be made at the loan rate in effect at the time the first loan was made; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> mature in 9 months less the quantity of time that the first loan was in effect.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Loan type; processor assurances</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonrecourse loans</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall carry out this section through the use of nonrecourse loans.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Processor assurances</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary shall obtain from each processor that receives a loan under this section such assurances as the Secretary considers adequate to ensure that the processor will provide payments to producers that are proportional to the value of the loan received by the processor for the sugar beets and sugarcane delivered by producers to the processor.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Minimum payments</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Subject to clause (ii), the Secretary may establish appropriate minimum payments for purposes of this paragraph.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">In the case of sugar beets, the minimum payment established under clause (i) shall not exceed the rate of payment provided for under the applicable contract between a sugar beet producer and a sugar beet processor.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may not impose or enforce any prenotification requirement, or similar administrative requirement not otherwise in effect on <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, that has the effect of preventing a processor from electing to forfeit the loan collateral (of an acceptable grade and quality) on the maturity of the loan.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Loans for in-process sugar</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition of in-process sugars and syrups</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In this subsection, the term “in-process sugars and syrups” does not include raw sugar, liquid sugar, invert sugar, invert syrup, or other finished product that is otherwise eligible for a loan under subsection (a) or (b).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall make nonrecourse loans available to processors of a crop of domestically grown sugarcane and sugar beets for in-process sugars and syrups derived from the crop.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Loan rate</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The loan rate shall be equal to 80 percent of the loan rate applicable to raw cane sugar or refined beet sugar, as determined by the Secretary on the basis of the source material for the in-process sugars and syrups.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Further processing on forfeiture</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">As a condition of the forfeiture of in-process sugars and syrups serving as collateral for a loan under paragraph (2), the processor shall, within such reasonable time period as the Secretary may prescribe and at no cost to the Commodity Credit Corporation, convert the in-process sugars and syrups into raw cane sugar or refined beet sugar of acceptable grade and quality for sugars eligible for loans under subsection (a) or (b).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer to corporation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Once the in-process sugars and syrups are fully processed into raw cane sugar or refined beet sugar, the processor shall transfer the sugar to the Commodity Credit Corporation.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payment to processor</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">On transfer of the sugar, the Secretary shall make a payment to the processor in an amount equal to the amount obtained by multiplying—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> the difference between—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the loan rate for raw cane sugar or refined beet sugar, as appropriate; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the loan rate the processor received under paragraph (3); by</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the quantity of sugar transferred to the Secretary.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Loan conversion</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the processor does not forfeit the collateral as described in paragraph (4), but instead further processes the in-process sugars and syrups into raw cane sugar or refined beet sugar and repays the loan on the in-process sugars and syrups, the processor may obtain a loan under subsection (a) or (b) for the raw cane sugar or refined beet sugar, as appropriate.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Term of loan</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term of a loan made under this subsection for a quantity of in-process sugars and syrups, when combined with the term of a loan made with respect to the raw cane sugar or refined beet sugar derived from the in-process sugars and syrups, may not exceed 9 months, consistent with subsection (c).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Avoiding forfeitures; Corporation inventory disposition</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subject to subsection (d)(3), to the maximum extent practicable, the Secretary shall operate the program established under this section at no cost to the Federal Government by avoiding the forfeiture of sugar to the Commodity Credit Corporation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inventory disposition</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">To carry out paragraph (1), the Commodity Credit Corporation may accept bids to obtain raw cane sugar or refined beet sugar in the inventory of the Commodity Credit Corporation from (or otherwise make available such commodities, on appropriate terms and conditions, to) processors of sugarcane and processors of sugar beets (acting in conjunction with the producers of the sugarcane or sugar beets processed by the processors) in return for the reduction of production of raw cane sugar or refined beet sugar, as appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Bioenergy feedstock</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">If a reduction in the quantity of production accepted under subparagraph (A) involves sugar beets or sugarcane that has already been planted, the sugar beets or sugarcane so planted may not be used for any commercial purpose other than as a bioenergy feedstock.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The authority provided under this paragraph is in addition to any authority of the Commodity Credit Corporation under any other law.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Information reporting</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duty of processors and refiners to report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A sugarcane processor, cane sugar refiner, and sugar beet processor shall furnish the Secretary, on a monthly basis, such information as the Secretary may require to administer sugar programs, including the quantity of purchases of sugarcane, sugar beets, and sugar, and production, importation, distribution, and stock levels of sugar.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duty of producers to report</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Proportionate share States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">As a condition of a loan made to a processor for the benefit of a producer, the Secretary shall require each producer of sugarcane located in a State (other than the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico) in which there are in excess of 250 producers of sugarcane to report, in the manner prescribed by the Secretary, the sugarcane yields and acres planted to sugarcane of the producer.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary may require each producer of sugarcane or sugar beets not covered by subparagraph (A) to report, in a manner prescribed by the Secretary, the yields of, and acres planted to, sugarcane or sugar beets, respectively, of the producer.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duty of importers to report</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the Secretary shall require an importer of sugars, syrups, or molasses to be used for human consumption or to be used for the extraction of sugar for human consumption to report, in the manner prescribed by the Secretary, the quantities of the products imported by the importer and the sugar content or equivalent of the products.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tariff-rate quotas</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Subparagraph (A) shall not apply to sugars, syrups, or molasses that are within the quantities of tariff-rate quotas that are subject to the lower rate of duties.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Collection of information on Mexico</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Collection</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Secretary shall collect—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> information on the production, consumption, stocks, and trade of sugar in Mexico, including United States exports of sugar to Mexico; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> publicly available information on Mexican production, consumption, and trade of high fructose corn syrups.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Publication</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The data collected under subparagraph (A) shall be published in each edition of the World Agricultural Supply and Demand Estimates.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Penalty</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any person willfully failing or refusing to furnish the information required to be reported by paragraph (1), (2), or (3), or furnishing willfully false information, shall be subject to a civil penalty of not more than $10,000 for each such violation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Monthly reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Taking into consideration the information received under this subsection, the Secretary shall publish on a monthly basis composite data on production, imports, distribution, and stock levels of sugar.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Substitution of refined sugar</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of Additional U.S. Note 6 to chapter 17 of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States and the reexport programs and polyhydric alcohol program administered by the Secretary, all refined sugars (whether derived from sugar beets or sugarcane) produced by cane sugar refineries and beet sugar processors shall be fully substitutable for the export of sugar and sugar-containing products under those programs.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective period</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall be effective only for the 2008 through 2023 crops of sugar beets and sugarcane.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title I, § 156</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 931</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–387, § 1(a) [title VIII, § 836]</ref>, <date date="2000-10-28">Oct. 28, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1549</ref>, 1549A–62; <ref>Pub. L. 107–171, title I, § 1401(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 183</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title I, § 1401(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 977</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title I, § 1401(a), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1705; <ref>Pub. L. 113–79, title I, § 1301(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 687</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title I, § 1301(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4511</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER V—</num>
<heading>ADMINISTRATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7281.</num>
<heading> Administration</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of Commodity Credit Corporation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall carry out this chapter through the Commodity Credit Corporation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determinations by Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A determination made by the Secretary under this chapter shall be final and conclusive.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 90 days after <date date="1996-04-04">April 4, 1996</date>, the Secretary and the Commodity Credit Corporation, as appropriate, shall issue such regulations as are necessary to implement this chapter. The issuance of the regulations shall be made without regard to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the notice and comment provisions of <ref>section 553 of title 5</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Statement of Policy of the Secretary of Agriculture effective <date date="1971-07-24">July 24, 1971</date> (36 Fed. Reg. 13804) relating to notices of proposed rulemaking and public participation in rulemaking; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> chapter 35 of title 44, United States Code (commonly know <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002329">1</ref> as the “Paperwork Reduction Act”).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title I, § 161</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 934</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7282.</num>
<heading> Adjustments of loans</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adjustment authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may make appropriate adjustments in the loan rates for any commodity for differences in grade, type, quality, location, and other factors.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Manner of adjustment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The adjustments under the authority of this section shall, to the maximum extent practicable, be made in such manner that the average loan level for the commodity will, on the basis of the anticipated incidence of the factors, be equal to the level of support determined as provided in this chapter and title I of the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 [<ref>7 U.S.C. 7901</ref> et seq.].</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adjustment on county basis</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may establish loan rates for a crop for producers in individual counties in a manner that results in the lowest such rate being 95 percent of the national average loan rate, except that such action shall not result in an increase in outlays. Adjustments under this subsection shall not result in an increase in the national average loan rate for any year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title I, § 162</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 935</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–171, title I, § 1606</ref>, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 218</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7283.</num>
<heading> Commodity Credit Corporation interest rate</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the monthly Commodity Credit Corporation interest rate applicable to loans provided for agricultural commodities by the Corporation shall be 100 basis points greater than the rate determined under the applicable interest rate formula in effect on <date date="1995-10-01">October 1, 1995</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sugar</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this section, raw cane sugar, refined beet sugar, and in-process sugar eligible for a loan under <ref>section 7272 of this title</ref> shall not be considered an agricultural commodity.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title I, § 163</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 935</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–171, title I, § 1401(c)</ref>, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 187</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7284.</num>
<heading> Personal liability of producers for deficiencies</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as provided in subsection (b), no producer shall be personally liable for any deficiency arising from the sale of the collateral securing any nonrecourse loan made under this chapter <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002330">1</ref> title I of the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 [<ref>7 U.S.C. 7901</ref> et seq.], title I of the Food, Conservation, and Energy Act of 2008 [<ref>7 U.S.C. 8701</ref> et seq.], and title I of the Agricultural Act of 2014 [<ref>7 U.S.C. 9001</ref> et seq.] unless the loan was obtained through a fraudulent representation by the producer.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subsection (a) shall not prevent the Commodity Credit Corporation or the Secretary from requiring a producer to assume liability for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a deficiency in the grade, quality, or quantity of a commodity stored on a farm or delivered by the producer;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a failure to properly care for and preserve a commodity; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a failure or refusal to deliver a commodity in accordance with a program established under this chapter <sup>1</sup> title I of the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 [<ref>7 U.S.C. 7901</ref> et seq.], title I of the Food, Conservation, and Energy Act of 2008 [<ref>7 U.S.C. 8701</ref> et seq.], and title I of the Agricultural Act of 2014 [<ref>7 U.S.C. 9001</ref> et seq.].</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Acquisition of collateral</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the case of a nonrecourse loan made under this chapter <sup>1</sup> title I of the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 [<ref>7 U.S.C. 7901</ref> et seq.], title I of the Food, Conservation, and Energy Act of 2008 [<ref>7 U.S.C. 8701</ref> et seq.], and title I of the Agricultural Act of 2014 [<ref>7 U.S.C. 9001</ref> et seq.] or the Commodity Credit Corporation Charter Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 714</ref> et seq.), if the Commodity Credit Corporation acquires title to the unredeemed collateral, the Corporation shall be under no obligation to pay for any market value that the collateral may have in excess of the loan indebtedness.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sugarcane and sugar beets</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A security interest obtained by the Commodity Credit Corporation as a result of the execution of a security agreement by the processor of sugarcane or sugar beets shall be superior to all statutory and common law liens on raw cane sugar and refined beet sugar in favor of the producers of sugarcane and sugar beets and all prior recorded and unrecorded liens on the crops of sugarcane and sugar beets from which the sugar was derived.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title I, § 164</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 935</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–171, title I, § 1607</ref>, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 218</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title I, § 1606</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1017</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title I, § 1606, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1746; <ref>Pub. L. 113–79, title I, § 1607</ref>, <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 708</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7285.</num>
<heading> Commodity Credit Corporation sales price restrictions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General sales authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commodity Credit Corporation may sell any commodity owned or controlled by the Corporation at any price that the Secretary determines will maximize returns to the Corporation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonapplication of sales price restrictions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subsection (a) shall not apply to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a sale for a new or byproduct use;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a sale of peanuts or oilseeds for the extraction of oil;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a sale for seed or feed if the sale will not substantially impair any loan program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> a sale of a commodity that has substantially deteriorated in quality or as to which there is a danger of loss or waste through deterioration or spoilage;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> a sale for the purpose of establishing a claim arising out of a contract or against a person who has committed fraud, misrepresentation, or other wrongful act with respect to the commodity;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> a sale for export, as determined by the Corporation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> a sale for other than a primary use.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Presidential disaster areas</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Notwithstanding subsection (a), on such terms and conditions as the Secretary may consider in the public interest, the Corporation may make available any commodity or product owned or controlled by the Corporation for use in relieving distress—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in any area in the United States (including the Virgin Islands) declared by the President to be an acute distress area because of unemployment or other economic cause, if the President finds that the use will not displace or interfere with normal marketing of agricultural commodities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in connection with any major disaster determined by the President to warrant assistance by the Federal Government under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 5121</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Costs</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Except on a reimbursable basis, the Corporation shall not bear any costs in connection with making a commodity available under paragraph (1) beyond the cost of the commodity to the Corporation incurred in—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the storage of the commodity; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the handling and transportation costs in making delivery of the commodity to designated agencies at 1 or more central locations in each State or other area.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Efficient operations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subsection (a) shall not apply to the sale of a commodity the disposition of which is desirable in the interest of the effective and efficient conduct of the operations of the Corporation because of the small quantity of the commodity involved, or because of the age, location, or questionable continued storability of the commodity.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title I, § 165</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 936</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7286.</num>
<heading> Commodity certificates</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In making in-kind payments under subchapter III of this chapter, title I of the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 [<ref>7 U.S.C. 7901</ref> et seq.], title I of the Food, Conservation, and Energy Act of 2008 [<ref>7 U.S.C. 8701</ref> et seq.], and Subtitle <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002331">1</ref> B of title I of the Agricultural Act of 2014 [<ref>7 U.S.C. 9031</ref> et seq.], the Commodity Credit Corporation may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> acquire and use commodities that have been pledged to the Commodity Credit Corporation as collateral for loans made by the Corporation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> use other commodities owned by the Commodity Credit Corporation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> redeem negotiable marketing certificates for cash under terms and conditions established by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Methods of payment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Commodity Credit Corporation may make in-kind payments—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> by delivery of the commodity at a warehouse or other similar facility;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> by the transfer of negotiable warehouse receipts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> by the issuance of negotiable certificates, which the Commodity Credit Corporation shall exchange for a commodity owned or controlled by the Corporation in accordance with regulations promulgated by the Corporation; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> by such other methods as the Commodity Credit Corporation determines appropriate to promote the efficient, equitable, and expeditious receipt of the in-kind payments so that a person receiving the payments receives the same total return as if the payments had been made in cash.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administration</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Form</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">At the option of a producer, the Commodity Credit Corporation shall make negotiable certificates authorized under subsection (b)(3) available to the producer, in the form of program payments or by sale, in a manner that the Corporation determines will encourage the orderly marketing of commodities pledged as collateral for loans made to producers under subchapter III of this chapter, title I of the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 [<ref>7 U.S.C. 7901</ref> et seq.], title I of the Food, Conservation, and Energy Act of 2008 [<ref>7 U.S.C. 8701</ref> et seq.], and Subtitle <sup>1</sup> B of title I of the Agricultural Act of 2014 [<ref>7 U.S.C. 9031</ref> et seq.].</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A negotiable certificate issued in accordance with this subsection may be transferred to another person in accordance with regulations promulgated by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application of authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Beginning with the 2015 crop marketing year, the Secretary shall carry out paragraph (1) under the same terms and conditions as were in effect for the 2008 crop year for loans made to producers under subtitle B [<ref>7 U.S.C. 8731</ref> et seq.] of title I of the Food, Conservation, and Energy Act of 2008 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 8701</ref> et seq.).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title I, § 166</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 106–78, title VIII, § 812</ref>, <date date="1999-10-22">Oct. 22, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1181</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–171, title I, § 1608</ref>, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 218</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title I, § 1607</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1018</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title I, § 1607, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1746, <ref>Pub. L. 114–113, div. A, title VII, § 740</ref>, <date date="2015-12-18">Dec. 18, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 2281</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7287.</num>
<heading> Commodity Credit Corporation storage payments</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initial crop years</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, for each of the 2008 through 2011 crop years, the Commodity Credit Corporation shall establish rates for the storage of forfeited sugar in an amount that is not less than—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in the case of refined sugar, 15 cents per hundredweight of refined sugar per month; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in the case of raw cane sugar, 10 cents per hundredweight of raw cane sugar per month.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Subsequent crop years</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For each of the 2012 and subsequent crop years, the Commodity Credit Corporation shall establish rates for the storage of forfeited sugar in the same manner as was used on the day before the date of enactment of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title I, § 167</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title I, § 1405</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 990</ref>, and <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title I, § 1405, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1718.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER VI—</num>
<heading>PERMANENT PRICE SUPPORT AUTHORITY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7301.</num>
<heading> Suspension and repeal of permanent price support authority</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agricultural Adjustment Act of 1938</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Suspensions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The following provisions of the Agricultural Adjustment Act of 1938 [<ref>7 U.S.C. 1281</ref> et seq.] shall not be applicable to the 1996 through 2001 crops of loan commodities, peanuts, and sugar and shall not be applicable to milk during the period beginning on <date date="1996-04-04">April 4, 1996</date>, and ending on <date date="2002-12-31">December 31, 2002</date>:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Parts II through V of subtitle B of title III (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1326–135</ref>1) [<ref>7 U.S.C. 1321</ref> et seq., 1331 et seq., 1341 et seq., 1351].</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Subsections (a) through (j) of section 358 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1358</ref>).<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002332">1</ref></content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Subsections (a) through (h) of section 358a (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1358a</ref>).<sup>1</sup></content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Subsections (a), (b), (d), and (e) of section 358d (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1359</ref>).<sup>1</sup></content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Part VII of subtitle B of title III (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1359aa–135</ref>9jj).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> In the case of peanuts, part I of subtitle C of title III (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1361–136</ref>8).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> In the case of upland cotton, section 377 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1377</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> Subtitle D of title III (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1379a–137</ref>9j).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> Title IV (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1401–140</ref>7).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agricultural Act of 1949</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Suspensions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The following provisions of the Agricultural Act of 1949 [<ref>7 U.S.C. 1421</ref> et seq.] shall not be applicable to the 1996 through 2002 crops of loan commodities, peanuts, and sugar and shall not be applicable to milk during the period beginning on <date date="1996-04-04">April 4, 1996</date>, and ending on <date date="2002-12-31">December 31, 2002</date>:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Section 101 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1441</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Section 103(a) (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1444(a)</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Section 105 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1444b</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Section 107 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1445a</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Section 110 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1445e</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Section 112 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1445g</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> Section 115 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1445k</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> Section 201 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1446</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> Title III (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1447–144</ref>9).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> Title IV (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1421–143</ref>3d), other than sections 404, 412, and 416 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1424</ref>, 1429, and 1431).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> Title V (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1461–146</ref>9).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(L)</num>
<content> Title VI (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1471–147</ref>1j).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Repeals</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The following provisions of the Agricultural Act of 1949 [<ref>7 U.S.C. 1421</ref> et seq.] are repealed:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Section 101B (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1441–2</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Section 103B (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1444–2</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Section 105B (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1444f</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Section 107B [<ref>7 U.S.C. 1445b–3a</ref>].</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Section 108B (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1445c–3</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Section 113 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1445h</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> Subsections (b) and (c) of section 114 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1445j</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> Sections 205, 206, and 207 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1446f</ref>, 1446g, and 1446h).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> Sections 406 and 427 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1426</ref> and 1433f).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Suspension of certain quota provisions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0"><ref>Section 1340 of this title</ref> shall not be applicable to the crops of wheat planted for harvest in the calendar years 1996 through 2002.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title I, § 171</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 937</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–171, title I, § 1602(d)</ref>, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 213</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7302.</num>
<heading> Effect of chapter</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect on prior crops</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as otherwise specifically provided in this chapter and notwithstanding any other provision of law, this chapter and the amendments made by this chapter shall not affect the authority of the Secretary to carry out a price support or production adjustment program for any of the 1991 through 1995 crops of an agricultural commodity established under a provision of law in effect immediately before <date date="1996-04-04">April 4, 1996</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Liability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A provision of this chapter or an amendment made by this chapter shall not affect the liability of any person under any provision of law as in effect before <date date="1996-04-04">April 4, 1996</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title I, § 172</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 938</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER VII—</num>
<heading>COMMISSION ON 21<inline class="small-caps">st</inline> CENTURY PRODUCTION AGRICULTURE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7311.</num>
<heading> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established a commission to be known as the “Commission on 21st Century Production Agriculture” (in this subchapter referred to as the “Commission”).</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title I, § 181</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 938</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7312.</num>
<heading> Composition</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Membership and appointment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Commission shall be composed of 11 members, appointed as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Three members shall be appointed by the President.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Four members shall be appointed by the Chairman of the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives in consultation with the ranking minority member of the Committee.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Four members shall be appointed by the Chairman of the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate in consultation with the ranking minority member of the Committee.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Qualifications</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">At least 1 of the members appointed under each of paragraphs (1), (2), and (3) of subsection (a) shall be an individual who is primarily involved in production agriculture. All other members of the Commission shall be appointed from among individuals having knowledge and experience in agricultural production, marketing, finance, or trade.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Term of members; vacancies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A member of the Commission shall be appointed for the life of the Commission. A vacancy on the Commission shall not affect its powers, but shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment was made.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Time for appointment; first meeting</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The members of the Commission shall be appointed not later than <date date="1997-10-01">October 1, 1997</date>. The Commission shall convene its first meeting to carry out its duties under this subchapter 30 days after 6 members of the Commission have been appointed.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Chairperson</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The chairperson of the Commission shall be designated jointly by the Chairman of the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Chairman of the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate from among the members of the Commission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title I, § 182</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 938</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7313.</num>
<heading> Comprehensive review of past and future of production agriculture</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initial review</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Commission shall conduct a comprehensive review of changes in the condition of production agriculture in the United States since <date date="1996-04-04">April 4, 1996</date>, and the extent to which the changes are the result of this chapter and the amendments made by this chapter. The review shall include the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> An assessment of the initial success of production flexibility contracts in supporting the economic viability of farming in the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> An assessment of economic risks to farms delineated by size of farm operation (such as small, medium, or large farms) and region of production.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> An assessment of the food security situation in the United States in the areas of trade, consumer prices, international competitiveness of United States production agriculture, food supplies, and humanitarian relief.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> An assessment of the changes in farmland values and agricultural producer incomes since <date date="1996-04-04">April 4, 1996</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> An assessment of the extent to which regulatory relief for agricultural producers has been enacted and implemented, including the application of cost/benefit principles in the issuance of agricultural regulations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> An assessment of the extent to which tax relief for agricultural producers has been enacted in the form of capital gains tax reductions, estate tax exemptions, and mechanisms to average tax loads over high- and low-income years.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> An assessment of the effect of any Federal Government interference in agricultural export markets, such as the imposition of trade embargoes, and the degree of implementation and success of international trade agreements and United States export programs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> An assessment of the likely effect of the sale, lease, or transfer of farm poundage quota for peanuts across State lines.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Subsequent review</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Commission shall conduct a comprehensive review of the future of production agriculture in the United States and the appropriate role of the Federal Government in support of production agriculture. The review shall include the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> An assessment of changes in the condition of production agriculture in the United States since the initial review conducted under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Identification of the appropriate future relationship of the Federal Government with production agriculture after 2002.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> An assessment of the personnel and infrastructure requirements of the Department of Agriculture necessary to support the future relationship of the Federal Government with production agriculture.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> An assessment of economic risks to farms delineated by size of farm operation (such as small, medium, or large farms) and region of production.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recommendations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In carrying out the subsequent review under subsection (b), the Commission shall develop specific recommendations for legislation to achieve the appropriate future relationship of the Federal Government with production agriculture identified under subsection (a)(2).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title I, § 183</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 939</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7314.</num>
<heading> Reports</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report on initial review</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than <date date="1998-06-01">June 1, 1998</date>, the Commission shall submit to the President, the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate a report containing the results of the initial review conducted under <ref>section 7313(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report on subsequent review</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than <date date="2001-01-01">January 1, 2001</date>, the Commission shall submit to the President and the congressional committees specified in subsection (a) a report containing the results of the subsequent review conducted under <ref>section 7313(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title I, § 184</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 940</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7315.</num>
<heading> Powers</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Hearings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission may, for the purpose of carrying out this subchapter, conduct such hearings, sit and act at such times, take such testimony, and receive such evidence, as the Commission considers appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistance from other agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission may secure directly from any department or agency of the Federal Government such information as may be necessary for the Commission to carry out its duties under this subchapter. On the request of the chairperson of the Commission, the head of the department or agency shall, to the extent permitted by law, furnish such information to the Commission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Mail</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission may use the United States mails in the same manner and under the same conditions as the departments and agencies of the Federal Government.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistance from Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall provide to the Commission appropriate office space and such reasonable administrative and support services as the Commission may request.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title I, § 185</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 940</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7316.</num>
<heading> Commission procedures</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Meetings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission shall meet on a regular basis (as determined by the chairperson) and at the call of the chairperson or a majority of its members.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Quorum</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A majority of the members of the Commission shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title I, § 186</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 941</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7317.</num>
<heading> Personnel matters</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each member of the Commission shall serve without compensation, but shall be allowed travel expenses including per diem in lieu of subsistence, as authorized by <ref>section 5703 of title 5</ref>, when engaged in the performance of Commission duties.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Staff</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Commission shall appoint a staff director, who shall be paid at a rate not to exceed the maximum rate of basic pay under <ref>section 5376 of title 5</ref>, and such professional and clerical personnel as may be reasonable and necessary to enable the Commission to carry out its duties under this subchapter without regard to the provisions of title 5 governing appointments in the competitive service, and without regard to the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of such title, or any other provision of law, relating to the number, classification, and General Schedule rates.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on compensation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">No employee appointed under this subsection (other than the staff director) may be compensated at a rate to exceed the maximum rate applicable to level GS–15 of the General Schedule.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Detailed personnel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On the request of the chairperson of the Commission, the head of any department or agency of the Federal Government is authorized to detail, without reimbursement, any personnel of the department or agency to the Commission to assist the Commission in carrying out its duties under this section. The detail of any individual may not result in the interruption or loss of civil service status or other privilege of the individual.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title I, § 187</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 941</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7318.</num>
<heading> Termination of Commission</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission shall terminate on submission of the final report required by <ref>section 7314 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title I, § 188</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 941</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER VIII—</num>
<heading>MISCELLANEOUS COMMODITY PROVISIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7331.</num>
<heading> Options pilot program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Pilot programs authorized</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Until <date date="2002-12-31">December 31, 2002</date>, the Secretary of Agriculture may conduct a pilot program for 1 or more agricultural commodities supported under this chapter to ascertain whether futures and options contracts can provide producers with reasonable protection from the financial risks of fluctuations in price, yield, and income inherent in the production and marketing of the commodities. The pilot program shall be an alternative to other related programs of the Department of Agriculture.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Distribution of pilot program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For each agricultural commodity included in the pilot program, the Secretary may operate the pilot program in not more than 300 counties, except that not more than 25 of the counties may be located in any 1 State. The pilot program for a commodity shall not be operated in any county for more than 3 of the 1996 through 2002 calendar years.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible participants</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In operating the pilot program, the Secretary may enter into contract with a producer who—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> is eligible for a production flexibility contract, a marketing assistance loan, or other assistance under this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> volunteers to participate in the pilot program during any calendar year in which a county in which the farm of the producer is located is included in the pilot program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> operates a farm located in a county selected for the pilot program; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> meets such other eligibility requirements as the Secretary may establish.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice to producers</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall provide notice to each producer participating in the pilot program that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the participation of the producer is voluntary; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> neither the United States, the Commodity Credit Corporation, the Federal Crop Insurance Corporation, the Department of Agriculture, nor any other Federal agency is authorized to guarantee that participants in the pilot program will be better or worse off financially as a result of participation in the pilot program than the producer would have been if the producer had not participated in the pilot program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contracts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall set forth in each contract under the pilot program the terms and conditions for participation in the pilot program and the notice required by subsection (d).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible markets</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Trades for futures and options contracts under the pilot program shall be carried out on commodity futures and options markets designated as contract markets under the Commodity Exchange Act (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1</ref> et seq.).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recordkeeping</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A producer participating in the pilot program shall compile, maintain, and submit (or authorize the compilation, maintenance, and submission) of such documentation as the regulations governing the pilot program require.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of Commodity Credit Corporation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall fund and operate the pilot program through the Commodity Credit Corporation, except that the amount of Commodity Credit Corporation funds used to carry out this section shall not exceed, to the maximum extent practicable, $9,000,000 for fiscal year 2001, $15,000,000 for fiscal year 2002, and $2,000,000 for fiscal year 2003. To the maximum extent practicable, the Secretary shall operate the pilot program in a budget neutral manner.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title I, § 191</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 941</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–224, title I, § 134</ref>, <date date="2000-06-20">June 20, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 388</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7332.</num>
<heading> Risk management education</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In consultation with the Commodity Futures Trading Commission, the Secretary shall provide such education in management of the financial risks inherent in the production and marketing of agricultural commodities as the Secretary considers appropriate. As part of such educational activities, the Secretary may develop and implement programs to facilitate the participation of agricultural producers in commodity futures trading programs, forward contracting options, and insurance protection programs by assisting and training producers in the usage of such programs. In implementing this authority, the Secretary may use existing research and extension authorities and resources of the Department of Agriculture.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title I, § 192</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 942</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7333.</num>
<heading> Administration and operation of noninsured crop assistance program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Operation and administration of program</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coverages</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In the case of an eligible crop described in paragraph (2), the Secretary of Agriculture shall operate a noninsured crop disaster assistance program to provide coverages based on individual yields (other than for value-loss crops) equivalent to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> catastrophic risk protection available under section 508(b) of the Federal Crop Insurance Act (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1508(b)</ref>); or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> except in the case of crops and grasses used for grazing, additional coverage available under subsections (c) and (h) of section 508 of that Act (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1508</ref>) that does not exceed 65 percent, as described in subsection (<i>l</i>).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary shall carry out this section through the Farm Service Agency (referred to in this section as the “Agency”).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Data collection and sharing</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Secretary shall coordinate with the Administrator of the Risk Management Agency on the type and format of data received under the noninsured crop disaster assistance program that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> best facilitates the use of that data in developing policies or plans of insurance offered under the Federal Crop Insurance Act (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1501</ref> et seq.); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> ensures the availability of that data on a regular basis.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Secretary shall coordinate between the agencies of the Department that provide programs or services to farmers and ranchers that are potentially eligible for the noninsured crop disaster assistance program under this section—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> to make available coverage under—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the fee waiver under subsection (k)(2); or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the premium discount under subsection (<i>l</i>)(3); and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> to share eligibility information to reduce paperwork and avoid duplication.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible crops</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Subject to subparagraph (B), in this section, the term “eligible crop” means each commercial crop or other agricultural commodity that is produced for food or fiber (except livestock) for which catastrophic risk protection under subsection (b) of section 508 of the Federal Crop Insurance Act (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1508</ref>) and additional coverage under subsections (c) and (h) of such section are not available or, if such coverage is available, it is only available under a policy that provides coverage for specific intervals based on weather indexes or under a whole farm plan of insurance.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Crops specifically included</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “eligible crop” shall include floricultural, ornamental nursery, and Christmas tree crops, turfgrass sod, seed crops, aquaculture (including ornamental fish), sea grass and sea oats, camelina, sweet sorghum, biomass sorghum, and industrial crops (including those grown expressly for the purpose of producing a feedstock for renewable biofuel, renewable electricity, or biobased products).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Combination of similar types or varieties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">At the option of the Secretary, all types or varieties of a crop or commodity, described in subparagraphs (A) and (B), may be considered to be a single eligible crop under this section.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cause of loss</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To qualify for assistance under this section, the losses of the noninsured commodity shall be due to drought, flood, or other natural disaster, as determined by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program reduction in benefits relating to crop production on native sod</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition of native sod</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In this paragraph, the term “native sod” means land—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> on which the plant cover is composed principally of native grasses, grasslike plants, forbs, or shrubs suitable for grazing and browsing; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> that has never been tilled, or the producer cannot substantiate that the ground has ever been tilled, for the production of an annual crop as of the date of enactment of this paragraph.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reduction in benefits</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(I)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agricultural Act of 2014</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent4">During the first 4 crop years of planting, as determined by the Secretary, native sod acreage that has been tilled for the production of an annual crop during the period beginning on <date date="2014-02-08">February 8, 2014</date>, and ending on <date date="2018-12-20">December 20, 2018</date>, shall be subject to a reduction in benefits under this section as described in this subparagraph.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(II)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Subsequent years</heading>
<chapeau class="indent4">Native sod acreage that has been tilled for the production of an eligible crop after <date date="2018-12-20">December 20, 2018</date>, shall be subject to a reduction in benefits under this section as described in this subparagraph for not more than any 4 crop years—</chapeau>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> during the first 10 crop years after the initial tillage; and</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> during which a crop on that acreage is enrolled under subsection (<i>l</i>)(2) or (k).</content>
</item>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> De minimis acreage exemption</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The Secretary shall exempt areas of 5 acres or less from clause (i).</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reduction</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">For purposes of the reduction in benefits for the acreage described in clause (i)—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the approved yield shall be determined by using a yield equal to 65 percent of the county expected yield; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the service fees or premiums for crops planted on native sod shall be equal to 200 percent of the amount determined in subsections <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002333">1</ref> (<i>l</i>)(2) or (k), as applicable, but in no case shall exceed the amount determined in subsection (<i>l</i>)(2)(B)(ii).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">This paragraph shall only apply to native sod acreage in the States of Minnesota, Iowa, North Dakota, South Dakota, Montana, and Nebraska.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application for noninsured crop disaster assistance</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Timely application</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To be eligible for assistance under this section, a producer shall submit an application for noninsured crop disaster assistance at a local office of the Department. The application shall be in such form, contain such information, and be submitted by an appropriate deadline before the beginning of the coverage period, as determined by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Records</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To be eligible for assistance under this section, a producer shall provide annually to the Secretary records of crop acreage, acreage yields, and production for each crop, as required by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Acreage reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A producer shall provide annual reports on acreage planted or prevented from being planted, as required by the Secretary, by the designated acreage reporting date for the crop and location as established by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Streamlined submission process</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall establish a streamlined process for the submission of records and acreage reports under paragraphs (2) and (3) for diverse production systems such as those typical of urban production systems, other small-scale production systems, and direct-to-consumer production systems.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Loss requirements</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cause</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To be eligible for assistance under this section, a producer of an eligible crop shall have suffered a loss of a noninsured commodity as the result of a cause described in subsection (a)(3).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistance</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">On making a determination described in subsection (a)(3), the Secretary shall provide assistance under this section to producers of an eligible crop that have suffered a loss as a result of the cause described in subsection (a)(3).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Aquaculture producers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">On making a determination described in subsection (a)(3) for aquaculture producers, the Secretary shall provide assistance under this section to aquaculture producers from all losses related to drought.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prevented planting</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subject to paragraph (1), the Secretary shall make a prevented planting noninsured crop disaster assistance payment if the producer is prevented from planting more than 35 percent of the acreage intended for the eligible crop because of drought, flood, or other natural disaster, as determined by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Area trigger</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall provide assistance to individual producers without any requirement of an area loss.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall make available to a producer eligible for noninsured assistance under this section a payment computed by multiplying—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the producer’s share of the total acres devoted to the eligible crop; by</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the quantity that is less than 50 percent of the approved yield for the crop, as determined by the Secretary; by</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the case of each of the 1996 through 1998 crop years, 60 percent of the average market price for the crop (or any comparable coverage determined by the Secretary); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of each of the 1999 and subsequent crop years, 55 percent of the average market price for the crop (or any comparable coverage determined by the Secretary); by</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> a payment rate for the type of crop (as determined by the Secretary) that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> in the case of a crop that is produced with a significant and variable harvesting expense, reflects the decreasing cost incurred in the production cycle for the crop that is—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> harvested;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> planted but not harvested; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> prevented from being planted because of drought, flood, or other natural disaster (as determined by the Secretary); and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of a crop that is not produced with a significant and variable harvesting expense, as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Yield determinations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall establish approved yields for purposes of providing noninsured crop disaster assistance under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Actual production history</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary shall determine an approved yield using the actual production history of the producer over a period of not less than the 4 previous consecutive crop years and not more than 10 consecutive crop years.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Calculation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Subject to paragraph (3), the approved yield for the year in which noninsured crop disaster assistance is sought shall be equal to the average of the actual production history of the producer during the period considered.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assignment of yield</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If a producer does not submit adequate documentation of production history to determine a crop yield under paragraph (2), the Secretary shall assign to the producer a yield equal to not less than 65 percent of the county expected yield (adjusted to reflect actual production reflected in the records acceptable to the Secretary for continuous years), as specified in regulations issued by the Secretary based on production history requirements.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition on assigned yields in certain counties</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Documentation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">If sufficient data are available to demonstrate that the acreage of a crop in a county for the crop year has increased by more than 100 percent over any year in the preceding 7 crop years or, if data are not available, if the acreage of the crop in the county has increased significantly from the previous crop years, a producer must provide such detailed documentation of production costs, acres planted, and yield for the crop year for which benefits are being claimed as is required by the Secretary. If the Secretary determines that the documentation provided is not sufficient, the Secretary may require documenting proof that the crop, had the crop been harvested, could have been marketed at a reasonable price.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), a producer who produces a crop on a farm located in a county described in clause (i) may not obtain an assigned yield.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">A crop or a producer shall not be subject to this subsection if—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the planted acreage of the producer for the crop has been inspected by a third party acceptable to the Secretary; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the County Executive Director and the State Executive Director recommend an exemption from the requirement to the Administrator of the Agency; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the Administrator approves the recommendation.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on receipt of subsequent assigned yield</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A producer who receives an assigned yield for the current year of a natural disaster because required production records were not submitted to the local office of the Department shall not be eligible for an assigned yield for the year of the next natural disaster unless the required production records of the previous 1 or more years (as applicable) are provided to the local office.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Yield variations due to different farming practices</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall ensure that noninsured crop disaster assistance accurately reflects significant yield variations due to different farming practices, such as between irrigated and nonirrigated acreage.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contract payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A producer who has received a guaranteed payment for production, as opposed to delivery, of a crop pursuant to a contract shall have the production of the producer adjusted upward by the amount of the production equal to the amount of the contract payment received.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of Commodity Credit Corporation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may use the funds of the Commodity Credit Corporation to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exclusions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Noninsured crop disaster assistance under this section shall not cover losses due to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the neglect or malfeasance of the producer;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the failure of the producer to reseed to the same crop in those areas and under such circumstances where it is customary to reseed; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the failure of the producer to follow good farming practices, as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payment and income limitations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In this subsection, the terms “legal entity” and “person” have the meanings given those terms in <ref>section 1308(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payment limitation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The total amount of payments received, directly or indirectly, by a person or legal entity (excluding a joint venture or general partnership) for any crop year may not exceed—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the case of catastrophic coverage under subsection (c), $125,000; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of additional coverage under subsection (<i>l</i>), $300,000.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on multiple benefits for same loss</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), if a producer who is eligible to receive benefits under this section is also eligible to receive assistance for the same loss under any other program administered by the Secretary, the producer shall be required to elect whether to receive benefits under this section or under the other program, but not both.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Subparagraph (A) shall not apply to emergency loans under subtitle C of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1961</ref> et seq.).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adjusted gross income limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A person or legal entity that has an average adjusted gross income in excess of the average adjusted gross income limitation applicable under section 1308–3a(b)(1)(A) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002334">2</ref> of this title, or a successor provision, shall not be eligible to receive noninsured crop disaster assistance under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary shall issue regulations prescribing such rules as the Secretary determines necessary—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to ensure a fair and equitable application of <ref>section 1308 of this title</ref>, the general payment limitation regulations of the Secretary, and the limitations established under this subsection; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to ensure that payments under this section are attributed to a person or legal entity (excluding a joint venture or general partnership) in accordance with the terms and conditions of sections 1308 through 1308–3a of this title, as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(k)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Service fee</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">To be eligible to receive assistance for an eligible crop for a crop year under this section, a producer shall pay to the Secretary (at the time at which the producer submits the application under subsection (b)(1)) a service fee for the eligible crop in an amount that is equal to the lesser of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> $325 per crop per county; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> $825 per producer per county, but not to exceed a total of $1,950 per producer.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Waiver</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall waive the service fee required under paragraph (1) in the case of a limited resource, beginning, or socially disadvantaged farmer, as defined by the Secretary, or a veteran farmer or rancher (as defined in <ref>section 2279(a) of this title</ref>).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall deposit service fees collected under this subsection in the Commodity Credit Corporation Fund.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(l)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payment equivalent to additional coverage</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary shall make available noninsured assistance under this subsection (other than for crops and grasses used for grazing) at a payment amount that is equivalent to an indemnity for additional coverage under subsections (c) and (h) of section 508 of the Federal Crop Insurance Act (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1508</ref>) and equal to the product obtained by multiplying—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the producer’s share of the total acres devoted to the crop;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> the amount that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> the additional coverage yield, which shall be equal to the product obtained by multiplying—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> an amount not less than 50 percent nor more than 65 percent, as elected by the producer and specified in 5-percent increments; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the approved yield for the crop, as determined by the Secretary; exceeds</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the actual yield;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> 100 percent of the average market price, contract price, or other premium price (such as a local, organic, or direct market price, as elected by the producer) for the crop, as determined by the Secretary; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> a payment rate for the type of crop, as determined by the Secretary, that reflects—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> in the case of a crop that is produced with a significant and variable harvesting expense, the decreasing cost incurred in the production cycle for the crop that is, as applicable—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> harvested;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> planted but not harvested; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> prevented from being planted because of drought, flood, or other natural disaster, as determined by the Secretary; or</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in the case of a crop that is produced without a significant and variable harvesting expense, such rate as shall be determined by the Secretary.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Service fee and premium</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">To be eligible to receive a payment under this subsection, a producer shall pay—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the service fee required by subsection (k); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> the lesser of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> the sum of the premiums for each eligible crop, with the premium for each eligible crop obtained by multiplying—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the number of acres devoted to the eligible crop;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the yield, as determined by the Secretary under subsection (e);</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> the coverage level elected by the producer;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> the average market price, as determined by the Secretary;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(V)</num>
<content> a 5.25-percent premium fee; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(VI)</num>
<content> the producer’s share of the crop; or</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> the product obtained by multiplying—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> a 5.25-percent premium fee; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the applicable payment limit.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limited resource, beginning, veteran, and socially disadvantaged farmers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The coverage made available under this subsection shall be available to limited resource, beginning, and socially disadvantaged farmers, as determined by the Secretary, and veteran farmers or ranchers (as defined in <ref>section 2279(a) of this title</ref>) in exchange for a premium that is 50 percent of the premium determined under paragraph (2).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title I, § 196</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 947</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. A, § 101(a) [title VIII, § 803(b)]</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681</ref>, 2681–38; <ref>Pub. L. 106–224, title I, § 109</ref>, <date date="2000-06-20">June 20, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 371</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–171, title X, § 10101</ref>, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 488</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title I, § 1603(f)(1)</ref>, title XII, §§ 12020(b), 12025(b), 12027, 12028, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1010</ref>, 1381, 1390; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title I, § 1603(f)(1), title XII, §§ 12020(b), 12025(b), 12027, 12028, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1739, 2143, 2152; <ref>Pub. L. 113–79, title XI, § 11014(b)</ref>, title XII, § 12305(a), <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 962</ref>, 986; <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title I, § 1601</ref>, title XII, § 12306(f), <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4523</ref>, 4970.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7334.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title II, § 2814</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4602</ref></heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>