<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 55A—</num>
<heading>DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE ADVISORY COMMITTEES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2281.</num>
<heading> Congressional declaration of purpose</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes of this chapter are to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> require strict financial and program accounting by advisory committees of the Department of Agriculture;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> assure balance and objectivity in the membership of such advisory committees; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> prevent the formation or continuation of unnecessary advisory committees by the Department of Agriculture.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–113, title XVIII, § 1801</ref>, <date date="1977-09-29">Sept. 29, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 1041</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–98, title XI, § 1116(a)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-22">Dec. 22, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1270</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2282.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">When used in this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Agriculture of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “Department of Agriculture” means the United States Department of Agriculture; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “advisory committee” means any committee, board, commission, council, conference, panel, task force, or other similar group, or any subcommittee or other subgroup thereof that is established or utilized by the Department of Agriculture in the interest of obtaining advice or recommendations for the President or the Department of Agriculture, except that such term excludes any committee which (A) is composed wholly of full-time officers or employees of the Federal Government, (B) is established by statute or reorganization plan, or (C) is established by the President.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–113, title XVIII, § 1802</ref>, <date date="1977-09-29">Sept. 29, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 1041</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–98, title XI, § 1116(a)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-22">Dec. 22, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1270</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2283.</num>
<heading> Membership on advisory committees</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Simultaneous service</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No person other than an officer or employee of the Department of Agriculture may serve simultaneously on more than one advisory committee, unless authorized by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Service by more than one officer or employee of corporation or non-Federal entity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not more than one officer or employee of any corporation or other non-Federal entity, including all subsidiaries and affiliates thereof, may serve on the same advisory committee at any one time, unless authorized by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Maximum length</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No person other than an officer or employee of the Department of Agriculture may serve for more than six consecutive years on an advisory committee, unless authorized by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–113, title XVIII, § 1803</ref>, <date date="1977-09-29">Sept. 29, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 1041</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–98, title XI, § 1116(a)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-22">Dec. 22, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1270</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2284.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 105–362, title I, § 101(c)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-10">Nov. 10, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3281</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2285.</num>
<heading> Budget prohibitions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No advisory committee may expend funds in excess of its estimated annual operating costs by more than 10 per centum or $500, whichever is greater, until it provides the Secretary with an explanation of the need for the additional expenditure and the Secretary approves such additional expenditure.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–113, title XVIII, § 1805</ref>, <date date="1977-09-29">Sept. 29, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 1042</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–98, title XI, § 1116(a)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-22">Dec. 22, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1271</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2286.</num>
<heading> Termination of committees</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall terminate any advisory committee upon a finding that any such advisory committee—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> has expended funds in excess of its estimated annual operating costs by more than 10 per centum or $500, whichever is greater, without the prior approval of the Secretary pursuant to the provisions of <ref>section 2285 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> has failed to file all reports required under the provisions of chapter 10 of title 5 or this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> has failed to meet for two consecutive years;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> is responsible for functions that otherwise would be or should be performed by Federal employees; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> does not serve or has ceased to serve an essential public function.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–113, title XVIII, § 1806</ref>, <date date="1977-09-29">Sept. 29, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 1042</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–98, title XI, § 1116(a)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-22">Dec. 22, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1271</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(a)(30)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4308</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 2287 to 2289.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
</chapter>