<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 33—</num>
<heading>FARM TENANCY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1000.</num>
<heading> Short title</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Sections 1001 to 1006, 1006c to 1006e, 1007, 1008 to 1010, 1011, 1012, and 1013 to 1029 of this title may be cited as “The Bankhead-Jones Farm Tenant Act”.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 22, 1937, ch. 517</ref>, <ref>50 Stat. 522</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>TENANT PURCHASE LOANS AND MORTGAGE INSURANCE</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 1001 to 1006.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 87–128, title III, § 341(a)</ref>, <date date="1961-08-08">Aug. 8, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 318</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1006a.</num>
<heading> Loans to homestead or desertland entrymen and purchasers of lands in reclamation projects; security; first repayment installment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture is authorized to make a loan or loans for any purpose authorized by and in accordance with the terms of the Bankhead-Jones Farm Tenant Act, as amended, or the Act of <date date="1937-08-28">August 28, 1937</date>, as amended, to any person eligible for assistance under said Acts who has made or makes a homestead or desertland entry on public land or who has contracted for or contracts for the purchase of other land of the United States in a reclamation project pursuant to the applicable provisions of the homestead and reclamation laws. Any such loans required by the Secretary of Agriculture or by law to be secured by a real-estate mortgage may be secured by a mortgage contract which shall create a lien against the land in favor of the United States acting through the Secretary of Agriculture and any patent thereafter issued shall recite the existence of such lien. The first installment for the repayment of any such loan or any other loan made under the Bankhead-Jones Farm Tenant Act, as amended, or the Act of <date date="1937-08-28">August 28, 1937</date>, as amended, to the owner of a newly irrigated farm in a reclamation project or to an entryman under the desertland laws, may be deferred for a period of not to exceed two years from the date of the first advance under such loan.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Oct. 19, 1949, ch. 697, § 1</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 883</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–419, title VI, § 602</ref>, <date date="1972-08-30">Aug. 30, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 675</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1006b.</num>
<heading> Cancellation of entry or purchase upon loan default; entry or resale; conditions; satisfaction of indebtedness</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any entry or purchase contract land with respect to which a loan is made under the authority of this section and <ref>section 1006a of this title</ref> shall be subject to cancellation by the Secretary of the Interior as provided by existing law or upon request of the Secretary of Agriculture whenever default occurs in the terms, conditions, covenants, or obligations contained in the mortgage. After cancellation or relinquishment of an entry or purchase contract, land on which there is a mortgage lien, pursuant to the provisions of said sections, shall thereafter, except as hereinafter provided, only be open to entry or resale to persons eligible for both an original entry or purchase contract and an original loan. Such entry or resale shall be subject to the outstanding balance of any amounts due the United States with respect to such land or such portion thereof as may be determined by the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior, or their delegates, to be within the entryman’s or purchaser’s ability to pay on the basis of the long-time earning capacity of the land. If no entry or purchase is made within one year after the cancellation or relinquishment of a prior entry or purchase of land on which there is such a mortgage lien, the land shall be disposed of by the Secretary of Agriculture on terms consistent with the provisions of section 1017 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002127">1</ref> of this title, for the satisfaction of the indebtedness secured by the mortgage, subject, however, to other outstanding charges on the land due the United States, and the purchaser of such land shall be entitled to the issuance of patent or deed upon the completion of all requirements with respect to the payment of such charges.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Oct. 19, 1949, ch. 697, § 2</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 883</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 1006c to 1006e.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 87–128, title III, § 341(a)</ref>, <date date="1961-08-08">Aug. 8, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 318</ref></heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>OPERATING LOANS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1007.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 87–128, title III, § 341(a)</ref>, <date date="1961-08-08">Aug. 8, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 318</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1007a.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 1008, 1009.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 87–128, title III, § 341(a)</ref>, <date date="1961-08-08">Aug. 8, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 318</ref></heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>LAND CONSERVATION AND LAND UTILIZATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1010.</num>
<heading> Land conservation and land utilization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized and directed to develop a program of land conservation and land utilization, in order thereby to correct maladjustments in land use, and thus assist in controlling soil erosion, reforestation, preserving natural resources, protecting fish and wildlife, developing and protecting recreational facilities, mitigating floods, preventing impairment of dams and reservoirs, developing energy resources, conserving surface and subsurface moisture, protecting the watersheds of navigable streams, and protecting the public lands, health, safety, and welfare, but not to build industrial parks or establish private industrial or commercial enterprises.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 22, 1937, ch. 517</ref>, title III, § 31, <ref>50 Stat. 525</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–703, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1962-09-27">Sept. 27, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 607</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–796, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1966-11-08">Nov. 8, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1478</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–98, title XV, § 1513</ref>, <date date="1981-12-22">Dec. 22, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1333</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1010a.</num>
<heading> Soil, water, and related resource data</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In recognition of the increasing need for soil, water, and related source data for land conservation, use, and development, for guidance of community development for a balanced rural-urban growth, for identification of prime agriculture producing areas that should be protected, and for use in protecting the quality of the environment, the Secretary of Agriculture is directed to carry out a land inventory and monitoring program to include, but not be limited to, studies and surveys of erosion and sediment damages, flood plain identification and utilization, land use changes and trends, and degradation of the environment resulting from improper use of soil, water, and related resources.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–419, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="1972-08-30">Aug. 30, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 670</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–470, title I, § 102(c)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-19">Oct. 19, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2237</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1011.</num>
<heading> Powers of Secretary of Agriculture</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">To effectuate the program provided for in <ref>section 1010 of this title</ref>, the Secretary is authorized—</chapeau>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 87–703, title I, § 102(b)</ref>, <date date="1962-09-27">Sept. 27, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 607</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> To protect, improve, develop, and administer any property so acquired and to construct such structures thereon as may be necessary to adapt it to its most beneficial use.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> To sell, exchange, lease, or otherwise dispose of, with or without a consideration, any property so acquired, under such terms and conditions as he deems will best accomplish the purposes of this subchapter, but any sale, exchange, or grant shall be made only to public authorities and agencies and only on condition that the property is used for public purposes: <i>Provided, however</i>, That an exchange may be made with private owners and with subdivisions or agencies of State governments in any case where the Secretary of Agriculture finds that such exchange would not conflict with the purposes of the Act, and that the value of the property received in exchange is substantially equal to that of the property conveyed. The Secretary may recommend to the President other Federal, State, or Territorial agencies to administer such property, together with the conditions of use and administration which will best serve the purposes of a land-conservation and land-utilization program, and the President is authorized to transfer such property to such agencies.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> With respect to any land, or any interest therein, acquired by, or transferred to, the Secretary for the purposes of this subchapter, to make dedications or grants, in his discretion, for any public purpose, and to grant licenses and easements upon such terms as he deems reasonable.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<chapeau> To cooperate with Federal, State, territorial, and other public agencies and local nonprofit organizations in developing plans for a program of land conservation and land utilization or plans for the conservation, development and utilization of water for aquacultural purposes, to assist in carrying out such plans by means of loans to State and local public agencies and local nonprofit organizations designated by the State legislature or the Governor, to conduct surveys and investigations relating to conditions and factors affecting, and the methods of accomplishing most effectively the purposes of this subchapter, and to disseminate information concerning these activities. As used in this subsection, the term “aquaculture” means the culture or husbandry of aquatic animals or plants. Loans to State and local public agencies and to local nonprofit organizations shall be made only if such plans have been submitted to, and not disapproved within 45 days by, the State agency having supervisory responsibility over such plans, or by the Governor if there is no such State agency. No appropriation shall be made for any single loan under this subsection in excess of $500,000 unless such loan has been approved by resolutions adopted by the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate and the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives. A loan under this subsection shall be made under a contract that provides, under such terms and conditions as the Secretary considers appropriate, for the repayment of the loan in not more than 30 years, with interest at a rate not to exceed the current market yield for outstanding municipal obligations with remaining periods to maturity comparable to the average maturity for the loan, adjusted to the nearest ⅛ of 1 percent. Repayment of principal and interest on such loans shall begin within 5 years. In providing assistance for carrying out plans developed under this subchapter, the Secretary shall be authorized to bear such proportionate share of the costs of installing any works of improvement applicable to public water-based fish and wildlife or recreational development as is determined by him to be equitable in consideration of national needs and assistance authorized for similar purposes under other Federal programs: <i>Provided</i>, That all engineering and other technical assistance costs relating to such development may be borne by the Secretary: <i>Provided further</i>, That when a State or other public agency or local nonprofit organization participating in a plan developed under this subchapter agrees to operate and maintain any reservoir or other area included in a plan for public waterbased fish and wildlife or recreational development, the Secretary shall be authorized to bear not to exceed one-half of the costs of (a) the land, easements, or rights-of-way acquired or to be acquired by the State or other public agency or local nonprofit organization for such reservoir or other area, and (b) minimum basic facilities needed for public health and safety, access to, and use of such reservoir or other area for such purposes: <i>Provided further</i>, That in no event shall the Secretary share any portion of the cost of installing more than one such work of improvement for each seventy-five thousand acres in any project; and that any such public water-based fish and wildlife or recreational development shall be consistent with any existing comprehensive statewide outdoor recreation plan found adequate for purposes of chapter 2003 of title 54; and that such cost-sharing assistance for any such development shall be authorized only if the Secretary determines that it cannot be provided under other existing authority.</chapeau>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall also be authorized in providing assistance for carrying out plans developed under this subchapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> To provide technical and other assistance, and to pay for any storage of water for present or anticipated future demands or needs for rural community water supply included in any reservoir structure constructed or modified pursuant to such plans: <i>Provided</i>, That the cost of water storage to meet future demands may not exceed 30 per centum of the total estimated cost of such reservoir structure and the public agency or local nonprofit organization shall give reasonable assurances, and there is evidence, that such demands for the use of such storage will be made within a period of time which will permit repayment of the cost of such water supply storage within the life of the reservoir structure: <i>Provided further</i>, That the public agency or local nonprofit organization prior to initiation or construction or modification of any reservoir structure including water supply storage, make provision satisfactory to the Secretary to pay for not less than 50 per centum of the cost of storage for present water supply demands, and all of the cost of storage for anticipated future demands: <i>And provided further</i>, That the cost to be borne by the public agency or local nonprofit organization for anticipated future demands may be repaid within the life of the reservoir structure but in no event to exceed fifty years after the reservoir structure is first used for the storage of water for anticipated future water supply demands except that (1) no payment on account of such cost need be made until such supply is first used, and (2) no interest shall be charged on such cost until such supply is first used, but in no case shall the interest-free period exceed ten years. The interest rate used for purposes of computing the interest on the unpaid balance shall be the average rate, as determined by the Secretary of the Treasury, payable by the Treasury upon its marketable public obligations outstanding at the beginning of the fiscal year in which the advancement for such water supply is first made, which are neither due nor callable for redemption for fifteen years from date of issue;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> To provide, for the benefit of rural communities, technical and other assistance and such proportionate share of the costs of installing measures and facilities for water quality management, for the control and abatement of agriculture-related pollution, for the disposal of solid wastes, and for the storage of water in reservoirs, farm ponds, or other impoundments, together with necessary water withdrawal appurtenances, for rural fire protection, as is determined by the Secretary to be equitable in consideration of national needs and assistance authorized for similar purposes under other Federal programs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> To make such rules and regulations as he deems necessary to prevent trespasses and otherwise regulate the use and occupancy of property acquired by, or transferred to, the Secretary for the purposes of this subchapter, in order to conserve and utilize it or advance the purposes of this subchapter. Any violation of such rules and regulations shall be punished by a fine of not more than $500 or imprisonment for not more than six months, or both. Any person charged with the violation of such rules and regulations may be tried and sentenced by any United States magistrate judge specially designated for that purpose by the court by which he was appointed, in the same manner and subject to the same conditions as provided for in section 3401(b) to (e) of title 18.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 22, 1937, ch. 517</ref>, title III, § 32, <ref>50 Stat. 525</ref>; <ref>July 28, 1942, ch. 531</ref>, <ref>56 Stat. 725</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–703, title I, § 102(b)</ref>, (c), <date date="1962-09-27">Sept. 27, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 607</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–869, § 7</ref>, <date date="1962-10-23">Oct. 23, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 1157</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–537</ref>, <date date="1964-08-31">Aug. 31, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 745</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–796, § 1(b)</ref>, <date date="1966-11-08">Nov. 8, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1478</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–578, title IV, § 402(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1968-10-17">Oct. 17, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1118</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–343</ref>, <date date="1970-07-18">July 18, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 439</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–419, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="1972-08-30">Aug. 30, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 669</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–113, title XV</ref>, §§ 1503(a), 1507, <date date="1977-09-29">Sept. 29, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 1021</ref>, 1022; <ref>Pub. L. 101–650, title III, § 321</ref>, <date date="1990-12-01">Dec. 1, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 5117</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–437, § 4(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4581</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title VII, § 791(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1151</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 5(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3263</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1012.</num>
<heading> Payments to counties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As soon as practicable after the end of each calendar year, the Secretary shall pay to the county in which any land is held by the Secretary under this subchapter, 25 per centum of the net revenues received by the Secretary from the use of the land during such year. In case the land is situated in more than one county, the amount to be paid shall be divided equitably among the respective counties. Payments to counties under this section shall be made on the condition that they are used for school or road purposes, or both. This section shall not be construed to apply to amounts received from the sale of land.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 22, 1937, ch. 517</ref>, title III, § 33, <ref>50 Stat. 526</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1012a.</num>
<heading> Townsites</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">When the Secretary of Agriculture determines that a tract of National Forest System land in Alaska or in the eleven contiguous Western States is located adjacent to or contiguous to an established community, and that transfer of such land would serve indigenous community objectives that outweigh the public objectives and values which would be served by maintaining such tract in Federal ownership, he may, upon application, set aside and designate as a townsite an area of not to exceed six hundred and forty acres of National Forest System land for any one application. After public notice, and satisfactory showing of need therefor by any county, city, or other local governmental subdivision, the Secretary may offer such area for sale to a governmental subdivision at a price not less than the fair market value thereof: <i>Provided, however</i>, That the Secretary may condition conveyances of townsites upon the enactment, maintenance, and enforcement of a valid ordinance which assures any land so conveyed will be controlled by the governmental subdivision so that use of the area will not interfere with the protection, management, and development of adjacent or contiguous National Forest System lands.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–569</ref>, <date date="1958-07-31">July 31, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 438</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–579, title II, § 213</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2760</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1013.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1013a.</num>
<heading> Benefits extended to Puerto Rico and Virgin Islands; “county” defined; payments to Governor or fiscal agent of county</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The provisions of this subchapter shall extend to Puerto Rico and the Virgin Islands. In the case of Alaska, Puerto Rico, and the Virgin Islands, the term “county” as used in this subchapter may be the entire area, or any subdivision thereof as may be determined by the Secretary, and payments under <ref>section 1012 of this title</ref> shall be made to the Governor or to the fiscal agent of such subdivision.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 22, 1937, ch. 517</ref>, title III, § 35, as added <ref>Pub. L. 87–128, title III, § 342</ref>, <date date="1961-08-08">Aug. 8, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 318</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 1014 to 1025.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 87–128, title III, § 341(a)</ref>, <date date="1961-08-08">Aug. 8, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 318</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1026.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645, § 21</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 862</ref>, eff. <date date="1948-09-01">Sept. 1, 1948</date></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 1027 to 1029.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 87–128, title III, § 341(a)</ref>, <date date="1961-08-08">Aug. 8, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 318</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1030.</num>
<heading> Consolidation of agricultural credit and service offices</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture and the Governor of the Farm Credit Administration are directed, wherever practicable, to make suitable arrangements whereby all field offices under their supervision or direction extending agricultural credit or furnishing agricultural services to farmers to utilize the same or adjacent offices to the end that eligible farmers in each locality will be enabled to obtain their agricultural credit and services at one central point.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 14, 1946, ch. 964, § 7</ref>, <ref>60 Stat. 1079</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1031.</num>
<heading> Conveyance of mineral rights with land</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any conveyance of real estate by the Government or any Government agency under this Act shall include all mineral rights.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 14, 1946, ch. 964, § 9</ref>, <ref>60 Stat. 1080</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1032.</num>
<heading> Transfer of rights and duties of Reconstruction Finance Corporation arising out of rehabilitation and farm tenancy loans to Secretary of the Treasury</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All rights, interests, obligations, and duties of the Reconstruction Finance Corporation arising out of loans made or authorized to be made to the Secretary of Agriculture for the purpose of making rural rehabilitation and farm tenancy loans in accordance with the Department of Agriculture Appropriation Act of 1947 and prior appropriations and loans under the Farmers Home Administration Act of 1946 are, as of the close of <date date="1947-06-30">June 30, 1947</date>, vested in the Secretary of the Treasury; the Reconstruction Finance Corporation is authorized and directed to transfer, as of the close of <date date="1947-06-30">June 30, 1947</date>, to the Secretary of the Treasury and the Secretary of the Treasury is authorized and directed to receive all loans outstanding on that date, plus accrued unpaid interest, theretofore made to the Secretary under the provisions of the Acts named above, and all notes and other evidences thereof and all obligations constituting the security therefor. The Secretary of the Treasury shall cancel notes of the Reconstruction Finance Corporation, and sums due and unpaid upon or in connection with such notes at the time of such cancellation, in an amount equal to the unpaid principal of the loans so transferred, plus accrued unpaid interest through <date date="1947-06-30">June 30, 1947</date>. Subsequent to <date date="1947-06-30">June 30, 1947</date>, the Reconstruction Finance Corporation shall make no further loans or advances to the Secretary and the Secretary of the Treasury is authorized and directed, in lieu of the Reconstruction Finance Corporation, to lend or advance to the Secretary, in accordance with the provisions of said Acts to any unobligated or unadvanced balances of the sums which the Reconstruction Finance Corporation has theretofore been authorized and directed to lend to the Secretary. For the purpose of making such loans or advances, the Secretary of the Treasury is authorized to use as a public-debt transaction the proceeds from the sale of any securities issued under chapter 31 of title 31, and the purposes for which securities may be issued under that chapter are extended to include such loans or advances to the Secretary of Agriculture. Repayments to the Secretary of Treasury on such loans or advances shall be treated as a public-debt transaction of the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 30, 1947, ch. 356</ref>, title I, § 1, <ref>61 Stat. 545</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1032a.</num>
<heading> Disbursing and certifying officers; exemption from liability for advances to defense relocation corporations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Comptroller General of the United States is authorized and directed to allow credit in the accounts of disbursing and certifying officers for advances made in good faith on behalf of the Department of Agriculture to defense relocation corporations and land purchasing associations.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 14, 1946, ch. 964, § 6</ref>, <ref>60 Stat. 1079</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1033.</num>
<heading> Sale of reserved mineral interests</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provisions of law, the Secretary of Agriculture (referred to in sections 1033 to 1035 and 1037 to 1039 of this title as the “Secretary”) is authorized and directed to sell, as provided in said sections, all mineral interests now owned by the United States, which have been reserved or acquired by it under any program heretofore administered by the Resettlement Administration, or the Farm Security Administration, or now administered by the Farmers Home Administration, except the program administered pursuant to sections 1010 to 1012 of this title and the program for the liquidation of labor camps pursuant to Public Law 298, Eightieth Congress.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Sept. 6, 1950, ch. 897, § 1</ref>, <ref>64 Stat. 769</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1034.</num>
<heading> Persons to whom mineral interests sold; conveyances</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Such mineral interests shall be sold only to private persons who shall apply therefor and who at the time of application are the owners of the surface of the land covered by the application. Applicants shall establish their title to the surface of the land covered by the application to the satisfaction of the Secretary at their own expense. Conveyances of mineral interests shall be by quitclaim deed executed by the Secretary or his delegate.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Sept. 6, 1950, ch. 897, § 2</ref>, <ref>64 Stat. 769</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1035.</num>
<heading> Sale of mineral interests; consideration; transfer of unsold interests to Secretary of the Interior</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In areas where the Secretary determines after consultation with the Department of the Interior and competent local authorities that there is no active mineral development or leasing, the mineral interests covered by a single application shall be sold for a consideration of $1. In other areas the mineral interests shall be sold at the fair market value thereof as determined by the Secretary after taking into consideration such appraisals as he deems necessary or appropriate. Area determinations made by the Secretary pursuant to this section may be revised from time to time and the consideration to be obtained for the mineral interests in connection with any particular tract of land shall be determined by the rule applicable to the area in which the tract is located at the time of the application therefor: <i>Provided</i>, That, in the event any mineral interests covered by sections 1033 to 1039 of this title are not sold as provided herein pursuant to application filed within seven years from <date date="1950-09-06">September 6, 1950</date>, or within seven years from the date of acquisition of the mineral interests of the United States, whichever date is later, the Secretary shall forthwith transfer title to such mineral interests, with the exception of those which were a part of or derived from the assets transferred pursuant to transfer agreements with State rural rehabilitation corporations, to the Secretary of the Interior to be administered under the mineral laws of the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Sept. 6, 1950, ch. 897, § 3</ref>, <ref>64 Stat. 769</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1036.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 87–353, § 3(m)</ref>, <date date="1961-10-04">Oct. 4, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 774</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1037.</num>
<heading> Sale of reserved mineral interests; disposition of proceeds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All proceeds from sales made under sections 1033 to 1039 of this title of mineral interests described in <ref>section 1033 of this title</ref> shall be covered into the Treasury of the United States as miscellaneous receipts, except that the proceeds from sales of mineral interests which were a part of or derived from the assets transferred pursuant to the transfer agreements with State rural rehabilitation corporations shall be credited to the appropriate corporation account.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Sept. 6, 1950, ch. 897, § 5</ref>, <ref>64 Stat. 770</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1038.</num>
<heading> Regulations; delegations of authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may make such rules and regulations and such delegations of authority as he may deem necessary to carry out the provisions of sections 1033 to 1039 of this title.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Sept. 6, 1950, ch. 897, § 6</ref>, <ref>64 Stat. 770</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1039.</num>
<heading> Time for filing purchase applications</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No application for the purchase of mineral interests under sections 1033 to 1039 of this title shall be filed until ninety days after <date date="1950-09-06">September 6, 1950</date>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Sept. 6, 1950, ch. 897, § 7</ref>, <ref>64 Stat. 770</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1040.</num>
<heading> Farmers’ Home Administration funds account</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">When authorized by appropriation or other law, funds of the Farmers’ Home Administration available for administrative expenses may be placed in a single account.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 3, 1956, ch. 950, § 9(b)</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 1034</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>