<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 83—</num>
<heading>AGRICULTURAL COMPETITIVENESS AND TRADE</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>FINDINGS, POLICY, AND PURPOSE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5201.</num>
<heading> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Congress finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> United States agricultural exports have declined by more than 36 percent since 1981, from $43,800,000,000 in 1981 to $27,900,000,000 in 1987;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the United States share of the world market for agricultural commodities and products has dropped by 20 percent during the last 6 years;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> for the first time in 15 years, the United States incurred monthly agricultural trade deficits in 1986;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the loss of $1,000,000,000 in United States agricultural exports causes the loss of 35,000 agricultural jobs and the loss of 60,000 nonagricultural jobs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the loss of agricultural exports threatens family farms and the economic well-being of rural communities in the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> factors contributing to the loss of United States agricultural exports include changes in world agricultural markets such as—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the addition of new exporting nations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> innovations in agricultural technology;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> increased use of export subsidies designed to lower the price of commodities on the world market;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the existence of barriers to agricultural trade;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the slowdown in the growth of world food demand in the 1980’s due to cyclical economic factors, including currency fluctuations and a debt-related slowdown in the economic growth of agricultural markets in certain developing countries; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the rapid buildup of surplus stocks as a consequence of favorable weather for agricultural production during the 1980’s;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> increasing the volume and value of exports is important to the financial well-being of the farm sector in the United States and to increasing farm income in the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> in order to increase agricultural exports and improve prices for farmers and ranchers in the United States, it is necessary that all agricultural export programs of the United States be used in an expeditious manner, including programs established under the Food for Peace Act (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1691</ref> et seq.), the Commodity Credit Corporation Charter Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 714</ref> et seq.), and section 416 of the Agricultural Act of 1949 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1431</ref>);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<chapeau> greater use should be made by the Secretary of Agriculture of the authorities established under section 4 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002299">1</ref> of the Food for Peace Act of 1966 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1707a</ref>), the Food for Peace Act (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1691</ref> et seq.), section 416 of the Agricultural Act of 1949 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1431</ref>), and the Commodity Credit Corporation Charter Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 714</ref> et seq.) to provide intermediate credit financing and other assistance for the establishment of facilities in importing countries to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> improve the handling, marketing, processing, storage, and distribution of imported agricultural commodities and products; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> increase livestock production to enhance the demand for United States feed grains;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> food aid and export assistance programs in developing countries stimulate economic activity which causes incomes to rise, and, as incomes rise, diets improve and the demand for and ability to purchase food increases;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> private voluntary organizations and cooperatives are important and successful partners in our food aid and development programs; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<chapeau> in addition to meeting humanitarian needs, food aid used in sales and barter programs by private voluntary organizations and cooperatives—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> provides communities with health care, credit systems, and tools for development; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> establishes the infrastructure that is essential to the expansion of markets for United States agricultural commodities and products.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title IV, § 4101</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1388</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, title III, § 3001(b)(1)(A)</ref>, (2)(J), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1820</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5202.</num>
<heading> Policy</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the policy of the United States—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to provide, through all possible means, agricultural commodities and products for export at competitive prices, with full assurance of quality and reliability of supply;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to support the principle of free trade and the promotion of fair trade in agricultural commodities and products;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to support fully the negotiating objectives set forth in <ref>section 2901(b) of title 19</ref> to eliminate or reduce substantially constraints on fair and open trade in agricultural commodities and products;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to use statutory authority to counter unfair foreign trade practices and to use all available means, including export promotion programs, and, if necessary, restrictions on United States imports of agricultural commodities and products, in order to encourage fair and open trade; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to provide for increased representation of United States agricultural trade interests in the formulation of national fiscal and monetary policy affecting trade.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title IV, § 4102</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1390</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5203.</num>
<heading> Purpose</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the purpose of this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to increase the effectiveness of the Department of Agriculture in agricultural trade policy formulation and implementation and in assisting United States agricultural producers to participate in international agricultural trade, by strengthening the operations of the Department of Agriculture; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to improve the competitiveness of United States agricultural commodities and products in the world market.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title IV, § 4103</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1390</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>AGRICULTURAL TRADE INITIATIVES</heading>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part A—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">General Provisions</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 5211, 5212.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XV, § 1571</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3702</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5213.</num>
<heading> Joint development assistance agreements with certain trading partners</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Development of plan</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">With respect to any country that has a substantial positive trade balance with the United States, the Secretary of Agriculture, in consultation with the Secretary of State and (through the Secretary of State) representatives of such country, may develop an appropriate plan under which that country would purchase United States agricultural commodities or products for use in development activities in developing countries. In developing such plan, the Secretary of Agriculture shall take into consideration the agricultural economy of such country, the nature and extent of such country’s programs to assist developing countries, and other relevant factors. The Secretary of Agriculture shall submit each such plan to the President as soon as practicable.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agreement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President may enter into an agreement with any country that has a positive trade balance with the United States under which that country would purchase United States agricultural commodities or products for use in agreed-on development activities in developing countries.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title IV, § 4203</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1392</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5214.</num>
<heading> Reorganization evaluation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture shall evaluate the reorganization proposal recommended by the National Commission on Agricultural Trade and Export Policy and other proposals to improve management of international trade activities of the Department of Agriculture. To assist the Secretary in the evaluation, the Secretary shall appoint a private sector advisory committee of not less than 4 members, who shall be appointed from among individuals representing farm and commodity organizations, market development cooperators, and agribusiness. Not later than <date date="1989-04-30">April 30, 1989</date>, the Secretary shall report the findings of the evaluation to Congress, together with the views and recommendations of the private sector advisory committee.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title IV, § 4204</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1392</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 5215, 5216.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XV, § 1571</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3702</ref></heading>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part B—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Foreign Agricultural Service</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 5231 to 5233.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XV, § 1571</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3702</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5234.</num>
<heading> Cooperator organizations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sense of Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is the sense of Congress that the foreign market development cooperator program of the Service, and the activities of individual foreign market cooperator organizations, have been among the most successful and cost-effective means to expand United States agricultural exports. Congress affirms its support for the program and the activities of the cooperator organizations. The Administrator and the private sector should work together to ensure that the program, and the activities of cooperator organizations, are expanded in the future.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Commodities for cooperator organizations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture may make available to cooperator organizations agricultural commodities owned by the Commodity Credit Corporation, for use by such cooperators in projects designed to expand markets for United States agricultural commodities and products.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Relation to funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Commodities made available to cooperator organizations under this section shall be in addition to, and not in lieu of, funds appropriated for market development activities of such cooperator organizations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conflicts of interest</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall take appropriate action to prevent conflicts of interest among cooperator organizations participating in the cooperator program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Evaluation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is the sense of Congress that the Secretary should establish a consistent, objective means for the evaluation of cooperator programs.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title IV, § 4214</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1394</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5235.</num>
<heading> Authorization of additional appropriations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated for the Service, in addition to any sums otherwise authorized to be appropriated by any provision of law other than this section, $20,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 1988, 1989, and 1990 for market development activities, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> expansion of the agricultural attache service;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> expansion of international trade policy activities of the Service;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> enhancement of the Service worldwide market information system;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> increasing the number of trade shows and exhibitions conducted by the Service and upgrading the quality of United States representation at trade shows and exhibitions; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> developing markets for value-added beef, pork, and poultry products.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title IV, § 4215</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1395</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
</subchapter>
</chapter>