<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 54—</num>
<heading>TRANSPORTATION, SALE, AND HANDLING OF CERTAIN ANIMALS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2131.</num>
<heading> Congressional statement of policy</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress finds that animals and activities which are regulated under this chapter are either in interstate or foreign commerce or substantially affect such commerce or the free flow thereof, and that regulation of animals and activities as provided in this chapter is necessary to prevent and eliminate burdens upon such commerce and to effectively regulate such commerce, in order—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to insure that animals intended for use in research facilities or for exhibition purposes or for use as pets are provided humane care and treatment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to assure the humane treatment of animals during transportation in commerce; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to protect the owners of animals from the theft of their animals by preventing the sale or use of animals which have been stolen.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">The Congress further finds that it is essential to regulate, as provided in this chapter, the transportation, purchase, sale, housing, care, handling, and treatment of animals by carriers or by persons or organizations engaged in using them for research or experimental purposes or for exhibition purposes or holding them for sale as pets or for any such purpose or use.</continuation>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–544, § 1(b)</ref>, formerly § 1, <date date="1966-08-24">Aug. 24, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 350</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–579, § 2</ref>, <date date="1970-12-24">Dec. 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1560</ref>; renumbered and amended <ref>Pub. L. 94–279, § 2</ref>, <date date="1976-04-22">Apr. 22, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 417</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2132.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The term “person” includes any individual, partnership, firm, joint stock company, corporation, association, trust, estate, or other legal entity.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Agriculture of the United States or his representative who shall be an employee of the United States Department of Agriculture.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> The term “commerce” means trade, traffic, transportation, or other commerce—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> between a place in a State and any place outside of such State, or between points within the same State but through any place outside thereof, or within any territory, possession, or the District of Columbia;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> which affects trade, traffic, transportation, or other commerce described in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The term “State” means a State of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, or any other territory or possession of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> The term “research facility” means any school (except an elementary or secondary school), institution, organization, or person that uses or intends to use live animals in research, tests, or experiments, and that (1) purchases or transports live animals in commerce, or (2) receives funds under a grant, award, loan, or contract from a department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States for the purpose of carrying out research, tests, or experiments: <i>Provided</i>, That the Secretary may exempt, by regulation, any such school, institution, organization, or person that does not use or intend to use live dogs or cats, except those schools, institutions, organizations, or persons, which use substantial numbers (as determined by the Secretary) of live animals the principal function of which schools, institutions, organizations, or persons, is biomedical research or testing, when in the judgment of the Secretary, any such exemption does not vitiate the purpose of this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> The term “dealer” means any person who, in commerce, for compensation or profit, delivers for transportation, or transports, except as a carrier, buys, or sells, or negotiates the purchase or sale of, (1) any dog or other animal whether alive or dead for research, teaching, exhibition, or use as a pet, or (2) any dog for hunting, security, or breeding purposes. Such term does not include a retail pet store (other than a retail pet store which sells any animals to a research facility, an exhibitor, or another dealer).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> The term “animal” means any live or dead dog, cat, monkey (nonhuman primate mammal), guinea pig, hamster, rabbit, or such other warm-blooded animal, as the Secretary may determine is being used, or is intended for use, for research, testing, experimentation, or exhibition purposes, or as a pet; but such term excludes (1) birds, rats of the genus Rattus, and mice of the genus Mus, bred for use in research, (2) horses not used for research purposes, and (3) other farm animals, such as, but not limited to livestock or poultry, used or intended for use as food or fiber, or livestock or poultry used or intended for use for improving animal nutrition, breeding, management, or production efficiency, or for improving the quality of food or fiber. With respect to a dog, the term means all dogs including those used for hunting, security, or breeding purposes.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<content> The term “exhibitor” means any person (public or private) exhibiting any animals, which were purchased in commerce or the intended distribution of which affects commerce, or will affect commerce, to the public for compensation, as determined by the Secretary, and such term includes carnivals, circuses, and zoos exhibiting such animals whether operated for profit or not; but such term excludes retail pet stores, an owner of a common, domesticated household pet who derives less than a substantial portion of income from a nonprimary source (as determined by the Secretary) for exhibiting an animal that exclusively resides at the residence of the pet owner, organizations sponsoring and all persons participating in State and country fairs, livestock shows, rodeos, purebred dog and cat shows, and any other fairs or exhibitions intended to advance agricultural arts and sciences, as may be determined by the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The term “intermediate handler” means any person including a department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States or of any State or local government (other than a dealer, research facility, exhibitor, any person excluded from the definition of a dealer, research facility, or exhibitor, an operator of an auction sale, or a carrier) who is engaged in any business in which he receives custody of animals in connection with their transportation in commerce.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<content> The term “carrier” means the operator of any airline, railroad, motor carrier, shipping line, or other enterprise, which is engaged in the business of transporting any animals for hire.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(k)</num>
<content> The term “Federal agency” means an Executive agency as such term is defined in <ref>section 105 of title 5</ref>, and with respect to any research facility means the agency from which the research facility receives a Federal award for the conduct of research, experimentation, or testing, involving the use of animals.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(l)</num>
<content> The term “Federal award for the conduct of research, experimentation, or testing, involving the use of animals” means any mechanism (including a grant, award, loan, contract, or cooperative agreement) under which Federal funds are provided to support the conduct of such research.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(m)</num>
<content> The term “quorum” means a majority of the Committee members.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(n)</num>
<content> The term “Committee” means the Institutional Animal Committee established under <ref>section 2143(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(o)</num>
<content> The term “Federal research facility” means each department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States which uses live animals for research or experimentation.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–544, § 2</ref>, <date date="1966-08-24">Aug. 24, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 350</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–579, § 3</ref>, <date date="1970-12-24">Dec. 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1560</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–279</ref>, §§ 3, 4, <date date="1976-04-22">Apr. 22, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 417</ref>, 418; <ref>Pub. L. 99–198, title XVII, § 1756(a)</ref>, <date date="1985-12-23">Dec. 23, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 1650</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–171, title X, § 10301</ref>, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 491</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–261, § 1</ref>, <date date="2013-01-10">Jan. 10, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 2428</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–79, title XII, § 12308(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 990</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2133.</num>
<heading> Licensing of dealers and exhibitors</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall issue licenses to dealers and exhibitors upon application therefor in such form and manner as he may prescribe and upon payment of such fee established pursuant to 2153 of this title: <i>Provided</i>, That no such license shall be issued until the dealer or exhibitor shall have demonstrated that his facilities comply with the standards promulgated by the Secretary pursuant to <ref>section 2143 of this title</ref>: <i>Provided, however</i>, That a dealer or exhibitor shall not be required to obtain a license as a dealer or exhibitor under this chapter if the size of the business is determined by the Secretary to be de minimis. The Secretary is further authorized to license, as dealers or exhibitors, persons who do not qualify as dealers or exhibitors within the meaning of this chapter upon such persons’ complying with the requirements specified above and agreeing, in writing, to comply with all the requirements of this chapter and the regulations promulgated by the Secretary hereunder.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–544, § 3</ref>, <date date="1966-08-24">Aug. 24, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 351</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–579, § 4</ref>, <date date="1970-12-24">Dec. 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1561</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–79, title XII, § 12308(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 990</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2134.</num>
<heading> Valid license for dealers and exhibitors required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No dealer or exhibitor shall sell or offer to sell or transport or offer for transportation, in commerce, to any research facility or for exhibition or for use as a pet any animal, or buy, sell, offer to buy or sell, transport or offer for transportation, in commerce, to or from another dealer or exhibitor under this chapter any animals, unless and until such dealer or exhibitor shall have obtained a license from the Secretary and such license shall not have been suspended or revoked.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–544, § 4</ref>, <date date="1966-08-24">Aug. 24, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 351</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–579, § 5</ref>, <date date="1970-12-24">Dec. 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1561</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–279, § 5</ref>, <date date="1976-04-22">Apr. 22, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 418</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2135.</num>
<heading> Time period for disposal of dogs or cats by dealers or exhibitors</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No dealer or exhibitor shall sell or otherwise dispose of any dog or cat within a period of five business days after the acquisition of such animal or within such other period as may be specified by the Secretary: <i>Provided</i>, That operators of auction sales subject to <ref>section 2142 of this title</ref> shall not be required to comply with the provisions of this section.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–544, § 5</ref>, <date date="1966-08-24">Aug. 24, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 351</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–579, § 6</ref>, <date date="1970-12-24">Dec. 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1561</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2136.</num>
<heading> Registration of research facilities, handlers, carriers and unlicensed exhibitors</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Every research facility, every intermediate handler, every carrier, and every exhibitor not licensed under <ref>section 2133 of this title</ref> shall register with the Secretary in accordance with such rules and regulations as he may prescribe.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–544, § 6</ref>, <date date="1966-08-24">Aug. 24, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 351</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–579, § 7</ref>, <date date="1970-12-24">Dec. 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1561</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–279, § 6</ref>, <date date="1976-04-22">Apr. 22, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 418</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2137.</num>
<heading> Purchase of dogs or cats by research facilities prohibited except from authorized operators of auction sales and licensed dealers or exhibitors</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It shall be unlawful for any research facility to purchase any dog or cat from any person except an operator of an auction sale subject to <ref>section 2142 of this title</ref> or a person holding a valid license as a dealer or exhibitor issued by the Secretary pursuant to this chapter unless such person is exempted from obtaining such license under <ref>section 2133 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–544, § 7</ref>, <date date="1966-08-24">Aug. 24, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 351</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–579, § 8</ref>, <date date="1970-12-24">Dec. 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1561</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2138.</num>
<heading> Purchase of dogs or cats by United States Government facilities prohibited except from authorized operators of auction sales and licensed dealers or exhibitors</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States which uses animals for research or experimentation or exhibition shall purchase or otherwise acquire any dog or cat for such purposes from any person except an operator of an auction sale subject to <ref>section 2142 of this title</ref> or a person holding a valid license as a dealer or exhibitor issued by the Secretary pursuant to this chapter unless such person is exempted from obtaining such license under <ref>section 2133 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–544, § 8</ref>, <date date="1966-08-24">Aug. 24, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 351</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–579, § 9</ref>, <date date="1970-12-24">Dec. 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1562</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2139.</num>
<heading> Principal-agent relationship established</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">When construing or enforcing the provisions of this chapter, the act, omission, or failure of any person acting for or employed by a research facility, a dealer, or an exhibitor or a person licensed as a dealer or an exhibitor pursuant to the second sentence of <ref>section 2133 of this title</ref>, or an operator of an auction sale subject to <ref>section 2142 of this title</ref>, or an intermediate handler, or a carrier, within the scope of his employment or office, shall be deemed the act, omission, or failure of such research facility, dealer, exhibitor, licensee, operator of an auction sale, intermediate handler, or carrier, as well as of such person.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–544, § 9</ref>, <date date="1966-08-24">Aug. 24, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 351</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–579, § 10</ref>, <date date="1970-12-24">Dec. 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1562</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–279, § 7</ref>, <date date="1976-04-22">Apr. 22, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 418</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2140.</num>
<heading> Recordkeeping by dealers, exhibitors, research facilities, intermediate handlers, and carriers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Dealers and exhibitors shall make and retain for such reasonable period of time as the Secretary may prescribe, such records with respect to the purchase, sale, transportation, identification, and previous ownership of animals as the Secretary may prescribe. Research facilities shall make and retain such records only with respect to the purchase, sale, transportation, identification, and previous ownership of live dogs and cats. At the request of the Secretary, any regulatory agency of the Federal Government which requires records to be maintained by intermediate handlers and carriers with respect to the transportation, receiving, handling, and delivery of animals on forms prescribed by the agency, shall require there to be included in such forms, and intermediate handlers and carriers shall include in such forms, such information as the Secretary may require for the effective administration of this chapter. Such information shall be retained for such reasonable period of time as the Secretary may prescribe. If regulatory agencies of the Federal Government do not prescribe requirements for any such forms, intermediate handlers and carriers shall make and retain for such reasonable period  as  the  Secretary  may  prescribe  such records with respect to the transportation, receiving, handling, and delivery of animals as the Secretary may prescribe. Such records shall be made available at all reasonable times for inspection and copying by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–544, § 10</ref>, <date date="1966-08-24">Aug. 24, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 351</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–579, § 11</ref>, <date date="1970-12-24">Dec. 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1562</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–279, § 8</ref>, <date date="1976-04-22">Apr. 22, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 418</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2141.</num>
<heading> Marking and identification of animals</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All animals delivered for transportation, transported, purchased, or sold, in commerce, by a dealer or exhibitor shall be marked or identified at such time and in such humane manner as the Secretary may prescribe: <i>Provided</i>, That only live dogs and cats need be so marked or identified by a research facility.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–544, § 11</ref>, <date date="1966-08-24">Aug. 24, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 351</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–579, § 12</ref>, <date date="1970-12-24">Dec. 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1562</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–279, § 5</ref>, <date date="1976-04-22">Apr. 22, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 418</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2142.</num>
<heading> Humane standards and recordkeeping requirements at auction sales</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to promulgate humane standards and recordkeeping requirements governing the purchase, handling, or sale of animals, in commerce, by dealers, research facilities, and exhibitors at auction sales and by the operators of such auction sales. The Secretary is also authorized to require the licensing of operators of auction sales where any dogs or cats are sold, in commerce, under such conditions as he may prescribe, and upon payment of such fee as prescribed by the Secretary under <ref>section 2153 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–544, § 12</ref>, <date date="1966-08-24">Aug. 24, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 351</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–579, § 13</ref>, <date date="1970-12-24">Dec. 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1562</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–279, § 5</ref>, <date date="1976-04-22">Apr. 22, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 418</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2143.</num>
<heading> Standards and certification process for humane handling, care, treatment, and transportation of animals</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Promulgation of standards, rules, regulations, and orders; requirements; research facilities; State authority</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall promulgate standards to govern the humane handling, care, treatment, and transportation of animals by dealers, research facilities, and exhibitors.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The standards described in paragraph (1) shall include minimum requirements—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> for handling, housing, feeding, watering, sanitation, ventilation, shelter from extremes of weather and temperatures, adequate veterinary care, and separation by species where the Secretary finds necessary for humane handling, care, or treatment of animals; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for exercise of dogs, as determined by an attending veterinarian in accordance with general standards promulgated by the Secretary, and for a physical environment adequate to promote the psychological well-being of primates.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> In addition to the requirements under paragraph (2), the standards described in paragraph (1) shall, with respect to animals in research facilities, include requirements—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> for animal care, treatment, and practices in experimental procedures to ensure that animal pain and distress are minimized, including adequate veterinary care with the appropriate use of anesthetic, analgesic, tranquilizing drugs, or euthanasia;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> that the principal investigator considers alternatives to any procedure likely to produce pain to or distress in an experimental animal;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> in any practice which could cause pain to animals—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> that a doctor of veterinary medicine is consulted in the planning of such procedures;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> for the use of tranquilizers, analgesics, and anesthetics;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> for pre-surgical and post-surgical care by laboratory workers, in accordance with established veterinary medical and nursing procedures;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> against the use of paralytics without anesthesia; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> that the withholding of tranquilizers, anesthesia, analgesia, or euthanasia when scientifically necessary shall continue for only the necessary period of time;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> that no animal is used in more than one major operative experiment from which it is allowed to recover except in cases of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> scientific necessity; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> other special circumstances as determined by the Secretary; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> that exceptions to such standards may be made only when specified by research protocol and that any such exception shall be detailed and explained in a report outlined under paragraph (7) and filed with the Institutional Animal Committee.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall also promulgate standards to govern the transportation in commerce, and the handling, care, and treatment in connection therewith, by intermediate handlers, air carriers, or other carriers, of animals consigned by any dealer, research facility, exhibitor, operator of an auction sale, or other person, or any department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States or of any State or local government, for transportation in commerce. The Secretary shall have authority to promulgate such rules and regulations as he determines necessary to assure humane treatment of animals in the course of their transportation in commerce including requirements such as those with respect to containers, feed, water, rest, ventilation, temperature, and handling.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> In promulgating and enforcing standards established pursuant to this section, the Secretary is authorized and directed to consult experts, including outside consultants where indicated.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> Nothing in this chapter—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> except as provided in paragraphs <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002240">1</ref> (7) of this subsection, shall be construed as authorizing the Secretary to promulgate rules, regulations, or orders with regard to the design, outlines, or guidelines of actual research or experimentation by a research facility as determined by such research facility;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> except as provided <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002241">2</ref> subparagraphs (A) and (C)(ii) through (v) of paragraph (3) and paragraph (7) of this subsection, shall be construed as authorizing the Secretary to promulgate rules, regulations, or orders with regard to the performance of actual research or experimentation by a research facility as determined by such research facility; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> shall authorize the Secretary, during inspection, to interrupt the conduct of actual research or experimentation.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> No rule, regulation, order, or part of this chapter shall be construed to require a research facility to disclose publicly or to the Institutional Animal Committee during its inspection, trade secrets or commercial or financial information which is privileged or confidential.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(7)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall require each research facility to show upon inspection, and to report at least annually, that the provisions of this chapter are being followed and that professionally acceptable standards governing the care, treatment, and use of animals are being followed by the research facility during actual research or experimentation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> In complying with subparagraph (A), such research facilities shall provide—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> information on procedures likely to produce pain or distress in any animal and assurances demonstrating that the principal investigator considered alternatives to those procedures;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> assurances satisfactory to the Secretary that such facility is adhering to the standards described in this section; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> an explanation for any deviation from the standards promulgated under this section.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Paragraph (1) shall not prohibit any State (or a political subdivision of such State) from promulgating standards in addition to those standards promulgated by the Secretary under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Research facility Committee; establishment, membership, functions, etc.</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary shall require that each research facility establish at least one Committee. Each Committee shall be appointed by the chief executive officer of each such research facility and shall be composed of not fewer than three members. Such members shall possess sufficient ability to assess animal care, treatment, and practices in experimental research as determined by the needs of the research facility and shall represent society’s concerns regarding the welfare of animal subjects used at such facility. Of the members of the Committee—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> at least one member shall be a doctor of veterinary medicine;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> at least one member—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> shall not be affiliated in any way with such facility other than as a member of the Committee;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> shall not be a member of the immediate family of a person who is affiliated with such facility; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> is intended to provide representation for general community interests in the proper care and treatment of animals; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> in those cases where the Committee consists of more than three members, not more than three members shall be from the same administrative unit of such facility.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A quorum shall be required for all formal actions of the Committee, including inspections under paragraph (3).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The Committee shall inspect at least semiannually all animal study areas and animal facilities of such research facility and review as part of the inspection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> practices involving pain to animals, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the condition of animals,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">to ensure compliance with the provisions of this chapter to minimize pain and distress to animals. Exceptions to the requirement of inspection of such study areas may be made by the Secretary if animals are studied in their natural environment and the study area is prohibitive to easy access.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> The Committee shall file an inspection certification report of each inspection at the research facility. Such report shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> be signed by a majority of the Committee members involved in the inspection;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> include reports of any violation of the standards promulgated, or assurances required, by the Secretary, including any deficient conditions of animal care or treatment, any deviations of research practices from originally approved proposals that adversely affect animal welfare, any notification to the facility regarding such conditions, and any corrections made thereafter;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> include any minority views of the Committee; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> include any other information pertinent to the activities of the Committee.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Such report shall remain on file for at least three years at the research facility and shall be available for inspection by the Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service and any funding Federal agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> In order to give the research facility an opportunity to correct any deficiencies or deviations discovered by reason of paragraph (3), the Committee shall notify the administrative representative of the research facility of any deficiencies or deviations from the provisions of this chapter. If, after notification and an opportunity for correction, such deficiencies or deviations remain uncorrected, the Committee shall notify (in writing) the Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service and the funding Federal agency of such deficiencies or deviations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The inspection results shall be available to Department of Agriculture inspectors for review during inspections. Department of Agriculture inspectors shall forward any Committee inspection records which include reports of uncorrected deficiencies or deviations to the Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service and any funding Federal agency of the project with respect to which such uncorrected deficiencies and deviations occurred.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal research facilities; establishment, composition, and responsibilities of Federal Committee</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In the case of Federal research facilities, a Federal Committee shall be established and shall have the same composition and responsibilities provided in subsection (b), except that the Federal Committee shall report deficiencies or deviations to the head of the Federal agency conducting the research rather than to the Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service. The head of the Federal agency conducting the research shall be responsible for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> all corrective action to be taken at the facility; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the granting of all exceptions to inspection protocol.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Training of scientists, animal technicians, and other personnel involved with animal care and treatment at research facilities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each research facility shall provide for the training of scientists, animal technicians, and other personnel involved with animal care and treatment in such facility as required by the Secretary. Such training shall include instruction on—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the humane practice of animal maintenance and experimentation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> research or testing methods that minimize or eliminate the use of animals or limit animal pain or distress;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> utilization of the information service at the National Agricultural Library, established under subsection (e); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> methods whereby deficiencies in animal care and treatment should be reported.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of information service at National Agricultural Library; service functions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish an information service at the National Agricultural Library. Such service shall, in cooperation with the National Library of Medicine, provide information—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> pertinent to employee training;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> which could prevent unintended duplication of animal experimentation as determined by the needs of the research facility; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> on improved methods of animal experimentation, including methods which could—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> reduce or replace animal use; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> minimize pain and distress to animals, such as anesthetic and analgesic procedures.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002242">3</ref> Suspension or revocation of Federal support for research projects; prerequisites; appeal procedure</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In any case in which a Federal agency funding a research project determines that conditions of animal care, treatment, or practice in a particular project have not been in compliance with standards promulgated under this chapter, despite notification by the Secretary or such Federal agency to the research facility and an opportunity for correction, such agency shall suspend or revoke Federal support for the project. Any research facility losing Federal support as a result of actions taken under the preceding sentence shall have the right of appeal as provided in sections 701 through 706 of title 5.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> <sup>3</sup> Veterinary certificate; contents; exceptions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No dogs or cats, or additional kinds or classes of animals designated by regulation of the Secretary, shall be delivered by any dealer, research facility, exhibitor, operator of an auction sale, or department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States or of any State or local government, to any intermediate handler or carrier for transportation in commerce, or received by any such handler or carrier for such transportation from any such person, department, agency, or instrumentality, unless the animal is accompanied by a certificate issued by a veterinarian licensed to practice veterinary medicine, certifying that he inspected the animal on a specified date, which shall not be more than ten days before such delivery, and, when so inspected, the animal appeared free of any infectious disease or physical abnormality which would endanger the animal or animals or other animals or endanger public health: <i>Provided, however</i>, That the Secretary may by regulation provide exceptions to this certification requirement, under such conditions as he may prescribe in the regulations, for animals shipped to research facilities for purposes of research, testing or experimentation requiring animals not eligible for such certification. Such certificates received by the intermediate handlers and the carriers shall be retained by them, as provided by regulations of the Secretary, in accordance with <ref>section 2140 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Age of animals delivered to registered research facilities; power of Secretary to designate additional classes of animals and age limits</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No dogs or cats, or additional kinds or classes of animals designated by regulation of the Secretary, shall be delivered by any person to any intermediate handler or carrier for transportation in commerce except to registered research facilities if they are less than such age as the Secretary may by regulation prescribe. The Secretary shall designate additional kinds and classes of animals and may prescribe different ages for particular kinds or classes of dogs, cats, or designated animals, for the purposes of this section, when he determines that such action is necessary or adequate to assure their humane treatment in connection with their transportation in commerce.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition of C.O.D. arrangements for transportation of animals in commerce; exceptions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No intermediate handler or carrier involved in the transportation of any animal in commerce shall participate in any arrangement or engage in any practice under which the cost of such animal or the cost of the transportation of such animal is to be paid and collected upon delivery of the animal to the consignee, unless the consignor guarantees in writing the payment of transportation charges for any animal not claimed within a period of 48 hours after notice to the consignee of arrival of the animal, including, where necessary, both the return transportation charges and an amount sufficient to reimburse the carrier for all out-of-pocket expenses incurred for the care, feeding, and storage of such animals.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–544, § 13</ref>, <date date="1966-08-24">Aug. 24, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 352</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–579, § 14</ref>, <date date="1970-12-24">Dec. 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1562</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–279</ref>, §§ 9, 10, <date date="1976-04-22">Apr. 22, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 418</ref>, 419; <ref>Pub. L. 99–198, title XVII, § 1752</ref>, <date date="1985-12-23">Dec. 23, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 1645</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2144.</num>
<heading> Humane standards for animals by United States Government facilities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States having laboratory animal facilities shall comply with the standards and other requirements promulgated by the Secretary for a research facility under sections <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002243">1</ref> 2143(a), (f), (g), and (h) of this title. Any department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States exhibiting animals shall comply with the standards promulgated by the Secretary under sections <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002243">1</ref> 2143(a), (f), (g), and (h) of this title.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–544, § 14</ref>, <date date="1966-08-24">Aug. 24, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 352</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–579, § 15</ref>, <date date="1970-12-24">Dec. 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1563</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–279, § 19</ref>, <date date="1976-04-22">Apr. 22, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 423</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–198, title XVII, § 1758</ref>, <date date="1985-12-23">Dec. 23, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 1650</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2145.</num>
<heading> Consultation and cooperation with Federal, State, and local governmental bodies by Secretary of Agriculture</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall consult and cooperate with other Federal departments, agencies, or instrumentalities concerned with the welfare of animals used for research, experimentation or exhibition, or administration of statutes regulating the transportation in commerce or handling in connection therewith of any animals when establishing standards pursuant to <ref>section 2143 of this title</ref> and in carrying out the purposes of this chapter. The Secretary shall consult with the Secretary of Health and Human Services prior to issuance of regulations. Before promulgating any standard governing the air transportation and handling in connection therewith, of animals, the Secretary shall consult with the Secretary of Transportation who shall have the authority to disapprove any such standard if he notifies the Secretary, within 30 days after such consultation, that changes in its provisions are necessary in the interest of flight safety. The Surface Transportation Board, the Secretary of Transportation, and the Federal Maritime Commission, to the extent of their respective lawful authorities, shall take such action as is appropriate to implement any standard established by the Secretary with respect to a person subject to regulation by it.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Secretary is authorized to cooperate with the officials of the various States or political subdivisions thereof in carrying out the purposes of this chapter and of any State, local, or municipal legislation or ordinance on the same subject.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–544, § 15</ref>, <date date="1966-08-24">Aug. 24, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 352</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–579, § 16</ref>, <date date="1970-12-24">Dec. 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1563</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–279, § 11</ref>, <date date="1976-04-22">Apr. 22, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 419</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–443, § 9(i)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-04">Oct. 4, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1708</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–198, title XVII, § 1757</ref>, <date date="1985-12-23">Dec. 23, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 1650</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title III, § 312</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 948</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2146.</num>
<heading> Administration and enforcement by Secretary</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Investigations and inspections</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall make such investigations or inspections as he deems necessary to determine whether any dealer, exhibitor, intermediate handler, carrier, research facility, or operator of an auction sale subject to <ref>section 2142 of this title</ref>, has violated or is violating any provision of this chapter or any regulation or standard issued thereunder, and for such purposes, the Secretary shall, at all reasonable times, have access to the places of business and the facilities, animals, and those records required to be kept pursuant to <ref>section 2140 of this title</ref> of any such dealer, exhibitor, intermediate handler, carrier, research facility, or operator of an auction sale. The Secretary shall inspect each research facility at least once each year and, in the case of deficiencies or deviations from the standards promulgated under this chapter, shall conduct such follow-up inspections as may be necessary until all deficiencies or deviations from such standards are corrected. The Secretary shall promulgate such rules and regulations as he deems necessary to permit inspectors to confiscate or destroy in a humane manner any animal found to be suffering as a result of a failure to comply with any provision of this chapter or any regulation or standard issued thereunder if (1) such animal is held by a dealer, (2) such animal is held by an exhibitor, (3) such animal is held by a research facility and is no longer required by such research facility to carry out the research, test, or experiment for which such animal has been utilized, (4) such animal is held by an operator of an auction sale, or (5) such animal is held by an intermediate handler or a carrier.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Penalties for interfering with official duties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any person who forcibly assaults, resists, opposes, impedes, intimidates, or interferes with any person while engaged in or on account of the performance of his official duties under this chapter shall be fined not more than $5,000, or imprisoned not more than three years, or both. Whoever, in the commission of such acts, uses a deadly or dangerous weapon shall be fined not more than $10,000, or imprisoned not more than ten years, or both. Who­ever kills any person while engaged in or on account of the performance of his official duties under this chapter shall be punished as provided under sections 1111 and 1114 of title 18.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Procedures</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the efficient administration and enforcement of this chapter and the regulations and standards promulgated under this chapter, the provisions (including penalties) of sections 46, 48, 49 and 50 of title 15 (except paragraph (c) through (h) of section 46 and the last paragraph of section 49 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002244">1</ref> of title 15), and the provisions of Title II of the Organized Crime Control Act of 1970, are made applicable to the jurisdiction, powers, and duties of the Secretary in administering and enforcing the provisions of this chapter and to any person, firm, or corporation with respect to whom such authority is exercised. The Secretary may prosecute any inquiry necessary to his duties under this chapter in any part of the United States, including any territory, or possession thereof, the District of Columbia, or the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico. The powers conferred by said sections 49 and 50 of title 15 on the district courts of the United States may be exercised for the purposes of this chapter by any district court of the United States. The United States district courts, the District Court of Guam, the District Court of the Virgin Islands, the highest court of American Samoa, and the United States courts of the other territories, are vested with jurisdiction specifically to enforce, and to prevent and restrain violations of this chapter, and shall have jurisdiction in all other kinds of cases arising under this chapter, except as provided in <ref>section 2149(c) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–544, § 16</ref>, <date date="1966-08-24">Aug. 24, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 352</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–579, § 17</ref>, <date date="1970-12-24">Dec. 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1563</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–279, § 12</ref>, <date date="1976-04-22">Apr. 22, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 420</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–198, title XVII, § 1753</ref>, <date date="1985-12-23">Dec. 23, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 1649</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XXV, § 2503(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4066</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2146a.</num>
<heading> Searchable database requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service shall, notwithstanding any other provision of law:</chapeau>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> within 60 calendar days, restore on its website the searchable database and its contents that were available on <date date="2017-01-30">January 30, 2017</date>, and all content generated since that date; and</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> hereafter, make publicly available via searchable database, in their entirety without redactions except signatures, the following records:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent2">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> all final Animal Welfare Act inspection reports, including all reports documenting all Animal Welfare Act violations and non-compliances observed by USDA officials and all animal inventories for the current year and the preceding three years;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> all final Animal Welfare Act and Horse Protection Act enforcement records for the current year and the preceding three years;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> all reports or other materials documenting any violations and non-compliances observed by USDA officials for the current year and the preceding three years; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> within six months of receipt by the agency, all final Animal Welfare Act research facility annual reports, including their attachments with appropriate redactions made for confidential business information that USDA could withhold under FOIA Exemption 4.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. B, title VII, § 788</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 2657</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–103, div. A, title VII, § 765</ref>, <date date="2022-03-15">Mar. 15, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 98</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2147.</num>
<heading> Inspection by legally constituted law enforcement agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall promulgate rules and regulations requiring dealers, exhibitors, research facilities, and operators of auction sales subject to <ref>section 2142 of this title</ref> to permit inspection of their animals and records at reasonable hours upon request by legally constituted law enforcement agencies in search of lost animals.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–544, § 17</ref>, <date date="1966-08-24">Aug. 24, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 352</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–579, § 18</ref>, <date date="1970-12-24">Dec. 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1564</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2148.</num>
<heading> Importation of live dogs</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Importer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “importer” means any person who, for purposes of resale, transports into the United States puppies from a foreign country.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Resale</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “resale” includes any transfer of ownership or control of an imported dog of less than 6 months of age to another person, for more than de minimis consideration.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (2), no person shall import a dog into the United States for purposes of resale unless, as determined by the Secretary, the dog—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is in good health;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> has received all necessary vaccinations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> is at least 6 months of age, if imported for resale.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Secretary, by regulation, shall provide an exception to any requirement under paragraph (1) in any case in which a dog is imported for—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> research purposes; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> veterinary treatment.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Lawful importation into Hawaii</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Paragraph (1)(C) shall not apply to the lawful importation of a dog into the State of Hawaii from the British Isles, Australia, Guam, or New Zealand in compliance with the applicable regulations of the State of Hawaii and the other requirements of this section, if the dog is not transported out of the State of Hawaii for purposes of resale at less than 6 months of age.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementation and regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Secretary of Commerce, and the Secretary of Homeland Security shall promulgate such regulations as the Secretaries determine to be necessary to implement and enforce this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Enforcement</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">An importer that fails to comply with this section shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> be subject to penalties under <ref>section 2149 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provide for the care (including appropriate veterinary care), forfeiture, and adoption of each applicable dog, at the expense of the importer.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–544, § 18</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title XIV, § 14210(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1464</ref>, and <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title XIV, § 14210(a), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2226.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2149.</num>
<heading> Violations by licensees</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Temporary license suspension; notice and hearing; revocation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the Secretary has reason to believe that any person licensed as a dealer, exhibitor, or operator of an auction sale subject to <ref>section 2142 of this title</ref>, has violated or is violating any provision of this chapter, or any of the rules or regulations or standards promulgated by the Secretary hereunder, he may suspend such person’s license temporarily, but not to exceed 21 days, and after notice and opportunity for hearing, may suspend for such additional period as he may specify, or revoke such license, if such violation is determined to have occurred.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Civil penalties for violation of any section, etc.; separate offenses; notice and hearing; appeal; considerations in assessing penalty; compromise of penalty; civil action by Attorney General for failure to pay penalty; district court jurisdiction; failure to obey cease and desist order</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any dealer, exhibitor, research facility, intermediate handler, carrier, or operator of an auction sale subject to <ref>section 2142 of this title</ref>, that violates any provision of this chapter, or any rule, regulation, or standard promulgated by the Secretary thereunder, may be assessed a civil penalty by the Secretary of not more than $10,000 for each such violation, and the Secretary may also make an order that such person shall cease and desist from continuing such violation. Each violation and each day during which a violation continues shall be a separate offense. No penalty shall be assessed or cease and desist order issued unless such person is given notice and opportunity for a hearing with respect to the alleged violation, and the order of the Secretary assessing a penalty and making a cease and desist order shall be final and conclusive unless the affected person files an appeal from the Secretary’s order with the appropriate United States Court of Appeals. The Secretary shall give due consideration to the appropriateness of the penalty with respect to the size of the business of the person involved, the gravity of the violation, the person’s good faith, and the history of previous violations. Any such civil penalty may be compromised by the Secretary. Upon any failure to pay the penalty assessed by a final order under this section, the Secretary shall request the Attorney General to institute a civil action in a district court of the United States or other United States court for any district in which such person is found or resides or transacts business, to collect the penalty, and such court shall have jurisdiction to hear and decide any such action. Any person who knowingly fails to obey a cease and desist order made by the Secretary under this section shall be subject to a civil penalty of $1,500 for each offense, and each day during which such failure continues shall be deemed a separate offense.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appeal of final order by aggrieved person; limitations; exclusive jurisdiction of United States Courts of Appeals</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any dealer, exhibitor, research facility, intermediate handler, carrier, or operator of an auction sale subject to <ref>section 2142 of this title</ref>, aggrieved by a final order of the Secretary issued pursuant to this section may, within 60 days after entry of such an order, seek review of such order in the appropriate United States Court of Appeals in accordance with the provisions of sections 2341, 2343 through 2350 of title 28, and such court shall have exclusive jurisdiction to enjoin, set aside, suspend (in whole or in part), or to determine the validity of the Secretary’s order.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Criminal penalties for violation; initial prosecution brought before United States magistrate judges; conduct of prosecution by attorneys of United States Department of Agriculture</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any dealer, exhibitor, or operator of an auction sale subject to <ref>section 2142 of this title</ref>, who knowingly violates any provision of this chapter shall, on conviction thereof, be subject to imprisonment for not more than 1 year, or a fine of not more than $2,500, or both. Prosecution of such violations shall, to the maximum extent practicable, be brought initially before United States magistrate judges as provided in <ref>section 636 of title 28</ref>, and sections 3401 and 3402 of title 18, and, with the consent of the Attorney General, may be conducted, at both trial and upon appeal to district court, by attorneys of the United States Department of Agriculture.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–544, § 19</ref>, <date date="1966-08-24">Aug. 24, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 352</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–579, § 20</ref>, <date date="1970-12-24">Dec. 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1564</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–279, § 13</ref>, <date date="1976-04-22">Apr. 22, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 420</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–198, title XVII, § 1755</ref>, <date date="1985-12-23">Dec. 23, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 1650</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–650, title III, § 321</ref>, <date date="1990-12-01">Dec. 1, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 5117</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title XIV, § 14214</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1466</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title XIV, § 14214, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2228.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2150.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 94–279, § 14</ref>, <date date="1976-04-22">Apr. 22, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 421</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2151.</num>
<heading> Rules and regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to promulgate such rules, regulations, and orders as he may deem necessary in order to effectuate the purposes of this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–544, § 21</ref>, <date date="1966-08-24">Aug. 24, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 353</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2152.</num>
<heading> Separability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If any provision of this chapter or the application of any such provision to any person or circumstances shall be held invalid, the remainder of this chapter and the application of any such provision to persons or circumstances other than those as to which it is held invalid shall not be affected thereby.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–544, § 22</ref>, <date date="1966-08-24">Aug. 24, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 353</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2153.</num>
<heading> Fees and authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall charge, assess, and cause to be collected reasonable fees for licenses issued. Such fees shall be adjusted on an equitable basis taking into consideration the type and nature of the operations to be licensed and shall be deposited and covered into the Treasury as miscellaneous receipts. There are hereby authorized to be appropriated such funds as Congress may from time to time provide: <i>Provided</i>, That there is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Agriculture for enforcement by the Department of Agriculture of the provisions of <ref>section 2156 of this title</ref> an amount not to exceed $100,000 for the transition quarter ending <date date="1976-09-30">September 30, 1976</date>, and not to exceed $400,000 for each fiscal year thereafter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–544, § 23</ref>, <date date="1966-08-24">Aug. 24, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 353</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–279, § 18</ref>, <date date="1976-04-22">Apr. 22, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 423</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2154.</num>
<heading> Effective dates</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The regulations referred to in sections 2140 and 2143 of this title shall be prescribed by the Secretary as soon as reasonable but not later than six months from <date date="1966-08-24">August 24, 1966</date>. Additions and amendments thereto may be prescribed from time to time as may be necessary or advisable. Compliance by dealers with the provisions of this chapter and such regulations shall commence ninety days after the promulgation of such regulations. Compliance by research facilities with the provisions of this chapter and such regulations shall commence six months after the promulgation of such regulations, except that the Secretary may grant extensions of time to research facilities which do not comply with the standards prescribed by the Secretary pursuant to <ref>section 2143 of this title</ref> provided that the Secretary determines that there is evidence that the research facilities will meet such standards within a reasonable time. Notwithstanding the other provisions of this section, compliance by intermediate handlers, and carriers, and other persons with those provisions of this chapter, as amended by the Animal Welfare Act Amendments of 1976, and those regulations promulgated thereunder, which relate to actions of intermediate handlers and carriers, shall commence 90 days after promulgation of regulations under <ref>section 2143 of this title</ref>, as amended, with respect to intermediate handlers and carriers, and such regulations shall be promulgated no later than 9 months after <date date="1976-04-22">April 22, 1976</date>; and compliance by dealers, exhibitors, operators of auction sales, and research facilities with other provisions of this chapter, as so amended, and the regulations thereunder, shall commence upon the expiration of 90 days after <date date="1976-04-22">April 22, 1976</date>: <i>Provided, however</i>, That compliance by all persons with subsections (b), (c), and (d) of section 2143 and with <ref>section 2156 of this title</ref>, as so amended, shall commence upon the expiration of said ninety-day period. In all other respects, said amendments shall become effective on <date date="1976-04-22">April 22, 1976</date>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–544, § 24</ref>, <date date="1966-08-24">Aug. 24, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 353</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–279, § 15</ref>, <date date="1976-04-22">Apr. 22, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 421</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2155.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2156.</num>
<heading> Animal fighting venture prohibition</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sponsoring or exhibiting an animal in, attending, or causing an individual who has not attained the age of 16 to attend, an animal fighting venture</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sponsoring or exhibiting</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">It shall be unlawful for any person to knowingly sponsor or exhibit an animal in an animal fighting venture.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Attending or causing an individual who has not attained the age of 16 to attend</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">It shall be unlawful for any person to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> knowingly attend an animal fighting venture; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> knowingly cause an individual who has not attained the age of 16 to attend an animal fighting venture.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Buying, selling, delivering, possessing, training, or transporting animals for participation in animal fighting venture</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It shall be unlawful for any person to knowingly sell, buy, possess, train, transport, deliver, or receive any animal for purposes of having the animal participate in an animal fighting venture.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of Postal Service or other interstate instrumentality for promoting or furthering animal fighting venture</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It shall be unlawful for any person to knowingly use the mail service of the United States Postal Service or any instrumentality of interstate commerce for commercial speech for purposes of advertising an animal, or an instrument described in subsection (d), for use in an animal fighting venture, promoting <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002245">1</ref> or in any other manner furthering an animal fighting venture except as performed outside the limits of the States of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Buying, selling, delivering, or transporting sharp instruments for use in animal fighting venture</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It shall be unlawful for any person to knowingly sell, buy, transport, or deliver in interstate or foreign commerce a knife, a gaff, or any other sharp instrument attached, or designed or intended to be attached, to the leg of a bird for use in an animal fighting venture.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Investigation of violations by Secretary; assistance by other Federal agencies; issuance of search warrant; forfeiture; costs recoverable in forfeiture or civil action</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary or any other person authorized by him shall make such investigations as the Secretary deems necessary to determine whether any person has violated or is violating any provision of this section, and the Secretary may obtain the assistance of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the Department of the Treasury, or other law enforcement agencies of the United States, and State and local governmental agencies, in the conduct of such investigations, under cooperative agreements with such agencies. A warrant to search for and seize any animal which there is probable cause to believe was involved in any violation of this section may be issued by any judge of the United States or of a State court of record or by a United States magistrate judge within the district wherein the animal sought is located. Any United States marshal or any person authorized under this section to conduct investigations may apply for and execute any such warrant, and any animal seized under such a warrant shall be held by the United States marshal or other authorized person pending disposition thereof by the court in accordance with this subsection. Necessary care including veterinary treatment shall be provided while the animals are so held in custody. Any animal involved in any violation of this section shall be liable to be proceeded against and forfeited to the United States at any time on complaint filed in any United States district court or other court of the United States for any jurisdiction in which the animal is found and upon a judgment of forfeiture shall be disposed of by sale for lawful purposes or by other humane means, as the court may direct. Costs incurred for care of animals seized and forfeited under this section shall be recoverable from the owner of the animals (1) if he appears in such forfeiture proceeding, or (2) in a separate civil action brought in the jurisdiction in which the owner is found, resides, or transacts business.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “animal fighting venture” means any event, in or affecting interstate or foreign commerce, that involves a fight conducted or to be conducted between at least 2 animals for purposes of sport, wagering, or entertainment, except that the term “animal fighting venture” shall not be deemed to include any activity the primary purpose of which involves the use of one or more animals in hunting another animal;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “instrumentality of interstate commerce” means any written, wire, radio, television or other form of communication in, or using a facility of, interstate commerce;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “State” means any State of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and any territory or possession of the United States; <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002246">2</ref></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the term “animal” means any live bird, or any live mammal, except man.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Relationship to other provisions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The conduct by any person of any activity prohibited by this section shall not render such person subject to the other sections of this chapter as a dealer, exhibitor, or otherwise.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conflict with State law</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The provisions of this chapter shall not supersede or otherwise invalidate any such State, local, or municipal legislation or ordinance relating to animal fighting ventures except in case of a direct and irreconcilable conflict between any requirements thereunder and this chapter or any rule, regulation, or standard hereunder.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Criminal penalties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The criminal penalties for violations of subsection (a), (b), (c), or (d) are provided in <ref>section 49 of title 18</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–544, § 26</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 94–279, § 17</ref>, <date date="1976-04-22">Apr. 22, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 421</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–650, title III, § 321</ref>, <date date="1990-12-01">Dec. 1, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 5117</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–171, title X</ref>, §§ 10302(a), 10303(a), <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 491</ref>, 492; <ref>Pub. L. 110–22, § 3</ref>, <date date="2007-05-03">May 3, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 88</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title XIV, § 14207(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1461</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title XIV, § 14207(a), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2223; <ref>Pub. L. 113–79, title XII, § 12308(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 990</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title XII, § 12616(a)</ref>–(c), <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5015</ref>, 5016.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2157.</num>
<heading> Release of trade secrets</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Release of confidential information prohibited</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It shall be unlawful for any member of an Institutional Animal Committee to release any confidential information of the research facility including any information that concerns or relates to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the trade secrets, processes, operations, style of work, or apparatus; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the identity, confidential statistical data, amount or source of any income, profits, losses, or expenditures,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">of the research facility.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Wrongful use of confidential information prohibited</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It shall be unlawful for any member of such Committee—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to use or attempt to use to his advantages; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to reveal to any other person,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">any information which is entitled to protection as confidential information under subsection (a).</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Penalties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A violation of subsection (a) or (b) is punishable by—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> removal from such Committee; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a fine of not more than $1,000 and imprisonment of not more than one year; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> if such violation is willful, a fine of not more than $10,000 and imprisonment of not more than three years.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recovery of damages by injured person; costs; attorney’s fee</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any person, including any research facility, injured in its business or property by reason of a violation of this section may recover all actual and consequential damages sustained by such person and the cost of the suit including a reasonable attorney’s fee.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other rights and remedies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall be construed to affect any other rights of a person injured in its business or property by reason of a violation of this section. Subsection (d) shall not be construed to limit the exercise of any such rights arising out of or relating to a violation of subsections (a) and (b).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–544, § 27</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 99–198, title XVII, § 1754</ref>, <date date="1985-12-23">Dec. 23, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 1649</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2158.</num>
<heading> Protection of pets</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Holding period</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In the case of each dog or cat acquired by an entity described in paragraph (2), such entity shall hold and care for such dog or cat for a period of not less than five days to enable such dog or cat to be recovered by its original owner or adopted by other individuals before such entity sells such dog or cat to a dealer.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Entities described</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">An entity subject to paragraph (1) is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> each State, county, or city owned and operated pound or shelter;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> each private entity established for the purpose of caring for animals, such as a humane society, or other organization that is under contract with a State, county, or city that operates as a pound or shelter and that releases animals on a voluntary basis; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> each research facility licensed by the Department of Agriculture.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certification</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A dealer may not sell, provide, or make available to any individual or entity a random source dog or cat unless such dealer provides the recipient with a valid certification that meets the requirements of paragraph (2) and indicates compliance with subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A valid certification shall contain—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the name, address, and Department of Agriculture license or registration number (if such number exists) of the dealer;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the name, address, Department of Agriculture license or registration number (if such number exists), and the signature of the recipient of the dog or cat;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> a description of the dog or cat being provided that shall include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the species and breed or type of such;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the sex of such;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the date of birth (if known) of such;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the color and any distinctive marking of such; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> any other information that the Secretary by regulation shall determine to be appropriate;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the name and address of the person, pound, or shelter from which the dog or cat was purchased or otherwise acquired by the dealer, and an assurance that such person, pound, or shelter was notified that such dog or cat may be used for research or educational purposes;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the date of the purchase or acquisition referred to in subparagraph (D);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> a statement by the pound or shelter (if the dealer acquired the dog or cat from such) that it satisfied the requirements of subsection (a); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> any other information that the Secretary of Agriculture by regulation shall determine appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Records</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The original certification required under paragraph (1) shall accompany the shipment of a dog or cat to be sold, provided, or otherwise made available by the dealer, and shall be kept and maintained by the research facility for a period of at least one year for enforcement purposes. The dealer shall retain one copy of the certification provided under this paragraph for a period of at least one year for enforcement purposes.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In instances where one research facility transfers animals to another research facility a copy of the certificate must accompany such transfer.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Modification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Certification requirements may be modified to reflect technological advances in identification techniques, such as microchip technology, if the Secretary determines that adequate information such as described in this section, will be collected, transferred, and maintained through such technology.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Enforcement</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Dealers who fail to act according to the requirements of this section or who include false information in the certification required under subsection (b), shall be subject to the penalties provided for under <ref>section 2149 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Subsequent violations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any dealer who violates this section more than one time shall be subject to a fine of $5,000 per dog or cat acquired or sold in violation of this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Permanent revocations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any dealer who violates this section three or more times shall have such dealers license permanently revoked.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after <date date="1990-11-28">November 28, 1990</date>, the Secretary shall promulgate regulations to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–544, § 28</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XXV, § 2503(2)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4066</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–237, title X, § 1004</ref>, <date date="1991-12-13">Dec. 13, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1894</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2159.</num>
<heading> Authority to apply for injunctions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Request</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever the Secretary has reason to believe that any dealer, carrier, exhibitor, or intermediate handler is dealing in stolen animals, or is placing the health of any animal in serious danger in violation of this chapter or the regulations or standards promulgated thereunder, the Secretary shall notify the Attorney General, who may apply to the United States district court in which such dealer, carrier, exhibitor, or intermediate handler resides or conducts business for a temporary restraining order or injunction to prevent any such person from operating in violation of this chapter or the regulations and standards prescribed under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Issuance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The court shall, upon a proper showing, issue a temporary restraining order or injunction under subsection (a) without bond. Such injunction or order shall remain in effect until a complaint pursuant to <ref>section 2149 of this title</ref> is issued and dismissed by the Secretary or until an order to cease and desist made thereon by the Secretary has become final and effective or is set aside on appellate review. Attorneys of the Department of Agriculture may, with the approval of the Attorney General, appear in the United States district court representing the Secretary in any action brought under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–544, § 29</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XXV, § 2503(2)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4067</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2160.</num>
<heading> Prohibition on slaughter of dogs and cats for human consumption</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except as provided in subsection (c), no person may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> knowingly slaughter a dog or cat for human consumption; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> knowingly ship, transport, move, deliver, receive, possess, purchase, sell, or donate—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a dog or cat to be slaughtered for human consumption; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a dog or cat part for human consumption.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Scope</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subsection (a) shall apply only with respect to conduct—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in or affecting interstate commerce or foreign commerce; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> within the special maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception for Indian tribes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The prohibition in subsection (a) shall not apply to an Indian (as defined in <ref>section 5304 of title 25</ref>) carrying out any activity described in subsection (a) for the purpose of a religious ceremony.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Penalty</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any person who violates subsection (a) shall be subject to a fine in an amount not greater than $5,000 for each violation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect on State law</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Nothing in this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> limits any State or local law or regulation protecting the welfare of animals; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> prevents a State or unit of local government from adopting and enforcing an animal welfare law or regulation that is more stringent than this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title XII, § 12515</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5000</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>