<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 102—</num>
<heading>EMERGENCY FOOD ASSISTANCE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7501.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional commodities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “additional commodities” means commodities made available under <ref>section 7515 of this title</ref> in addition to the commodities made available under sections 7502 and 7507 of this title.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Average monthly number of unemployed persons</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “average monthly number of unemployed persons” means the average monthly number of unemployed persons in each State during the most recent fiscal year for which information concerning the number of unemployed persons is available, as determined by the Bureau of Labor Statistics of the Department of Labor.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible recipient agency</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “eligible recipient agency” means a public or nonprofit organization that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> administers—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an emergency feeding organization;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a charitable institution (including a hospital and a retirement home, but excluding a penal institution) to the extent that the institution serves needy persons;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a summer camp for children, or a child nutrition program providing food service;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> a nutrition project operating under the Older Americans Act of 1965 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 3001</ref> et seq.), including a project that operates a congregate nutrition site and a project that provides home-delivered meals; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> a disaster relief program;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> has been designated by the appropriate State agency, or by the Secretary; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> has been approved by the Secretary for participation in the program established under this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Emergency feeding organization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “emergency feeding organization” means a public or nonprofit organization that administers activities and projects (including the activities and projects of a charitable institution, a food bank, a food pantry, a hunger relief center, a soup kitchen, or a similar public or private nonprofit eligible recipient agency) providing nutrition assistance to relieve situations of emergency and distress through the provision of food to needy persons, including low-income and unemployed persons.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Food bank</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “food bank” means a public or charitable institution that maintains an established operation involving the provision of food or edible commodities, or the products of food or edible commodities, to food pantries, soup kitchens, hunger relief centers, or other food or feeding centers that, as an integral part of their normal activities, provide meals or food to feed needy persons on a regular basis.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Food pantry</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “food pantry” means a public or private nonprofit organization that distributes food to low-income and unemployed households, including food from sources other than the Department of Agriculture, to relieve situations of emergency and distress.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Poverty line</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “poverty line” has the meaning provided in <ref>section 9902(2) of title 42</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Soup kitchen</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “soup kitchen” means a public or charitable institution that, as an integral part of the normal activities of the institution, maintains an established feeding operation to provide food to needy homeless persons on a regular basis.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Total value of additional commodities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “total value of additional commodities” means the actual cost of all additional commodities that are paid by the Secretary (including the distribution and processing costs incurred by the Secretary).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(10)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Value of additional commodities allocated to each State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “value of additional commodities allocated to each State” means the actual cost of additional commodities allocated to each State that are paid by the Secretary (including the distribution and processing costs incurred by the Secretary).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–8, title II, § 201A</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 98–92, § 2(2)</ref>, <date date="1983-09-02">Sept. 2, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 608</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 99–198, title XV, § 1563</ref>, <date date="1985-12-23">Dec. 23, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 1590</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–193, title VIII, § 871(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-22">Aug. 22, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2343</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7502.</num>
<heading> Availability of CCC commodities</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, in order to complement the domestic nutrition programs, make maximum use of the Nation’s agricultural abundance, and expand and improve the domestic distribution of price-supported commodities, commodities acquired by the Commodity Credit Corporation that the Secretary of Agriculture (hereinafter referred to as the “Secretary”) determines, in his discretion, are in excess of quantities needed to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> carry out other domestic donation programs,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> meet other domestic obligations (including quantities needed to carry out a payment-in-kind acreage diversion program),</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> meet international market development and food aid commitments, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> carry out the farm price and income stabilization purposes of the Agricultural Adjustment Act of 1938 [<ref>7 U.S.C. 1281</ref> et seq.], the Agricultural Act of 1949 [<ref>7 U.S.C. 1421</ref> et seq.], and the Commodity Credit Corporation Charter Act [<ref>15 U.S.C. 714</ref> et seq.],</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be made available by the Secretary, without charge or credit for such commodities, for use by eligible recipient agencies for food assistance.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 99–198, title XV, § 1565(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1985-12-23">Dec. 23, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 1591</ref></heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional commodities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In addition to any commodities described in subsection (a), in carrying out this chapter, the Secretary may use agricultural commodities and the products thereof made available under clause (2) of the second sentence of <ref>section 612c of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Varieties of commodities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Commodities made available under this chapter shall include a variety of commodities and products thereof that are most useful to eligible recipient agencies, including, but not be <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002336">1</ref> limited to, dairy products, wheat or the products thereof, rice, honey, and cornmeal.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Effective <date date="1986-04-01">April 1, 1986</date>, the Secretary shall submit semiannually to the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate a report on the types and amounts of commodities made available for distribution under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Relation to other programs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the programs authorized by <ref>section 713a–14 of title 15</ref> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002337">1</ref> and section 1163 of the Food Security Act of 1985 shall not be operated in a manner that will, in any way, reduce the quantities of dairy products that traditionally are made available to carry out this chapter or any other domestic feeding program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Donations to emergency feeding organizations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Whenever commodities acquired by the Commodity Credit Corporation are made available for donation to domestic food programs in quantities that exceed Federal obligations, the Secretary shall give equal consideration to making donations of such commodities to emergency feeding organizations participating in the program authorized by this chapter as is given to other commodity recipient agencies, taking into account the types and amounts of commodities available and appropriate for distribution to these organizations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In determining the commodities that will be made available to emergency feeding organizations under this chapter, the Secretary may distribute commodities that become available on a seasonal or irregular basis.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Kosher and Halal food</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As soon as practicable after <date date="2014-02-07">February 7, 2014</date>, the Secretary shall finalize and implement a plan—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to increase the purchase of Kosher and Halal food from food manufacturers with a Kosher or Halal certification to carry out the program established under this chapter if the Kosher and Halal food purchased is cost neutral as compared to food that is not from food manufacturers with a Kosher or Halal certification; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to modify the labeling of the commodities list used to carry out the program in a manner that enables Kosher and Halal distribution entities to identify which commodities to obtain from local food banks.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–8, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="1983-03-24">Mar. 24, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 35</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–92, § 2(3)</ref>, (4), <date date="1983-09-02">Sept. 2, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 609</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–198, title XV</ref>, §§ 1564(a), 1565(a), <date date="1985-12-23">Dec. 23, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 1591</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–77, title VIII, § 811</ref>, <date date="1987-07-22">July 22, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 536</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–435, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1988-09-19">Sept. 19, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1647</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XVII, § 1772(b)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3808</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–79, title IV, § 4207</ref>, <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 826</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7503.</num>
<heading> State plan</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Plans</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To receive commodities under this chapter, a State shall submit to the Secretary an operation and administration plan for the provision of benefits under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Updates</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A State shall submit to the Secretary for approval any amendment to a plan submitted under paragraph (1) in any case in which the State proposes to make a change to the operation or administration of a program described in the plan.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each plan shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> designate the State agency responsible for distributing the commodities received under this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> set forth a plan of operation and administration to expeditiously distribute commodities under this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> set forth the standards of eligibility for recipient agencies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> set forth the standards of eligibility for individual or household recipients of commodities, which shall require—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> individuals or households to be comprised of needy persons; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> individual or household members to be residing in the geographic location served by the distributing agency at the time of applying for assistance;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> at the option of the State agency, describe a plan of operation for 1 or more projects in partnership with 1 or more emergency feeding organizations located in the State to harvest, process, package, or transport donated commodities received under <ref>section 7507(d) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> describe a plan, which may include the use of a State advisory board established under subsection (c), that provides emergency feeding organizations or eligible recipient agencies within the State an opportunity to provide input on the commodity preferences and needs of the emergency feeding organization or eligible recipient agency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State advisory board</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall encourage each State receiving commodities under this chapter to establish a State advisory board consisting of representatives of all entities in the State, both public and private, interested in the distribution of commodities received under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–8, title II, § 202A</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 100–77, title VIII, § 812</ref>, <date date="1987-07-22">July 22, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 537</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–193, title VIII, § 871(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-22">Aug. 22, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2344</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title IV, § 4201(b)</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1121</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title IV, § 4201(b), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1882; <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title IV, § 4018(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4648</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7504.</num>
<heading> Initial processing costs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may use funds of the Commodity Credit Corporation to pay costs of initial processing and packaging of commodities to be distributed under the program established under this chapter into forms, and in quantities, suitable, as determined by the Secretary, for use in individual households when such commodities are to be consumed by individual households or for institutional use, as applicable. The Secretary may pay such costs in the form of Corporation-owned commodities equal in value to such costs. The Secretary shall ensure that any such payments in kind will not displace commercial sales of such commodities.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–8, title II, § 203A</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 98–92, § 2(5)</ref>, <date date="1983-09-02">Sept. 2, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 609</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 99–198, title XV, § 1565(b)</ref>, <date date="1985-12-23">Dec. 23, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 1591</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7505.</num>
<heading> Federal and State responsibilities</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal responsibility; optional State priority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall, as expeditiously as possible, provide the commodities made available under this chapter in such quantities as can be used without waste to State agencies designated by the Governor or other appropriate State official for distribution to eligible recipient agencies, except that the Secretary may provide such commodities directly to eligible recipient agencies and to private companies that process such commodities for eligible recipient agencies under sections <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002338">1</ref> 7504 of this title. Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, in the distribution of commodities under this chapter, each State agency shall have the option to give priority to existing food bank networks and other organizations whose ongoing primary function is to facilitate the distribution of food to low-income households, including food from sources other than the Department of Agriculture.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Distribution by State agencies; priority; rural areas</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">State agencies receiving commodities under this chapter shall, as expeditiously as possible, distribute such commodities, in the quantities requested (to the extent practicable), to eligible recipient agencies within their respective States. However, if a State agency cannot meet all requests for a particular commodity under this chapter, the State agency shall give priority in the distribution of such commodity to eligible recipient agencies providing nutrition assistance to relieve situations of emergency and distress through the provision of food to needy persons, including low-income and unemployed persons. Each State agency shall encourage distribution of such commodities in rural areas.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Distribution to needy persons</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each State agency receiving commodities for individual household use under this chapter shall distribute such commodities to eligible recipient agencies in the State that serve needy persons, and shall, with the approval of the Secretary, determine those persons in the State that shall qualify as needy persons eligible for such commodities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cooperative agreements with adjoining States</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each State agency receiving commodities under this chapter may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> enter into cooperative agreements with State agencies of other States for joint provision of such commodities to an emergency feeding organization that serves needy persons in a single geographical area part of which is situated in each of such States; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> transfer such commodities to any such emergency feeding organization in the other State under such agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–8, title II, § 203B</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 98–92, § 2(5)</ref>, <date date="1983-09-02">Sept. 2, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 610</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 99–198, title XV, § 1568</ref>, <date date="1985-12-23">Dec. 23, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 1592</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–435, title I, § 105(c)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-19">Sept. 19, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1651</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–193, title VIII, § 871(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-22">Aug. 22, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2345</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7506.</num>
<heading> Assurances; anticipated use</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall take such precautions as the Secretary deems necessary to assure that any eligible recipient agency receiving commodities under this chapter will provide such commodities to persons served by the eligible recipient agency and will not diminish its normal expenditures for food by reason of the receipt of such commodities. The Secretary shall also take such precautions as the Secretary deems necessary to assure that commodities made available under this chapter will not displace commercial sales of such commodities or the products thereof. The Secretary shall not make commodities available for donation in any quantity or manner that the Secretary, in the Secretary’s discretion, determines may, substitute for the same or any other agricultural produce that would otherwise be purchased in the market.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Commodities provided under this chapter shall be distributed only in quantities that can be consumed without waste. No eligible recipient agency may receive commodities under this chapter in excess of anticipated use, based on inventory records and controls, or in excess of its ability to accept and store such commodities.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–8, title II, § 203C</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 98–92, § 2(5)</ref>, <date date="1983-09-02">Sept. 2, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 610</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 99–198, title XV, § 1566</ref>, <date date="1985-12-23">Dec. 23, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 1591</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–66, title I, § 1011(k)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-21">Dec. 21, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 710</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7507.</num>
<heading> State and local supplementation of commodities</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish procedures under which State and local agencies, charitable institutions, or any other persons may supplement the commodities distributed under the program authorized by this chapter for use by emergency feeding organizations with nutritious and wholesome commodities that such entities or persons donate to State agencies and emergency feeding organizations for distribution, in all or part of the State, in addition to the commodities otherwise made available under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of funds and facilities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">States and emergency feeding organizations may use the funds appropriated under this chapter and equipment, structures, vehicles, and all other facilities involved in the storage, handling, or distribution of commodities made available under this chapter, and the personnel, both paid or volunteer, involved in such storage, handling, or distribution, to store, handle or distribute commodities donated for the use of emergency feeding organizations under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Volunteer workers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">State and emergency feeding organizations shall continue, to the maximum extent practicable, to use volunteer workers and commodities and other foodstuffs donated by charitable and other organizations in the operation of the program authorized by this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Projects to harvest, process, package, or transport donated commodities</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition of project</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In this subsection, the term “project” means the harvesting, processing, packaging, or transportation of unharvested, unprocessed, or unpackaged commodities donated by agricultural producers, processors, or distributors for use by emergency feeding organizations under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal funding for projects</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Subject to subparagraphs (B) and (C) and paragraph (3), using funds made available under paragraph (5), the Secretary may provide funding to States to pay for the costs of carrying out a project.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal share</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Federal share of the cost of a project under subparagraph (A) shall not exceed 50 percent of the total cost of the project.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Allocation</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Each fiscal year, the Secretary shall allocate the funds made available under subparagraph (A), based on a formula determined by the Secretary, to States that have submitted a State plan describing a plan of operation for a project under <ref>section 7503(b)(5) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reallocation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">If the Secretary determines that a State will not expend all of the funds allocated to the State for a fiscal year under clause (i), the Secretary shall reallocate the unexpended funds to other States that have submitted under <ref>section 7503(b)(5) of this title</ref> a State plan describing a plan of operation for a project during that fiscal year or the subsequent fiscal year, as the Secretary determines appropriate.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Each State to which funds are allocated for a fiscal year under this subparagraph shall, on a regular basis, submit to the Secretary financial reports describing the use of the funds.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Project purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A State may only use Federal funds received under paragraph (2) for a project the purposes of which are—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to reduce food waste at the agricultural production, processing, or distribution level through the donation of food;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to provide food to individuals in need; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to build relationships between agricultural producers, processors, and distributors and emergency feeding organizations through the donation of food.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cooperative agreements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may encourage a State agency that carries out a project using Federal funds received under paragraph (2) to enter into cooperative agreements with State agencies of other States under <ref>section 7505(d) of this title</ref> to maximize the use of commodities donated under the project.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Funding</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Out of funds not otherwise appropriated, the Secretary of the Treasury shall transfer to the Secretary to carry out this subsection $4,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2019 through 2024, to remain available until the end of the subsequent fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Food waste</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall issue guidance outlining best practices to minimize the food waste of the commodities donated under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Food donation standards</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In this subsection:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Apparently wholesome food</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “apparently wholesome food” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 1791(b) of title 42</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Institution of higher education</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “institution of higher education” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 1002 of title 20</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Qualified direct donor</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “qualified direct donor” means a retail food store, wholesaler, agricultural producer, restaurant, caterer, school food authority, or institution of higher education.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Guidance</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2018-12-20">December 20, 2018</date>, the Secretary shall issue guidance to promote awareness of donations of apparently wholesome food protected under <ref>section 1791(c) of title 42</ref> by qualified direct donors in compliance with applicable State and local health, food safety, and food handling laws (including regulations).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Issuance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary shall encourage State agencies and emergency feeding organizations to share the guidance issued under subparagraph (A) with qualified direct donors.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–8, title II, § 203D</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 100–435, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1988-09-19">Sept. 19, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1647</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title IV</ref>, §§ 4018(b), (c), 4104, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4648</ref>, 4649, 4655; <ref>Pub. L. 118–22, div. B, title I, § 102(d)(3)</ref>, <date date="2023-11-17">Nov. 17, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 116</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7508.</num>
<heading> Authorization and appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> There are authorized to be appropriated $100,000,000 for fiscal year 2008 and each fiscal year thereafter for the Secretary to make available to the States to pay for the direct and indirect costs of the States related to the processing, storage, transporting, and distributing to eligible recipient agencies of commodities provided by the Secretary under this chapter and commodities secured from other sources, including commodities secured by gleaning (as defined in section 111(a) of the Hunger Prevention Act of 1988 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 612c</ref> note; <ref>Public Law 100–435</ref>)) and donated wild game. Funds appropriated under this paragraph for any fiscal year shall be allocated to the States on an advance basis, dividing such funds among the States in the same proportions as the commodities distributed under this chapter for such fiscal year are divided among the States. If a State agency is unable to use all of the funds so allocated to it, the Secretary shall reallocate such unused funds among the other States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Each State shall make available to emergency feeding organizations in the State not less than 40 per centum of the funds provided as authorized in paragraph (1) that it has been allocated for a fiscal year, as necessary to pay for, or provide advance payments to cover, the direct expenses of the emergency feeding organizations for distributing commodities to needy persons, but only to the extent such expenses are actually so incurred by such organizations. As used in this paragraph, the term “direct expenses” includes costs of transporting, storing, handling, repackaging, processing, and distributing commodities incurred after they are received by the organization; costs associated with determinations of eligibility, verification, and documentation; costs of providing information to persons receiving commodities under this chapter concerning the appropriate storage and preparation of such commodities; costs involved in publishing announcements of times and locations of distribution; and costs of recordkeeping, auditing, and other administrative procedures required for participation in the program under this chapter. If a State makes a payment, using State funds, to cover direct expenses of emergency feeding organizations, the amount of such payment shall be counted toward the amount a State must make available for direct expenses of emergency feeding organizations under this paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> States to which funds are allocated for a fiscal year under this subsection shall submit financial reports to the Secretary, on a regular basis, as to the use of such funds. No such funds may be used by States or emergency feeding organizations for costs other than those involved in covering the expenses related to the distribution of commodities by emergency feeding organizations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> Except as provided in subparagraph (B), effective <date date="1987-01-01">January 1, 1987</date>, to be eligible to receive funds under this subsection, a State shall provide in cash or in kind (according to procedures approved by the Secretary for certifying these in-kind contributions) from non-Federal sources a contribution equal to the difference between—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the amount of such funds so received; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> any part of the amount allocated to the State and paid by the State—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> to emergency feeding organizations; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> for the direct expenses of such organizations;</content>
</subclause>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">for use in carrying out this chapter.</continuation>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Except as provided in clause (ii), subparagraph (A) shall apply to States beginning on <date date="1987-01-01">January 1, 1987</date>.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> If the legislature of a State does not convene in regular session before <date date="1987-01-01">January 1, 1987</date>, paragraph (1) shall apply to such State beginning on <date date="1987-10-01">October 1, 1987</date>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Funds allocated to a State under this section may, upon State request, be allocated before States satisfy the matching requirement specified in subparagraph (A), based on the estimated contribution required. The Secretary shall periodically reconcile estimated and actual contributions and adjust allocations to the State to correct for overpayments and underpayments.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> States may not charge for commodities made available to emergency feeding organizations, and may not pass on to such organizations the cost of any matching requirements, under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The value of the commodities made available under this chapter and the funds of the Corporation used to pay the costs of initial processing, packaging (including forms suitable for home use), and delivering commodities to the States shall not be charged against appropriations made or authorized under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–8, title II, § 204</ref>, <date date="1983-03-24">Mar. 24, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 35</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–92, § 2(6)</ref>, <date date="1983-09-02">Sept. 2, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 610</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–198, title XV, § 1569</ref>, <date date="1985-12-23">Dec. 23, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 1592</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–77, title VIII, § 813</ref>, <date date="1987-07-22">July 22, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 537</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–435, title I</ref>, §§ 103(a)–(c), 105(a), <date date="1988-09-19">Sept. 19, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1647</ref>, 1650; <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XVII, § 1772(c)</ref>, (d), <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3808</ref>, 3809; <ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title IV, § 403(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1029</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–193, title VIII, § 871(c)</ref>, (e)(2), <date date="1996-08-22">Aug. 22, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2345</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–171, title IV, § 4204</ref>, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 330</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title IV</ref>, §§ 4201(c), 4406(b)(1), <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1121</ref>, 1141; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title IV, §§ 4201(c), 4406(b)(1), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1882, 1902.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7509.</num>
<heading> Relationship to other programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content><ref>Section 2013(b) of this title</ref> shall not apply with respect to the distribution of commodities under this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Except as otherwise provided in <ref>section 7504 of this title</ref>, none of the commodities distributed under this chapter shall be sold or otherwise disposed of in commercial channels in any form.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–8, title II, § 205</ref>, <date date="1983-03-24">Mar. 24, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 36</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–92, § 2(7)</ref>, <date date="1983-09-02">Sept. 2, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 611</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title I, § 4002(b)(1)(B)</ref>, (2)(I), <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1096</ref>, 1097; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title IV, § 4002(b)(1)(B), (2)(I), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1857, 1858.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7510.</num>
<heading> Commodities not income</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, commodities distributed under this chapter shall not be considered income or resources for any purposes under any Federal, State, or local law.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–8, title II, § 206</ref>, <date date="1983-03-24">Mar. 24, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 36</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7511.</num>
<heading> Prohibition against certain State charges</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever a commodity is made available without charge or credit under any nutrition program administered by the Secretary for distribution within the States to eligible recipient agencies, the State may not charge recipient agencies any amount that is in excess of the State’s direct costs of storing and transporting the commodities to recipient agencies minus any amount the Secretary provides the State for the costs of storing and transporting such commodities.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–8, title II, § 208</ref>, <date date="1983-03-24">Mar. 24, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 36</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7511a.</num>
<heading> Emergency food program infrastructure grants</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition of eligible entity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this section, the term “eligible entity” means an emergency feeding organization.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program authorized</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall use funds made available under subsection (d) to make grants to eligible entities to pay the costs of an activity described in subsection (c).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rural preference</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary shall use not less than 50 percent of the funds described in paragraph (1) for a fiscal year to make grants to eligible entities that serve predominantly rural communities for the purposes of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> expanding the capacity and infrastructure of food banks, State-wide food bank associations, and food bank collaboratives that operate in rural areas; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> improving the capacity of the food banks to procure, receive, store, distribute, track, and deliver time-sensitive or perishable food products.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">An eligible entity shall use a grant received under this section for any fiscal year to carry out activities of the eligible entity, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the development and maintenance of a computerized system for the tracking of time-sensitive food products;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> capital, infrastructure, and operating costs associated with the collection, storage, distribution, and transportation of time-sensitive and perishable food products;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> improving the security and diversity of the emergency food distribution and recovery systems of the United States through the support of small or mid-size farms and ranches, fisheries, and aquaculture, and donations from local food producers and manufacturers to persons in need;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> providing recovered foods to food banks and similar nonprofit emergency food providers to reduce hunger in the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> improving the identification of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> potential providers of donated foods;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> potential nonprofit emergency food providers; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> persons in need of emergency food assistance in rural areas; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> constructing, expanding, or repairing a facility or equipment to support hunger relief agencies in the community.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $15,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2008 through 2023.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–8, title II, § 209</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title IV, § 4202</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1121</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title IV, § 4202, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1883; amended <ref>Pub. L. 113–79, title IV, § 4027(b)</ref>, <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 812</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title IV, § 4018(d)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4650</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7512.</num>
<heading> Regulations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Issuance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall issue regulations within 30 days to implement this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Minimization of regulatory requirements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In administering this chapter, the Secretary shall minimize, to the maximum extent practicable, the regulatory, recordkeeping, and paperwork requirements imposed on eligible recipient agencies.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Publication in Federal Register</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall as early as feasible but not later than the beginning of each fiscal year, publish in the Federal Register an estimate of the types and quantities of commodities that the Secretary anticipates are likely to be made available under the commodity distribution program under this chapter during the fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The actual types and quantities of commodities made available by the Secretary under this chapter may differ from the estimates made under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Standards of liability for commodity losses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The regulations issued by the Secretary under this section shall include provisions that set standards with respect to liability for commodity losses under the program under this chapter in situations in which there is no evidence of negligence or fraud, and conditions for payment to cover such losses. Such provisions shall take into consideration the special needs and circumstances of emergency feeding organizations <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002339">1</ref></p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Final regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to issue final regulations without first issuing proposed regulations for public comment in order to carry out the provisions of sections 7514 and 7515 of this title. If final regulations are issued without such prior public comment the Secretary shall permit public comment on such regulations, consider pertinent comments, and make modifications of such regulations as appropriate not later than 1 year after <date date="1988-09-19">September 19, 1988</date>. Such final and modified regulations shall be accompanied by a statement of the basis and purpose for such regulations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–8, title II, § 210</ref>, <date date="1983-03-24">Mar. 24, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 36</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–92, § 2(9)</ref>, <date date="1983-09-02">Sept. 2, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 611</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–198, title XV, § 1570</ref>, <date date="1985-12-23">Dec. 23, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 1594</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–77, title VIII, § 814(b)</ref>, <date date="1987-07-22">July 22, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 538</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–435, title I</ref>, §§ 103(d), 105(b), <date date="1988-09-19">Sept. 19, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1648</ref>, 1651; <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XVII, § 1772(e)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3809</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–193, title VIII, § 871(e)(3)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-22">Aug. 22, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2345</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7513.</num>
<heading> Finality of determinations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Determinations made by the Secretary of Agriculture under this chapter and the facts constituting the basis for any donation of commodities under this chapter, or the amount thereof, when officially determined in conformity with the applicable regulations prescribed by the Secretary, shall be final and conclusive and shall not be reviewable by any other officer or agency of the Government.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–8, title II, § 211</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 98–92, § 2(10)</ref>, <date date="1983-09-02">Sept. 2, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 612</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7514.</num>
<heading> Incorporation of additional commodities</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall administer the program authorized under this chapter in a manner that incorporates into the program additional commodities purchased by the Secretary under <ref>section 7515 of this title</ref> to be distributed to States for use in such States by emergency feeding organizations, as defined in section 7501(1) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002340">1</ref> of this title. Such additional commodities, to the extent practicable and appropriate, shall include commodities purchased within a given State for distribution within such State.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Supplement commodities available</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall supplement the commodities made available to emergency feeding organizations under sections 7502 and 7507(a) of this title with nutritious and useful commodities purchased by the Secretary under <ref>section 7515 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–8, title II, § 213</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 100–435, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="1988-09-19">Sept. 19, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1648</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7515.</num>
<heading> Allotment and delivery of commodities</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Mandatory allotments</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In each fiscal year, the Secretary shall allot—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> 60 percent of the total value of additional commodities provided to States in a manner such that the value of additional commodities allocated to each State bears the same ratio to 60 percent of the total value of additional commodities as the number of persons in households within the State having incomes below the poverty line bears to the total number of persons in households within all States having incomes below such poverty line, and each State shall be entitled to receive such value of additional commodities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> 40 percent of the total value of additional commodities provided to States in a manner such that the value of additional commodities allocated to each State bears the same ratio to 40 percent of the total value of additional commodities as the average monthly number of unemployed persons within the State bears to the average monthly number of unemployed persons within all States during the same fiscal year, and each State shall be entitled to receive such value of additional commodities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reallocation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall notify each State of the amount of the additional commodities that such State is allotted to receive under subsection (a), and each State shall promptly notify the Secretary if such State determines that it will not accept any or all of the commodities made available under such allocation. On such a notification by a State, the Secretary shall reallocate and distribute the amount the State was allocated to receive under the formula prescribed in subsection (a) but declined to accept. The Secretary shall further establish procedures to permit States to decline to receive portions of such allocation during each fiscal year as the State determines is appropriate and the Secretary shall reallocate and distribute such allocation. In the event of any drought, flood, hurricane, or other natural disaster affecting substantial numbers of persons in a State, county or parish, the Secretary may request that States unaffected by such a disaster consider assisting affected States by allowing the Secretary to reallocate commodities to which each such unaffected State is entitled to States containing areas adversely affected by the disaster.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administration</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Commodities made available for each fiscal year under this section shall be delivered at reasonable intervals to States based on the grants calculated under subsection (a), or reallocated under subsection (b), before December 31 of the following fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Entitlement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Each State shall be entitled to receive the value of additional commodities determined under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Maintenance of effort</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If a State uses its own funds to provide commodities or services to organizations receiving funds or services under this section, such State shall not diminish the level of support it provides to such organizations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–8, title II, § 214</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 100–435, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="1988-09-19">Sept. 19, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1648</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XVII, § 1772(g)</ref>, (h)(1), <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3809</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title IV, § 403(c)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1029</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–193, title VIII, § 871(d)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-22">Aug. 22, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2345</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7516.</num>
<heading> Settlement and adjustment of claims</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary or a designee of the Secretary shall have the authority to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> determine the amount of, settle, and adjust any claim arising under this chapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> waive such a claim if the Secretary determines that to do so will serve the purposes of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Litigation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing contained in this section shall be construed to diminish the authority of the Attorney General of the United States under <ref>section 516 of title 28</ref> to conduct litigation on behalf of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–8, title II, § 215</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 102–237, title IX, § 922(b)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-13">Dec. 13, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1888</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7517.</num>
<heading> The Gus Schumacher nutrition incentive program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible entity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “eligible entity” means a governmental agency or nonprofit organization.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Emergency feeding organization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “emergency feeding organization” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 7501 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Supplemental nutrition assistance program</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “supplemental nutrition assistance program” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the supplemental nutrition assistance program established under the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 2011</ref> et seq.); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the programs for nutrition assistance under section 19 of such Act (<ref>7 U.S.C. 2028</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Healthcare partner</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “healthcare partner” means a healthcare provider, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a hospital;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a Federally-qualified health center (as defined in section 1905(<i>l</i>) of the Social Security Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 1396d</ref>(<i>l</i>)));</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a hospital or clinic operated by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a healthcare provider group.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Member</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “member” means, as determined by the applicable eligible entity or healthcare partner carrying out a project under subsection (c) in accordance with procedures established by the Secretary—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> an individual eligible for—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> benefits under the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 2011</ref> et seq.); or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> medical assistance under a State plan or a waiver of such a plan under title XIX of the Social Security Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 1396</ref> et seq.) and enrolled under such plan or waiver; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a member of a low-income household that suffers from, or is at risk of developing, a diet-related health condition.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Food insecurity nutrition incentive grants</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In each of the years specified in subsection (c), the Secretary shall make grants to eligible entities in accordance with paragraph (2).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Partners and collaborators</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">An eligible entity that receives a grant under this subsection may partner with, or make subgrants to, public, private, nonprofit, or for-profit entities, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an emergency feeding organization;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> an agricultural cooperative;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a producer network or association;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> a community health organization;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> a public benefit corporation;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> an economic development corporation;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> a farmers’ market;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> a community-supported agriculture program;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ix)</num>
<content> a buying club;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(x)</num>
<content> a retail food store participating in the supplemental nutrition assistance program;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(xi)</num>
<content> a State, local, or tribal agency;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(xii)</num>
<content> another eligible entity that receives a grant under this subsection; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(xiii)</num>
<content> any other entity the Secretary designates.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal share</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Except as provided in subparagraph (D)(iii), the Federal share of the cost of carrying out an activity under this subsection shall not exceed 50 percent of the total cost of the activity.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Non-Federal share</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">The non-Federal share of the cost of an activity under this subsection may be provided—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> in cash or in-kind contributions as determined by the Secretary, including facilities, equipment, or services; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> by a State or local government or a private source.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">In the case of a for-profit entity, the non-Federal share described in clause (i) shall not include services of an employee, including salaries paid or expenses covered by the employer.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tribal agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The Secretary may allow a Tribal agency to use funds provided to the Indian Tribe of the Tribal agency through a Federal agency (including the Indian Health Service) or other Federal benefit to satisfy all or part of the non-Federal share described in clause (i) if such use is otherwise consistent with the purpose of such funds.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Criteria</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">To receive a grant under this subsection, an eligible entity shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> meet the application criteria set forth by the Secretary; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> propose a project that, at a minimum—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> has the support of the State agency administering the supplemental nutrition assistance program;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> would increase the purchase of fruits and vegetables by low-income households participating in the supplemental nutrition assistance program by providing an incentive for the purchase of fruits and vegetables at the point of purchase to a household purchasing food with supplemental nutrition assistance program benefits;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> except in the case of projects receiving $100,000 or less over 1 year, would measure the purchase of fruits and vegetables by low-income households participating in the supplemental nutrition assistance program;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> ensures that the same terms and conditions apply to purchases made by individuals with benefits issued under the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 [<ref>7 U.S.C. 2011</ref> et seq.] and incentives provided for in this subsection as apply to purchases made by individuals who are not members of households receiving benefits, such as provided for in section 278.2(b) of title 7, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation);</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(V)</num>
<content> has adequate plans to collect data for reporting and agrees to provide that information for the report described in subsection (e)(2)(B)(iii); and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(VI)</num>
<content> would share information with the Nutrition Incentive Program Training, Technical Assistance, Evaluation, and Information Centers established under subsection (e).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Priority</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to projects that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> maximize the share of funds used for direct incentives to participants;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> use direct-to-consumer sales marketing;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> demonstrate a track record of designing and implementing successful nutrition incentive programs that connect low-income consumers and agricultural producers;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> provide locally or regionally produced fruits and vegetables;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<chapeau> include a project design—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> that provides incentives when fruits or vegetables are purchased using supplemental nutrition assistance program benefits; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> in which the incentives earned may be used only to purchase fruits or vegetables;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> have demonstrated the ability to provide services to underserved communities;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> include coordination with multiple stakeholders, such as farm organizations, nutrition education programs, cooperative extension services, public health departments, health providers, private and public health insurance agencies, cooperative grocers, grocery associations, and community-based and nongovernmental organizations;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> offer supplemental services in high-need communities, including online ordering, transportation between home and store, and delivery services;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ix)</num>
<chapeau> include food retailers that are open—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> for extended hours; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> most or all days of the year; or</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(x)</num>
<content> address other criteria as established by the Secretary.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Produce prescription program</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary shall establish a grant program under which the Secretary shall award grants to eligible entities to conduct projects that demonstrate and evaluate the impact of the projects on—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the improvement of dietary health through increased consumption of fruits and vegetables;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the reduction of individual and household food insecurity; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the reduction in healthcare use and associated costs.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Healthcare partners</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In carrying out a project using a grant received under paragraph (1), an eligible entity shall partner with 1 or more healthcare partners.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grant applications</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">To be eligible to receive a grant under paragraph (1), an eligible entity—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> shall—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> prescribe fresh fruits and vegetables to members;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> submit to the Secretary an application containing such information as the Secretary may require, including the information described in subparagraph (B); and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> may—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> provide financial or non-financial incentives for members to purchase or procure fresh fruits and vegetables;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> provide educational resources on nutrition to members; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> establish additional accessible locations for members to procure fresh fruits and vegetables.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">An application shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> identify the 1 or more healthcare partners with which the eligible entity is partnering under paragraph (2); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> include—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<chapeau> a description of the methods by which an eligible entity shall—</chapeau>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> screen and verify eligibility for members for participation in a produce prescription project, in accordance with procedures established under subsection (a)(5);</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> implement an effective produce prescription project, including the role of each healthcare partner in implementing the produce prescription project;</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(cc)</num>
<content> evaluate members participating in a produce prescription project with respect to the matters described in subparagraphs (A) through (C) of paragraph (1);</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(dd)</num>
<content> provide educational opportunities relating to nutrition to members participating in a produce prescription project; and</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(ee)</num>
<content> inform members of the availability of the produce prescription project, including locations at which produce prescriptions may be redeemed;</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> a description of any additional nonprofit or emergency feeding organizations that shall be involved in the project and the role of each additional nonprofit or emergency feeding organization in implementing and evaluating an effective produce prescription project;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> documentation of a partnership agreement with a relevant State Medicaid agency or other appropriate entity, as determined by the Secretary, to evaluate the effectiveness of the produce prescription project in reducing healthcare use and associated costs;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> adequate plans to collect data for reporting and agreement to provide that information for the report described in subsection (e)(2)(B)(iii); and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(V)</num>
<content> agreement to share information with the Nutrition Incentive Program Training, Technical Assistance, Evaluation, and Information Centers established under subsection (e).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In carrying out the grant program established under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall coordinate with the Secretary of Health and Human Services and the heads of other appropriate Federal agencies that carry out activities relating to healthcare partners.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Partnerships</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In carrying out the grant program under paragraph (1), the Secretary may enter into 1 or more memoranda of understanding with a Federal agency, a State, or a private entity to ensure the effective implementation and evaluation of each project.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Memorandum of understanding</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">A memorandum of understanding entered into under subparagraph (A) shall include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a description of a plan to provide educational opportunities relating to nutrition to members participating in produce prescription projects;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a description of the role of the Federal agency, State, or private entity, as applicable, in implementing and evaluating an effective produce prescription project; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> documentation of a partnership agreement with a relevant State Medicaid agency or other appropriate entity, as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The value of any benefit provided to a participant in any activity funded under subsections (b) or (c) shall be treated as supplemental nutrition benefits under section 8(b) of the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 2017(b)</ref>).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition on collection of sales taxes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Each State shall ensure that no State or local tax is collected on a purchase of food with assistance provided under subsections (b) and (c).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> No limitation on benefits</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Grants made available under subsections (b) and (c) shall not be used to carry out any project that limits the use of benefits under the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 2011</ref> et seq.) or any other Federal nutrition law.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Household allotment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Assistance provided under subsections (b) and (c) to households receiving benefits under the supplemental nutrition assistance program shall not—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> be considered part of the supplemental nutrition assistance program benefits of the household; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> be used in the collection or disposition of claims under section 13 of the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 2022</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nutrition Incentive Program Training, Technical Assistance, Evaluation, and Information Centers</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> establish 1 or more Nutrition Incentive Program Training, Technical Assistance, Evaluation, and Information Centers, in consultation with the Director of the National Institute of Food and Agriculture; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to the extent practicable, consult on the design and scope of such Centers with grocers, farmers, health professionals, researchers, incentive program managers, and employees of the Department of Agriculture with direct experience with implementation of existing incentive programs or projects.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Centers shall be capable of providing services related to grants under subsections (b) and (c), including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> offering incentive program training and technical assistance to applicants and grantees to the extent practicable, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> collecting and providing information on best practices that may include communications, signage, record-keeping, incentive instruments, development and integration of point of sale systems, and reporting;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> disseminating information and assisting with collaboration among grantee projects, applicable State agencies, and nutrition education programs;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> facilitating communication between grantees and the Department of Agriculture and applicable State agencies; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> providing support for the development of best practices for produce prescription projects and the sharing of information among eligible entities and healthcare providers that participate in a produce prescription project under subsection (c); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> other services identified by the Secretary; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> creating a system to collect and compile core data sets from eligible entities that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> uses standard metrics with consideration of outcome measures for existing projects;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> includes to the extent practicable grocers, farmers, health professionals, researchers, incentive program managers, and employees of the Department of Agriculture with direct experience with implementation of existing incentive programs in the design of the instrument through which data will be collected and the mechanism for reporting;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> compiles project data from grantees, and beginning in fiscal year 2020 generates an annual report to Congress on grant outcomes, including—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the results of the project; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the amount of grant funds used for the project; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> creates and maintains a publicly accessible online site that makes annual reports and incentive program information available in an anonymized format that protects confidential, personal, or other sensitive data.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cooperative agreement</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">To carry out paragraph (1), the Secretary may, on a competitive basis, enter into 1 or more cooperative agreements with 1 or more organizations with expertise in developing outcome-based reporting, at least 1 of which has expertise in the food insecurity nutrition incentive program and at least 1 of which has expertise in produce prescription projects.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inclusion</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The organizations referred to in subparagraph (A) may include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> nongovernmental organizations;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> State cooperative extension services;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> regional food system centers;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> Federal, State, or Tribal agencies;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> institutions of higher education (as defined in <ref>section 1001(a) of title 20</ref>); or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> other appropriate entities as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Funding</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2014 through 2023.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Mandatory funding</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Of the funds of the Commodity Credit Corporation, the Secretary shall use to carry out this section—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> $35,000,000 for the period of fiscal years 2014 and 2015;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> $20,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2016 and 2017;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002341">1</ref> $25,000,000 for fiscal year 2018;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> <sup>1</sup> $45,000,000 for fiscal year 2019;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> $48,000,000 for fiscal year 2020;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> $48,000,000 for fiscal year 2021;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> $53,000,000 for fiscal year 2022; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> $56,000,000 for fiscal year 2023 and each fiscal year thereafter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">With respect to funds made available under this section for fiscal years 2019 through 2023—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> for each fiscal year the Secretary shall use not more than 10 percent of such funds available for such fiscal year for the produce prescription program described in subsection (c);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for each fiscal year not more than 8 percent of such funds available for such fiscal year shall be used by the National Institute of Food and Agriculture and the Food and Nutrition Service for administration; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> the Secretary shall use for the Nutrition Incentive Program Training, Technical Assistance, Evaluation, and Information Centers established under subsection (e) not more than—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> $17,000,000 in the aggregate for fiscal years 2019 and 2020; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> $7,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2021 through 2023.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title IV, § 4405</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1138</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title IV, § 4405, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1899; <ref>Pub. L. 113–79, title IV, § 4208</ref>, <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 826</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title IV, § 4205(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4656</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7518.</num>
<heading> Micro-grants for food security</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purpose</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The purpose of this section is to increase the quantity and quality of locally grown food through small-scale gardening, herding, and livestock operations in food insecure communities in areas of the United States that have significant levels of food insecurity and import a significant quantity of food.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible entity</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “eligible entity” means an entity that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> is—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an individual;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> an Indian tribe or tribal organization, as defined in <ref>section 5304 of title 25</ref>;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> a nonprofit organization engaged in increasing food security, as determined by the Secretary, including—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> a religious organization;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> a food bank; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> a food pantry;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<chapeau> a federally funded educational facility, including—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> a Head Start program or an Early Head Start program carried out under the Head Start Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 9831</ref> et seq.);</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> a public elementary school or public secondary school;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> a public institution of higher education (as defined in <ref>section 1001 of title 20</ref>);</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> a Tribal College or University (as defined in <ref>section 1059c(b) of title 20</ref>); or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(V)</num>
<content> a job training program; or</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> a local or Tribal government that may not levy local taxes under State or Federal law; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is located in an eligible State.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible State</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “eligible State” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the State of Alaska;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the State of Hawaii;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> American Samoa;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the Federated States of Micronesia;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> Guam;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> the Republic of the Marshall Islands;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the Republic of Palau; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> the United States Virgin Islands.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall distribute funds to the agricultural department or agency of each eligible State for the competitive distribution of subgrants to eligible entities to increase the quantity and quality of locally grown food in food insecure communities, including through small-scale gardening, herding, and livestock operations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Distribution of funds</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Of the amount made available under subsection (g), the Secretary shall distribute—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> 40 percent to the State of Alaska;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> 40 percent to the State of Hawaii; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> 2.5 percent to each eligible State described in any of subparagraphs (C) through (J) of subsection (b)(2).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Carryover of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Funds distributed under paragraph (1) shall remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrative funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">An eligible State that receives funds under paragraph (1) may use not more than 3 percent of those funds—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to administer the competition for providing subgrants to eligible entities in that eligible State;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to provide oversight of the subgrant recipients in that eligible State; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to collect data and submit a report to the Secretary under subsection (f)(2).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Subgrants to eligible entities</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amount of subgrants</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The amount of a subgrant to an eligible entity under this section shall be—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> in the case of an eligible entity that is an individual, not greater than $5,000 per year; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in the case of an eligible entity described in any of clauses (ii) through (v) of subsection (b)(1)(A), not greater than $10,000 per year.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Matching requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">As a condition of receiving a subgrant under this section, an eligible entity shall provide funds equal to 10 percent of the amount received by the eligible entity under the subgrant, to be derived from non-Federal sources. A State may waive the matching requirement for an individual who otherwise meets the requirements to receive a subgrant by the eligible State.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Project period</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Funds received by an eligible entity that is awarded a subgrant under this section shall remain available for expenditure not later than 3 years after the date the funds are received.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Priority</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In carrying out the competitive distribution of subgrants under subsection (c), an eligible State may give priority to an eligible entity that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> has not previously received a subgrant under this section; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is located in a community or region in that eligible State with the highest degree of food insecurity, as determined by the agricultural department or agency of the eligible State.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Projects</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">An eligible State may provide subgrants to 2 or more eligible entities to carry out the same project.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of subgrant funds by eligible entities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">An eligible entity that receives a subgrant under this section shall use the funds to engage in activities that will increase the quantity and quality of locally grown food for food insecure individuals, families, neighborhoods, and communities, including by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> purchasing gardening tools or equipment, soil, soil amendments, seeds, plants, animals, canning equipment, refrigeration, or other items necessary to grow and store food;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> purchasing or building composting units;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> purchasing or building towers designed to grow leafy green vegetables;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> expanding an area under cultivation or engaging in other activities necessary to be eligible to receive funding under the environmental quality incentives program established under chapter 4 of subtitle D of title XII of the Food Security Act of 1985 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 3839aa</ref> et seq.) for a high tunnel;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> engaging in an activity that extends the growing season;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> starting or expanding hydroponic and aeroponic farming of any scale;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> building, buying, erecting, or repairing fencing for livestock, poultry, or reindeer;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> purchasing and equipping a slaughter and processing facility approved by the Secretary;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<chapeau> traveling to participate in agricultural education provided by—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a State cooperative extension service;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a land-grant college or university (as defined in <ref>section 3103 of this title</ref>);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a Tribal College or University (as defined in <ref>section 1059c(b) of title 20</ref>);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> an Alaska Native-serving institution or a Native Hawaiian-serving institution (as such terms are defined in <ref>section 1059d(b) of title 20</ref>); or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> a Federal or State agency;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> paying for shipping of purchased items relating to growing or raising food for local consumption or purchase;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(K)</num>
<chapeau> creating or expanding avenues for—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the sale of food commodities, specialty crops, and meats that are grown by the eligible entity for sale in the local community; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> increasing the availability of fresh, locally grown, and nutritious food; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(L)</num>
<content> engaging in other activities relating to increasing food security (including subsistence), as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility for other financial assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">An eligible entity shall not be ineligible to receive financial assistance under another program administered by the Secretary as a result of receiving a subgrant under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reporting requirement</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Subgrant recipients</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">As a condition of receiving a subgrant under this section, an eligible entity shall agree to submit to the eligible State in which the eligible entity is located a report—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> not later than 60 days after the end of the project funded by the subgrant; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> that describes the use of the subgrants by eligible entities, the quantity of food grown through small-scale gardening, herding, and livestock operations, and the number of food insecure individuals fed as a result of the subgrant.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report to the Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 120 days after the date on which an eligible State receives a report from each eligible entity in that State under paragraph (1), the eligible State shall submit to the Secretary a report that describes, in the aggregate, the information and data contained in the reports received from those eligible entities.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Funding</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this section $10,000,000 for fiscal year 2019 and each fiscal year thereafter, to remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appropriations in advance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Only funds appropriated under paragraph (1) in advance specifically to carry out this section shall be available to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title IV, § 4206</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4663</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>