<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 49—</num>
<heading>CONSULTATION ON AGRICULTURAL PROGRAMS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1911.</num>
<heading> Consultation of Secretary of Agriculture with farmers, farm and commodity organizations and other persons and organizations; travel and per diem expenses</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, whenever the Secretary of Agriculture determines that additional legislative authority is necessary to develop new agricultural programs involving supply adjustments or marketing regulations through marketing orders, marketing quotas, or price support programs with respect to any agricultural commodity, or to make substantial revisions in any existing agricultural legislation or programs, he may consult and advise with farmers, farm organizations, and appropriate commodity organizations, if any, for the commodity involved, to review the problems involved, the need for new legislation, and the provisions which should be included in any such proposed legislation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> In addition, whenever and to the extent he deems such action necessary or desirable, the Secretary of Agriculture may consult and advise with any person or group of persons, or organizations, including farmers, handlers, processors, or others connected with the production, processing, handling, or use of the commodity involved, with respect to the problems involved and need for legislation and the provisions which should be included in any such proposed legislation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> In order that the Secretary of Agriculture may be assured of being able to obtain the advice of any such person or organization, he is authorized, whenever he determines such action necessary, to pay for each day’s attendance at meetings and while traveling to and from such meetings, transportation expenses and in lieu of subsistence, a per diem in the amount authorized under subchapter I of chapter 57 of title 5 for Federal employees. No salary or other compensation shall be paid.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–128, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1961-08-08">Aug. 8, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 295</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1912.</num>
<heading> Submission of legislative proposals</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the Secretary of Agriculture, after such consultation and receipt of such advice as provided in <ref>section 1911 of this title</ref>, determines that additional legislative authority is necessary to develop agricultural programs involving supply adjustments or marketing regulations through the use of marketing orders, marketing quotas or price-support programs, he shall formulate specific recommendations in the form of proposed legislation which shall be submitted to the Congress together with a statement setting forth the purpose and need for such proposed legislation.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–128, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1961-08-08">Aug. 8, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 295</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1913.</num>
<heading> Authority of Secretary of Agriculture under other provisions of law and to establish and consult with advisory committees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this Act shall be deemed to limit the authority of the Secretary of Agriculture under other provision of law or to establish or consult with advisory committees.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–128, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="1961-08-08">Aug. 8, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 295</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>