<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 67—</num>
<heading>IMPLEMENTATION OF INTERNATIONAL SUGAR AGREEMENT, 1977</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3601.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “Agreement” means the International Sugar Agreement, 1977, signed at New York City on <date date="1977-12-09">December 9, 1977</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “sugar” has the same meaning as is given to such term in paragraph (12) of Article 2 of the Agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “entry” means entry, or withdrawal from warehouse, for consumption in the customs territory of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–236, § 1</ref>, <date date="1980-04-22">Apr. 22, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 336</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3602.</num>
<heading> Implementation of Agreement</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">On and after the entering into force of the Agreement with respect to the United States, and for such period before <date date="1985-01-01">January 1, 1985</date>, as the Agreement remains in force, the President may, in order to carry out and enforce the provisions of the Agreement—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> regulate the entry of sugar by appropriate means, including, but not limited to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the imposition of limitations on the entry of sugar which is the product of foreign countries, territories, or areas not members of the International Sugar Organization, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the prohibition of the entry of any shipment or quantity of sugar not accompanied by a valid certificate of contribution or such other documentation as may be required under the Agreement;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> require of appropriate persons the keeping of such records, statistics, and other information, and the submission of such reports, relating to the entry, distribution, prices, and consumption of sugar and alternative sweeteners as he may from time to time prescribe; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> take such other action, and issue and enforce such rules or regulations, as he may consider necessary or appropriate in order to implement the rights and obligations of the United States under the Agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–236, § 2</ref>, <date date="1980-04-22">Apr. 22, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 336</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–446, title I, § 153</ref>, <date date="1983-01-12">Jan. 12, 1983</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2344</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3603.</num>
<heading> Delegation of powers and duties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President may exercise any power or duty conferred on him by this chapter through such agencies or offices of the United States as he shall designate. Such agencies or offices shall issue such regulations as they determine are necessary to implement this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–236, § 3</ref>, <date date="1980-04-22">Apr. 22, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 336</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3604.</num>
<heading> Criminal offenses</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Any person who—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> knowingly fails to keep any information, or to submit any report, required under <ref>section 3602 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> submits any report under <ref>section 3602 of this title</ref> knowing that the report or any part thereof is false; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> knowingly violates any rule or regulation issued to carry out this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">is guilty of an offense and upon conviction thereof is punishable by a fine of not more than $1,000.</continuation>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–236, § 4</ref>, <date date="1980-04-22">Apr. 22, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 337</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3605.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. B, title XXII, § 2219(a)(5), <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–817</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3606.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 105–362, title I, § 101(g)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-10">Nov. 10, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3281</ref></heading>
</section>
</chapter>