<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 66—</num>
<heading>AGRICULTURAL FOREIGN INVESTMENT DISCLOSURE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3501.</num>
<heading> Reporting requirements</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Acquisitions or transfers of certain agricultural land interests by foreign persons</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Any foreign person who acquires or transfers any interest, other than a security interest, in agricultural land shall submit a report to the Secretary of Agriculture not later than 90 days after the date of such acquisition or transfer. Such report shall be submitted in such form and in accordance with such procedures as the Secretary may require and shall contain—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the legal name and the address of such foreign person;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in any case in which such foreign person is an individual, the citizenship of such foreign person;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> in any case in which such foreign person is not an individual or a government, the nature of the legal entity holding the interest, the country in which such foreign person is created or organized, and the principal place of business of such foreign person;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the type of interest in agricultural land which such foreign person acquired or transferred;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the legal description and acreage of such agricultural land;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the purchase price paid for, or any other consideration given for, such interest;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<chapeau> in any case in which such foreign person transfers such interest, the legal name and the address of the person to whom such interest is transferred and—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in any case in which such transferee is an individual, the citizenship of such transferee; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in any case in which such transferee is not an individual or a government, the nature of the legal entity holding the interest, the country in which such transferee is created or organized, and the principal place of business of such transferee;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> the agricultural purposes for which such foreign person intends, on the date on which such report is submitted to the Secretary, to use such agricultural land; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> such other information as the Secretary may require by regulation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agricultural land interests presently held by foreign persons</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Any foreign person who holds any interest, other than a security interest, in agricultural land on the day before the effective date of this section shall submit a report to the Secretary not later than 180 days after such effective date. Such report shall be submitted in such form and in accordance with such procedures as the Secretary may require and shall contain—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the legal name and the address of such foreign person;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in any case in which such foreign person is an individual, the citizenship of such foreign person;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> in any case in which such foreign person is not an individual or a government, the nature of the legal entity holding the interest, the country in which such foreign person is created or organized, and the principal place of business of such foreign person;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the type of interest in agricultural land which is held by such foreign person;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the legal description and acreage of such agricultural land;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the purchase price paid for, or any other consideration given for, such interest;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<chapeau> the agricultural purposes for which such foreign person—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is using such agricultural land on the date on which such report is submitted to the Secretary; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> intends, as of such date, to use such agricultural land; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> such other information as the Secretary may require by regulation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Change in foreign person status of interest holders</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any person who holds or acquires (on or after the effective date of this section) any interest, other than a security interest, in agricultural land at a time when such person is not a foreign person and who subsequently becomes a foreign person shall submit a report to the Secretary not later than 90 days after the date on which such person becomes a foreign person. Such report shall be submitted in such form and in accordance with such procedures as the Secretary may require and shall contain the information required by subsection (b) of this section. This subsection shall not apply with respect to any person who is required to submit a report with respect to such land under subsection (b) of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conversion of land to agricultural uses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any foreign person who holds or acquires (on or after the effective date of this section) any interest, other than a security interest, in land at a time when such land is not agricultural land and such land subsequently becomes agricultural land shall submit a report to the Secretary not later than 90 days after the date on which such land becomes agricultural land. Such report shall be submitted in such form and in accordance with such procedures as the Secretary may require and shall contain the information required by subsection (b) of this section. This subsection shall not apply with respect to any person who is required to submit a report with respect to such land under subsection (b) of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional reports by foreign persons other than individuals or governments</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">With respect to any foreign person, other than an individual or a government, who is required by subsection (a), (b), (c), or (d) of this section to submit a report, the Secretary may, in addition, require such foreign person to submit to the Secretary a report containing—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the legal name and the address of each person who holds any interest in such foreign person;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in any case in which the holder of such interest is an individual, the citizenship of such holder; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> in any case in which the holder of such interest is not an individual or a government, the nature of the legal entity holding the interest, the country in which such holder is created or organized, and the principal place of business of such holder.</content>
</subparagraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Persons holding interests under subsection (e)</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">With respect to any person, other than an individual or a government, whose legal name is contained in any report submitted under subsection (e) of the section, the Secretary may require such person to submit to the Secretary a report containing—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the legal name and the address of any person who holds any interest in the person submitting the report under this subsection;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in any case in which the holder of such interest is an individual, the citizenship of such holder; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> in any case in which the holder of such interest is not an individual or a government, the nature of the legal entity holding the interest, the country in which such holder is created or organized, and the principle <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002279">1</ref> place of business of such holder.</content>
</subparagraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–460, § 2</ref>, <date date="1978-10-14">Oct. 14, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1263</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3502.</num>
<heading> Civil penalty</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> If the Secretary determines that a person—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> has failed to submit a report in accordance with the provisions of <ref>section 3501 of this title</ref>, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> has knowingly submitted a report under <ref>section 3501 of this title</ref>—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> which does not contain all the information required to be in such report, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> which contains information that is misleading or false,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">such person shall be subject to a civil penalty imposed by the Secretary. The amount of any such civil penalty shall be determined in accordance with the provisions of subsection (b) of this section. Any such civil penalty shall be recoverable in a civil action brought by the Attorney General of the United States in an appropriate district court of the United States.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The amount of any civil penalty imposed by the Secretary under subsection (a) of this section shall be such amount as the Secretary determines to be appropriate to carry out the purposes of this chapter, except that such amount shall not exceed 25 percent of the fair market value, on the date of the assessment of such penalty, of the interest in agricultural land with respect to which such violation occurred.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–460, § 3</ref>, <date date="1978-10-14">Oct. 14, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1265</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3503.</num>
<heading> Investigative actions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may take such actions as the Secretary considers necessary to monitor compliance with the provisions of this chapter and to determine whether the information contained in any report submitted under <ref>section 3501 of this title</ref> accurately and fully reveals the ownership interest of all foreign persons in any foreign person who is required to submit a report under such section.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–460, § 4</ref>, <date date="1978-10-14">Oct. 14, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1265</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3504.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 105–362, title I, § 101(f)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-10">Nov. 10, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3281</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3505.</num>
<heading> Reports to the States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 30 days after the end of each 6-month period beginning after the effective date of <ref>section 3501 of this title</ref>, the Secretary shall transmit to each State department of agriculture, or such other appropriate State agency as the Secretary considers advisable, a copy of each report which was submitted to the Secretary under <ref>section 3501 of this title</ref> during such 6-month period and which involved agricultural land located in such State.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–460, § 6</ref>, <date date="1978-10-14">Oct. 14, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1266</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3506.</num>
<heading> Public inspection</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any report submitted to the Secretary under <ref>section 3501 of this title</ref> shall be available for public inspection at the Department of Agriculture located in the District of Columbia not later than 10 days after the date on which such report is received by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–460, § 7</ref>, <date date="1978-10-14">Oct. 14, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1266</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3507.</num>
<heading> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 90 days after <date date="1978-10-14">October 14, 1978</date>, the Secretary shall prescribe regulations for purposes of carrying out the provisions of this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–460, § 8</ref>, <date date="1978-10-14">Oct. 14, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1266</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3508.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “agricultural land” means any land located in one or more States and used for agricultural, forestry, or timber production purposes as determined by the Secretary under regulations to be prescribed by the Secretary;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “foreign government” means any government other than the Federal Government or any government of a State or a political subdivision of a State;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> the term “foreign person” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> any individual—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> who is not a citizen or national of the United States;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> who is not a citizen of the Northern Mariana Islands or the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> who is not lawfully admitted to the United States for permanent residence, or paroled into the United States, under the Immigration and Nationality Act [<ref>8 U.S.C. 1101</ref> et seq.];</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any person, other than an individual or a government, which is created or organized under the laws of a foreign government or which has its principal place of business located outside of all the States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> any person, other than an individual or a government—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> which is created or organized under the laws of any State; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> in which, as determined by the Secretary under regulations which the Secretary shall prescribe, a significant interest or substantial control is directly or indirectly held—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> by any individual referred to in subparagraph (A);</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> by any person referred to in subparagraph (B);</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> by any foreign government; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> by any combination of such individuals, persons, or governments; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> any foreign government;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the term “person” includes any individual, corporation, company, association, firm, partnership, society, joint stock company, trust, estate, or any other legal entity;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Agriculture; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the term “State” means any of the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Northern Mariana Islands, Guam, the Virgin Islands, American Samoa, the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, or any other territory or possession of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–460, § 9</ref>, <date date="1978-10-14">Oct. 14, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1266</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>