<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 61—</num>
<heading>NOXIOUS WEEDS</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 2801 to 2813.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 106–224, title IV, § 438(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="2000-06-20">June 20, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 454</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2814.</num>
<heading> Management of undesirable plants on Federal lands</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties of agencies</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each Federal agency shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> designate an office or person adequately trained in the management of undesirable plant species to develop and coordinate an undesirable plants management program for control of undesirable plants on Federal lands under the agency’s jurisdiction;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> establish and adequately fund an undesirable plants management program through the agency’s budgetary process;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> complete and implement cooperative agreements with State agencies regarding the management of undesirable plant species on Federal lands under the agency’s jurisdiction; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> establish integrated management systems to control or contain undesirable plant species targeted under cooperative agreements.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Environmental impact statements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the event an environmental assessment or environmental impact statement is required under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.) to implement plant control agreements, Federal agencies shall complete such assessments or statements within 1 year after the requirement for such assessment or statement is ascertained.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cooperative agreements with State agencies</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Federal agencies, as appropriate, shall enter into cooperative agreements with State agencies to coordinate the management of undesirable plant species on Federal lands.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents of plan</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A cooperative agreement entered into pursuant to paragraph (1) shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> prioritize and target undesirable plant species or group of species to be controlled or contained within a specific geographic area;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> describe the integrated management system to be used to control or contain the targeted undesirable plant species or group of species; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> detail the means of implementing the integrated management system, define the duties of the Federal agency and the State agency in prosecuting that method, and establish a timeframe for the initiation and completion of the tasks specified in the integrated management system.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A Federal agency is not required under this section to carry out programs on Federal lands unless similar programs are being implemented generally on State or private lands in the same area.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cooperative agreement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “cooperative agreement” means a written agreement between a Federal agency and a State agency entered into pursuant to this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal agency</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Federal agency” means a department, agency, or bureau of the Federal Government responsible for administering or managing Federal lands under its jurisdiction.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal lands</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Federal lands” means lands managed by or under the jurisdiction of the Federal Government.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Integrated management system</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “integrated management systems” means a system for the planning and implementation of a program, using an interdisciplinary approach, to select a method for containing or controlling an undesirable plant species or group of species using all available methods, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> education;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> preventive measures;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> physical or mechanical methods;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> biological agents;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> herbicide methods;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> cultural methods; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> general land management practices such as manipulation of livestock or wildlife grazing strategies or improving wildlife or livestock habitat.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interdisciplinary approach</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “interdisciplinary approach” means an approach to making decisions regarding the containment or control of an undesirable plant species or group of species, which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> includes participation by personnel of Federal or State agencies with experience in areas including weed science, range science, wildlife biology, land management, and forestry; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> includes consideration of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the most efficient and effective method of containing or controlling the undesirable plant species;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> scientific evidence and current technology;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the physiology and habitat of a plant species; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the economic, social, and ecological consequences of implementing the program.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “State agency” means a State department of agriculture, or other State agency or political subdivision thereof, responsible for the administration or implementation of undesirable plants laws of a State.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Undesirable plant species</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “undesirable plants” means plant species that are classified as undesirable, noxious, harmful, exotic, injurious, or poisonous, pursuant to State or Federal law. Species listed as endangered by the Endangered Species Act of 1973 [<ref>16 U.S.C. 1531</ref> et seq.] shall not be designated as undesirable plants under this section and shall not include plants indigenous to an area where control measures are to be taken under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior shall take such actions as may be necessary to coordinate Federal agency programs for control, research, and educational efforts associated with Federal, State, and locally designated noxious weeds.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior, shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> identify regional priorities for noxious weed control;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> incorporate into existing technical guides regionally appropriate technical information; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> disseminate such technical information to interested State, local, and private entities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cost share assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may provide cost share assistance to State and local agencies to manage noxious weeds in an area if a majority of landowners in that area agree to participate in a noxious weed management program.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary in each of fiscal years 1991 through 1995 to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–629, § 15</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XIV, § 1453</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3611</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>