<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 16—</num>
<heading>BUREAU OF DAIRY INDUSTRY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 401.</num>
<heading> Establishment of bureau</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established in the Department of Agriculture a bureau to be known as the “Bureau of Dairy Industry.”</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 29, 1924, ch. 208, § 1</ref>, <ref>43 Stat. 243</ref>; <ref>May 11, 1926, ch. 286</ref>, <ref>44 Stat. 499</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 402.</num>
<heading> Chief of bureau; appointment and duties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A Chief of the Bureau of Dairy Industry shall be appointed by the Secretary of Agriculture, who shall be subject to the general direction of the Secretary of Agriculture. He shall devote his time to the investigation of the dairy industry, and the dissemination of information for the promotion of the dairy industry.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 29, 1924, ch. 208, § 2</ref>, <ref>43 Stat. 243</ref>; <ref>May 11, 1926, ch. 286</ref>, <ref>44 Stat. 499</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 403.</num>
<heading> Transfer of activities of Department of Agriculture to bureau; employment of clerks, etc.</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purpose of enabling the Secretary of Agriculture and the Chief of the Bureau of Dairy Industry to carry out the purposes of this chapter, the Secretary of Agriculture is authorized to transfer to the Bureau of Dairy Industry such activities of the Department of Agriculture as he may designate which relate primarily to the dairy industry, and to employ such additional persons in the city of Washington and elsewhere, as may be necessary.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 29, 1924, ch. 208, § 3</ref>, <ref>43 Stat. 243</ref>; <ref>May 11, 1926, ch. 286</ref>, <ref>44 Stat. 499</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 404.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purpose of carrying out the provisions of this chapter and the activities of the Bureau of Dairy Industry, such sums of money as Congress may deem necessary are authorized to be appropriated.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 29, 1924, ch. 208, § 4</ref>, <ref>43 Stat. 243</ref>; <ref>May 11, 1926, ch. 286</ref>, <ref>44 Stat. 499</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>