<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 48—</num>
<heading>HUMANE METHODS OF LIVESTOCK SLAUGHTER</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1901.</num>
<heading> Findings and declaration of policy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Congress finds that the use of humane methods in the slaughter of livestock prevents needless suffering; results in safer and better working conditions for persons engaged in the slaughtering industry; brings about improvement of products and economies in slaughtering operations; and produces other benefits for producers, processors, and consumers which tend to expedite an orderly flow of livestock and livestock products in interstate and foreign commerce. It is therefore declared to be the policy of the United States that the slaughtering of livestock and the handling of livestock in connection with slaughter shall be carried out only by humane methods.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–765, § 1</ref>, <date date="1958-08-27">Aug. 27, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 862</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1902.</num>
<heading> Humane methods</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">No method of slaughtering or handling in connection with slaughtering shall be deemed to comply with the public policy of the United States unless it is humane. Either of the following two methods of slaughtering and handling are hereby found to be humane:</chapeau>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> in the case of cattle, calves, horses, mules, sheep, swine, and other livestock, all animals are rendered insensible to pain by a single blow or gunshot or an electrical, chemical or other means that is rapid and effective, before being shackled, hoisted, thrown, cast, or cut; or</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> by slaughtering in accordance with the ritual requirements of the Jewish faith or any other religious faith that prescribes a method of slaughter whereby the animal suffers loss of consciousness by anemia of the brain caused by the simultaneous and instantaneous severance of the carotid arteries with a sharp instrument and handling in connection with such slaughtering.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–765, § 2</ref>, <date date="1958-08-27">Aug. 27, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 862</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–445, § 5(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-10">Oct. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1069</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1903.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 95–445, § 5(b)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-10">Oct. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1069</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1904.</num>
<heading> Methods research; designation of methods</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In furtherance of the policy expressed herein the Secretary is authorized and directed—</chapeau>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> to conduct, assist, and foster research, investigation, and experimentation to develop and determine methods of slaughter and the handling of livestock in connection with slaughter which are practicable with reference to the speed and scope of slaughtering operations and humane with reference to other existing methods and then current scientific knowledge; and</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> on or before <date date="1959-03-01">March 1, 1959</date>, and at such times thereafter as he deems advisable, to designate methods of slaughter and of handling in connection with slaughter which, with respect to each species of livestock, conform to the policy stated in this chapter. If he deems it more effective, the Secretary may make any such designation by designating methods which are not in conformity with such policy. Designations by the Secretary subsequent to <date date="1959-03-01">March 1, 1959</date>, shall become effective 180 days after their publication in the Federal Register.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–765, § 4</ref>, <date date="1958-08-27">Aug. 27, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 863</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–445, § 5(b)</ref>–(e), <date date="1978-10-10">Oct. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1069</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1905.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 95–445, § 5(b)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-10">Oct. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1069</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1906.</num>
<heading> Exemption of ritual slaughter</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to prohibit, abridge, or in any way hinder the religious freedom of any person or group. Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, in order to protect freedom of religion, ritual slaughter and the handling or other preparation of livestock for ritual slaughter are exempted from the terms of this chapter. For the purposes of this section the term “ritual slaughter” means slaughter in accordance with <ref>section 1902(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–765, § 6</ref>, <date date="1958-08-27">Aug. 27, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 864</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1907.</num>
<heading> Practices involving nonambulatory livestock</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture shall investigate and submit to Congress a report on—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the scope of nonambulatory livestock;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the causes that render livestock nonambulatory;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the humane treatment of nonambulatory livestock; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the extent to which nonambulatory livestock may present handling and disposition problems for stockyards, market agencies, and dealers.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Based on the findings of the report, if the Secretary determines it necessary, the Secretary shall promulgate regulations to provide for the humane treatment, handling, and disposition of nonambulatory livestock by stockyards, market agencies, and dealers.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administration and enforcement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purpose of administering and enforcing any regulations promulgated under subsection (b), the authorities provided under sections 10414 [<ref>7 U.S.C. 8313</ref>] and 10415 [<ref>7 U.S.C. 8314</ref>] shall apply to the regulations in a similar manner as those sections apply to the Animal Health Protection Act [<ref>7 U.S.C. 8301</ref> et seq.]. Any person that violates regulations promulgated under subsection (b) shall be subject to penalties provided in section 10414.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–171, title X, § 10815</ref>, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 532</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>