<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 26—</num>
<heading>AGRICULTURAL ADJUSTMENT</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>DECLARATION OF CONDITIONS AND POLICY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 601.</num>
<heading> Declaration of conditions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is declared that the disruption of the orderly exchange of commodities in interstate commerce impairs the purchasing power of farmers and destroys the value of agricultural assets which support the national credit structure and that these conditions affect transactions in agricultural commodities with a national public interest, and burden and obstruct the normal channels of interstate commerce.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 12, 1933, ch. 25</ref>, title I, § 1, <ref>48 Stat. 31</ref>; <ref>June 3, 1937, ch. 296</ref>, §§ 1, 2(a), <ref>50 Stat. 246</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 602.</num>
<heading> Declaration of policy; establishment of price basing period; marketing standards; orderly supply flow; circumstances for continued regulation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is declared to be the policy of Congress—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Through the exercise of the powers conferred upon the Secretary of Agriculture under this chapter, to establish and maintain such orderly marketing conditions for agricultural commodities in interstate commerce as will establish, as the prices to farmers, parity prices as defined by <ref>section 1301(a)(1) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> To protect the interest of the consumer by (a) approaching the level of prices which it is declared to be the policy of Congress to establish in subsection (1) of this section by gradual correction of the current level at as rapid a rate as the Secretary of Agriculture deems to be in the public interest and feasible in view of the current consumptive demand in domestic and foreign markets, and (b) authorizing no action under this chapter which has for its purpose the maintenance of prices to farmers above the level which it is declared to be the policy of Congress to establish in subsection (1) of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Through the exercise of the powers conferred upon the Secretary of Agriculture under this chapter, to establish and maintain such production research, marketing research, and development projects provided in <ref>section 608c(6)(I) of this title</ref>, such container and pack requirements provided in <ref>section 608c(6)(H) of this title</ref> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002099">1</ref> such minimum standards of quality and maturity and such grading and inspection requirements for agricultural commodities enumerated in section 608c (2) of this title, other than milk and its products, in interstate commerce as will effectuate such orderly marketing of such agricultural commodities as will be in the public interest.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Through the exercise of the powers conferred upon the Secretary of Agriculture under this chapter, to establish and maintain such orderly marketing conditions for any agricultural commodity enumerated in <ref>section 608c(2) of this title</ref> as will provide, in the interests of producers and consumers, an orderly flow of the supply thereof to market throughout its normal marketing season to avoid unreasonable fluctuations in supplies and prices.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Through the exercise of the power conferred upon the Secretary of Agriculture under this chapter, to continue for the remainder of any marketing season or marketing year, such regulation pursuant to any order as will tend to avoid a disruption of the orderly marketing of any commodity and be in the public interest, if the regulation of such commodity under such order has been initiated during such marketing season or marketing year on the basis of its need to effectuate the policy of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 12, 1933, ch. 25</ref>, title I, § 2, <ref>48 Stat. 32</ref>; <ref>Aug. 24, 1935, ch. 641</ref>, §§ 1, 62, <ref>49 Stat. 750</ref>, 782; <ref>June 3, 1937, ch. 296</ref>, §§ 1, 2(b), <ref>50 Stat. 246</ref>, 247; <ref>Aug. 1, 1947, ch. 425, § 1</ref>, <ref>61 Stat. 707</ref>; <ref>July 3, 1948, ch. 827</ref>, title III, § 302(a), <ref>62 Stat. 1257</ref>; <ref>Aug. 28, 1954, ch. 1041</ref>, title IV, § 401(a), <ref>68 Stat. 906</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–128, title I, § 141(1)</ref>, <date date="1961-08-08">Aug. 8, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 303</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–330, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1965-11-08">Nov. 8, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 1270</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–292, § 1(1)</ref>, <date date="1970-06-25">June 25, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 333</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>COTTON OPTION CONTRACTS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 603.</num>
<heading> Government owned cotton; transfer to Secretary of Agriculture; powers of Secretary</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Farm Credit Administration and all departments and other agencies of the Government, not including the Federal intermediate credit banks are directed—</chapeau>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> To sell to the Secretary of Agriculture at such price as may be agreed upon, not in excess of the market price, all cotton now owned by them.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> To take such action and to make such settlements as are necessary in order to acquire full legal title to all cotton on which money has been loaned or advanced by any department or agency of the United States, including futures contracts for cotton or which is held as collateral for loans or advances and to make final settlement of such loans and advances as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In making such settlements with regard to cotton, including operations to which such cotton is related, such cotton shall be taken over by all such departments or agencies other than the Secretary of Agriculture at a price or sum equal to the amounts directly or indirectly loaned or advanced thereon and outstanding, including loans by the Government, department or agency and any loans senior thereto, plus any sums required to adjust advances to growers to 90 per centum of the value of their cotton at the date of its delivery in the first instance as collateral to the department or agency involved, such sums to be computed by subtracting the total amount already advanced to growers on account of pools of which such cotton was a part, from 90 per centum of the value of the cotton to be taken over as of the time of such delivery as collateral, plus unpaid accrued carrying charges and operating costs on such cotton, less, however, any existing assets of the borrower derived from net income, earnings, or profits arising from such cotton, and from operations to which such cotton is related; all as determined by the department or agency making the settlement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Agriculture shall make settlements with respect to cotton held as collateral for loans or advances made by him on such terms as in his judgment may be deemed advisable, and to carry out the provisions of this section, is authorized to indemnify or furnish bonds to warehousemen for lost warehouse receipts and to pay the premiums on such bonds.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0">When full legal title to the cotton referred to in this subsection has been acquired, it shall be sold to the Secretary of Agriculture for the purposes of this section, in the same manner as provided in subsection (a).</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Agriculture is authorized to purchase the cotton specified in subsections (a) and (b).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 12, 1933, ch. 25</ref>, title I, § 3, <ref>48 Stat. 32</ref>; 1933 Ex. Ord. No. 6084, <date date="1933-03-27">Mar. 27, 1933</date>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 604.</num>
<heading> Borrowing money; expenditures; authority of Secretary</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Agriculture shall have authority to borrow money upon all cotton in his possession or control and may, at his discretion, deposit as collateral for such loans the warehouse receipts for such cotton.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Treasury is authorized to advance, in his discretion, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, the sum of $100,000,000, to the Secretary of Agriculture, for paying off any debt or debts which may have been or may be incurred by the Secretary of Agriculture and discharging any lien or liens which may have arisen or may arise pursuant to sections 603, 604, and 607 of this title, for protecting title to any cotton which may have been or may be acquired by the Secretary of Agriculture under authority of said sections, and for paying any expenses (including, but not limited to, warehouse charges, insurance, salaries, interest, costs, and commissions) incident to carrying, handling, insuring, and marketing of said cotton and for the purposes described in subsection (e) of this section. This sum shall be available until the cotton acquired by the Secretary of Agriculture under authority of this chapter including cotton futures, shall have been finally marketed by any agency which may have been or may be established by the Secretary of Agriculture for the handling, carrying, insuring, or marketing of any cotton acquired by the Secretary of Agriculture.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The funds authorized by subsection (b) of this section shall be made available to the Secretary of Agriculture from time to time upon his request and with the approval of the Secretary of the Treasury. Each such request shall be accompanied by a statement showing by weight and average grade and staple the quantity of cotton held by the Secretary of Agriculture and the approximate aggregate market value thereof.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> It is the purpose of subsections (b) and (c) to provide an alternative method to that provided by subsection (a), for enabling the Secretary of Agriculture to finance the acquisition, carrying, handling, insuring, and marketing of cotton acquired by him under authority of <ref>section 603 of this title</ref>. The Secretary of Agriculture may at his discretion make use of either or both of the methods provided in this section for obtaining funds for the purposes hereinabove enumerated.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Agriculture is authorized to use in his discretion any funds obtained by him pursuant to the provisions of subsection (a) or (b) of this section for making advances to any agency which may have been or may be established by the Secretary of Agriculture for the handling, carrying, insuring, or marketing of any cotton acquired by the Secretary of Agriculture, to enable any such agency to perform, exercise, and discharge any of the duties, privileges, and functions which such agency may be authorized to perform, exercise, or discharge.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> The proceeds derived from the sale of cotton shall be held for the Secretary of Agriculture by the Treasurer of the United States in a special deposit account and shall be used by the Secretary of Agriculture to discharge the obligations incurred under authority of sections 603, 604, and 607 of this title. Whenever any cotton shall be marketed the net proceeds (after discharge of other obligations incurred with respect thereto) derived from the sale thereof shall be used, to the extent required, to reimburse the Treasury for such portion of the funds hereby provided for as shall have been used, which shall be covered into the Treasury as a miscellaneous receipt. If when all of the cotton acquired by the Secretary of Agriculture shall have been marketed and all of the obligations incurred with respect to such cotton shall have been discharged, and the Treasury reimbursed for any and all sums which may have been advanced pursuant to subsection (b), there shall remain any balance in the hands of the Secretary of Agriculture, such balance shall be covered into the Treasury as miscellaneous receipts.<p class="indent0">The word “obligation” when used in this section shall include (without being limited to) administrative expenses, warehouse charges, insurance, salaries, interest, costs, commissions, and other expenses incident to handling, carrying, insuring, and marketing of said cotton.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 12, 1933, ch. 25</ref>, title I, § 4, <ref>48 Stat. 33</ref>; <ref>June 19, 1934, ch. 648</ref>, title II, § 1, <ref>48 Stat. 1058</ref>; <ref>Aug. 24, 1935, ch. 641</ref>, §§ 35, 36, <ref>49 Stat. 775</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 605.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>June 30, 1947, ch. 166</ref>, title II, § 206(d), <ref>61 Stat. 208</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 606.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Aug. 24, 1935, ch. 641, § 34</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 775</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 607.</num>
<heading> Sale by Secretary; additional options; validation of assignments; publication of information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall sell cotton held or acquired by him pursuant to authority of this chapter at his discretion subject only to the conditions and limitations of this chapter: <i>Provided</i>, That the Secretary shall have authority to enter into option contracts with producers of cotton to sell to or for the producers such cotton held and/or acquired by him in such amounts and at such prices and upon such terms and conditions as he, the Secretary, may deem advisable, and such option contracts may be transferred or assigned in such manner as the Secretary of Agriculture may prescribe.</p>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any provisions contained in option contracts heretofore issued and/or any provision of law, assignments made prior to <date date="1934-01-11">January 11, 1934</date>, of option contracts exercised prior to <date date="1934-01-18">January 18, 1934</date>, shall be deemed valid upon determination by the Secretary that such assignment was an assignment in good faith of the full interest in such contract and for full value and is free from evidence of fraud or speculation by the assignee.</p>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any provision of existing law, the Secretary of Agriculture may, in the administration of this chapter, make public such information as he deems necessary in order to effectuate the purposes of this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 12, 1933, ch. 25</ref>, title I, § 7, <ref>48 Stat. 34</ref>; <ref>June 16, 1933, ch. 90</ref>, title II, § 221, <ref>48 Stat. 210</ref>; <ref>Aug. 24, 1935, ch. 641, § 33</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 775</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>COMMODITY BENEFITS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 608.</num>
<heading> Powers of Secretary</heading>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Investigations; proclamation of findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Whenever the Secretary of Agriculture has reason to believe that:</chapeau>
<level class="indent1">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The current average farm price for any basic agricultural commodity is less than the fair exchange value thereof, or the average farm price of such commodity is likely to be less than the fair exchange value thereof for the period in which the production of such commodity during the current or next succeeding marketing year is normally marketed, and</content>
</level>
<level class="indent1">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The conditions of and factors relating to the production, marketing, and consumption of such commodity are such that the exercise of any one or more of the powers conferred upon the Secretary under subsections (2) and (3) of this section would tend to effectuate the declared policy of this chapter,</content>
</level>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">he shall cause an immediate investigation to be made to determine such facts. If, upon the basis of such investigation, the Secretary finds the existence of such facts, he shall proclaim such determination and shall exercise such one or more of the powers conferred upon him under subsections (2) and (3) of this section as he finds, upon the basis of an investigation, administratively practicable and best calculated to effectuate the declared policy of this chapter.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agreements for adjustment of acreage or production and for rental or benefit payments</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subject to the provisions of subsection (1) of this section, the Secretary of Agriculture shall provide, through agreements with producers or by other voluntary methods,</chapeau>
<level class="indent1">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> For such adjustment in the acreage or in the production for market, or both, of any basic agricultural commodity, as he finds, upon the basis of the investigation made pursuant to subsection (1) of this section, will tend to effectuate the declared policy of this chapter, and to make such adjustment program practicable to operate and administer, and</content>
</level>
<level class="indent1">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> For rental or benefit payments in connection with such agreements or methods in such amounts as he finds, upon the basis of such investigation, to be fair and reasonable and best calculated to effectuate the declared policy of this chapter, and to make such program practicable to operate and administer, to be paid out of any moneys available for such payments or, subject to the consent of the producer, to be made in quantities of one or more basic agricultural commodities acquired by the Secretary pursuant to this chapter.</content>
</level>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payments by Secretary</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subject to the provisions of subsection (1) of this section, the Secretary of Agriculture shall make payments, out of any moneys available for such payments, in such amounts as he finds, upon the basis of the investigation made pursuant to subsection (1) of this section, to be fair and reasonable and best calculated to effectuate the declared policy of this chapter:</chapeau>
<level class="indent1">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> To remove from the normal channels of trade and commerce quantities of any basic agricultural commodity or product thereof;</content>
</level>
<level class="indent1">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> To expand domestic or foreign markets for any basic agricultural commodity or product thereof;</content>
</level>
<level class="indent1">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> In connection with the production of that part of any basic agricultural commodity which is required for domestic consumption.</content>
</level>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional investigation; suspension of exercise of powers</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Whenever, during a period during which any of the powers conferred in subsection (2) or (3) is being exercised, the Secretary of Agriculture has reason to believe that, with respect to any basic agricultural commodity:</chapeau>
<level class="indent1">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The current average farm price for such commodity is not less than the fair exchange value thereof, and the average farm price for such commodity is not likely to be less than the fair exchange value thereof for the period in which the production of such commodity during the current or next succeeding marketing year is normally marketed, or</content>
</level>
<level class="indent1">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The conditions of and factors relating to the production, marketing, and consumption of such commodity are such that none of the powers conferred in subsections (2) and (3), and no combination of such powers, would, if exercised, tend to effectuate the declared policy of this chapter,</content>
</level>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">he shall cause an immediate investigation to be made to determine such facts. If, upon the basis of such investigation, the Secretary finds the existence of such facts, he shall proclaim such determination, and shall not exercise any of such powers with respect to such commodity after the end of the marketing year current at the time when such proclamation is made and prior to a new proclamation under subsection (1) of this section, except insofar as the exercise of such power is necessary to carry out obligations of the Secretary assumed, prior to the date of such proclamation made pursuant to this subsection, in connection with the exercise of any of the powers conferred upon him under subsections (2) or (3) of this section.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Hearings; notice</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the course of any investigation required to be made under subsection (1) or (4) of this section, the Secretary of Agriculture shall hold one or more hearings, and give due notice and opportunity for interested parties to be heard.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Commodity in which payment made</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No payment under this chapter made in an agricultural commodity acquired by the Secretary in pursuance of this chapter shall be made in a commodity other than that in respect of which the payment is being made. For the purposes of this subsection, hogs and field corn may be considered as one commodity.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional payments to producers of sugar beets or sugarcane</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the case of sugar beets or sugarcane, in the event that it shall be established to the satisfaction of the Secretary of Agriculture that returns to growers or producers, under the contracts for the 1933–1934 crop of sugar beets or sugarcane, entered into by and between the processors and producers and/or growers thereof, were reduced by reason of the payment of the processing tax, and/or the corresponding floor stocks tax, on sugar beets or sugarcane, in addition to the foregoing rental or benefit payments, the Secretary of Agriculture shall make such payments, representing in whole or in part such tax, as the Secretary deems fair and reasonable, to producers who agree, or have agreed, to participate in the program for reduction in the acreage or reduction in the production for market, or both, of sugar beets or sugarcane.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Pledge by rice producer for production credit of right to rental or benefit payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the case of rice, the Secretary of Agriculture, in exercising the power conferred upon him by subsection (2) of this section to provide for rental or benefit payments, is directed to provide in any agreement entered into by him with any rice producer pursuant to such subsection, upon such terms and conditions as the Secretary determines will best effectuate the declared policy of this chapter, that the producer may pledge for production credit in whole or in part his right to any rental or benefit payments under the terms of such agreement and that such producer may designate therein a payee to receive such rental or benefit payments.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Advances of payments on stored nonperishable commodity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Under regulations of the Secretary of Agriculture requiring adequate facilities for the storage of any nonperishable agricultural commodity on the farm, inspection and measurement of any such commodity so stored, and the locking and sealing thereof, and such other regulations as may be prescribed by the Secretary of Agriculture for the protection of such commodity and for the marketing thereof, a reasonable percentage of any benefit payment may be advanced on any such commodity so stored. In any such case such deduction may be made from the amount of the benefit payment as the Secretary of Agriculture determines will reasonably compensate for the cost of inspection and sealing but no deduction may be made for interest.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 12, 1933, ch. 25</ref>, title I, § 8, <ref>48 Stat. 34</ref>; <ref>Apr. 7, 1934, ch. 103, § 7</ref>, <ref>48 Stat. 528</ref>; <ref>May 9, 1934, ch. 263, § 14</ref>, <ref>48 Stat. 676</ref>; <ref>Mar. 18, 1935, ch. 32, § 7</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 46</ref>; <ref>Aug. 24, 1935, ch. 641</ref>, §§ 2, 4–7, <ref>49 Stat. 751</ref>, 753–762.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 608–1.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 608a.</num>
<heading> Enforcement of chapter</heading>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> to (4) Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Forfeitures</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any person exceeding any quota or allotment fixed for him under this chapter by the Secretary of Agriculture and any other person knowingly participating or aiding in the exceeding of such quota or allotment shall forfeit to the United States a sum equal to the value of such excess at the current market price for such commodity at the time of violation, which forfeiture shall be recoverable in a civil suit brought in the name of the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Jurisdiction of district courts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The several district courts of the United States are vested with jurisdiction specifically to enforce, and to prevent and restrain any person from violating any order, regulation, or agreement, heretofore or hereafter made or issued pursuant to this chapter, in any proceeding now pending or hereafter brought in said courts.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties of United States attorneys; investigation of violations by Secretary; hearings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon the request of the Secretary of Agriculture, it shall be the duty of the several United States attorneys, in their respective districts, under the directions of the Attorney General, to institute proceedings to enforce the remedies and to collect the forfeitures provided for in, or pursuant to this chapter. Whenever the Secretary, or such officer or employee of the Department of Agriculture as he may designate for the purpose, has reason to believe that any handler has violated, or is violating, the provisions of any order or amendment thereto issued pursuant to this chapter, the Secretary shall have power to institute an investigation and, after due notice to such handler, to conduct a hearing in order to determine the facts for the purpose of referring the matter to the Attorney General for appropriate action.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cumulative remedies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The remedies provided for in this section shall be in addition to, and not exclusive of, any of the remedies or penalties provided for elsewhere in this chapter or now or hereafter existing at law or in equity.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> “Person” defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The term “person” as used in this chapter includes an individual, partnership, corporation, association, and any other business unit.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 12, 1933, ch. 25</ref>, title I, § 8a, as added <ref>May 9, 1934, ch. 263, § 4</ref>, <ref>48 Stat. 672</ref>; amended <ref>Aug. 24, 1935, ch. 641</ref>, §§ 8–10, <ref>49 Stat. 762</ref>; <ref>June 3, 1937, ch. 296</ref>, §§ 1, 2(c), <ref>50 Stat. 246</ref>, 247; <ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646, § 1</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 909</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–128, title I, § 141(2)</ref>, <date date="1961-08-08">Aug. 8, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 304</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 608a–1.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Sept. 1, 1937, ch. 898</ref>, title V, § 510, <ref>50 Stat. 916</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 608b.</num>
<heading> Marketing agreements; exemption from anti-trust laws; inspection requirements for handlers not subject to agreements</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> In order to effectuate the declared policy of this chapter, the Secretary of Agriculture shall have the power, after due notice and opportunity for hearing, to enter into marketing agreements with processors, producers, associations of producers, and others engaged in the handling of any agricultural commodity or product thereof, only with respect to such handling as is in the current of interstate or foreign commerce or which directly burdens, obstructs, or affects, interstate or foreign commerce in such commodity or product thereof. The making of any such agreement shall not be held to be in violation of any of the antitrust laws of the United States, and any such agreement shall be deemed to be lawful: <i>Provided</i>, That no such agreement shall remain in force after the termination of this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> If an agreement with the Secretary is in effect with respect to peanuts pursuant to this section—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> all peanuts handled by persons who have not entered into such an agreement with the Secretary shall be subject to inspection to the same extent and manner as is required by such agreement;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> no such peanuts shall be sold or otherwise disposed of for human consumption if such peanuts fail to meet the quality requirements of such agreement; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> any assessment (except with respect to any assessment for the indemnification of losses on rejected peanuts) imposed under the agreement shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> apply to peanut handlers (as defined by the Secretary) who have not entered into such an agreement with the Secretary in addition to those handlers who have entered into the agreement; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> be paid to the Secretary.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Violation of this subsection by a person who has not entered into such an agreement shall result in the assessment by the Secretary of a penalty equal to 140 percent of the support price for quota peanuts multiplied by the quantity of peanuts sold or disposed of in violation of subsection (b)(1)(B), as determined under section 1445c–3 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002100">1</ref> of this title, for the marketing year for the crop with respect to which such violation occurs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 12, 1933, ch. 25</ref>, title I, § 8b, formerly § 8(2), <ref>48 Stat. 34</ref>; <ref>Apr. 7, 1934, ch. 103, § 7</ref>, <ref>48 Stat. 528</ref>; renumbered and amended <ref>Aug. 24, 1935, ch. 641, § 4</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 753</ref>; <ref>June 3, 1937, ch. 296, § 1</ref>, <ref>50 Stat. 246</ref>; <ref>June 30, 1947, ch. 166</ref>, title II, § 206(d), <ref>61 Stat. 208</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–220, § 4</ref>, <date date="1989-12-12">Dec. 12, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1878</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–237, title I, § 115(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-13">Dec. 13, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1840</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–66, title I, § 1109(b)</ref>, <date date="1993-08-10">Aug. 10, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 326</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 608c.</num>
<heading> Orders</heading>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Issuance by Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture shall, subject to the provisions of this section, issue, and from time to time amend, orders applicable to processors, associations of producers, and others engaged in the handling of any agricultural commodity or product thereof specified in subsection (2) of this section. Such persons are referred to in this chapter as “handlers”. Such orders shall regulate, in the manner hereinafter in this section provided, only such handling of such agricultural commodity, or product thereof, as is in the current of interstate or foreign commerce, or which directly burdens, obstructs, or affects, interstate or foreign commerce in such commodity or product thereof. In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall complete all informal rulemaking actions necessary to respond to recommendations submitted by administrative committees for such orders as expeditiously as possible, but not more than 45 days (to the extent practicable) after submission of the committee recommendations. The Secretary is authorized to implement a producer allotment program and a handler withholding program under the cranberry marketing order in the same crop year through informal rulemaking based on a recommendation and supporting economic analysis submitted by the Cranberry Marketing Committee. Such recommendation and analysis shall be submitted by the Committee no later than March 1 of each year. The Secretary shall establish time frames for each office and agency within the Department of Agriculture to consider the committee recommendations.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Commodities to which applicable</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Orders issued pursuant to this section shall be applicable only to (A) the following agricultural commodities and the products thereof (except canned or frozen pears, grapefruit, cherries, apples, or cranberries, the products of naval stores, and the products of honeybees), or to any regional, or market classification of any such commodity or product: Milk, fruits (including filberts, almonds, pecans and walnuts but not including apples, other than apples produced in the States of Washington, Oregon, Idaho, New York, Michigan, Maryland, New Jersey, Indiana, California, Maine, Vermont, New Hampshire, Rhode Island, Massachusetts, Connecticut, Colorado, Utah, New Mexico, Illinois, and Ohio, and not including fruits for canning or freezing other than pears, olives, grapefruit, cherries, caneberries (including raspberries, blackberries, and loganberries), cranberries, and apples produced in the States named above except Washington, Oregon, and Idaho), tobacco, vegetables (not including vegetables, other than asparagus, for canning or freezing and not including potatoes for canning, freezing, or other processing), hops, honeybees and naval stores as included in the Naval Stores Act [<ref>7 U.S.C. 91</ref> et seq.] and standards established thereunder (including refined or partially refined oleoresin): <i>Provided</i>, That no order issued pursuant to this section shall be effective as to any grapefruit for canning or freezing unless the Secretary of Agriculture determines, in addition to other findings and determinations required by this chapter, that the issuance of such order is approved or favored by the processors who, during a representative period determined by the Secretary, have been engaged in canning or freezing such commodity for market and have canned or frozen for market more than 50 per centum of the total volume of such commodity canned or frozen for market during such representative period; and (B) any agricultural commodity (except honey, cotton, rice, wheat, corn, grain sorghums, oats, barley, rye, sugarcane, sugarbeets, wool, mohair, livestock, soybeans, cottonseed, flaxseed, poultry (but not excepting turkeys and not excepting poultry which produce commercial eggs), fruits and vegetables for canning or freezing, including potatoes for canning, freezing, or other processing <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002101">1</ref> and apples), or any regional or market classification thereof, not subject to orders under (A) of this subdivision, but not the products (including canned or frozen commodities or products) thereof. No order issued pursuant to this section shall be effective as to cherries, apples, or cranberries for canning or freezing unless the Secretary of Agriculture determines, in addition to other required findings and determinations, that the issuance of such order is approved or favored by processors who, during a representative period determined by the Secretary, have engaged in canning or freezing such commodity for market and have frozen or canned more than 50 per centum of the total volume of the commodity to be regulated which was canned or frozen within the production area, or marketed within the marketing area, defined in such order, during such representative period. No order issued pursuant to this section shall be applicable to peanuts produced in more than one of the following production areas: the Virginia-Carolina production area, the Southeast production area, and the Southwest production area. If the Secretary determines that the declared policy of this chapter will be better achieved thereby (i) the commodities of the same general class and used wholly or in part for the same purposes may be combined and treated as a single commodity and (ii) the portion of an agricultural commodity devoted to or marketed for a particular use or combination of uses, may be treated as a separate agricultural commodity. All agricultural commodities and products covered hereby shall be deemed specified herein for the purposes of subsections (6) and (7).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice and hearing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever the Secretary of Agriculture has reason to believe that the issuance of an order will tend to effectuate the declared policy of this chapter with respect to any commodity or product thereof specified in subsection (2) of this section, he shall give due notice of and an opportunity for a hearing upon a proposed order.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Finding and issuance of order</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">After such notice and opportunity for hearing, the Secretary of Agriculture shall issue an order if he finds, and sets forth in such order, upon the evidence introduced at such hearing (in addition to such other findings as may be specifically required by this section) that the issuance of such order and all of the terms and conditions thereof will tend to effectuate the declared policy of this chapter with respect to such commodity.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Terms—Milk and its products</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In the case of milk and its products, orders issued pursuant to this section shall contain one or more of the following terms and conditions, and (except as provided in subsection (7)) no others:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Classifying milk in accordance with the form in which or the purpose for which it is used, and fixing, or providing a method for fixing, minimum prices for each such use classification which all handlers shall pay, and the time when payments shall be made, for milk purchased from producers or associations of producers. Such prices shall be uniform as to all handlers, subject only to adjustments for (1) volume, market, and production differentials customarily applied by the handlers subject to such order, (2) the grade or quality of the milk purchased, and (3) the locations at which delivery of such milk, or any use classification thereof, is made to such handlers. Throughout the 2-year period beginning on the effective date of this sentence (and subsequent to such 2-year period unless modified by amendment to the order involved), for purposes of determining prices for milk of the highest use classification, the Class I skim milk price per hundredweight specified in section 1000.50(b) of title 7, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations), shall be the sum of the adjusted Class I differential specified in section 1000.52 of such title 7 (or successor regulations), plus the adjustment to Class I prices specified in sections 1005.51(b), 1006.51(b), and 1007.51(b) of such title 7 (or successor regulations), plus the simple average of the advanced pricing factors computed in sections 1000.50(q)(1) and 1000.50(q)(2) of such title 7 (or successor regulations), plus $0.74.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> Providing:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> for the payment to all producers and associations of producers delivering milk to the same handler of uniform prices for all milk delivered by them: <i>Provided</i>, That, except in the case of orders covering milk products only, such provision is approved or favored by at least three-fourths of the producers who, during a representative period determined by the Secretary of Agriculture, have been engaged in the production for market of milk covered in such order or by producers who, during such representative period, have produced at least three-fourths of the volume of such milk produced for market during such period; the approval required hereunder shall be separate and apart from any other approval or disapproval provided for by this section; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> for the payment to all producers and associations of producers delivering milk to all handlers of uniform prices for all milk so delivered, irrespective of the uses made of such milk by the individual handler to whom it is delivered;</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">subject, in either case, only to adjustments for (a) volume, market, and production differentials customarily applied by the handlers subject to such order, (b) the grade or quality of the milk delivered, (c) the locations at which delivery of such milk is made, and (d) a further adjustment, equitably to apportion the total value of the milk purchased by any handler, or by all handlers, among producers and associations of producers, on the basis of their marketings of milk during a representative period of time.,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002102">2</ref> [(e) omitted] and (f) a further adjustment, equitably to apportion the total value of milk purchased by any handler or by all handlers among producers on the basis of the milk components contained in their marketings of milk <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002103">3</ref></continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> In order to accomplish the purposes set forth in paragraphs (A) and (B) of this subsection, providing a method for making adjustments in payments, as among handlers (including producers who are also handlers), to the end that the total sums paid by each handler shall equal the value of the milk purchased by him at the prices fixed in accordance with paragraph (A) of this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Providing that, in the case of all milk purchased by handlers from any producer who did not regularly sell milk during a period of 30 days next preceding the effective date of such order for consumption in the area covered thereby, payments to such producer, for the period beginning with the first regular delivery by such producer and continuing until the end of two full calendar months following the first day of the next succeeding calendar month, shall be made at the price for the lowest use classification specified in such order, subject to the adjustments specified in paragraph (B) of this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Providing (i) except as to producers for whom such services are being rendered by a cooperative marketing association, qualified as provided in paragraph (F) of this subsection, for market information to producers and for the verification of weights, sampling, and testing of milk purchased from producers, and for making appropriate deductions therefor from payments to producers, and (ii) for assurance of, and security for, the payment by handlers for milk purchased.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Nothing contained in this subsection is intended or shall be construed to prevent a cooperative marketing association qualified under the provisions of sections 291 and 292 of this title, engaged in making collective sales or marketing of milk or its products for the producers thereof, from blending the net proceeds of all of its sales in all markets in all use classifications, and making distribution thereof to its producers in accordance with the contract between the association and its producers: <i>Provided</i>, That it shall not sell milk or its products to any handler for use or consumption in any market at prices less than the prices fixed pursuant to paragraph (A) of this subsection for such milk.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> No marketing agreement or order applicable to milk and its products in any marketing area shall prohibit or in any manner limit, in the case of the products of milk, the marketing in that area of any milk or product thereof produced in any production area in the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> Omitted</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> Establishing or providing for the establishment of research and development projects, and advertising (excluding brand advertising), sales promotion, educational, and other programs designed to improve or promote the domestic marketing and consumption of milk and its products, to be financed by producers in a manner and at a rate specified in the order, on all producer milk under the order. Producer contributions under this subparagraph <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002104">4</ref> may be deducted from funds due producers in computing total pool value or otherwise computing total funds due producers and such deductions shall be in addition to the adjustments authorized by paragraph (B) of this subsection. Provision may be made in the order to exempt, or allow suitable adjustments or credits in connection with, milk on which a mandatory checkoff for advertising or marketing research is required under the authority of any State law. Such funds shall be paid to an agency organized by milk producers and producers’ cooperative associations in such form and with such methods of operation as shall be specified in the order. Such agency may expend such funds for any of the purposes authorized by this subparagraph <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002104">4</ref> and may designate, employ, and allocate funds to persons and organizations engaged in such programs which meet the standards and qualifications specified in the order. All funds collected under this subparagraph <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002104">4</ref> shall be separately accounted for and shall be used only for the purposes for which they were collected. Programs authorized by this subparagraph <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002104">4</ref> may be either local or national in scope, or both, as provided in the order, but shall not be international. Order provisions under this subparagraph <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002104">4</ref> shall not become effective in any marketing order unless such provisions are approved by producers separately from other order provisions, in the same manner provided for the approval of marketing orders, and may be terminated separately whenever the Secretary makes a determination with respect to such provisions as is provided for the termination of an order in subsection (16)(B). Disapproval or termination of such order provisions shall not be considered disapproval of the order or of other terms of the order. Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, any producer against whose marketings any assessment is withheld or collected under the authority of this subparagraph,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002104">4</ref> and who is not in favor of supporting the research and promotion programs, as provided for herein, shall have the right to demand and receive a refund of such assessment pursuant to the terms and conditions specified in the order.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(J)</num>
<chapeau> Providing for the payment, from the total sums payable by all handlers for milk (irrespective of the use classification of such milk) and before computing uniform prices under paragraph (A) and making adjustments in payments under paragraph (C), to handlers that are cooperative marketing associations described in paragraph (F) and to handlers with respect to which adjustments in payments are made under paragraph (C), for services of marketwide benefit, including but not limited to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> providing facilities to furnish additional supplies of milk needed by handlers and to handle and dispose of milk supplies in excess of quantities needed by handlers;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> handling on specific days quantities of milk that exceed the quantities needed by handlers; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> transporting milk from one location to another for the purpose of fulfilling requirements for milk of a higher use classification or for providing a market outlet for milk of any use classification.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(K)</num>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, milk produced by dairies—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent1">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> owned or controlled by foreign persons; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent1">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> financed by or with the use of bonds the interest on which is exempt from Federal income tax under <ref>section 103 of title 26</ref>;</content>
</subclause>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be treated as other-source milk, and shall be allocated as milk received from producer-handlers for the purposes of classifying producer milk, under the milk marketing program established under this chapter. For the purposes of this subparagraph,<sup>4</sup> the term “foreign person” has the meaning given such term under <ref>section 3508(3) of this title</ref>.</continuation>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Agriculture shall prescribe regulations to carry out this subparagraph.<sup>4</sup></content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> This subparagraph <sup>4</sup> shall not apply with respect to any dairy that began operation before <date date="1986-05-06">May 6, 1986</date>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(L)</num>
<content> Providing that adjustments in payments by handlers under paragraph (A) need not be the same as adjustments to producers under paragraph (B) with regard to adjustments authorized by subparagraphs (2) and (3) of paragraph (A) and clauses (b), (c), and (d) of paragraph (B)(ii).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(M)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Minimum Milk Prices for Handlers.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Application of minimum price requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, a milk handler described in clause (ii) shall be subject to all of the minimum and uniform price requirements of a Federal milk marketing order issued pursuant to this section applicable to the county in which the plant of the handler is located, at Federal order class prices, if the handler has packaged fluid milk product route dispositions, or sales of packaged fluid milk products to other plants, in a marketing area located in a State that requires handlers to pay minimum prices for raw milk purchases.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered milk handlers</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Except as provided in clause (iv), clause (i) applies to a handler of Class I milk products (including a producer-handler or producer operating as a handler) that—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> operates a plant that is located within the boundaries of a Federal order milk marketing area (as those boundaries are in effect as of <date date="2006-04-11">April 11, 2006</date>);</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> has packaged fluid milk product route dispositions, or sales of packaged fluid milk products to other plants, in a milk marketing area located in a State that requires handlers to pay minimum prices for raw milk purchases; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> is not otherwise obligated by a Federal milk marketing order, or a regulated milk pricing plan operated by a State, to pay minimum class prices for the raw milk that is used for such dispositions or sales.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<heading> Obligation to pay minimum class prices.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of clause (ii)(III), the Secretary may not consider a handler of Class I milk products to be obligated by a Federal milk marketing order to pay minimum class prices for raw milk unless the handler operates the plant as a fully regulated fluid milk distributing plant under a Federal milk marketing order.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iv)</num>
<heading> Certain handlers exempted.—</heading>
<chapeau>Clause (i) does not apply to—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> a handler (otherwise described in clause (ii)) that operates a nonpool plant (as defined in section 1000.8(e) of title 7, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on <date date="2006-04-11">April 11, 2006</date>);</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> a producer-handler (otherwise described in clause (ii)) for any month during which the producer-handler has route dispositions, and sales to other plants, of packaged fluid milk products equaling less than 3,000,000 pounds of milk; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(III)</num>
<chapeau> a handler (otherwise described in clause (ii)) for any month during which—</chapeau>
<item class="indent3">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> less than 25 percent of the total quantity of fluid milk products physically received at the plant of the handler (excluding concentrated milk received from another plant by agreement for other than Class I use) is disposed of as route disposition or is transferred in the form of packaged fluid milk products to other plants; or</content>
</item>
<item class="indent3">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> less than 25 percent in aggregate of the route disposition or transfers are in a marketing area or areas located in one or more States that require handlers to pay minimum prices for raw milk purchases.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(N)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exemption for Certain Milk Handlers</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, no handler with distribution of Class I milk products in the marketing area described in Order No. 131 shall be exempt during any month from any minimum price requirement established by the Secretary under this subsection if the total distribution of Class I products during the preceding month of any such handler’s own farm production exceeds 3,000,000 pounds.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(O)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rule of Construction Regarding Producer-Handlers</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subparagraphs (M) and (N) shall not be construed as affecting, expanding, or contracting the treatment of producer-handlers under this subsection except as provided in such subparagraphs.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Terms—Other commodities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In the case of the agricultural commodities and the products thereof, other than milk and its products, specified in subsection (2) orders issued pursuant to this section shall contain one or more of the following terms and conditions, and (except as provided in subsection (7)), no others:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Limiting, or providing methods for the limitation of, the total quantity of any such commodity or product, or of any grade, size, or quality thereof, produced during any specified period or periods, which may be marketed in or transported to any or all markets in the current of interstate or foreign commerce or so as directly to burden, obstruct, or affect interstate or foreign commerce in such commodity or product thereof, during any specified period or periods by all handlers thereof.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Allotting, or providing methods for allotting, the amount of such commodity or product, or any grade, size, or quality thereof, which each handler may purchase from or handle on behalf of any and all producers thereof, during any specified period or periods, under a uniform rule based upon the amounts sold by such producers in such prior period as the Secretary determines to be representative, or upon the current quantities available for sale by such producers, or both, to the end that the total quantity thereof to be purchased, or handled during any specified period or periods shall be apportioned equitably among producers.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Allotting, or providing methods for allotting, the amount of any such commodity or product, or any grade, size, or quality thereof, which each handler may market in or transport to any or all markets in the current of interstate or foreign commerce or so as directly to burden, obstruct, or affect interstate or foreign commerce in such commodity or product thereof, under a uniform rule based upon the amounts which each such handler has available for current shipment, or upon the amounts shipped by each such handler in such prior period as the Secretary determines to be representative, or both, to the end that the total quantity of such commodity or product, or any grade, size, or quality thereof, to be marketed in or transported to any or all markets in the current of interstate or foreign commerce or so as directly to burden, obstruct, or affect interstate or foreign commerce in such commodity or product thereof, during any specified period or periods shall be equitably apportioned among all of the handlers thereof.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Determining, or providing methods for determining, the existence and extent of the surplus of any such commodity or product, or of any grade, size, or quality thereof, and providing for the control and disposition of such surplus, and for equalizing the burden of such surplus elimination or control among the producers and handlers thereof.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Establishing or providing for the establishment of reserve pools of any such commodity or product, or of any grade, size, or quality thereof, and providing for the equitable distribution of the net return derived from the sale thereof among the persons beneficially interested therein.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Requiring or providing for the requirement of inspection of any such commodity or product produced during specified periods and marketed by handlers.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(G)</num>
<chapeau> In the case of hops and their products in addition to, or in lieu of, the foregoing terms and conditions, orders may contain one or more of the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Limiting, or providing methods for the limitation of, the total quantity thereof, or of any grade, type, or variety thereof, produced during any specified period or periods, which all handlers may handle in the current of or so as directly to burden, obstruct, or affect interstate or foreign commerce in hops or any product thereof.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Apportioning, or providing methods for apportioning, the total quantity of hops of the production of the then current calendar year permitted to be handled equitably among all producers in the production area to which the order applies upon the basis of one or more or a combination of the following: The total quantity of hops available or estimated will become available for market by each producer from his production during such period; the normal production of the acreage of hops operated by each producer during such period upon the basis of the number of acres of hops in production, and the average yield of that acreage during such period as the Secretary determines to be representative, with adjustments determined by the Secretary to be proper for age of plantings or abnormal conditions affecting yield; such normal production or historical record of any acreage for which data as to yield of hops are not available or which had no yield during such period shall be determined by the Secretary on the basis of the yields of other acreage of hops of similar characteristics as to productivity, subject to adjustment as just provided for.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Allotting, or providing methods for allotting, the quantity of hops which any handler may handle so that the allotment fixed for that handler shall be limited to the quantity of hops apportioned under preceding section <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002105">5</ref> (ii) to each respective producer of hops; such allotment shall constitute an allotment fixed for that handler within the meaning of subsection (5) of <ref>section 608a of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> providing <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002106">6</ref> a method for fixing the size, capacity, weight, dimensions, or pack of the container, or containers, which may be used in the packaging, transportation, sale, shipment, or handling of any fresh or dried fruits, vegetables, or tree nuts: <i>Provided, however</i>, That no action taken hereunder shall conflict with the Standard Containers Act of 1916 (<ref>15 U.S.C. 251–256</ref>) and the Standard Containers Act of 1928 (<ref>15 U.S.C. 257–257i</ref>); <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002107">7</ref></content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> establishing <sup>6</sup> or providing for the establishment of production research, marketing research and development projects designed to assist, improve, or promote the marketing, distribution, and consumption or efficient production of any such commodity or product, the expense of such projects to be paid from funds collected pursuant to the marketing order: <i>Provided</i>, That with respect to orders applicable to almonds, filberts (otherwise known as hazelnuts), California-grown peaches, cherries, papayas, carrots, citrus fruits, onions, Tokay grapes, pears, dates, plums, nectarines, celery, sweet corn, limes, olives, pecans, eggs, avocados, apples, raisins, walnuts, tomatoes, caneberries (including raspberries, blackberries, and loganberries), Florida grown <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002108">8</ref> strawberries, or cranberries, such proj­ects may provide for any form of marketing promotion including paid advertising and with respect to almonds, filberts (otherwise known as hazelnuts), raisins, walnuts, olives, Florida Indian River grapefruit, and cranberries may provide for crediting the pro rata expense assessment obligations of a handler with all or any portion of his direct expenditures for such marketing promotion including paid advertising as may be authorized by the order and when the handling of any commodity for canning or freezing is regulated, then any such projects may also deal with the commodity or its products in canned or frozen form: <i>Provided further</i>, That the inclusion in a Federal marketing order of provisions for research and marketing promotion, including paid advertising, shall not be deemed to preclude, preempt or supersede any such provisions in any State program covering the same commodity.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> In the case of pears for canning or freezing, any order for a production area encompassing territory within two or more States or portions thereof shall provide that the grade, size, quality, maturity, and inspection regulation under the order applicable to pears grown within any such State or portion thereof may be recommended to the Secretary by the agency established to administer the order only if a majority of the representatives from that State on such agency concur in the recommendation each year.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Terms common to all orders</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In the case of the agricultural commodities and the products thereof specified in subsection (2) orders shall contain one or more of the following terms and conditions:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Prohibiting unfair methods of competition and unfair trade practices in the handling thereof.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Providing that (except for milk and cream to be sold for consumption in fluid form) such commodity or product thereof, or any grade, size, or quality thereof shall be sold by the handlers thereof only at prices filed by such handlers in the manner provided in such order.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> Providing for the selection by the Secretary of Agriculture, or a method for the selection, of an agency or agencies and defining their powers and duties, which shall include only the powers:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> To administer such order in accordance with its terms and provisions;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> To make rules and regulations to effectuate the terms and provisions of such order;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> To receive, investigate, and report to the Secretary of Agriculture complaints of violations of such order; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> To recommend to the Secretary of Agriculture amendments to such order.</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">No person acting as a member of an agency established pursuant to this paragraph shall be deemed to be acting in an official capacity, within the meaning of <ref>section 610(g) of this title</ref>, unless such person receives compensation for his personal services from funds of the United States. There shall be included in the membership of any agency selected to administer a marketing order applicable to grapefruit for canning or freezing one or more representatives of processors of the commodity specified in such order.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Incidental to, and not inconsistent with, the terms and conditions specified in subsections (5), (6), and (7) and necessary to effectuate the other provisions of such order.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Orders with marketing agreement</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except as provided in subsection (9) of this section, no order issued pursuant to this section shall become effective until the handlers (excluding cooperative associations of producers who are not engaged in processing, distributing, or shipping the commodity or product thereof covered by such order) of not less than 50 per centum of the volume of the commodity or product thereof covered by such order which is produced or marketed within the production or marketing area defined in such order have signed a marketing agreement, entered into pursuant to <ref>section 608b of this title</ref>, which regulates the handling of such commodity or product in the same manner as such order, except that as to citrus fruits produced in any area producing what is known as California citrus fruits no order issued pursuant to this subsection shall become effective until the handlers of not less than 80 per centum of the volume of such commodity or product thereof covered by such order have signed such a marketing agreement: <i>Provided</i>, That no order issued pursuant to this subsection shall be effective unless the Secretary of Agriculture determines that the issuance of such order is approved or favored:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> By at least two-thirds of the producers who (except that as to citrus fruits produced in any area producing what is known as California citrus fruits said order must be approved or favored by three-fourths of the producers), during a representative period determined by the Secretary, have been engaged, within the production area specified in such marketing agreement or order, in the production for market of the commodity specified therein, or who, during such representative period, have been engaged in the production of such commodity for sale in the marketing area specified in such marketing agreement, or order, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> By producers who, during such representative period, have produced for market at least two-thirds of the volume of such commodity produced for market within the production area specified in such marketing agreement or order, or who, during such representative period, have produced at least two-thirds of the volume of such commodity sold within the marketing area specified in such marketing agreement or order.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Orders with or without marketing agreement</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Any order issued pursuant to this section shall become effective in the event that, notwithstanding the refusal or failure of handlers (excluding cooperative associations of producers who are not engaged in processing, distributing, or shipping the commodity or product thereof covered by such order) of more than 50 per centum of the volume of the commodity or product thereof (except that as to citrus fruits produced in any area producing what is known as California citrus fruits said per centum shall be 80 per centum) covered by such order which is produced or marketed within the production or marketing area defined in such order to sign a marketing agreement relating to such commodity or product thereof, on which a hearing has been held, the Secretary of Agriculture determines:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> That the refusal or failure to sign a marketing agreement (upon which a hearing has been held) by the handlers (excluding cooperative associations of producers who are not engaged in processing, distributing, or shipping the commodity or product thereof covered by such order) of more than 50 per centum of the volume of the commodity or product thereof (except that as to citrus fruits produced in any area producing what is known as California citrus fruits said per centum shall be 80 per centum) specified therein which is produced or marketed within the production or marketing area specified therein tends to prevent the effectuation of the declared policy of this chapter with respect to such commodity or product, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> That the issuance of such order is the only practical means of advancing the interests of the producers of such commodity pursuant to the declared policy, and is approved or favored:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> By at least two-thirds of the producers (except that as to citrus fruits produced in any area producing what is known as California citrus fruits said order must be approved or favored by three-fourths of the producers) who, during a representative period determined by the Secretary, have been engaged, within the production area specified in such marketing agreement or order, in the production for market of the commodity specified therein, or who, during such representative period, have been engaged in the production of such commodity for sale in the marketing area specified in such marketing agreement, or order, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> By producers who, during such representative period, have produced for market at least two-thirds of the volume of such commodity produced for market within the production area specified in such marketing agreement or order, or who, during such representative period, have produced at least two-thirds of the volume of such commodity sold within the marketing area specified in such marketing agreement or order.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(10)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Manner of regulation and applicability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No order shall be issued under this section unless it regulates the handling of the commodity or product covered thereby in the same manner as, and is made applicable only to persons in the respective classes of industrial or commercial activity specified in, a marketing agreement upon which a hearing has been held. No order shall be issued under this chapter prohibiting, regulating, or restricting the advertising of any commodity or product covered thereby, nor shall any marketing agreement contain any provision prohibiting, regulating, or restricting the advertising of any commodity, or product covered by such marketing agreement.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(11)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regional application</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> No order shall be issued under this section which is applicable to all production areas or marketing areas, or both, of any commodity or product thereof unless the Secretary finds that the issuance of several orders applicable to the respective regional production areas or regional marketing areas, or both, as the case may be, of the commodity or product would not effectively carry out the declared policy of this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Except in the case of milk and its products, orders issued under this section shall be limited in their application to the smallest regional production areas or regional marketing areas, or both, as the case may be, which the Secretary finds practicable, consistently with carrying out such declared policy.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> All orders issued under this section which are applicable to the same commodity or product thereof shall, so far as practicable, prescribe such different terms, applicable to different production areas and marketing areas, as the Secretary finds necessary to give due recognition to the differences in production and marketing of such commodity or product in such areas.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> In the case of milk and its products, no county or other political subdivision of the State of Nevada shall be within the marketing area definition of any order issued under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(12)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cooperative association representation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever, pursuant to the provisions of this section, the Secretary is required to determine the approval or disapproval of producers with respect to the issuance of any order, or any term or condition thereof, or the termination thereof, the Secretary shall consider the approval or disapproval by any cooperative association of producers, bona fide engaged in marketing the commodity or product thereof covered by such order, or in rendering services for or advancing the interests of the producers of such commodity, as the approval or disapproval of the producers who are members of, stockholders in, or under contract with, such cooperative association of producers.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(13)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Retailer and producer exemption</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> No order issued under subsection (9) of this section shall be applicable to any person who sells agricultural commodities or products thereof at retail in his capacity as such retailer, except to a retailer in his capacity as a retailer of milk and its products.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> No order issued under this chapter shall be applicable to any producer in his capacity as a producer.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(14)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Violation of order</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Any handler subject to an order issued under this section, or any officer, director, agent, or employee of such handler, who violates any provision of such order shall, on conviction, be fined not less than $50 or more than $5,000 for each such violation, and each day during which such violation continues shall be deemed a separate violation. If the court finds that a petition pursuant to subsection (15) of this section was filed and prosecuted by the defendant in good faith and not for delay, no penalty shall be imposed under this subsection for such violations as occurred between the date upon which the defendant’s petition was filed with the Secretary, and the date upon which notice of the Secretary’s ruling thereon was given to the defendant in accordance with regulations prescribed pursuant to subsection (15).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Any handler subject to an order issued under this section, or any officer, director, agent, or employee of such handler, who violates any provision of such order may be assessed a civil penalty by the Secretary not exceeding $1,000 for each such violation. Each day during which such violation continues shall be deemed a separate violation, except that if the Secretary finds that a petition pursuant to paragraph (15) was filed and prosecuted by the handler in good faith and not for delay, no civil penalty may be assessed under this paragraph for such violations as occurred between the date on which the handler’s petition was filed with the Secretary, and the date on which notice of the Secretary’s ruling thereon was given to the handler in accordance with regulations prescribed pursuant to paragraph (15). The Secretary may issue an order assessing a civil penalty under this paragraph only after notice and an opportunity for an agency hearing on the record. Such order shall be treated as a final order reviewable in the district courts of the United States in any district in which the handler subject to the order is an inhabitant, or has the handler’s principal place of business. The validity of such order may not be reviewed in an action to collect such civil penalty.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(15)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Petition by handler and review</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Any handler subject to an order may file a written petition with the Secretary of Agriculture, stating that any such order or any provision of any such order or any obligation imposed in connection therewith is not in accordance with law and praying for a modification thereof or to be exempted therefrom. He shall thereupon be given an opportunity for a hearing upon such petition, in accordance with regulations made by the Secretary of Agriculture, with the approval of the President. After such hearing, the Secretary shall make a ruling upon the prayer of such petition which shall be final, if in accordance with law.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The District Courts of the United States in any district in which such handler is an inhabitant, or has his principal place of business, are hereby vested with jurisdiction in equity to review such ruling, provided a bill in equity for that purpose is filed within twenty days from the date of the entry of such ruling. Service of process in such proceedings may be had upon the Secretary by delivering to him a copy of the bill of complaint. If the court determines that such ruling is not in accordance with law, it shall remand such proceedings to the Secretary with directions either (1) to make such ruling as the court shall determine to be in accordance with law, or (2) to take such further proceedings as, in its opinion, the law requires. The pendency of proceedings instituted pursuant to this subsection (15) shall not impede, hinder, or delay the United States or the Secretary of Agriculture from obtaining relief pursuant to <ref>section 608a(6) of this title</ref>. Any proceedings brought pursuant to <ref>section 608a(6) of this title</ref> (except where brought by way of counterclaim in proceedings instituted pursuant to this subsection (15)) shall abate whenever a final decree has been rendered in proceedings between the same parties, and covering the same subject matter, instituted pursuant to this subsection (15).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(16)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination of orders and marketing agreements</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Except as provided in clause (ii), the Secretary of Agriculture shall, whenever he finds that any order issued under this section, or any provision thereof, obstructs or does not tend to effectuate the declared policy of this chapter, terminate or suspend the operation of such order or such provision thereof.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The Secretary may not terminate any order issued under this section for a commodity for which there is no Federal program established to support the price of such commodity unless the Secretary gives notice of, and a statement of the reasons relied upon by the Secretary for, the proposed termination of such order to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate and the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives not later than 60 days before the date such order will be terminated.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall terminate any marketing agreement entered into under <ref>section 608b of this title</ref>, or order issued under this section, at the end of the then current marketing period for such commodity, specified in such marketing agreement or order, whenever he finds that such termination is favored by a majority of the producers who, during a representative period determined by the Secretary, have been engaged in the production for market of the commodity specified in such marketing agreement or order, within the production area specified in such marketing agreement or order, or who, during such representative period, have been engaged in the production of such commodity for sale within the marketing area specified in such marketing agreement or order: <i>Provided</i>, That such majority have, during such representative period, produced for market more than 50 per centum of the volume of such commodity produced for market within the production area specified in such marketing agreement or order, or have, during such representative period, produced more than 50 per centum of the volume of such commodity sold in the marketing area specified in such marketing agreement or order, but such termination shall be effective only if announced on or before such date (prior to the end of the then current marketing period) as may be specified in such marketing agreement or order.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Except as otherwise provided in this subsection with respect to the termination of an order issued under this section, the termination or suspension of any order or amendment thereto or provision thereof, shall not be considered an order within the meaning of this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(17)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Provisions applicable to amendments</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability to amendments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The provisions of this section and <ref>section 608d of this title</ref> applicable to orders shall be applicable to amendments to orders.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Supplemental rules of practice</heading>
<clause class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this subparagraph, the Secretary shall issue, using informal rulemaking, supplemental rules of practice to define guidelines and timeframes for the rulemaking process relating to amendments to orders.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Issues</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">At a minimum, the supplemental rules of practice shall establish—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> proposal submission requirements;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> pre-hearing information session specifications;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> written testimony and data request requirements;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> public participation timeframes; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(V)</num>
<content> electronic document submission standards.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The supplemental rules of practice shall take effect not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this subparagraph, as determined by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Hearing timeframes</heading>
<clause class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Not more than 30 days after the receipt of a proposal for an amendment hearing regarding a milk marketing order, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> issue a notice providing an action plan and expected timeframes for completion of the hearing not more than 120 days after the date of the issuance of the notice;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<item class="indent3">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> issue a request for additional information to be used by the Secretary in making a determination regarding the proposal; and</content>
</item>
<item class="indent3">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> if the additional information is not provided to the Secretary within the timeframe requested by the Secretary, issue a denial of the request; or</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> issue a denial of the request.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A post-hearing brief may be filed under this paragraph not later than 60 days after the date of an amendment hearing regarding a milk marketing order.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recommended decisions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A recommended decision on a proposed amendment to an order shall be issued not later than 90 days after the deadline for the submission of post-hearing briefs.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iv)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Final decisions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A final decision on a proposed amendment to an order shall be issued not later than 60 days after the deadline for submission of comments and exceptions to the recommended decision issued under clause (iii).</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Industry assessments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the Secretary determines it is necessary to improve or expedite rulemaking under this subsection, the Secretary may impose an assessment on the affected industry to supplement appropriated funds for the procurement of service providers, such as court reporters.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(E)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of informal rulemaking</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may use rulemaking under <ref>section 553 of title 5</ref> to amend orders, other than provisions of orders that directly affect milk prices.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(F)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Avoiding duplication</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary shall not be required to hold a hearing on any amendment proposed to be made to a milk marketing order in response to an application for a hearing on the proposed amendment if—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the application requesting the hearing is received by the Secretary not later than 90 days after the date on which the Secretary has announced the decision on a previously proposed amendment to that order; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the 2 proposed amendments are essentially the same, as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(G)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Monthly feed and fuel costs for make allowances</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">As part of any hearing to adjust make allowances under marketing orders commencing prior to <date date="2012-09-30">September 30, 2012</date>, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> determine the average monthly prices of feed and fuel incurred by dairy producers in the relevant marketing area;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> consider the most recent monthly feed and fuel price data available; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> consider those prices in determining whether or not to adjust make allowances.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(18)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Milk prices</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture, prior to prescribing any term in any marketing agreement or order, or amendment thereto, relating to milk or its products, if such term is to fix minimum prices to be paid to producers or associations of producers, or prior to modifying the price fixed in any such term, shall ascertain the parity prices of such commodities. The prices which it is declared to be the policy of Congress to establish in <ref>section 602 of this title</ref> shall, for the purposes of such agreement, order, or amendment, be adjusted to reflect the price of feeds, the available supplies of feeds, and other economic conditions which affect market supply and demand for milk or its products in the marketing area to which the contemplated marketing agreement, order, or amendment relates. Whenever the Secretary finds, upon the basis of the evidence adduced at the hearing required by <ref>section 608b of this title</ref> or this section, as the case may be, that the parity prices of such commodities are not reasonable in view of the price of feeds, the available supplies of feeds, and other economic conditions which affect market supply and demand for milk and its products in the marketing area to which the contemplated agreement, order, or amendment relates, he shall fix such prices as he finds will reflect such factors, insure a sufficient quantity of pure and wholesome milk, and be in the public interest. Thereafter, as the Secretary finds necessary on account of changed circumstances, he shall, after due notice and opportunity for hearing, make adjustments in such prices.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(19)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Producer referendum</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purpose of ascertaining whether the issuance of an order is approved or favored by producers or processors, as required under the applicable provisions of this chapter, the Secretary may conduct a referendum among producers or processors and in the case of an order other than an amendatory order shall do so. The requirements of approval or favor under any such provision shall be held to be complied with if, of the total number of producers or processors, or the total volume of production, as the case may be, represented in such referendum, the percentage approving or favoring is equal to or in excess of the percentage required under such provision. The terms and conditions of the proposed order shall be described by the Secretary in the ballot used in the conduct of the referendum. The nature, content, or extent of such description shall not be a basis for attacking the legality of the order or any action relating thereto. Nothing in this subsection shall be construed as limiting representation by cooperative associations as provided in subsection (12) of this section. For the purpose of ascertaining whether the issuance of an order applicable to pears for canning or freezing is approved or favored by producers as required under the applicable provisions of this chapter, the Secretary shall conduct a referendum among producers in each State in which pears for canning or freezing are proposed to be included within the provisions of such marketing order and the requirements of approval or favor under any such provisions applicable to pears for canning or freezing shall be held to be complied with if, of the total number of producers, or the total volume of production, as the case may be, represented in such referendum, the percentage approving or favoring is equal to or in excess of 66⅔ per centum except that in the event that pear producers in any State fail to approve or favor the issuance of any such marketing order, it shall not be made effective in such State.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 12, 1933, ch. 25</ref>, title I, § 8c, as added <ref>Aug. 24, 1935, ch. 641, § 5</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 753</ref>; amended <ref>June 25, 1936, ch. 804</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 1921</ref>; <ref>June 3, 1937, ch. 296</ref>, §§ 1, 2(d)–(f), <ref>50 Stat. 246</ref>, 247; <ref>June 3, 1937, ch. 296, § 2(k)</ref>, (<i>l</i>), as added <ref>Aug. 5, 1937, ch. 567</ref>, <ref>50 Stat. 563</ref>; <ref>Apr. 13, 1938, ch. 143</ref>, §§ 1, 2, <ref>52 Stat. 215</ref>; <ref>May 31, 1939, ch. 157</ref>, <ref>53 Stat. 793</ref>; <ref>Feb. 10, 1942, ch. 52</ref>, §§ 2, 3, <ref>56 Stat. 85</ref>; 1947 Reorg. Plan No. 1, § 102, eff. <date date="1947-07-01">July 1, 1947</date>, 12 F.R. 4534, <ref>61 Stat. 951</ref>; <ref>Aug. 1, 1947, ch. 425</ref>, §§ 2, 4, <ref>61 Stat. 707</ref>, 710; <ref>July 3, 1948, ch. 827</ref>, title III, § 302(b), (c), <ref>62 Stat. 1258</ref>; <ref>June 29, 1949, ch. 273</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 282</ref>; <ref>Aug. 28, 1954, ch. 1041</ref>, title IV, § 401(b)–(d), <ref>68 Stat. 906</ref>, 907; <ref>Pub. L. 87–128, title I, § 141(3)</ref>, (4), <date date="1961-08-08">Aug. 8, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 304</ref>, 305; <ref>Pub. L. 87–703, title IV, § 403</ref>, <date date="1962-09-27">Sept. 27, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 632</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–321, title I</ref>, §§ 101, 102, <date date="1965-11-03">Nov. 3, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 1187</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–330, § 1(b)</ref>, <date date="1965-11-08">Nov. 8, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 1270</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–196, § 1</ref>, <date date="1970-02-20">Feb. 20, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 14</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–292, § 1(2)</ref>, <date date="1970-06-25">June 25, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 333</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–341</ref>, <date date="1970-07-18">July 18, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 438</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–363</ref>, <date date="1970-07-31">July 31, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 687</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–384</ref>, <date date="1970-08-18">Aug. 18, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 827</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–522</ref>, <date date="1970-11-25">Nov. 25, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1357</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–524, title II, § 201(a)</ref>, <date date="1970-11-30">Nov. 30, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1359</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–670, title I, § 101</ref>, title II, § 201, <date date="1971-01-11">Jan. 11, 1971</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 2040</ref>, 2041; <ref>Pub. L. 92–120</ref>, <date date="1971-08-13">Aug. 13, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 340</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–233</ref>, <date date="1972-02-15">Feb. 15, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 39</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–466</ref>, <date date="1972-10-06">Oct. 6, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 780</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–524, title II, § 201(f)</ref>, <date date="1970-11-30">Nov. 30, 1970</date>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 93–86, § 1(2)(B)</ref>, <date date="1973-08-10">Aug. 10, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 222</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–230</ref>, <date date="1973-12-29">Dec. 29, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 945</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–279, title IV, § 401(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-05-15">May 15, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 242</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–494, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1980-12-03">Dec. 3, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2570</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–98, title I, § 101(a)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-22">Dec. 22, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1218</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–171, § 1</ref>, <date date="1983-11-29">Nov. 29, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 1117</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–180, title III, § 304</ref>, <date date="1983-11-29">Nov. 29, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 1151</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–198, title I</ref>, §§ 131(a), 133, title XVI, §§ 1661(a), 1662(a), <date date="1985-12-23">Dec. 23, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 1372</ref>, 1373, 1630, 1631; <ref>Pub. L. 100–203, title I, § 1501</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1330–27</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title IV</ref>, §§ 4601, 4602, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1407</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title I</ref>, §§ 112, 113, title XIII, § 1306, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3380</ref>, 3561; <ref>Pub. L. 102–237, title I, § 115(2)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-13">Dec. 13, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1840</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–553, § 2</ref>, <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4141</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–78, title VII</ref>, §§ 757(a), 760, <date date="1999-10-22">Oct. 22, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1171</ref>, 1173; <ref>Pub. L. 107–76, title VII, § 765</ref>, <date date="2001-11-28">Nov. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 743</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–171, title X, § 10601(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 511</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–379, § 1</ref>, <date date="2004-10-30">Oct. 30, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2209</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–215, § 2(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2006-04-11">Apr. 11, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 328</ref>, 329; <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title I, § 1504</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 993</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title I, § 1504, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1721; <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title I, § 1403(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4518</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 608c–1.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>June 29, 1945, ch. 196</ref>, <ref>59 Stat. 263</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 608d.</num>
<heading> Books and records</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> All parties to any marketing agreement, and all handlers subject to an order, shall severally, from time to time, upon the request of the Secretary, furnish him with such information as he finds to be necessary to enable him to ascertain and determine the extent to which such agreement or order has been carried out or has effectuated the declared policy of this chapter and with such information as he finds to be necessary to determine whether or not there has been any abuse of the privilege of exemptions from the antitrust laws. Such information shall be furnished in accordance with forms of reports to be prescribed by the Secretary. For the purpose of ascertaining the correctness of any report made to the Secretary pursuant to this subsection, or for the purpose of obtaining the information required in any such report, where it has been requested and has not been furnished, the Secretary is authorized to examine such books, papers, records, copies of income-tax reports, accounts, correspondence, contracts, documents, or memoranda, as he deems relevant and which are within the control (1) of any such party to such marketing agreement, or any such handler, from whom such report was requested or (2) of any person having, either directly or indirectly, actual or legal control of or over such party or such handler or (3) of any subsidiary of any such party, handler, or person.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding the provisions of <ref>section 607 of this title</ref>, all information furnished to or acquired by the Secretary of Agriculture pursuant to this section, as well as information for marketing order programs that is categorized as trade secrets and commercial or financial information exempt under <ref>section 552(b)(4) of title 5</ref> from disclosure under section 552 of such title, shall be kept confidential by all officers and employees of the Department of Agriculture and only such information so furnished or acquired as the Secretary deems relevant shall be disclosed by them, and then only in a suit or administrative hearing brought at the direction, or upon the request, of the Secretary of Agriculture, or to which he or any officer of the United States is a party, and involving the marketing agreement or order with reference to which the information so to be disclosed was furnished or acquired. Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, any such information relating to a marketing agreement or order applicable to milk may be released upon the authorization of any regulated milk handler to whom such information pertains. The Secretary shall notify the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate and the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives not later than 10 legislative days before the contemplated release under law, of the names and addresses of producers participating in such marketing agreements and orders, and shall include in such notice a statement of reasons relied upon by the Secretary in making the determination to release such names and addresses. Nothing in this section shall be deemed to prohibit (A) the issuance of general statements based upon the reports of a number of parties to a marketing agreement or of handlers subject to an order, which statements do not identify the information furnished by any person, or (B) the publication by direction of the Secretary, of the name of any person violating any marketing agreement or any order, together with a statement of the particular provisions of the marketing agreement or order violated by such person. Any such officer or employee violating the provisions of this section shall upon conviction be subject to a fine of not more than $1,000 or to imprisonment for not more than one year, or to both, and shall be removed from office.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Collection of cranberry inventory data.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If an order is in effect with respect to cranberries, the Secretary of Agriculture may require persons engaged in the handling or importation of cranberries or cranberry products (including producer-handlers, second handlers, processors, brokers, and importers) to provide such information as the Secretary considers necessary to effectuate the declared policy of this chapter, including information on acquisitions, inventories, and dispositions of cranberries and cranberry products.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Delegation to committee</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may delegate the authority to carry out subparagraph (A) to any committee that is responsible for administering an order covering cranberries.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Confidentiality</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Paragraph (2) shall apply to information provided under this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Violations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any person who violates this paragraph shall be subject to the penalties provided under <ref>section 608c(14) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 12, 1933, ch. 25</ref>, title I, § 8d, as added <ref>Aug. 24, 1935, ch. 641, § 6</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 761</ref>; amended <ref>June 3, 1937, ch. 296, § 1</ref>, <ref>50 Stat. 246</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–198, title XVI, § 1663</ref>, <date date="1985-12-23">Dec. 23, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 1631</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–78, title VII, § 757(b)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-22">Oct. 22, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1171</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 608e.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>July 3, 1948, ch. 827</ref>, title III, § 302(d), <ref>62 Stat. 1258</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 608e–1.</num>
<heading> Import prohibitions on specified foreign produce</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Import prohibitions on tomatoes, avocados, limes, etc.</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to the provisions of subsections (c) and (d) and notwithstanding any other provision of law, whenever a marketing order issued by the Secretary of Agriculture pursuant to <ref>section 608c of this title</ref> contains any terms or conditions regulating the grade, size, quality, or maturity of tomatoes, raisins, olives (other than Spanish-style green olives), prunes, avocados, mangoes, limes, grapefruit, green peppers, Irish potatoes, cucumbers, oranges, onions, walnuts, cherries, pecans, dates, filberts, table grapes, eggplants, kiwifruit, nectarines, clementines, plums, pistachios, apples, or caneberries (including raspberries, blackberries, and loganberries) produced in the United States the importation into the United States of any such commodity, other than dates for processing, during the period of time such order is in effect shall be prohibited unless it complies with the grade, size, quality, and maturity provisions of such order or comparable restrictions promulgated hereunder: <i>Provided</i>, That this prohibition shall not apply to such commodities when shipped into continental United States from the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico or any Territory or possession of the United States where this chapter has force and effect: <i>Provided further</i>, That whenever two or more such marketing orders regulating the same agricultural commodity produced in different areas of the United States are concurrently in effect, the importation into the United States of any such commodity, other than dates for processing, shall be prohibited unless it complies with the grade, size, quality, and maturity provisions of the order which, as determined by the Secretary of Agriculture, regulates the commodity produced in the area with which the imported commodity is in most direct competition. Such prohibition shall not become effective until after the giving of such notice as the Secretary of Agriculture determines reasonable, which shall not be less than three days. In determining the amount of notice that is reasonable in the case of tomatoes the Secretary of Agriculture shall give due consideration to the time required for their transportation and entry into the United States after picking. Whenever the Secretary of Agriculture finds that the application of the restrictions under a marketing order to an imported commodity is not practicable because of variations in characteristics between the domestic and imported commodity he shall establish with respect to the imported commodity, other than dates for processing, such grade, size, quality, and maturity restrictions by varieties, types, or other classifications as he finds will be equivalent or comparable to those imposed upon the domestic commodity under such order. The Secretary of Agriculture may promulgate such rules and regulations as he deems necessary, to carry out the provisions of this section. Any person who violates any provision if <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002109">1</ref> this section or of any rule, regulation, or order promulgated hereunder shall be subject to a forfeiture in the amount prescribed in <ref>section 608a(5) of this title</ref> or, upon conviction, a penalty in the amount prescribed in <ref>section 608c(14) of this title</ref>, or to both such forfeiture and penalty.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Extension of time for marketing order; factors; review</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary may provide for a period of time (not to exceed 35 days) in addition to the period of time covered by a marketing order during which the marketing order requirements would be in effect for a particular commodity during any year if the Secretary determines that such additional period of time is necessary—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to effectuate the purposes of this chapter; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to prevent the circumvention of the grade, size, quality, or maturity standards of a seasonal marketing order applicable to a commodity produced in the United States by imports of such commodity.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> In making the determination required by paragraph (1), the Secretary, through notice and comment procedures, shall consider—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to what extent, during the previous year, imports of a commodity that did not meet the requirements of a marketing order applicable to such commodity were marketed in the United States during the period that such marketing order requirements were in effect for available domestic commodities (or would have been marketed during such time if not for any additional period established by the Secretary);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> if the importation into the United States of such commodity did, or was likely to, circumvent the grade, size, quality or maturity standards of a seasonal marketing order applicable to such commodity produced in the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the availability and price of commodities of the variety covered by the marketing order during any additional period the marketing order requirements are to be in effect.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> An additional period established by the Secretary in accordance with this subsection shall be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> announced not later than 30 days before the date such additional period is to be in effect; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> reviewed by the Secretary on request, through notice and comment procedures, at least every 3 years in order to determine if the additional period is still needed to prevent circumvention of the seasonal marketing order by imported commodities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> For the purposes of carrying out this subsection, the Secretary is authorized to make such reasonable inspections as may be necessary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification of United States Trade Representative of import restrictions; advisement of Secretary of Agriculture</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Prior to any import prohibition or regulation under this section being made effective with respect to any commodity—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Agriculture shall notify the United States Trade Representative of such import prohibition or regulation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the United States Trade Representative shall advise the Secretary of Agriculture, within 60 days of the notification under paragraph (1), to ensure that the application of the grade, size, quality, and maturity provisions of the relevant marketing order, or comparable restrictions, to imports is not inconsistent with United States international obligations under any trade agreement, including the General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Proposed prohibition or regulation; authority of Secretary of Agriculture to proceed</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may proceed with the proposed prohibition or regulation if the Secretary receives the advice and concurrence of the United States Trade Representative within 60 days of the notification under subsection (c)(1).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 12, 1933, ch. 25</ref>, title I, § 8e, as added <ref>Aug. 28, 1954, ch. 1041</ref>, title IV, § 401(e), <ref>68 Stat. 907</ref>; amended <ref>Aug. 31, 1954, ch. 1172, § 3(a)</ref>, <ref>68 Stat. 1047</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–128, title I, § 141(5)</ref>, <date date="1961-08-08">Aug. 8, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 305</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–670, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="1971-01-11">Jan. 11, 1971</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 2047</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–113, title X, § 1006</ref>, <date date="1977-09-29">Sept. 29, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 951</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–312, § 2</ref>, <date date="1982-10-14">Oct. 14, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1461</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title IV, § 4603</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1407</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XIII</ref>, §§ 1307, 1308, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3561</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–171, title X, § 10601(b)</ref>, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 511</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title X, § 10102</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1335</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title X, § 10102, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2097; <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title XII, § 12503</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4987</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 608f.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 89–106, § 9</ref>, <date date="1965-08-04">Aug. 4, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 432</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 609.</num>
<heading> Processing tax; methods of computation; rate; what constitutes processing; publicity as to tax to avoid profiteering</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> To obtain revenue for extraordinary expenses incurred by reason of the national economic emergency, there shall be levied processing taxes as hereinafter provided. When the Secretary of Agriculture determines that any one or more payments authorized to be made under <ref>section 608 of this title</ref> are to be made with respect to any basic agricultural commodity, he shall proclaim such determination, and a processing tax shall be in effect with respect to such commodity from the beginning of the marketing year therefor next following the date of such proclamation; except that (1) in the case of sugar beets and sugarcane, the Secretary of Agriculture shall, on or before the thirtieth day after <date date="1934-05-09">May 9, 1934</date>, proclaim that rental or benefit payments with respect to said commodities are to be made, and the processing tax shall be in effect on and after the thirtieth day after <date date="1934-05-09">May 9, 1934</date>, and (2) in the case of rice, the Secretary of Agriculture shall, before <date date="1935-04-01">April 1, 1935</date>, proclaim that rental or benefit payments are to be made with respect thereto, and the processing tax shall be in effect on and after <date date="1935-04-01">April 1, 1935</date>. In the case of sugar beets and sugarcane, the calendar year shall be considered to be the marketing year and for the year 1934 the marketing year shall begin <date date="1934-01-01">January 1, 1934</date>. In the case of rice, the period from August 1 to July 31, both inclusive, shall be considered to be the marketing year. The processing tax shall be levied, assessed, and collected upon the first domestic processing of the commodity, whether of domestic production or imported, and shall be paid by the processor. The rate of tax shall conform to the requirements of subsection (b). Such rate shall be determined by the Secretary of Agriculture as of the date the tax first takes effect, and the rate so determined shall, at such intervals as the Secretary finds necessary to effectuate the declared policy, be adjusted by him to conform to such requirements. The processing tax shall terminate at the end of the marketing year current at the time the Secretary proclaims that all payments authorized under <ref>section 608 of this title</ref> which are in effect are to be discontinued with respect to such commodity. The marketing year for each commodity shall be ascertained and prescribed by regulations of the Secretary of Agriculture: <i>Provided</i>, That upon any article upon which a manufacturers’ sales tax is levied under the authority of the Revenue Act of 1932 and which manufacturers’ sales tax is computed on the basis of weight, such manufacturers’ sales tax shall be computed on the basis of the weight of said finished article less the weight of the processed cotton contained therein on which a processing tax has been paid.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The processing tax shall be at such rate as equals the difference between the current average farm price for the commodity and the fair exchange value of the commodity, plus such percentage of such difference, not to exceed 20 per centum, as the Secretary of Agriculture may determine will result in the collection, in any marketing year with respect to which such rate of tax may be in effect pursuant to the provisions of this chapter, of an amount of tax equal to (A) the amount of credits or refunds which he estimates will be allowed or made during such period pursuant to <ref>section 615(c) of this title</ref> with respect to the commodity and (B) the amount of tax which he estimates would have been collected during such period upon all processings of such commodity, which are exempt from tax by reason of the fact that such processings are done by or for a State, or a political subdivision or an institution thereof, had such processings been subject to tax. If, prior to the time the tax takes effect, or at any time thereafter, the Secretary has reason to believe that the tax at such rate, or at the then existing rate, on the processing of the commodity generally or for any designated use or uses, or on the processing of the commodity in the production of any designated product or products thereof for any designated use or uses, will cause or is causing such reduction in the quantity of the commodity or products thereof domestically consumed as to result in the accumulation of surplus stocks of the commodity or products thereof or in the depression of the farm price of the commodity, then the Secretary shall cause an appropriate investigation to be made, and afford due notice and opportunity for hearing to interested parties. If thereupon the Secretary determines and proclaims that any such result will occur or is occurring, then the processing tax on the processing of the commodity generally or for any designated use or uses, or on the processing of the commodity in the production of any designated product or products thereof for any designated use or uses, shall be at such lower rate or rates as he determines and proclaims will prevent such accumulation of surplus stocks and depression of the farm price of the commodity, and the tax shall remain during its effective period at such lower rate until the Secretary, after due notice and opportunity for hearing to interested parties, determines and proclaims that an increase in the rate of such tax will not cause such accumulation of surplus stocks or depression of the farm price of the commodity. Thereafter the processing tax shall be at the highest rate which the Secretary determines will not cause such accumulation of surplus stocks or depression of the farm price of the commodity, but it shall not be higher than the rate provided in the first sentence of this paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In the case of wheat, cotton, field corn, hogs, peanuts, paper, and jute, and (except as provided in paragraph (8) of this subsection) in the case of sugarcane and sugar beets, the tax on the first domestic processing of the commodity generally or for any particular use, or in the production of any designated product for any designated use, shall be levied, assessed, collected, and paid at the rate prescribed by the regulations of the Secretary of Agriculture in effect on <date date="1935-08-24">August 24, 1935</date>, during the period from such date to <date date="1937-12-31">December 31, 1937</date>, both dates inclusive.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> For the period from <date date="1935-04-01">April 1, 1935</date>, to <date date="1936-07-31">July 31, 1936</date>, both inclusive, the processing tax with respect to rice shall be levied, assessed, collected, and paid at the rate of 1 cent per pound of rough rice.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> For the period from <date date="1935-09-01">September 1, 1935</date>, to <date date="1937-12-31">December 31, 1937</date>, both inclusive, the processing tax with respect to rye shall be levied, assessed, collected, and paid at the rate of 30 cents per bushel of fifty-six pounds. In the case of rye, the first marketing year shall be considered to be the period commencing <date date="1935-09-01">September 1, 1935</date>, and ending <date date="1936-06-30">June 30, 1936</date>. Subsequent marketing years shall commence on July 1 and end on June 30 of the succeeding year. The provisions of <ref>section 616 of this title</ref> shall not apply in the case of rye.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> If at any time prior to <date date="1937-12-31">December 31, 1937</date>, a tax with respect to barley becomes effective pursuant to proclamation as provided in subsection (a) of this section, such tax shall be levied, assessed, collected, and paid during the period from the date upon which such tax becomes effective to <date date="1937-12-31">December 31, 1937</date>, both inclusive, at the rate of 25 cents per bushel of forty-eight pounds. The provisions of <ref>section 616 of this title</ref> shall not apply in the case of barley.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Any rate of tax which is prescribed in paragraphs (2) to (4), or (5) of this subsection or which is established pursuant to this paragraph on the processing of any commodity generally or for any designated use or uses, or on the processing of the commodity in the production of any designated product or products thereof for any designated use or uses, shall be decreased (including a decrease to zero) in accordance with the formulae, standards, and requirements of paragraph (1) of this subsection, in order to prevent such reduction in the quantity of such commodity or the products thereof domestically consumed as will result in the accumulation of surplus stocks of such commodity or the products thereof or in the depression of the farm price of the commodity, and shall thereafter be increased in accordance with the provisions of paragraph (1) of this subsection but subject to the provisions of subdivision (B) of this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> If the average farm price of any commodity, the rate of tax on the processing of which is prescribed in paragraphs (2) to (4), or (5) of this subsection or is established pursuant to this paragraph, during any period of twelve successive months ending after <date date="1935-07-01">July 1, 1935</date>, consisting of the first ten months of any marketing year and the last two months of the preceding marketing year—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is equal to, or exceeds by 10 per centum or less, the fair exchange value thereof <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002110">1</ref> the rate of such tax shall (subject to the provisions of subdivision (A) of this paragraph) be adjusted, at the beginning of the next succeeding marketing year, to such rate as equals 20 per centum of the fair exchange value thereof.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> exceeds by more than 10 per centum, but not more than 20 per centum, the fair exchange value thereof, the rate of such tax shall (subject to the provisions of subdivision (A) of this paragraph) be adjusted, at the beginning of the next succeeding marketing year, to such rate as equals 15 per centum of the fair exchange value thereof.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> exceeds by more than 20 per centum the fair exchange value thereof, the rate of such tax shall (subject to the provisions of subdivision (A) of this paragraph) be adjusted, at the beginning of the next succeeding marketing year, to such rate as equals 10 per centum of the fair exchange value thereof.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Any rate of tax which has been adjusted pursuant to this paragraph shall remain at such adjusted rate unless further adjusted or terminated pursuant to this paragraph, until <date date="1937-12-31">December 31, 1937</date>, or until <date date="1936-07-31">July 31, 1936</date>, in the case of rice.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> In accordance with the formulae, standards, and requirements prescribed in this chapter, any rate of tax prescribed in paragraphs (2) to (4) or (5) of this subsection or which is established pursuant to this paragraph shall be increased.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Any tax, the rate of which is prescribed in paragraphs (2) to (4), or (5) of this subsection or which is established pursuant to this paragraph, shall terminate pursuant to proclamation as provided in subsection (a) or pursuant to <ref>section 613 of this title</ref>. Any such tax with respect to any basic commodity which terminates pursuant to proclamation as provided in subsection (a) shall again become effective at the rate prescribed in paragraphs (2) to (4), or (5) of this subsection, subject however to the provisions of subdivisions (A) and (B) of this paragraph, from the beginning of the marketing year for such commodity next following the date of a new proclamation by the Secretary as provided in subsection (a), if such marketing year begins prior to <date date="1937-12-31">December 31, 1937</date>, or prior to <date date="1936-07-31">July 31, 1936</date>, in the case of rice, and shall remain at such rate until altered or terminated pursuant to this section or terminated pursuant to <ref>section 613 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> After <date date="1937-12-31">December 31, 1937</date> (in the case of the commodities specified in paragraphs (2), (4), and (5) of this subsection), and after <date date="1936-07-31">July 31, 1936</date> (in the case of rice), rates of tax shall be determined by the Secretary of Agriculture in accordance with the formulae, standards, and requirements prescribed in this chapter but not in this paragraph, and shall, subject to such formulae, standards, and requirements, thereafter be effective.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> If the applicability to any person or circumstances of any tax, the rate of which is fixed in pursuance of this paragraph, is finally held invalid by reason of any provision of the Constitution, or is finally held invalid by reason of the Secretary of Agriculture’s exercise or failure to exercise any power conferred on him under this chapter, there shall be levied, assessed, collected, and paid (in lieu of all rates of tax fixed in pursuance of this paragraph with respect to all tax liabilities incurred under this chapter on or after the effective date of each of the rates of tax fixed in pursuance of this paragraph), rates of tax fixed under paragraphs (2) to (4), or (5) of this subsection, and such rates shall be in effect (unless the particular tax is terminated pursuant to proclamation, as provided in subsection (a) or pursuant to <ref>section 613 of this title</ref>) until altered by Act of Congress; except that, for any period prior to the effective date of such holding of invalidity, the amount of tax which represents the difference between the tax at the rate fixed in pursuance of this paragraph (6) and the tax at the rate fixed under paragraphs (2) to (4), and (5) shall not be levied, assessed, collected or paid.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> In the case of rice, the weight to which the rate of tax shall be applied shall be the weight of rough rice when delivered to a processor, except that, where the producer processes his own rice, the weight to which the rate of tax shall be applied shall be the weight of rough rice when delivered to the place of processing.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> In the case of sugar beets or sugarcane the rate of tax shall be applied to the direct-consumption sugar, resulting from the first domestic processing, translated into terms of pounds of raw value according to regulations to be issued by the Secretary of Agriculture, and in the event that the Secretary increases or decreases the rate of tax fixed by paragraph (2) of this subsection, pursuant to the provisions of paragraph (6) of this subsection, then the rate of tax to be so applied shall be the higher of the two following quotients: The difference between the current average farm price and the fair exchange value (A) of a ton of sugar beets and (B) of a ton of sugarcane, divided in the case of each commodity by the average extraction therefrom of sugar in terms of pounds of raw value (which average extraction shall be determined from available statistics of the Department of Agriculture); the rate of tax fixed by paragraph (2) of this subsection or adjusted pursuant to the provisions of paragraph (6) of this subsection shall in no event exceed the amount of the reduction by the President on a pound of sugar raw value of the rate of duty in effect on <date date="1934-01-01">January 1, 1934</date>, under paragraph 501 of section 1001 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002111">2</ref> of title 19, as adjusted to the treaty of commercial reciprocity concluded between the United States and the Republic of Cuba on <date date="1902-12-11">December 11, 1902</date>, and/or the provisions of sections 124 and 125 of title 19.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> In computing the current average farm price in the case of wheat, premiums paid producers for protein content shall not be taken into account.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> For the purposes of this chapter, the fair exchange value of a commodity shall be the price therefor that will give the commodity the same purchasing power, with respect to articles farmers buy, as such commodity had during the base period specified in <ref>section 602 of this title</ref>; and, in the case of all commodities where the base period is the prewar period, August 1909 to July 1914, will also reflect interest payments per acre on farm indebtedness secured by real estate and tax payments per acre on farm real estate, as contrasted with such interest payments and tax payments during said base period; and the current average farm price and the fair exchange value shall be ascertained by the Secretary of Agriculture from available statistics of the Department of Agriculture. The rate of tax upon the processing of any commodity in effect on <date date="1935-08-24">August 24, 1935</date>, shall not be affected by the adoption of this amendment and shall not be required to be adjusted or altered, unless the Secretary of Agriculture finds that it is necessary to adjust or alter any such rate pursuant to subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> As used in this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In case of wheat, rye, barley and corn, the term “processing” means the milling or other processing (except cleaning and drying) of wheat, rye, barley or corn for market, including custom milling for toll as well as commercial milling, but shall not include the grinding or cracking thereof not in the form of flour for feed purposes only.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In case of cotton, the term “processing” means the spinning, manufacturing, or other processing (except ginning) of cotton; and the term “cotton” shall not include cotton linters.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> In case of tobacco, the term “processing” means the manufacturing or other processing (except drying or converting into insecticides and fertilizers) of tobacco.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Repealed. <ref>June 26, 1934, ch. 759, § 2(a)</ref>, <ref>48 Stat. 1242</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Repealed. <ref>Aug. 24, 1935, ch. 641, § 14(b)</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 767</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> In the case of sugar beets and sugarcane—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The term “first domestic processing” means each domestic processing, including each processing of successive domestic processings, of sugar beets, sugarcane, or raw sugar, which directly results in direct-consumption sugar.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The term “sugar” means sugar in any form whatsoever, derived from sugar beets or sugarcane, whether raw sugar or direct-consumption sugar, including also edible molasses, sirups, and any mixture containing sugar (except blackstrap molasses and beet molasses).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The term “blackstrap molasses” means the commercially so-designated “byproduct” of the cane-sugar industry, not used for human consumption or for the extraction of sugar.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The term “beet molasses” means the commercially so-designated “byproduct” of the beet-sugar industry, not used for human consumption or for the extraction of sugar.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The term “raw sugar” means any sugar, as defined above, manufactured or marketed in, or brought into, the United States, in any form whatsoever, for the purpose of being, or which shall be, further refined (or improved in quality, or further prepared for distribution or use).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> The term “direct-consumption sugar” means any sugar, as defined above, manufactured or marketed in, or brought into, the United States in any form whatsoever, for any purpose other than to be further refined (or improved in quality, or further prepared for distribution or use).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> The term “raw value” means a standard unit of sugar testing ninety-six sugar degrees by the polariscope. All taxes shall be imposed and all quotas shall be established in terms of “raw value” and for purposes of quota and tax measurements all sugar shall be translated into terms of “raw value” according to regulations to be issued by the Secretary, except that in the case of direct-consumption sugar produced in continental United States from sugar beets the raw value of such sugar shall be one and seven one-hundredths times the weight thereof.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(7)</num>
<chapeau> In the case of rice—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The term “rough rice” means rice in that condition which is usual and customary when delivered by the producer to a processor.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The term “processing” means the cleaning, shelling, milling (including custom milling for toll as well as commercial milling), grinding, rolling, or other processing (except grinding or cracking by or for the producer thereof for feed for his own livestock, cleaning by or directly for a producer for seed purposes, and drying) of rough rice; and in the case of rough rice with respect to which a tax-payment warrant has been previously issued or applied for by application then pending, the term “processing” means any one of the above mentioned processings or any preparation or handling in connection with the sale or other disposition thereof.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The term “cooperating producer” means any person (including any share-tenant or share-cropper) whom the Secretary of Agriculture finds to be willing to participate in the 1935 production-adjustment program for rice.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The term “processor”, as used in subsection (b–1) of <ref>section 615 of this title</ref>, means any person (including a cooperative association of producers) engaged in the processing of rice on a commercial basis (including custom milling for toll as well as commercial milling).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> In the case of any other commodity, the term “processing” means any manufacturing or other processing involving a change in the form of the commodity or its preparation for distribution or use, as defined by regulations of the Secretary of Agriculture; and in prescribing such regulations the Secretary shall give due weight to the customs of the industry.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> When any processing tax, or increase or decrease therein, takes effect in respect of a commodity the Secretary of Agriculture, in order to prevent pyramiding of the processing tax and profiteering in the sale of the products derived from the commodity, shall make public such information as he deems necessary regarding (1) the relationship between the processing tax and the price paid to producers of the commodity, (2) the effect of the processing tax upon prices to consumers of products of the commodity, (3) the relationship, in previous periods, between prices paid to the producers of the commodity and prices to consumers of the products thereof, and (4) the situation in foreign countries relating to prices paid to producers of the commodity and prices to consumers of the products thereof.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> For the purposes of this chapter, processing shall be held to include manufacturing.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> Nothing contained in this chapter shall be construed to authorize any tax upon the processing of any commodity which processing results in the production of newsprint.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 12, 1933, ch. 25</ref>, title I, § 9, <ref>48 Stat. 35</ref>; <ref>Apr. 7, 1934, ch. 103, § 3(a)</ref>, <ref>48 Stat. 528</ref>; <ref>May 9, 1934, ch. 263</ref>, §§ 2, 3, 5, 6, 9, <ref>48 Stat. 670</ref>, 671, 675, 676; <ref>June 26, 1934, ch. 759, § 2</ref>, <ref>48 Stat. 1242</ref>; <ref>Mar. 18, 1935, ch. 32</ref>, §§ 1–6, <ref>49 Stat. 45</ref>, 46; <ref>Aug. 24, 1935, ch. 641</ref>, §§ 11–15, <ref>49 Stat. 762–767</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–357, title VI, § 611(d)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-22">Oct. 22, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1522</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 610.</num>
<heading> Administration</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment of officers and employees; impounding appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture may appoint such officers and employees, subject to the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5, and such experts, as are necessary to execute the functions vested in him by this chapter: <i>Provided</i>, That the Secretary shall establish the Agricultural Adjustment Administration in the Department of Agriculture for the administration of the functions vested in him by this chapter: And <i>provided further</i>, That the State Administrator appointed to administer this chapter in each State shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. Section 8 of Title II of the Act entitled “An Act to maintain the credit of the United States Government,” approved <date date="1933-03-20">March 20, 1933</date>, to the extent that it provides for the impoundment of appropriations on account of reductions in compensation, shall not operate to require such impoundment under appropriations contained in this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State and local committees or associations of producers; handlers’ share of expenses of authority or agency</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Agriculture is authorized to establish, for the more effective administration of the functions vested in him by this chapter, State and local committees, or associations of producers, and to permit cooperative associations of producers, when in his judgment they are qualified to do so, to act as agents of their members and patrons in connection with the distribution of payments authorized to be made under <ref>section 608 of this title</ref>. The Secretary, in the administration of this chapter, shall accord such recognition and encouragement to producer-owned and producer-controlled cooperative associations as will be in harmony with the policy toward cooperative associations set forth in existing Acts of Congress, and as will tend to promote efficient methods of marketing and distribution.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Each order relating to milk and its products issued by the Secretary under this chapter shall provide that each handler subject thereto shall pay to any authority or agency established under such order such handler’s pro rata share (as approved by the Secretary) of such expenses as the Secretary may find will necessarily be incurred by such authority or agency, during any period specified by him, for the maintenance and functioning of such authority or agency, other than expenses incurred in receiving, handling, holding, or disposing of any quantity of milk or products thereof received, handled, held, or disposed of by such authority or agency for the benefit or account of persons other than handlers subject to such order. The pro rata share of the expenses payable by a cooperative association of producers shall be computed on the basis of the quantity of milk or product thereof covered by such order which is distributed, processed, or shipped by such cooperative association of producers.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Each order relating to any other commodity or product issued by the Secretary under this chapter shall provide that each handler subject thereto shall pay to any authority or agency established under such order such handler’s pro rata share (as approved by the Secretary) of such expenses as the Secretary may find are reasonable and are likely to be incurred by such authority or agency, during any period specified by him, for such purposes as the Secretary may, pursuant to such order, determine to be appropriate, and for the maintenance and functioning of such authority or agency, other than expenses incurred in receiving, handling, holding, or disposing of any quantity of a commodity received, handled, held, or disposed of by such authority or agency for the benefit or account of persons other than handlers subject to such order. The pro rata share of the expenses payable by a cooperative association of producers shall be computed on the basis of the quantity of the agricultural commodity or product thereof covered by such order which is distributed, processed, or shipped by such cooperative association of producers. The payment of assessments for the maintenance and functioning of such authority or agency, as provided for herein, may be required under a marketing agreement or marketing order throughout the period the marketing agreement or order is in effect and irrespective of whether particular provisions thereof are suspended or become inoperative.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Any authority or agency established under an order may maintain in its own name, or in the name of its members, a suit against any handler subject to an order for the collection of such handler’s pro rata share of expenses. The several district courts of the United States are vested with jurisdiction to entertain such suits regardless of the amount in controversy.</content>
</clause>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations; penalty for violation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture is authorized, with the approval of the President, to make such regulations with the force and effect of law as may be necessary to carry out the powers vested in him by this chapter. Any violation of any regulation shall be subject to such penalty, not in excess of $100, as may be provided therein.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations of Secretary of the Treasury</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Treasury is authorized to make such regulations as may be necessary to carry out the powers vested in him by this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review of official acts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The action of any officer, employee, or agent in determining the amount of and in making any payment authorized to be made under <ref>section 608 of this title</ref> shall not be subject to review by any officer of the Government other than the Secretary of Agriculture or Secretary of the Treasury.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Geographical application</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The provisions of this chapter shall be applicable to the United States and its possessions, except the Virgin Islands, American Samoa, the Canal Zone, and the island of Guam; except that, in the case of sugar beets and sugarcane, the President, if he finds it necessary in order to effectuate the declared policy of this chapter, is authorized by proclamation to make the provisions of this chapter applicable to the Virgin Islands, American Samoa, the Canal Zone, and/or the island of Guam.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Officers; dealing or speculating in agricultural products; penalties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No person shall, while acting in any official capacity in the administration of this chapter, speculate, directly or indirectly, in any agricultural commodity or product thereof to which this chapter applies, or in contracts relating thereto, or in the stock or membership interest of any association or corporation engaged in handling, processing, or disposing of any such commodity or product. Any person violating this subsection shall upon conviction thereof be fined not more than $10,000 or imprisoned not more than two years, or both.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adoption of Federal Trade Commission Act; hearings; report of violations to Attorney General</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the efficient administration of the provisions of this chapter, the provisions, including penalties, of sections 48, 49, and 50 of title 15, are made applicable to the jurisdiction, powers, and duties of the Secretary in administering the provisions of this chapter, and to any person subject to the provisions of this chapter, whether or not a corporation. Hearings authorized or required under this chapter shall be conducted by the Secretary of Agriculture or such officer or employee of the Department as he may designate for the purpose. The Secretary may report any violation of any agreement entered into under this chapter, to the Attorney General of the United States, who shall cause appropriate proceedings to enforce such agreement to be commenced and prosecuted in the proper courts of the United States without delay.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cooperation with State authorities; imparting information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture upon the request of the duly constituted authorities of any State is directed, in order to effectuate the declared policy of this chapter and in order to obtain uniformity in the formulation, administration, and enforcement of Federal and State programs relating to the regulation of the handling of agricultural commodities or products thereof, to confer with and hold joint hearings with the duly constituted authorities of any State, and is authorized to cooperate with such authorities; to accept and utilize, with the consent of the State, such State and local officers and employees as may be necessary; to avail himself of the records and facilities of such authorities; to issue orders (subject to the provisions of <ref>section 608c of this title</ref>) complementary to orders or other regulations issued by such authorities; and to make available to such State authorities the records and facilities of the Department of Agriculture: <i>Provided</i>, That information furnished to the Secretary of Agriculture pursuant to <ref>section 608d(1) of this title</ref> shall be made available only to the extent that such information is relevant to transactions within the regulatory jurisdiction of such authorities, and then only upon a written agreement by such authorities that the information so furnished shall be kept confidential by them in a manner similar to that required of Federal officers and employees under the provisions of <ref>section 608d(2) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The term “interstate or foreign commerce” means commerce between any State, Territory, or possession, or the District of Columbia, and any place outside thereof; or between points within the same State, Territory, or possession, or the District of Columbia, but through any place outside thereof; or within any Territory or possession, or the District of Columbia. For the purpose of this chapter (but in nowise limiting the foregoing definition) a marketing transaction in respect to an agricultural commodity or the product thereof shall be considered in interstate or foreign commerce if such commodity or product is part of that current of interstate or foreign commerce usual in the handling of the commodity or product whereby they, or either of them, are sent from one State to end their transit, after purchase, in another, including all cases where purchase or sale is either for shipment to another State or for the processing within the State and the shipment outside the State of the products so processed. Agricultural commodities or products thereof normally in such current of interstate or foreign commerce shall not be considered out of such current through resort being had to any means or device intended to remove transactions in respect thereto from the provisions of said sections. As used herein, the word “State” includes Territory, the District of Columbia, possession of the United States, and foreign nations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 12, 1933, ch. 25</ref>, title I, § 10, <ref>48 Stat. 37</ref>; <ref>June 16, 1933, ch. 98</ref>, title VIII, § 86, <ref>48 Stat. 273</ref>; <ref>May 9, 1934, ch. 263, § 7</ref>, <ref>48 Stat. 675</ref>; <ref>Aug. 24, 1935, ch. 641</ref>, §§ 16–18, <ref>49 Stat. 767</ref>; <ref>Aug. 26, 1935, ch. 685</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 801</ref>; <ref>June 22, 1936, ch. 690, § 601(a)</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 1739</ref>; <ref>June 3, 1937, ch. 296</ref>, §§ 1, 2(g)–(i), <ref>50 Stat. 246</ref>, 248; Proc. No. 2695, eff. <date date="1946-07-04">July 4, 1946</date>, 11 F.R. 7817, <ref>60 Stat. 1352</ref>; <ref>Aug. 1, 1947, ch. 425, § 3</ref>, <ref>61 Stat. 709</ref>; <ref>Oct. 28, 1949, ch. 782</ref>, title XI, § 1106(a), <ref>63 Stat. 972</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 611.</num>
<heading> “Basic agricultural commodity” defined; exclusion of commodities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As used in this chapter, the term “basic agricultural commodity” means wheat, rye, flax, barley, cotton, field corn, grain sorghums, hogs, cattle, rice, potatoes, tobacco, sugar beets and sugarcane, peanuts, and milk and its products, and any regional or market classification, type, or grade thereof; but the Secretary of Agriculture shall exclude from the operation of the provisions of this chapter, during any period, any such commodity or classification, type, or grade thereof if he finds, upon investigation at any time and after due notice and opportunity for hearing to interested parties, that the conditions of production, marketing, and consumption are such that during such period this chapter can not be effectively administered to the end of effectuating the declared policy with respect to such commodity or classification, type, or grade thereof. As used in this chapter, the term “potatoes” means all varieties of potatoes included in the species Solanum tuberosum.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 12, 1933, ch. 25</ref>, title I, § 11, <ref>48 Stat. 38</ref>; <ref>Apr. 7, 1934, ch. 103</ref>, §§ 1, 3(b), 4, 5, <ref>48 Stat. 528</ref>; <ref>May 9, 1934, ch. 263, § 1</ref>, <ref>48 Stat. 670</ref>; <ref>Aug. 24, 1935, ch. 641, § 61</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 782</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 612.</num>
<heading> Appropriation; use of revenues; administrative expenses</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> There is appropriated, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, the sum of $100,000,000 to be available to the Secretary of Agriculture for administrative expenses under this chapter, and for payments authorized to be made under <ref>section 608 of this title</ref>. Such sum shall remain available until expended.<p class="indent0">To enable the Secretary of Agriculture to finance under such terms and conditions as he may prescribe, surplus reductions with respect to the dairy- and beef-cattle industries, and to carry out any of the purposes described in subsections (a) and (b) of this section and to support and balance the markets for the dairy and beef cattle industries, there is authorized to be appropriated, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, the sum of $200,000,000: <i>Provided</i>, That not more than 60 per centum of such amount shall be used for either of such industries.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> In addition to the foregoing, for the purpose of effectuating the declared policy of this chapter, a sum equal to the proceeds derived from all taxes imposed under this chapter is appropriated to be available to the Secretary of Agriculture for (1) the acquisition of any agricultural commodity pledged as security for any loan made by any Federal agency, which loan was conditioned upon the borrower agreeing or having agreed to cooperate with a program of production adjustment or marketing adjustment adopted under the authority of this chapter, and (2) the following purposes under this chapter: Administrative expenses, payments authorized to be made under <ref>section 608 of this title</ref>, and refunds on taxes. The Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Treasury shall jointly estimate from time to time the amounts, in addition to any money available under subsection (a), currently required for such purposes; and the Secretary of the Treasury shall, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, advance to the Secretary of Agriculture the amounts so estimated. The amount of any such advance shall be deducted from such tax proceeds as shall subsequently become available under this subsection.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The administrative expenses provided for under this section shall include, among others, expenditures for personal services and rent in the District of Columbia and elsewhere, for law books and books of reference, for contract stenographic reporting services, and for printing and paper in addition to allotments under the existing law. The Secretary of Agriculture shall transfer to the Treasury Department, and is authorized to transfer to other agencies, out of funds available for administrative expenses under this chapter, such sums as are required to pay administrative expenses incurred and refunds made by such department or agencies in the administration of this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 12, 1933, ch. 25</ref>, title I, § 12, <ref>48 Stat. 38</ref>; <ref>Apr. 7, 1934, ch. 103, § 2</ref>, <ref>48 Stat. 528</ref>; <ref>Aug. 24, 1935, ch. 641</ref>, §§ 3, 19, <ref>49 Stat. 753</ref>, 768; <ref>June 3, 1937, ch. 296</ref>, §§ 1, 2(j), <ref>50 Stat. 246</ref>, 248.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 612a, 612b.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 612c.</num>
<heading> Appropriation to encourage exportation and domestic consumption of agricultural products</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is appropriated for each fiscal year beginning with the fiscal year ending <date date="1936-06-30">June 30, 1936</date> an amount equal to 30 per centum of the gross receipts from duties collected under the customs laws during the period January 1 to December 31, both inclusive, preceding the beginning of each such fiscal year. Such sums shall be maintained in a separate fund and shall be used by the Secretary of Agriculture only to (1) encourage the exportation of agricultural commodities and products thereof by the payment of benefits in connection with the exportation thereof or of indemnities for losses incurred in connection with such exportation or by payments to producers in connection with the production of that part of any agricultural commodity required for domestic consumption; (2) encourage the domestic consumption of such commodities or products by diverting them, by the payment of benefits or indemnities or by other means, from the normal channels of trade and commerce or by increasing their utilization through benefits, indemnities, donations or by other means, among persons in low income groups as determined by the Secretary of Agriculture; and (3) reestablish farmers’ purchasing power by making payments in connection with the normal production of any agricultural commodity for domestic consumption. Determinations by the Secretary as to what constitutes diversion and what constitutes normal channels of trade and commerce and what constitutes normal production for domestic consumption shall be final. The sums appropriated under this section shall be expended for such one or more of the above-specified purposes, and at such times, in such manner, and in such amounts as the Secretary of Agriculture finds will effectuate substantial accomplishment of any one or more of the purposes of this section. Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, the amount that may be devoted, during any fiscal year after <date date="1939-06-30">June 30, 1939</date>, to any one agricultural commodity or the products thereof in such fiscal year, shall not exceed 25 per centum of the funds available under this section for such fiscal year. The sums appropriated under this section shall be devoted principally to perishable nonbasic agricultural commodities (other than those receiving price support under <ref>section 1446 of this title</ref>) and their products. The sums appropriated under this section shall, notwithstanding the provisions of any other law, continue to remain available for the purposes of this section until expended; but any excess of the amount remaining unexpended at the end of any fiscal year over $500,000,000 shall, in the same manner as though it had been appropriated for the service of such fiscal year, be subject to the provisions of section 3690 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002112">1</ref> of the Revised Statutes, and section 5 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002112">1</ref> of the Act entitled “An Act making appropriations for the legislative, executive, and judicial expenses of the Government for the year ending June thirtieth, eighteen hundred and seventy-five, and for other purposes”. A public or private nonprofit organization that receives agricultural commodities or the products thereof under clause (2) of the second sentence may transfer such commodities or products to another public or private nonprofit organization that agrees to use such commodities or products to provide, without cost or waste, nutrition assistance to individuals in low-income groups.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 24, 1935, ch. 641, § 32</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 774</ref>; <ref>Feb. 29, 1936, ch. 104, § 2</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 1151</ref>; <ref>Feb. 16, 1938, ch. 30</ref>, title II, § 203, <ref>52 Stat. 38</ref>; <ref>June 30, 1939, ch. 253</ref>, title I, <ref>53 Stat. 975</ref>; <ref>July 3, 1948, ch. 827</ref>, title III, § 301, <ref>62 Stat. 1257</ref>; <ref>Oct. 31, 1949, ch. 792</ref>, title IV, § 411, <ref>63 Stat. 1057</ref>; <ref>Jan. 30, 1954, ch. 2, § 5(b)</ref>, <ref>68 Stat. 7</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–198, title XV, § 1561</ref>, <date date="1985-12-23">Dec. 23, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 1589</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–171, title X, § 10602</ref>, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 511</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 612c–1.</num>
<heading> Authorization for appropriations to increase domestic consumption of surplus farm commodities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On and after <date date="1963-12-30">December 30, 1963</date>, such sums (not in excess of $25,000,000 in any one year) as may be approved by the Congress shall be available for the purpose of increasing domestic consumption of any farm commodity or farm commodities determined by the Secretary of Agriculture to be in surplus supply, such authorization not to restrict authority in existing law, of which amount $11,000,000 shall remain available until expended for construction and equipping of research facilities determined to be needed as a result of a special survey.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 88–250, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1963-12-30">Dec. 30, 1963</date>, <ref>77 Stat. 826</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 612c–2.</num>
<heading> Technical support to exporters and importers of United States agricultural products; scope of support provided by Department of Agriculture</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Department of Agriculture shall provide technical support to exporters and importers of United States agricultural products when so requested. Such support shall include, but not be limited to, a review of the feasibility of the export proposal, adequacy of sources of supply, compliance with trade regulations of the United States and the importing country and such other information or guidance as may be needed to expand and expedite United States agricultural exports by private trading interests.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–524, title VIII, § 811</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 93–86, § 1(27)(B)</ref>, <date date="1973-08-10">Aug. 10, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 238</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 612c–3.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XV, § 1578</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3702</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 612c–4.</num>
<heading> Purchase of specialty crops</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General purchase authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Of the funds made available under <ref>section 612c of this title</ref>, for fiscal year 2002 and each subsequent fiscal year, the Secretary of Agriculture shall use not less than $200,000,000 each fiscal year to purchase fruits, vegetables, and other specialty food crops.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purchase of fresh fruits and vegetables for distribution to schools and service institutions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture shall purchase fresh fruits and vegetables for distribution to schools and service institutions in accordance with <ref>section 1755(a) of title 42</ref> using, of the amount specified in subsection (a), not less than $50,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2008 through 2023.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this section, the terms “fruits”, “vegetables”, and “other specialty food crops” shall have the meaning given the terms by the Secretary of Agriculture.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–171, title X, § 10603</ref>, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 511</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title IV, § 4404(c)</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1138</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title IV, § 4404(c), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1899; <ref>Pub. L. 113–79, title IV, § 4201</ref>, <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 821</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title IV, § 4202</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4655</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 612c–5.</num>
<heading> Section 612c funds for purchase of fruits, vegetables, and nuts to support domestic nutrition assistance programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Funding for additional purchases of fruits, vegetables, and nuts</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In addition to the purchases of fruits, vegetables, and nuts required by <ref>section 612c–4 of this title</ref>, the Secretary of Agriculture shall purchase fruits, vegetables, and nuts for the purpose of providing nutritious foods for use in domestic nutrition assistance programs, using, of the funds made available under <ref>section 612c of this title</ref>, the following amounts:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> $190,000,000 for fiscal year 2008.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> $193,000,000 for fiscal year 2009.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> $199,000,000 for fiscal year 2010.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> $203,000,000 for fiscal year 2011.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> $206,000,000 for fiscal year 2012 and each fiscal year thereafter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Form of purchases</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Fruits, vegetables, and nuts may be purchased under this section in the form of frozen, canned, dried, or fresh fruits, vegetables, and nuts.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title IV, § 4404</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1137</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title IV, § 4404, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1899.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 612c–6.</num>
<heading> Domestic food assistance programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition of section 32</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this section, the term “section 32” means <ref>section 32 of the Act of August 24, 1935</ref> (<ref>7 U.S.C. 612c</ref>).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer to Food and Nutrition Service</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Amounts made available for a fiscal year to carry out section 32 in excess of the maximum amount calculated under paragraph (2) shall be transferred to the Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Food and Nutrition Service, to be used to carry out the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 1751</ref> et seq.) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002113">1</ref> except section 21 [<ref>42 U.S.C. 1769b–1</ref>], and the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 1771</ref> et seq.), except sections 17 and 21 [<ref>42 U.S.C. 1786</ref>, 1790]”.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Maximum amount</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The maximum amount calculated under this paragraph for a fiscal year is the sum of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> in the case of fiscal year 2009, $1,173,000,000;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in the case of fiscal year 2010, $1,199,000,000;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> in the case of fiscal year 2011, $1,215,000,000;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> in the case of fiscal year 2012, $1,231,000,000;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> in the case of fiscal year 2013, $1,248,000,000;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> in the case of fiscal year 2014, $1,266,000,000;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> in the case of fiscal year 2015, $1,284,000,000;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> in the case of fiscal year 2016, $1,303,000,000;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ix)</num>
<content> in the case of fiscal year 2017, $1,322,000,000; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(x)</num>
<content> for fiscal year 2018 and each fiscal year thereafter, the amount made available for the preceding fiscal year, as adjusted to reflect changes for the 12-month period ending on the preceding November 30 in the Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers published by the Bureau of Labor Statistics of the Department of Labor; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any transfers for the fiscal year from section 32 to the Department of Commerce under the Fish and Wildlife Act of 1956 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 742a</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fresh fruit and vegetable program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Of amounts made available to carry out section 32 under subsection (b)(2)(A), the Secretary shall transfer for use to carry out the fresh fruit and vegetable program under section 19 of the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act [<ref>42 U.S.C. 1769a</ref>] the amounts specified in subsection (i) of that section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Whole grain products</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Of amounts made available to carry out section 32 under subsection (b)(2)(A), the Secretary shall use to carry out <ref>section 1755a of title 42</ref> $4,000,000 for fiscal year 2009.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Maintenance of funding</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The funding provided under subsections (c) and (d) shall supplement (and not supplant) other Federal funding (including section 32 funding) for programs carried out under—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 1751</ref> et seq.), except for section 19 of that Act [<ref>42 U.S.C. 1769a</ref>];</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Emergency Food Assistance Act of 1983 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 7501</ref> et seq.); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> section 2036 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002114">2</ref> of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title XIV, § 14222</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1483</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title XIV, § 14222, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2245; <ref>Pub. L. 112–55, div. A, title IV</ref>, <date date="2011-11-18">Nov. 18, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 574</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 613.</num>
<heading> Termination date; investigations and reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This chapter shall cease to be in effect whenever the President finds and proclaims that the national economic emergency in relation to agriculture has been ended; and pending such time the President shall by proclamation terminate with respect to any basic agricultural commodity such provisions of this chapter as he finds are not requisite to carrying out the declared policy with respect to such commodity. In the case of sugar beets and sugarcane, the taxes provided by this chapter shall cease to be in effect, and the powers vested in the President or in the Secretary of Agriculture shall terminate on <date date="1937-12-31">December 31, 1937</date> unless this chapter ceases to be in effect at an earlier date, as hereinabove provided. The Secretary of Agriculture shall make such investigations and reports thereon to the President as may be necessary to aid him in executing this section.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 12, 1933, ch. 25</ref>, title I, § 13, <ref>48 Stat. 39</ref>; <ref>May 9, 1934, ch. 263, § 15</ref>, <ref>48 Stat. 677</ref>; <ref>Aug. 24, 1935, ch. 641, § 20(a)</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 768</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 613a.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Sept. 1, 1937, ch. 898</ref>, title V, § 510, <ref>50 Stat. 916</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 614.</num>
<heading> Separability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If any provision of this chapter is declared unconstitutional, or the applicability thereof to any person, circumstance, or commodity is held invalid the validity of the remainder of this chapter and the applicability thereof to other persons, circumstances, or commodities shall not be affected thereby.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 12, 1933, ch. 25</ref>, title I, § 14, <ref>48 Stat. 39</ref>; <ref>June 3, 1937, ch. 296, § 1</ref>, <ref>50 Stat. 246</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 615.</num>
<heading> Refunds of tax; exemptions from tax; compensating tax; compensating tax on foreign goods; covering into Treasury</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> If at any time the Secretary of Agriculture finds, upon investigation and after due notice and opportunity for hearing to interested parties, that any class of products of any commodity is of such low value, considering the quantity of the commodity used for their manufacture, that the imposition of the processing tax would prevent in whole or in large part the use of the commodity in the manufacture of such products and thereby substantially reduce consumption and increase the surplus of the commodity, then the Secretary of Agriculture shall so certify to the Secretary of the Treasury, specifying whether such results will in his judgment most effectively be prevented by a suspension of the imposition of the processing tax or a refund of the tax paid, with respect to such amount of the commodity or any product thereof as is used in the manufacture of such products, and thereafter, as shall be specified in such certification, (1) the imposition of the processing tax shall be suspended with respect to such amount of the commodity as is used in the manufacture of such products, and thereafter, as shall be specified in such certification, (2) the imposition of the processing tax shall be suspended with respect to such amount of the commodity as is used in the manufacture of such products until such time as the Secretary of Agriculture, after further investigation and due notice and opportunity for hearing to interested parties, revokes his certification to the Secretary of the Treasury, or (3) the Secretary of the Treasury shall refund (in accordance with the provisions of, to such persons and in such manner as shall be specified in, such certification) the amount of any tax paid (prior to the date of any revocation by the Secretary of Agriculture of his certification to the Secretary of the Treasury, upon further investigation and after due notice and opportunity for hearing to interested parties) under this chapter with respect to such amount of the commodity or any product thereof as is used after the date of such certification in the manufacture of such products, or shall credit against any tax due and payable under this chapter the amount of tax which would be refundable. During the period in which any certificate under this section is effective, the provisions of subsection (e) of this section shall be suspended with respect to all imported articles of the kind described in such certificate; and notwithstanding the provisions of <ref>section 623 of this title</ref>, any compensating taxes, which have heretofore, during the period in which any certificate under this section has been effective, become due and payable upon imported articles of the kind described in such certificate, shall be refunded by the Secretary of the Treasury if the same have been paid, or, if the same have not been paid the amount thereof shall be abated. Notwithstanding the provisions of <ref>section 623 of this title</ref>, the Secretary of the Treasury shall refund or credit any processing tax paid on or before <date date="1934-06-12">June 12, 1934</date>, with respect to such amount of cotton as was used in the manufacture of large cotton bags (as defined in the Certificate of the Secretary of Agriculture, dated <date date="1934-06-12">June 12, 1934</date>) between June 13, and <date date="1934-07-07">July 7, 1934</date>, both inclusive.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> No tax shall be required to be paid on the processing of any commodity by or for the producer thereof for consumption by his own family, employees, or household; and the Secretary of Agriculture is authorized, by regulations, to exempt from the payment of the processing tax the processing of commodities by or for the producer thereof for sale by him where, in the judgment of the Secretary, the imposition of a processing tax with respect thereto is unnecessary to effectuate the declared policy.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b–1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Agriculture is authorized and directed to issue tax-payment warrants, with respect to rough rice produced in 1933 and 1934 (provided the processing of such rice is not exempt from the tax, and provided no tax payment warrant has been previously issued with respect thereto or previously applied for by application then pending, sufficient to cover the tax with respect to the processing thereof at the rate in effect at the time of such issuance, to any processor with respect to any such rice which he had in his possession on <date date="1935-03-31">March 31, 1935</date>, and to, or at the direction of any other person with respect to any such rice which, on or after <date date="1935-04-01">April 1, 1935</date>, he delivers for processing or sells to a processor: <i>Provided</i>, That in case any such processor or other person is the producer of such rice (or has received such rice by gift, bequest, or descent from the producer thereof) that such processor or other person is, if eligible, a cooperating producer: <i>And provided further</i>, That in case such processor or other person is not the producer thereof (nor a person who has received such rice by gift, bequest, or descent from the producer thereof), (a) that, if the title to such rice was transferred from the producer thereof, whether by operation of law or otherwise, prior to <date date="1935-04-01">April 1, 1935</date>, such producer received the price prescribed in any marketing agreement, license, regulation, or administrative ruling, pursuant to this chapter, applicable to the sale of such rice by the producer, and (b) that, if the title to such rice was transferred from the producer thereof, whether by operation of law or otherwise, on or after <date date="1935-04-01">April 1, 1935</date>, such producer received at least the full market price therefor plus an amount equal to 99 per centum of the face value of tax-payment warrants sufficient to cover the tax on the processing of such rice at rate in effect at the time title was so transferred, and was, if eligible, a cooperating producer.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b–2)</num>
<chapeau> The warrants authorized and directed to be issued by subsection (b–1) of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall be issued by the Secretary of Agriculture or his duly authorized agent in such manner, at such time or times, at such place or places, in such form, and subject to such terms and conditions with reference to the transfer thereof or the voiding of warrants fraudulently obtained and/or erroneously issued, as the Secretary of Agriculture may prescribe, and the Secretary of Agriculture is authorized to discontinue the further issuance of tax-payment warrants at any time or times and in any region or regions when he shall determine that the rice in any such region or regions can no longer be identified adequately as rice grown in 1933 or 1934; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall be accepted by the Collector of Internal Revenue and the Secretary of the Treasury at the face value thereof in payment of any processing tax on rice.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b–3)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Any person who deals or traffics in, or purchases any such tax-payment warrant or the right of any person thereto at less than 99 per centum of its face value shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and upon conviction thereof shall be fined not more than $1,000 or imprisoned for not more than one year or both.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any person who, with intent to defraud, secures or attempts to secure, or aids or assists in or procures, counsels, or advises, the securing or attempting to secure any tax-payment warrant with respect to rice as to which any tax-payment warrant has been theretofore issued shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and upon conviction thereof shall be fined not more than $1,000 or imprisoned for not more than one year, or both.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Any person who with intent to defraud forges, makes, alters, or counterfeits any tax-payment warrant or any stamp, tag, or other means of identification provided for by this chapter or any regulation issued pursuant thereto, or makes any false entry upon such warrant or any false statement in any application for the issuance of such warrant, or who uses, sells, lends, or has in his possession any such altered, forged, or counterfeited warrant or stamp, tag, or other means of identification, or who makes, uses, sells, or has in his possession any material in imitation of the material used in the manufacture of such warrants or stamps, tags, or other means of identification, shall, upon conviction thereof, be punished by a fine not exceeding $5,000 or by imprisonment not exceeding five years, or both.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> All producers, warehousemen, processors, and common carriers, having information with respect to rice produced in the years 1933 or 1934, may be required to furnish to the Secretary of Agriculture such information as he shall, by order, prescribe as necessary to safeguard the issuance, transfer, and/or use of tax-payment warrants.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Agriculture may make regulations protecting the interests of producers (including share-tenants and share-croppers) and others, in the issuance, holding, use, and/or transfer of such tax-payment warrants.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Any person, including any State or Federal organization or institution, delivering any product to any organization for charitable distribution or use, including any State or Federal welfare organization, for its own use, whether the product is delivered as merchandise, or as a container for merchandise, or otherwise, shall, if such product or the commodity from which processed is under this chapter subject to tax, be entitled to a refund of the amount of any tax due and paid under this chapter with respect to such product so delivered, or to a credit against any tax due and payable under this chapter of the amount of tax which would be refundable under this section with respect to such product so delivered: <i>Provided, however</i>, That no tax shall be refunded or credited under this section, unless the person claiming the refund or credit establishes, in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Commissioner of Internal Revenue, with the approval of the Secretary of the Treasury (1) that he has not included the tax in the price of the product so delivered or collected the amount of the tax from the said organization, or (2) that he has repaid, or has agreed in writing to repay, the amount of the tax to the said organization. The word “State” as used in this section shall include a State and any political subdivision thereof.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Agriculture shall ascertain from time to time whether the payment of the processing tax upon any basic agricultural commodity is causing or will cause to the processors or producers thereof disadvantages in competition from competing commodities by reason of excessive shifts in consumption between such commodities or products thereof. If the Secretary of Agriculture finds, after investigation and due notice and opportunity for hearing to interested parties, that such disadvantages in competition exist, or will exist, he shall proclaim such finding. The Secretary shall specify in this proclamation the competing commodity and the compensating rate of tax on the processing thereof necessary to prevent such disadvantages in competition. Thereafter there shall be levied, assessed, and collected upon the first domestic processing of such competing commodity a tax, to be paid by the processor, at the rate specified, until such rate is altered pursuant to a further finding under this section, or the tax or rate thereof on the basic agricultural commodity is altered or terminated. In no case shall the tax imposed upon such competing commodity exceed that imposed per equivalent unit, as determined by the Secretary, upon the basic agricultural commodity.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> During any period for which a processing tax is in effect with respect to any commodity there shall be levied, assessed, collected, and paid upon any article processed or manufactured wholly or partly from such commodity and imported into the United States or any possession thereof to which this chapter applies, from any foreign country or from any possession of the United States to which this chapter does not apply, whether imported as merchandise, or as a container of merchandise, or otherwise, a compensating tax equal to the amount of the processing tax in effect with respect to domestic processing of such commodity into such an article at the time of importation: <i>Provided</i>, (1) That in the event any of the provisions of this chapter have been or are hereafter made applicable to any possession of the United States in the case of any particular commodity or commodities, but not generally, this chapter, for the purposes of this subsection, shall be deemed applicable to such possession with respect to such commodity or commodities but shall not be deemed applicable to such possession with respect to other commodities; and (2) That all taxes collected under this subsection upon articles coming from the possessions of the United States to which this chapter does not apply shall not be covered into the general fund of the Treasury of the United States but shall be held as a separate fund and paid into the Treasury of the said possessions, respectively, to be used and expended by the governments thereof for the benefit of agriculture. Such tax shall be paid prior to the release of the article from customs custody or control.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> The President, in his discretion, is authorized by proclamation to decree that all or part of the taxes collected from the processing of sugar beets or sugarcane in Puerto Rico, the Territory of Hawaii, the Virgin Islands, American Samoa, the Canal Zone, and/or the island of Guam (if the provisions of this chapter are made applicable thereto), and/or upon the processing in continental United States of sugar produced in, or coming from, said areas, shall not be covered into the general fund of the Treasury of the United States but shall be held as a separate fund, in the name of the respective area to which related, to be used and expended for the benefit of agriculture and/or paid as rental or benefit payments in connection with the reduction in the acreage, or reduction in the production for market, or both, of sugar beets and/or sugarcane, and/or used and expended for expansion of markets and for removal of surplus agricultural products in such areas, respectively, as the Secretary of Agriculture, with the approval of the President, shall direct.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 12, 1933, ch. 25</ref>, title I, § 15, <ref>48 Stat. 39</ref>; <ref>May 9, 1934, ch. 263</ref>, §§ 8, 11, <ref>48 Stat. 675</ref>, 676; <ref>June 16, 1934, ch. 551</ref>, <ref>48 Stat. 973</ref>; <ref>June 26, 1934, ch. 759, § 1</ref>, <ref>48 Stat. 1241</ref>; <ref>Mar. 18, 1935, ch. 32</ref>, §§ 8, 9, <ref>49 Stat. 47</ref>, 48; <ref>Aug. 24, 1935, ch. 641</ref>, §§ 21–24, <ref>49 Stat. 768</ref>; <ref>June 22, 1936, ch. 690, § 601(a)</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 1739</ref>; Proc. No. 2695, eff. <date date="1946-07-04">July 4, 1946</date>, 11 F.R. 7871, <ref>60 Stat. 1352</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 616.</num>
<heading> Stock on hand when tax takes effect or terminates</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Upon the sale or other disposition of any article processed wholly or in chief value from any commodity with respect to which a processing tax is to be levied, that on the date the tax first takes effect or wholly terminates with respect to the commodity, is held for sale or other disposition (including articles in transit) by any person, there shall be made a tax adjustment as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Whenever the processing tax first takes effect, there shall be levied, assessed, and collected a tax to be paid by such person equivalent to the amount of the processing tax which would be payable with respect to the commodity from which processed if the processing had occurred on such date. Such tax upon articles imported prior to, but in customs custody or control on, the effective date, shall be paid prior to release therefrom. In the case of sugar, the tax on floor stocks, except the retail stocks of persons engaged in retail trade, shall be paid for the month in which the stocks are sold, or used in the manufacture of other articles, under rules and regulations prescribed by the Commissioner of Internal Revenue with the approval of the Secretary of the Treasury.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Whenever the processing tax is wholly terminated, (A) there shall be refunded or credited in the case of a person holding such stocks with respect to which a tax under this chapter has been paid, or (B) there shall be credited or abated in the case of a person holding such stocks with respect to which a tax under this chapter is payable, where such person is the processor liable for the payment of such tax, or (C) there shall be refunded or credited (but not before the tax has been paid) in the case of a person holding such stocks with respect to which a tax under this chapter is payable, where such person is not the processor liable for the payment of such tax, a sum in an amount equivalent to the processing tax which would have been payable with respect to the commodity from which processed if the processing had occurred on such date: <i>Provided</i>, That in the case of any commodity with respect to which there was any increase, effective prior to <date date="1934-06-01">June 1, 1934</date>, in the rate of the processing tax, no such refund, credit, or abatement, shall be in an amount which exceeds the equivalent of the initial rate of the processing tax in effect with respect to such commodity.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The tax imposed by subsection (a) of this section shall not apply to the retail stocks of persons engaged in retail trade, held at the date the processing tax first takes effect; but such retail stocks shall not be deemed to include stocks held in a warehouse on such date, or such portion of other stocks held on such date as are not sold or otherwise disposed of within thirty days thereafter. Except as to flour and prepared flour, and cereal preparations made chiefly from wheat, as classified in Wheat Regulations, Series 1, Supplement 1, and as to any article processed wholly or in chief value from cotton, the tax refund, credit, or abatement provided in subsection (a) of this section shall not apply to the retail stocks of persons engaged in retail trade, nor to any article (except sugar) processed wholly or in chief value from sugar beets, sugarcane, or any product thereof, nor to any article (except flour, prepared flour and cereal preparations made chiefly from wheat, as classified in Wheat Regulations, Series 1, Supplement 1) processed wholly or in chief value from wheat, held on the date the processing tax is wholly terminated.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Any sugar, imported prior to the effective date of a processing tax on sugar beets and sugarcane, with respect to which it is established (under regulations prescribed by the Commissioner of Internal Revenue, with the approval of the Secretary of the Treasury) that there was paid at the time of importation a duty at the rate in effect on <date date="1934-01-01">January 1, 1934</date>, and (2) any sugar held on <date date="1934-04-25">April 25, 1934</date>, by, or to be delivered under a bona fide contract of sale entered into prior to <date date="1934-04-25">April 25, 1934</date>, to, any manufacturer or converter, for use in the production of any article (except sugar) and not for ultimate consumption as sugar, and (3) any article (except sugar) processed wholly or in chief value from sugar beets, sugarcane, or any product thereof, shall be exempt from taxation under subsection (a) of this section, but sugar held in customs custody or control on <date date="1934-04-25">April 25, 1934</date>, shall not be exempt from taxation under subsection (a) of this section, unless the rate of duty paid upon the withdrawal thereof was the rate of duty in effect on <date date="1934-01-01">January 1, 1934</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Agriculture is authorized to purchase, out of such proceeds of taxes as are available therefor, during the period this chapter is in effect with respect to sugar beets and sugarcane, not in excess of three hundred thousand tons of sugar raw value from the surplus stocks of direct-consumption sugar produced in the United States beet-sugar area, at a price not in excess of the market price for direct consumption sugar on the date of purchase, and to dispose of such sugar by sale or otherwise, including distribution to any organization for the relief of the unemployed, under such conditions and at such times as will tend to effectuate the declared policy of <ref>section 608a of this title</ref>. The sugar so purchased shall not be included in the quota for the United States beet-sugar area. All proceeds received by the Secretary of Agriculture, in the exercise of the powers granted, are appropriated to be available to the Secretary of Agriculture for the purposes described in subsections (a) and (b) of <ref>section 612 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<chapeau> Upon the sale or other disposition of any article processed wholly or in chief value from any commodity with respect to which the existing rate of the processing tax is to be increased, or decreased, that on the date such increase, or decrease, first takes effect with respect to the commodity, is held for sale or other disposition (including articles in transit) by any person, and upon the production of any article from a commodity in process on the date on which the rate of the processing tax is to be increased or decreased, there shall be made a tax adjustment as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Whenever, on or after <date date="1934-06-01">June 1, 1934</date>, the rate of the processing tax on the processing of the commodity generally or for any designated use or uses, or as to any designated product or products thereof for any designated use or uses, or as to any class of products, is decreased, there shall be credited or refunded to such person an amount equivalent to the difference between the rate of the processing tax payable or paid at the time immediately preceding the decrease in rate and the rate of the processing tax which would have been payable with respect to the commodity from which processed, if the processing had occurred on such date: <i>Provided, however</i>, That no such credit or refund shall be made in the case of hogs unless the rate of the processing tax immediately preceding said decrease is equal to, or less than, the rate of the processing tax in effect on the date on which any floor stocks tax was paid prior to the adoption of this subsection. In the case of wheat the provisions of this paragraph and of paragraph (2) of this subsection shall apply to flour, prepared flour and cereal preparations made chiefly from wheat, as classified in Wheat Regulations, Series 1, Supplement 1 only; in the case of sugarcane and sugar beets the provisions of this paragraph and of paragraph (2) of this subsection shall apply to sugar only.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Whenever the rate of the processing tax on the processing of the commodity generally, or for any designated use or uses, or as to any designated product or products thereof for any designated use or uses, or as to any class of products, is increased, there shall be levied, assessed and collected a tax to be paid by such person equivalent to the difference between the rate of the processing tax payable or paid at the time immediately preceding the increase in rate and the rate of the processing tax which would be payable with respect to the commodity from which processed, if the processing had occurred on such date.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Whenever the processing tax is suspended or is to be refunded pursuant to a certification of the Secretary of Agriculture to the Secretary of the Treasury, under <ref>section 615(a) of this title</ref>, the provisions of paragraph (1) of this subsection shall become applicable.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Whenever the Secretary of Agriculture revokes any certification to the Secretary of the Treasury under <ref>section 615(a) of this title</ref>, the provisions of paragraph (2) of this subsection shall become applicable.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The provisions of this subsection shall be effective on and after <date date="1934-06-01">June 1, 1934</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> The provisions of this section shall not be applicable with respect to rice.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 12, 1933, ch. 25</ref>, title I, § 16, <ref>48 Stat. 40</ref>; <ref>May 9, 1934, ch. 263</ref>, §§ 10, 17, <ref>48 Stat. 676</ref>, 678; <ref>June 26, 1934, ch. 759, § 1</ref>, <ref>48 Stat. 1241</ref>; <ref>Mar. 18, 1935, ch. 32, § 10</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 48</ref>; <ref>Aug. 24, 1935, ch. 641</ref>, §§ 20(b), 25–27, <ref>49 Stat. 768</ref>, 769; <ref>June 4, 1936, ch. 501</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 1464</ref>; <ref>June 22, 1936, ch. 690, § 601(a)</ref>, (c), (g), <ref>49 Stat. 1739</ref>, 1740.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 617.</num>
<heading> Refund on goods exported; bond to suspend tax on commodity intended for export</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Upon the exportation to any foreign country (and/or to the Virgin Islands, American Samoa, the Canal Zone, and the island of Guam) of any product processed wholly or partly from a commodity with respect to which product or commodity a tax has been paid or is payable under this chapter, the tax due and payable or due and paid shall be credited or refunded. Under regulations prescribed by the Commissioner of Internal Revenue, with the approval of the Secretary of the Treasury, the credit or refund shall be allowed to the consignor named in the bill of lading under which the product is exported or to the shipper or to the person liable for the tax provided the consignor waives any claim thereto in favor of such shipper or person liable for the tax. In the case of rice, a tax due under this chapter which has been paid by a tax-payment warrant shall be deemed for the purposes of this subsection to have been paid; and with respect to any refund authorized under this section, the amount scheduled by the Commissioner of Internal Revenue for refunding shall be paid, any provision of law notwithstanding. In the case of sugar beets and sugarcane, this subsection shall be applicable to exports of products thereof to the Virgin Islands, American Samoa, the Canal Zone, and/or the island of Guam only if this chapter with respect to sugar beets and sugarcane is not made applicable thereto. The term “product” includes any product exported as merchandise, or as a container for merchandise, or otherwise.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Upon the giving of bond satisfactory to the Secretary of the Treasury for the faithful observance of the provisions of this chapter requiring the payment of taxes, any person shall be entitled, without payment of the tax, to process for such exportation any commodity with respect to which a tax is imposed by this chapter, or to hold for such exportation any article processed wholly or partly therefrom.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 12, 1933, ch. 25</ref>, title I, § 17, <ref>48 Stat. 40</ref>; <ref>May 9, 1934, ch. 263</ref>, §§ 12, 13, <ref>48 Stat. 676</ref>; <ref>Mar. 18, 1935, ch. 32, § 11</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 48</ref>; <ref>Aug. 24, 1935, ch. 641, § 28</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 770</ref>; <ref>June 22, 1936, ch. 690, § 601(a)</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 1739</ref>; Proc. No. 2695, eff. <date date="1946-07-04">July 4, 1946</date>, 11 F.R. 7871, <ref>60 Stat. 1352</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 618.</num>
<heading> Existing contracts; imposition of tax on vendee; collection</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> If (1) any processor, jobber, or wholesaler has, prior to the date a tax with respect to any commodity is first imposed under this chapter, made a bona fide contract of sale for delivery on or after such date, of any article processed wholly or in chief value from such commodity, and if (2) such contract does not permit the addition to the amount to be paid thereunder of the whole of such tax, then (unless the contract prohibits such addition) the vendee shall pay so much of the tax as is not permitted to be added to the contract price.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Taxes payable by the vendee shall be paid to the vendor at the time the sale is consummated and shall be collected and paid to the United States by the vendor in the same manner as other taxes under this chapter. In case of failure or refusal by the vendee to pay such taxes to the vendor, the vendor shall report the facts to the Commissioner of Internal Revenue who shall cause collections of such taxes to be made from the vendee.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 12, 1933, ch. 25</ref>, title I, § 18, <ref>48 Stat. 41</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 619.</num>
<heading> Collection of tax; provisions of internal revenue laws applicable; returns</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The taxes provided in this chapter shall be collected by the Bureau of Internal Revenue under the direction of the Secretary of the Treasury. Such taxes shall be paid into the Treasury of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> All provisions of law, including penalties, applicable with respect to the taxes imposed by section 600 of the Revenue Act of 1926, and the provisions of section 626 of the Revenue Act of 1932, shall, insofar as applicable and not inconsistent with the provisions of this chapter, be applicable in respect of taxes imposed by this chapter: <i>Provided</i>, That the Secretary of the Treasury is authorized to permit postponement, for a period not exceeding one hundred and eighty days, of the payment of not exceeding three-fourths of the amount of the taxes covered by any return under this chapter, but postponement of all taxes covered by returns under this chapter for a period not exceeding one hundred and eighty days may be permitted in cases in which the Secretary of the Treasury authorizes such taxes to be paid each month on the amount of the commodity marketed during the next preceding month.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Repealed. <ref>June 30, 1947, ch. 166</ref>, title II, § 206(d), <ref>61 Stat. 208</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Under regulations made by the Commissioner of Internal Revenue, with the approval of the Secretary of the Treasury, any person required pursuant to the provisions of this chapter to file a return may be required to file such return and pay the tax shown to be due thereon to the collector of internal revenue for the district in which the processing was done or the liability was incurred. Whenever the Commissioner of Internal Revenue deems it necessary, he may require any person or class of persons handling or dealing in any commodity or product thereof, with respect to which a tax is imposed under the provisions of this chapter, to make a return, render under oath such statements, or to keep such records, as the Commissioner deems sufficient to show whether or not such person, or any other person, is liable for the tax.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 12, 1933, ch. 25</ref>, title I, § 19, <ref>48 Stat. 41</ref>; <ref>June 26, 1934, ch. 759, § 3</ref>, <ref>48 Stat. 1242</ref>; <ref>Aug. 24, 1935, ch. 641, § 29</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 770</ref>; <ref>June 30, 1947, ch. 166</ref>, title II, § 206(d), <ref>61 Stat. 208</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 619a.</num>
<heading> Cotton tax, time for payment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The processing tax authorized by <ref>section 609 of this title</ref>, when levied upon cotton, shall be payable ninety days after the filing of the processor’s report: <i>Provided</i>, That, under regulations to be prescribed by the Secretary of the Treasury, the time for payment of such tax upon cotton may be extended, but in no case to exceed six months from the date of the filing of the report.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 17, 1935, ch. 131</ref>, title I, § 2, <ref>49 Stat. 281</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 620.</num>
<heading> Falsely ascribing deductions or charges to taxes; penalty</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Whoever in connection with the purchase of, or offer to purchase, any commodity, subject to any tax under this chapter, or which is to be subjected to any tax under this chapter, makes any statement, written or oral, (1) intended or calculated to lead any person to believe that any amount deducted from the market price or the agreed price of the commodity consists of a tax imposed under this chapter, or (2) ascribing a particular part of the deduction from the market price or the agreed price of the commodity, to a tax imposed under this chapter, knowing that such statement is false or that the tax is not so great as the amount deducted from the market price or the agreed price of the commodity, ascribed to such tax, shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and, upon conviction thereof, shall be punished by a fine of not more than $1,000 or by imprisonment for not exceeding six months, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Whoever in connection with the processing of any commodity subject to any tax under this chapter, whether commercially, for toll, upon an exchange, or otherwise, makes any statement, written or oral, (1) intended or calculated to lead any person to believe that any part of the charge for said processing, whether commercially, for toll, upon an exchange, or otherwise, consists of a tax imposed under this chapter, or (2) ascribing a particular part of the charge for processing, whether commercially, for toll, upon an exchange, or otherwise, to a tax imposed under this chapter, knowing that such statement is false, or that the tax is not so great as the amount charged for said processing ascribed to such tax, shall be guilty of a misdemeanor, and upon conviction thereof, shall be punished by a fine of not more than $1,000 or by imprisonment for not exceeding six months, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Whoever in connection with any settlement, under a contract to buy any commodity, and/or to sell such commodity, or any product or byproduct thereof, subject to any tax under this chapter, makes any statement, written or oral, (1) intended or calculated to lead any person to believe that any amount deducted from the gross sales price, in arriving at the basis of settlement under the contract, consists of a tax under this chapter, or (2) ascribing a particular amount deducted from the gross sales price, in arriving at the basis of settlement under the contract, to a tax imposed under this chapter, knowing that such statement is false, or that the tax is not so great as the amount so deducted and/or ascribed to such tax, shall be guilty of a misdemeanor, and, upon conviction thereof, shall be punished by a fine of not more than $1,000 or by imprisonment for not exceeding six months, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 12, 1933, ch. 25</ref>, title I, § 20, as added <ref>May 9, 1934, ch. 263, § 16</ref>, <ref>48 Stat. 677</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 621.</num>
<heading> Machinery belting processed from cotton; exemption from tax</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The provisions of <ref>section 616 of this title</ref>, shall not apply to articles of machinery belting processed wholly or in chief value from cotton, if such processing was completed prior to <date date="1930-01-01">January 1, 1930</date>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 26, 1934, ch. 753, § 1</ref>, <ref>48 Stat. 1223</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 622.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 623.</num>
<heading> Actions relating to tax; legalization of prior taxes</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Action to restrain collection of tax or obtain declaratory judgment forbidden</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No suit, action, or proceeding (including probate, administration, and receivership proceedings) shall be brought or maintained in any court if such suit, action, or proceeding is for the purpose or has the effect (1) of preventing or restraining the assessment or collection of any tax imposed or the amount of any penalty or interest accrued under this chapter on or after <date date="1935-08-24">August 24, 1935</date>, or (2) of obtaining a declaratory judgment under sections 2201 and 2202 of title 28 in connection with any such tax or such amount of any such interest or penalty. In probate, administration, receivership, or other similar proceedings, the claim of the United States for any such tax or such amount of any such interest or penalty, in the amount assessed by the Commissioner of Internal Revenue, shall be allowed and ordered to be paid, but the right to claim the refund or credit thereof and to maintain such claim pursuant to the applicable provisions of law, including subsection (d) of this section, may be reserved in the court’s order.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Taxes imposed prior to <date date="1935-08-24">August 24, 1935</date>, legalized and ratified</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The taxes imposed under this chapter, as determined, prescribed, proclaimed and made effective by the proclamations and certificates of the Secretary of Agriculture or of the President and by the regulations of the Secretary with the approval of the President prior to <date date="1935-08-24">August 24, 1935</date>, are legalized and ratified, and the assessment, levy, collection, and accrual of all such taxes (together with penalties and interest with respect thereto) prior to said date are legalized and ratified and confirmed as fully to all intents and purposes as if each such tax had been made effective and the rate thereof fixed specifically by prior Act of Congress. All such taxes which had accrued and remained unpaid <date date="1935-08-24">August 24, 1935</date>, shall be assessed and collected pursuant to <ref>section 619 of this title</ref>, and to the provisions of law made applicable thereby. Nothing in this section shall be construed to import illegality to any act, determination, proclamation, certificate, or regulation of the Secretary of Agriculture or of the President done or made prior to <date date="1935-08-24">August 24, 1935</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rental and benefit payments, agreements, and programs made prior to <date date="1935-08-24">August 24, 1935</date>, legalized and ratified</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The making of rental and benefit payments under this chapter, prior to <date date="1935-08-24">August 24, 1935</date>, as determined, prescribed, proclaimed and made effective by the proclamations of the Secretary of Agriculture or of the President or by regulations of the Secretary, and the initiation, if formally approved by the Secretary of Agriculture prior to such date of adjustment programs under <ref>section 608(1) of this title</ref>, and the making of agreements with producers prior to such date, and the adoption of other voluntary methods prior to such date, by the Secretary of Agriculture under this chapter, and rental and benefit payments made pursuant thereto, are legalized and ratified, and the making of all such agreements and payments, the initiation of such programs, and the adoption of all such methods prior to such date are legalized, ratified, and confirmed as fully to all intents and purposes as if each such agreement, program, method, and payment had been specifically authorized and made effective and the rate and amount thereof fixed specifically by prior Act of Congress.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 12, 1933, ch. 25</ref>, title I, § 21, as added <ref>Aug. 24, 1935, ch. 641, § 30</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 770</ref>; amended <ref>June 22, 1936, ch. 690</ref>, §§ 601(c), 901, <ref>49 Stat. 1740</ref>, 1747; <ref>Pub. L. 95–598, title III, § 304</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2673</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 624.</num>
<heading> Limitation on imports; authority of President</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Whenever the Secretary of Agriculture has reason to believe that any article or articles are being or are practically certain to be imported into the United States under such conditions and in such quantities as to render or tend to render ineffective, or materially interfere with, any program or operation undertaken under this chapter or the Soil Conservation and Domestic Allotment Act, as amended [<ref>16 U.S.C. 590a</ref> et seq.], or <ref>section 612c of this title</ref>, or any loan, purchase, or other program or operation undertaken by the Department of Agriculture, or any agency operating under its direction, with respect to any agricultural commodity or product thereof, or to reduce substantially the amount of any product processed in the United States from any agricultural commodity or product thereof with respect to which any such program or operation is being undertaken, he shall so advise the President, and, if the President agrees that there is reason for such belief, the President shall cause an immediate investigation to be made by the United States International Trade Commission, which shall give precedence to investigations under this section to determine such facts. Such investigation shall be made after due notice and opportunity for hearing to interested parties, and shall be conducted subject to such regulations as the President shall specify.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> If, on the basis of such investigation and report to him of findings and recommendations made in connection therewith, the President finds the existence of such facts, he shall by proclamation impose such fees not in excess of 50 per centum ad valorem or such quantitative limitations on any article or articles which may be entered, or withdrawn from warehouse, for consumption as he finds and declares shown by such investigation to be necessary in order that the entry of such article or articles will not render or tend to render ineffective, or materially interfere with, any program or operation referred to in subsection (a) of this section, or reduce substantially the amount of any product processed in the United States from any such agricultural commodity or product thereof with respect to which any such program or operation is being undertaken: <i>Provided</i>, That no proclamation under this section shall impose any limitation on the total quantity of any article or articles which may be entered, or withdrawn from warehouse, for consumption which reduces such permissible total quantity to proportionately less than 50 per centum of the total quantity of such article or articles which was entered, or withdrawn from warehouse, for consumption during a representative period as determined by the President: <i>And provided further</i>, That in designating any article or articles, the President may describe them by physical qualities, value, use, or upon such other bases as he shall determine.<p class="indent0">In any case where the Secretary of Agriculture determines and reports to the President with regard to any article or articles that a condition exists requiring emergency treatment, the President may take immediate action under this section without awaiting the recommendations of the International Trade Commission, such action to continue in effect pending the report and recommendations of the International Trade Commission and action thereon by the President.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The fees and limitations imposed by the President by proclamation under this section and any revocation, suspension, or modification thereof, shall become effective on such date as shall be therein specified, and such fees shall be treated for administrative purposes and for the purposes of <ref>section 612c of this title</ref>, as duties imposed by the Tariff Act of 1930 [<ref>19 U.S.C. 1202</ref> et seq.], but such fees shall not be considered as duties for the purpose of granting any preferential concession under any international obligation of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> After investigation, report, finding, and declaration in the manner provided in the case of a proclamation issued pursuant to subsection (b) of this section, any proclamation or provision of such proclamation may be suspended or terminated by the President whenever he finds and proclaims that the circumstances requiring the proclamation or provision thereof no longer exist or may be modified by the President whenever he finds and proclaims that changed circumstances require such modification to carry out the purposes of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> Any decision of the President as to facts under this section shall be final.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> No quantitative limitation or fee shall be imposed under this section with respect to any article that is the product of a WTO member (as defined in <ref>section 3501(10) of title 19</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 12, 1933, ch. 25</ref>, title I, § 22, as added <ref>Aug. 24, 1935, ch. 641, § 31</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 773</ref>; amended <ref>Feb. 29, 1936, ch. 104, § 5</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 1152</ref>; <ref>June 3, 1937, ch. 296, § 1</ref>, <ref>50 Stat. 246</ref>; <ref>Jan. 25, 1940, ch. 13</ref>, <ref>54 Stat. 17</ref>; <ref>July 3, 1948, ch. 827</ref>, title I, § 3, <ref>62 Stat. 1248</ref>; <ref>June 28, 1950, ch. 381, § 3</ref>, <ref>64 Stat. 261</ref>; <ref>June 16, 1951, ch. 141, § 8(b)</ref>, <ref>65 Stat. 75</ref>; <ref>Aug. 7, 1953, ch. 348</ref>, title I, § 104, <ref>67 Stat. 472</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–618, title I, § 171(b)</ref>, <date date="1975-01-03">Jan. 3, 1975</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 2009</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–449, title III, § 301(c)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-28">Sept. 28, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1868</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–465, title IV, § 401(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4957</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 625.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 108–357, title VI, § 611(s)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-22">Oct. 22, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1523</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 626.</num>
<heading> Import inventory</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compilation and report on imports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture, in consultation with the Secretary of Commerce, the International Trade Commission, the United States Trade Representative, and the heads of all other appropriate Federal agencies, shall compile and report to the public statistics on the total value and quantity of imported raw and processed agricultural products. The report shall be limited to those statistics that such agencies already obtain for other purposes.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compilation and report on consumption</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall compile and report to the public data on the total quantity of production and consumption of domestically produced raw and processed agricultural products.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Issuing of data</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The reports required by this section shall be made in a format that correlates statistics for the quantity and value of imported agricultural products to the production and consumption of domestic agricultural products. The Secretary shall issue such reports on an annual basis, with the first report required not later than 1 year after <date date="1988-08-23">August 23, 1988</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title IV, § 4502</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1403</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 627.</num>
<heading> Dairy forward pricing pilot program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Pilot program required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 90 days after <date date="1999-11-29">November 29, 1999</date>, the Secretary of Agriculture shall establish a temporary pilot program under which milk producers and cooperatives are authorized to voluntarily enter into forward price contracts with milk handlers.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Minimum milk price requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Payments made by milk handlers to milk producers and cooperatives, and prices received by milk producers and cooperatives, under the forward contracts shall be deemed to satisfy—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> all regulated minimum milk price requirements of paragraphs (B) and (F) of subsection (5) of <ref>section 608c of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the requirement of paragraph (C) of such subsection regarding total payments by each handler.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Milk covered by pilot program</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Covered milk</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The pilot program shall apply only with respect to the marketing of federally regulated milk that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is not classified as Class I milk or otherwise intended for fluid use; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is in the current of interstate or foreign commerce or directly burdens, obstructs, or affects interstate or foreign commerce in federally regulated milk.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Relation to Class I milk</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To assist milk handlers in complying with the limitation in paragraph (1)(A) without having to segregate or otherwise individually track the source and disposition of milk, a milk handler may allocate milk receipts from producers, cooperatives, and other sources that are not subject to a forward contract to satisfy the handler’s obligations with regard to Class I milk usage.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The authority of the Secretary of Agriculture to carry out the pilot program shall terminate on <date date="2004-12-31">December 31, 2004</date>. No forward price contract entered into under the program may extend beyond that date.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Study and report on effect of pilot program</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Study</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary of Agriculture shall conduct a study on forward contracting between milk producers and cooperatives and milk handlers to determine the impact on milk prices paid to producers in the United States. To obtain information for the study, the Secretary may use the authorities available to the Secretary under <ref>section 608d of this title</ref>, subject to the confidentiality requirements of subsection (2) of such section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than <date date="2002-04-30">April 30, 2002</date>, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition and Forestry of the Senate and the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives a report containing the results of the study.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 12, 1933, ch. 25</ref>, title I, § 23, as added <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(8) [§ 3]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–519.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>REFUNDS</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 641 to 659.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>