<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 11—</num>
<heading>HONEYBEES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 281.</num>
<heading> Honeybee importation</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture is authorized to prohibit or restrict the importation or entry of honeybees and honeybee semen into or through the United States in order to prevent the introduction and spread of diseases and parasites harmful to honeybees, the introduction of genetically undesirable germ plasm of honeybees, or the introduction and spread of undesirable species or subspecies of honeybees and the semen of honeybees.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Treasury are each authorized to prescribe such regulations as the respective Secretary determines necessary to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Enforcement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Honeybees or honeybee semen offered for importation into, intercepted entering, or having entered the United States, other than in accordance with regulations promulgated by the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Treasury, shall be destroyed or immediately exported.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> “Honeybee” defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As used in this chapter, the term “honeybee” means all life stages and the germ plasm of honeybees of the genus Apis, except honeybee semen.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 31, 1922, ch. 301, § 1</ref>, <ref>42 Stat. 833</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–539, § 1</ref>, <date date="1962-07-19">July 19, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 169</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–319, § 1</ref>, <date date="1976-06-25">June 25, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 709</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–182, title III, § 361(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="1993-12-08">Dec. 8, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 2123</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–465, title IV, § 431(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4968</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 282.</num>
<heading> Punishment for unlawful importation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any person who violates any provision of <ref>section 281 of this title</ref> or any regulation issued under it is guilty of an offense against the United States and shall, upon conviction, be fined not more than $1,000, or imprisoned for not more than one year, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 31, 1922, ch. 301, § 2</ref>, <ref>42 Stat. 834</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–319, § 2</ref>, <date date="1976-06-25">June 25, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 709</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 283.</num>
<heading> Propagation of stock and release of germ plasm</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture may propagate bee-breeding stock and may release bee germ plasm to the public.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Sept. 21, 1944, ch. 412</ref>, title I, § 103, <ref>58 Stat. 735</ref>; <ref>Oct. 31, 1951, ch. 654, § 3(1)</ref>, <ref>65 Stat. 708</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–98, title XI, § 1120</ref>, <date date="1981-12-22">Dec. 22, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1273</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 284.</num>
<heading> Eradication and control of undesirable species and subspecies</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Operations in United States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture either independently or in cooperation with States or political subdivisions thereof, farmers’ associations, and similar organizations and individuals, is authorized to carry out operations or measures in the United States to eradicate, suppress, control, and to prevent or retard the spread of undesirable species and subspecies of honeybees.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cooperation with certain foreign governments; measure and character; consultation with Secretary of State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture is authorized to cooperate with the Governments of Canada, Mexico, Guatemala, Belize, Honduras, El Salvador, Nicaragua, Costa Rica, Panama, and Colombia, or the local authorities thereof, in carrying out necessary research, surveys, and control operations in those countries in connection with the eradication, suppression, control, and prevention or retardation of the spread of undesirable species and subspecies of honeybees, including but not limited to Apis mellifera adansonii, commonly known as the African or Brazilian honeybee. The measure and character of cooperation carried out under this subsection on the part of such countries, including the expenditure or use of funds appropriated pursuant to this chapter, shall be such as may be prescribed by the Secretary of Agriculture. Arrangements for the cooperation authorized by this subsection shall be made through and in consultation with the Secretary of State.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Responsibility for authority to carry out operations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In performing the operations or measures authorized in this chapter, the cooperating foreign country, State, or local agency shall be responsible for the authority to carry out such operations or measures on all lands and properties within the foreign country or State, other than those owned or controlled by the Federal Government of the United States, and for such other facilities and means as in the discretion of the Secretary of Agriculture are necessary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 31, 1922, ch. 301, § 3</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 94–319, § 3</ref>, <date date="1976-06-25">June 25, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 709</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 285.</num>
<heading> Uses of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Funds appropriated to carry out the provisions of this chapter may also be used for printing and binding without regard to <ref>section 501 of title 44</ref> for employment, by contract or otherwise, of civilian nationals of Canada, Mexico, Guatemala, Belize, Honduras, El Salvador, Nicaragua, Costa Rica, Panama, and Colombia for services abroad, and for the construction and operation of research laboratories, quarantine stations, and other buildings and facilities.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 31, 1922, ch. 301, § 4</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 94–319, § 3</ref>, <date date="1976-06-25">June 25, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 710</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 286.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are hereby authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 31, 1922, ch. 301, § 5</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 94–319, § 3</ref>, <date date="1976-06-25">June 25, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 710</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>