<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 70—</num>
<heading>ANIMAL CANCER RESEARCH</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3901.</num>
<heading> Congressional findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Congress finds that—</chapeau>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> basic research on malignant tumors or cancers is essential to protect the health of domestic animals, poultry, and wildlife, including birds;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> carcinogenic agents have not been adequately identified in domestic animals, poultry, and wildlife management;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> basic research in diagnosis, prevention, and control of malignant tumors in animals and birds has not been adequately coordinated;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> significant theories of a common factor in malignant tumors, such as chorionic gonad­otropin, have not been pursued in depth;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> research on diagnosis, prevention, and control of cancer in animals and birds will be beneficial in identifying any common factors in human and animal malignant tumors, if such exist; and</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> it is imperative for the Department of Agriculture and the National Institutes of Health to coordinate and consult with regard to the research authorized under this chapter to achieve the maximum benefits from such research.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–469, § 2</ref>, <date date="1980-10-17">Oct. 17, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2235</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3902.</num>
<heading> Research program on cancer in animals and birds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture shall conduct a program of basic research on cancer in animals and birds at appropriate facilities within the Department of Agriculture or by grants to other qualified research facilities.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–469, § 3</ref>, <date date="1980-10-17">Oct. 17, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2235</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3903.</num>
<heading> Annual program review to achieve coordination with National Cancer Institute program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture and the Director of the National Institutes of Health shall annually review the research program conducted under this chapter in order to coordinate the program with the National Cancer Institute research program.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–469, § 4</ref>, <date date="1980-10-17">Oct. 17, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2235</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3904.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations; restriction</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> There are hereby authorized to be appropriated to administer the program under this chapter $25,000,000 for fiscal year 1982, and $25,000,000 annually thereafter through the end of fiscal year 1986.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Not more than 30 per centum of any of the amounts appropriated under this section in any fiscal year may be obligated for research under <ref>section 3902 of this title</ref> at facilities of the Department of Agriculture.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–469, § 5</ref>, <date date="1980-10-17">Oct. 17, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2235</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>