<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 43—</num>
<heading>FOREIGN MARKET DEVELOPMENT</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS; AGRICULTURAL COUNSELORS AND AGRICULTURAL ATTACHÉS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1761.</num>
<heading> Foreign markets; collection of information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purpose of encouraging and promoting the marketing of agricultural commodities of the United States and assisting American farmers, processors, distributors, and exporters to adjust their operations and practices to meet world conditions, the Secretary of Agriculture shall acquire information regarding the competition and demand for United States agricultural commodities, the marketing and distribution of such commodities in foreign countries and shall be responsible for the interpretation and dissemination of such information in the United States and shall make investigations abroad regarding the factors affecting and influencing the export of United States agricultural commodities, and shall conduct abroad any other activities including the demonstration of standards of quality for American agricultural commodities for which the Department of Agriculture now has or in the future may have such standards, as he deems necessary. Nothing contained herein shall be construed as prohibiting the Department of Agriculture from conducting abroad any activity for which authority now exists.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 28, 1954, ch. 1041</ref>, title VI, § 601, <ref>68 Stat. 908</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–501, title III, § 301(3)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-21">Oct. 21, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1688</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1762.</num>
<heading> Personnel</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To effectuate the carrying out of the purposes of this subchapter, the Secretary of Agriculture is authorized to appoint such personnel as he determines to be necessary and, with the concurrence of the Secretary of State, to assign such personnel to service abroad.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Titles; rank and privileges; appointments of Agricultural Counselors</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Officers or employees assigned or appointed to posts abroad under this subchapter shall have the designation of Agricultural Counselor, Agricultural Attaché, or such other titles or designations that shall be agreed to by the Secretary of State and the Secretary of Agriculture, and shall be accorded the same rank and privileges as those of other counselors or attachés in United States embassies. An Agricultural Counselor shall be appointed in any nation—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to which a substantial number of governments with which the United States competes directly for agricultural markets in such nation assign agricultural representatives with the diplomatic status of counselor or its equivalent; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> in which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the potential is great for long-term expansion of a market for United States agricultural commodities, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> competition with other nations for existing and potential agricultural markets is extremely intense.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Not less than ten Agricultural Counselors shall be appointed within three years after <date date="1978-10-21">October 21, 1978</date>.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Attachment to diplomatic missions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon the request of the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of State shall regularly and officially attach the officers or employees of the United States Department of Agriculture to the diplomatic mission of the United States in the country in which such officers or employees are to be assigned by the Secretary of Agriculture, and shall obtain for them diplomatic privileges and immunities equivalent to those enjoyed by Foreign Service personnel of comparable rank and salary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assignment to United States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any officer or employee appointed and assigned to a post abroad pursuant to this subchapter may, in the discretion of the Secretary of Agriculture, be assigned for duty in the continental United States, without regard to the civil service laws (and without reduction in grade if an appropriate position at the employee’s grade is not available in any agency of the Department of Agriculture), for a period of not more than three years: <i>Provided,</i> That the total number of such employees assigned for duty in the continental United States under this provision shall not exceed fifteen at any one time: <i>Provided further,</i> That this Act shall not increase the number of persons employed at grade GS–16, GS–17, or GS–18.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 28, 1954, ch. 1041</ref>, title VI, § 602(a)–(d), formerly § 602(a)–(c), (e), <ref>68 Stat. 908</ref>, 909; amended <ref>June 28, 1955, ch. 189, § 12(c)(13)</ref>, <ref>69 Stat. 182</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–106, § 4</ref>, <date date="1965-08-04">Aug. 4, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 431</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–449</ref>, <date date="1976-10-01">Oct. 1, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1500</ref>; renumbered § 602(a)–(d) and amended <ref>Pub. L. 95–501, title III, § 301(4)</ref>, (5), title IV, § 401(3), (5), <date date="1978-10-21">Oct. 21, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1688</ref>, 1691.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1763.</num>
<heading> Transferred</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1764.</num>
<heading> Reports and dispatches</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability to Department of State and interested Government agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The reports and dispatches prepared by the officers appointed or assigned under this subchapter shall be made available to the Department of State, and may be made available to other interested agencies of the Government, and the agricultural reports and dispatches and related information produced by officers of the Foreign Service shall be available to the Secretary of Agriculture.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Office space, equipment, and administrative and clerical services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of State is authorized upon request of the Secretary of Agriculture to provide office space, equipment, facilities, and such other administrative and clerical services as may be required for the personnel affected by this subchapter. The Secretary of Agriculture is authorized to reimburse or advance funds to the Secretary of State for such services.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agency services, personnel, and facilities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon the request of the Secretary of Agriculture, each Federal agency may make its services, personnel, and facilities available to officers and employees appointed and assigned to a post abroad under this subchapter in the performance of the functions of such officers and employees. The Secretary of Agriculture may reimburse or advance funds to any such agency for services, personnel, and facilities so made available.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 28, 1954, ch. 1041</ref>, title VI, § 604, <ref>68 Stat. 909</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–501, title III, § 301(4)</ref>, (6), <date date="1978-10-21">Oct. 21, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1688</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1765.</num>
<heading> Foreign service appropriations; applicability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Provisions in annual appropriation Acts of the Department of State facilitating the work of the Foreign Service of the United States shall be applicable under rules and regulations prescribed by the President or his designee to activities pursuant to this subchapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 28, 1954, ch. 1041</ref>, title VI, § 605, <ref>68 Stat. 909</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–501, title III, § 301(4)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-21">Oct. 21, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1688</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>UNITED STATES AGRICULTURAL TRADE OFFICES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1765a.</num>
<heading> Agricultural Trade Offices</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purpose of developing, maintaining, and expanding international markets for United States agricultural commodities, the Secretary of Agriculture, after consultation with the Secretary of State, shall establish not less than six nor more than twenty-five United States Agricultural Trade Offices in other nations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">each <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002201">1</ref> United States Agricultural Trade Office shall be directed and administered by an Agricultural Trade Officer who by reason of training, experience, and attainments is qualified to carry out the purposes of this subchapter. Such Officer shall be appointed by the Secretary of Agriculture.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment and compensation of officers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each Agricultural Trade Officer may be appointed without regard to the provisions of title 5 governing appointments in the competitive service, and may be paid without regard to the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5 relating to classification and General Schedule pay rates, except that no Agricultural Trade Officer (1) may be paid basic pay at a rate in excess of the maximum annual rate of basic pay payable for GS–17 of the General Schedule under section 5332 of such title, or (2) may be paid at a rate in excess of the highest rate paid to an Agricultural Counselor or Attaché, as the case may be, who is appointed under subchapter I of this chapter to the nation in which such Officer is to serve.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transmittal of information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each Agricultural Trade Officer shall, through the Agricultural Counselor or Attaché or other senior representative of the Secretary of Agriculture in each nation in which the United States Agricultural Trade Office administered by such Officer exercises its functions, keep the Chief of the United States diplomatic mission fully and currently informed with respect to all activities and operations of such Office.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Office functions and activities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each Agricultural Trade Officer shall be responsible for the exercise of the functions of the United States Agricultural Trade Office, and shall have the authority to direct and supervise all personnel and activities thereof.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Personnel; employment of local nationals</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To carry out the functions of United States Agricultural Trade Offices, the Secretary of Agriculture may appoint such other personnel as the Secretary determines to be necessary and may, with the concurrence of the Secretary of State, assign such personnel abroad and employ local nationals for necessary professional and clerical help.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conflicts of interest</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No employee of any United States Agricultural Trade Office may engage in any business, vocation, or other employment, or have other interests, that are inconsistent with official responsibilities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Diplomatic privileges and immunities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon the request of the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of State shall request for Agricultural Trade Officers and personnel of United States Agricultural Trade Offices diplomatic privileges and immunities equivalent to those enjoyed by members of the Foreign Service of comparable rank and salary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 28, 1954, ch. 1041</ref>, title VI, § 605A, as added <ref>Pub. L. 95–501, title IV, § 401(1)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-21">Oct. 21, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1688</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 96–465, title II, § 2206(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-17">Oct. 17, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2162</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1765b.</num>
<heading> Functions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The functions of each United States Agricultural Trade Office shall be to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> increase the effectiveness of agricultural export promotion efforts through consolidation of activities, providing services and facilities for foreign buyers and United States trade representatives, and coordination of market development activities sponsored by the Department of Agriculture;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> establish goals by nation or region and agricultural commodity for developing, expanding, and maintaining markets for United States agricultural commodities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> initiate programs to achieve the export marketing goals approved by the Department of Agriculture;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> maintain facilities for use by nonresident cooperators, private trade groups, and other individuals engaged in the import and export of United States agricultural commodities where the use of such facilities would aid in the conduct of market development activities, and cooperate, to the maximum extent practicable, with such cooperators, groups, and individuals to expand the level of United States agricultural exports;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> develop and maintain a current listing of trade, government, and other appropriate organizations for each agricultural commodity area and make such listing available to persons with a bona fide interest in exporting or importing United States agricultural commodities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> originate and provide assistance for exhibits, sales teams, and other functions for the promotion of United States agricultural commodities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> provide practical assistance for the use of the programs under the Food for Peace Act [<ref>7 U.S.C. 1691</ref> et seq.], the export credit sales program, the export incentives program, and related programs of the United States Government where use of such programs will serve as a market development tool for United States agriculture;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> supervise project agreements with United States cooperators, coordinate the activities of the United States Agricultural Trade Office with those of the cooperators, and submit annual recommendations to the Secretary of Agriculture on the efficacy of cooperator programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> publicize the services offered by the United States Agricultural Trade Office through advertisements in trade journals or by other appropriate means; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> perform such other functions as the Secretary of Agriculture, in consultation with the Secretary of State, determines to be necessary and proper for achieving the purposes of this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 28, 1954, ch. 1041</ref>, title VI, § 605B, as added <ref>Pub. L. 95–501, title IV, § 401(1)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-21">Oct. 21, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1689</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, title III, § 3001(b)(1)(A)</ref>, (2)(H), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1820</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1765b–1.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1765c.</num>
<heading> Performance of functions in foreign localities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each United States Agricultural Trade Office shall carry out its functions under <ref>section 1765b of this title</ref> in the nation where the United States Agricultural Trade Office is located and in such other nations as the Secretary of Agriculture, in consultation with the Secretary of State, may prescribe in order to carry out the purposes of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 28, 1954, ch. 1041</ref>, title VI, § 605C, as added <ref>Pub. L. 95–501, title IV, § 401(1)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-21">Oct. 21, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1690</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1765d.</num>
<heading> Acquisition of property</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon the request of the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of State may use the authorities contained in the Foreign Service Buildings Act, 1926 [<ref>22 U.S.C. 292</ref> et seq.], to acquire sites and buildings, including living quarters, for the purpose of establishing United States Agricultural Trade Offices.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 28, 1954, ch. 1041</ref>, title VI, § 605D, as added <ref>Pub. L. 95–501, title IV, § 401(1)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-21">Oct. 21, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1690</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1765d–1.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 107–228, div. A, title II, § 213</ref>, <date date="2002-09-30">Sept. 30, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1365</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1765e.</num>
<heading> Location of offices</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">United States Agricultural Trade Offices shall be centrally located in the cities of assignment to facilitate foreign trade meetings and foreign trade reliance on such offices for assistance in marketing activities.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 28, 1954, ch. 1041</ref>, title VI, § 605E, as added <ref>Pub. L. 95–501, title IV, § 401(1)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-21">Oct. 21, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1690</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1765f.</num>
<heading> Availability of agency services, personnel, and facilities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon the request of the Secretary of Agriculture, each Federal agency may make its services, personnel, and facilities available to a United States Agricultural Trade Office in the performance of its functions. The Secretary of Agriculture may reimburse or advance funds to any such agency for services, personnel, and facilities so made available.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 28, 1954, ch. 1041</ref>, title VI, § 605F, as added <ref>Pub. L. 95–501, title IV, § 401(1)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-21">Oct. 21, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1690</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1765g.</num>
<heading> Availability of reports and dispatches</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The provisions of <ref>section 1764(a) of this title</ref> shall apply with respect to personnel appointed and assigned under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 28, 1954, ch. 1041</ref>, title VI, § 605G, as added <ref>Pub. L. 95–501, title IV, § 401(1)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-21">Oct. 21, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1690</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>REPRESENTATION ALLOWANCES, REGULATIONS, GENERAL PROVISIONS, AND AUTHORIZATION FOR APPROPRIATIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1765h.</num>
<heading> Representation allowance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any Agricultural Trade Officer and the senior representative of the Secretary of Agriculture assigned to a nation under subchapter I of this chapter may, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Agriculture, be entitled to receive a representation allowance in an amount determined by considering (1) the extent to which such Agricultural Trade Officer or senior representative can effectively use such funds to further the purposes of this chapter, (2) travel and entertainment expenses customary in the private trade for persons of comparable rank and salary, and (3) customs and practices in the nation where such Agricultural Trade Officer or senior representative is assigned.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 28, 1954, ch. 1041</ref>, title VI, § 606, as added <ref>Pub. L. 95–501, title IV, § 401(2)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-21">Oct. 21, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1690</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1766.</num>
<heading> Rules and regulations; advance payment for rent and other service; funds for courtesies to foreign representatives</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture may make rules and regulations necessary to carry out the purposes of this chapter and may cooperate with any Department or agency of the United States Government, State, Territory, or possession or any organization or person. In any foreign country where custom or practice requires payment in advance for rent or other service, such payment may be authorized by the Secretary of Agriculture. Funds available for the purposes of this chapter may be used for extending courtesies to representatives of foreign countries, when so provided in appropriation or other law.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 28, 1954, ch. 1041</ref>, title VI, § 606A, formerly § 606, <ref>68 Stat. 909</ref>; amended <ref>Aug. 3, 1956, ch. 950, § 8</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 1034</ref>; renumbered § 606A, <ref>Pub. L. 95–501, title IV, § 401(2)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-21">Oct. 21, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1690</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1766a.</num>
<heading> Presidential regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall prescribe regulations to insure that the official activities of persons assigned abroad under this chapter are carried on (1) consonant with United States foreign policy objectives as defined by the Secretary of State; (2) in accordance with instructions of the Secretary of Agriculture with respect to agricultural matters; and (3) in coordination with other representatives of the United States Government in each country, under the leadership of the Chief of the United States Diplomatic Mission.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 28, 1954, ch. 1041</ref>, title VI, § 606B, formerly § 602(d), <ref>68 Stat. 909</ref>; renumbered <ref>Pub. L. 95–501, title IV, § 401(3)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-21">Oct. 21, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1691</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1766b.</num>
<heading> Language training for families of officers and employees assigned abroad</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Effective <date date="1976-10-01">October 1, 1976</date>, the Secretary of Agriculture is authorized to provide appropriate orientation and language training to families of officers and employees of the Department of Agriculture in anticipation of an assignment abroad of such officers and employees or while abroad pursuant to this chapter or other authority: <i>Provided</i>, That the facilities of the George P. Shultz National Foreign Affairs Training Center or other Government facilities shall be used wherever practicable, and the Secretary may utilize foreign currencies generated under title I of the Food for Peace Act, as amended [<ref>7 U.S.C. 1701</ref> et seq.], to carry out the purposes of this section in the foreign nations to which such officers, employees, and families are assigned. There are hereby authorized to be appropriated such sums, not to exceed $50,000 annually, as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this section: <i>Provided</i>, That for the fiscal year ending <date date="1977-09-30">September 30, 1977</date>, any appropriations available to the Secretary of Agriculture (not to exceed $50,000) may be used to carry out the purposes of this section.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 28, 1954, ch. 1041</ref>, title VI, § 606C, formerly § 602(f), as added <ref>Pub. L. 94–449</ref>, <date date="1976-10-01">Oct. 1, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1500</ref>; renumbered § 606C, and amended <ref>Pub. L. 95–501, title IV, § 401(3)</ref>, (4), <date date="1978-10-21">Oct. 21, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1691</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–470, title I, § 102(f)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-19">Oct. 19, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2237</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–132, § 1(b)</ref>, <date date="2002-01-16">Jan. 16, 2002</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 2412</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, title III, § 3001(b)(1)(A)</ref>, (2)(H), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1820</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1766c.</num>
<heading> Allowances and benefits</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture may, under such rules and regulations as may be prescribed by the President or his designee, provide to personnel appointed or assigned by the Secretary of Agriculture under this chapter or other authority allowance and benefits similar to those provided by chapter 9 of title I of the Foreign Service Act of 1980 [<ref>22 U.S.C. 4081</ref> et seq.]. Leaves of absence for personnel under this chapter shall be on the same basis as is provided for the Foreign Service of the United States by subchapter I of chapter 63 of title 5.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 28, 1954, ch. 1041</ref>, title VI, § 606D, formerly § 603, <ref>68 Stat. 909</ref>; renumbered § 606D, <ref>Pub. L. 95–501, title IV, § 401(3)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-21">Oct. 21, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1691</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 96–465, title II, § 2206(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-17">Oct. 17, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2162</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1767.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Unexpended balances</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the fiscal year 1955 so much of the Department of State and Department of Agriculture unexpended balances of appropriations, allocations, and other funds employed, held, used, available, or to be made available, in connection with the functions covered by this chapter as the Director of the Office of Management and Budget or the Congress by appropriation or other law shall determine shall be transferred to or established in accounts under the control of the Department of Agriculture, and there are hereby authorized to be established such additional accounts as may be necessary for this purpose.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are hereby authorized to be appropriated to the Department of Agriculture such amounts as may be necessary for the purpose of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Funds for 1955; expenditures</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the fiscal year 1955 funds which become available for the purposes of this chapter may be expended under the provisions of law, including current appropriation Acts, applicable to the Department of State: <i>Provided</i>, That the provisions of <ref>section 961(d) of title 22</ref> with respect to the source of payment for Foreign Service officers and employees shall not apply to personnel employed under this chapter. Obligations incurred by the Department of State prior to <date date="1954-09-01">September 1, 1954</date>, with respect to functions affected by this Act, shall be paid from appropriations available to the Department of State.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 28, 1954, ch. 1041</ref>, title VI, § 607, <ref>68 Stat. 909</ref>; 1970 Reorg. Plan No. 2, § 102, eff. <date date="1970-07-01">July 1, 1970</date>, 35 F.R. 7959, <ref>84 Stat. 2085</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1768.</num>
<heading> Foreign Operations Administration unaffected</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to affect personnel employed by or funds available to the Foreign Operations Administration or programs conducted under its authorities.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 28, 1954, ch. 1041</ref>, title VI, § 608, <ref>68 Stat. 910</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1769.</num>
<heading> “Agricultural commodity” defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The term “agricultural commodity” as used in this chapter includes any agricultural commodity or product thereof.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 28, 1954, ch. 1041</ref>, title VI, § 609, as added <ref>Pub. L. 95–501, title IV, § 401(6)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-21">Oct. 21, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1691</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>