<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 1—</num>
<heading>ADMINISTRATION</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this title, unless the context requires another meaning or unless it is otherwise provided—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “Bureau” means the Bureau of the Census;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> “Secretary” means the Secretary of Commerce; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> “respondent” includes a corporation, company, association, firm, partnership, proprietorship, society, joint stock company, individual, or other organization or entity which reported information, or on behalf of which information was reported, in response to a questionnaire, inquiry, or other request of the Bureau.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 31, 1954, ch. 1158</ref>, <ref>68 Stat. 1012</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–521, § 1</ref>, <date date="1976-10-17">Oct. 17, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2459</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2.</num>
<heading> Bureau of the Census</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Bureau is continued as an agency within, and under the jurisdiction of, the Department of Commerce.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 31, 1954, ch. 1158</ref>, <ref>68 Stat. 1012</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3.</num>
<heading> Seal</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Bureau shall have a seal containing such device as has been selected heretofore, or as the Secretary may select hereafter. A description of such seal with an impression thereof shall be filed in the office of the Secretary of State. The seal shall remain in the custody of the Secretary or such officer or employee of the Bureau as he designates, and shall be affixed to all documents authenticated by the Bureau. Judicial notice shall be taken of the seal.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 31, 1954, ch. 1158</ref>, <ref>68 Stat. 1012</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–207, § 2</ref>, <date date="1957-08-28">Aug. 28, 1957</date>, <ref>71 Stat. 481</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–521, § 2</ref>, <date date="1976-10-17">Oct. 17, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2459</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4.</num>
<heading> Functions of Secretary; regulations; delegation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall perform the functions and duties imposed upon him by this title, may issue such rules and regulations as he deems necessary to carry out such functions and duties, and may delegate the performance of such functions and duties and the authority to issue such rules and regulations to such officers and employees of the Department of Commerce as he may designate.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 31, 1954, ch. 1158</ref>, <ref>68 Stat. 1013</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–521, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-17">Oct. 17, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2459</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5.</num>
<heading> Questionnaires; number, form, and scope of inquiries</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall prepare questionnaires, and shall determine the inquiries, and the number, form, and subdivisions thereof, for the statistics, surveys, and censuses provided for in this title.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 31, 1954, ch. 1158</ref>, <ref>68 Stat. 1013</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–521, § 4(a)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-17">Oct. 17, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2459</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6.</num>
<heading> Information from other Federal departments and agencies; acquisition of reports from other governmental and private sources</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary, whenever he considers it advisable, may call upon any other department, agency, or establishment of the Federal Government, or of the government of the District of Columbia, for information pertinent to the work provided for in this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Secretary may acquire, by purchase or otherwise, from States, counties, cities, or other units of government, or their instrumentalities, or from private persons and agencies, such copies of records, reports, and other material as may be required for the efficient and economical conduct of the censuses and surveys provided for in this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> To the maximum extent possible and consistent with the kind, timeliness, quality and scope of the statistics required, the Secretary shall acquire and use information available from any source referred to in subsection (a) or (b) of this section instead of conducting direct inquiries.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 31, 1954, ch. 1158</ref>, <ref>68 Stat. 1013</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–207, § 3</ref>, <date date="1957-08-28">Aug. 28, 1957</date>, <ref>71 Stat. 481</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–521, § 5(a)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-17">Oct. 17, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2460</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7.</num>
<heading> Printing; requisitions upon Director of the Government Publishing Office; publication of bulletins and reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may make requisition upon the Director of the Government Publishing Office for miscellaneous printing necessary to carry out the provisions of this title. He may further have printed by the Director of the Government Publishing Office, in such editions as he deems necessary, preliminary and other census bulletins, and final reports of the results of the several investigations authorized by this title, and may publish and distribute such bulletins and reports.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 31, 1954, ch. 1158</ref>, <ref>68 Stat. 1013</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–235, div. H, title I, § 1301(d)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-16">Dec. 16, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 2537</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8.</num>
<heading> Authenticated transcripts or copies of certain returns; other data; restriction on use; disposition of fees received</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary may, upon written request, furnish to any respondent, or to the heir, successor, or authorized agent of such respondent, authenticated transcripts or copies of reports (or portions thereof) containing information furnished by, or on behalf of, such respondent in connection with the surveys and census provided for in this title, upon payment of the actual or estimated cost of searching the rec­ords and furnishing such transcripts or copies.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Subject to the limitations contained in sections 6(c) and 9 of this title, the Secretary may furnish copies of tabulations and other statistical materials which do not disclose the information reported by, or on behalf of, any particular respondent, and may make special statistical compilations and surveys, for departments, agencies, and establishments of the Federal Government, the government of the District of Columbia, the government of any possession or area (including political subdivisions thereof) referred to in <ref>section 191(a) of this title</ref>, State or local agencies, or other public and private persons and agencies, upon payment of the actual or estimated cost of such work. In the case of nonprofit agencies or organizations, the Secretary may engage in joint statistical projects, the purpose of which are otherwise authorized by law, but only if the cost of such projects are shared equitably, as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> In no case shall information furnished under this section be used to the detriment of any respondent or other person to whom such information relates, except in the prosecution of alleged violations of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> All moneys received in payment for work or services enumerated under this section shall be deposited in a separate account which may be used to pay directly the costs of such work or services, to repay appropriations which initially bore all or part of such costs, or to refund excess sums when necessary.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 31, 1954, ch. 1158</ref>, <ref>68 Stat. 1013</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–207, § 4</ref>, <date date="1957-08-28">Aug. 28, 1957</date>, <ref>71 Stat. 481</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–521, § 6(a)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-17">Oct. 17, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2460</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9.</num>
<heading> Information as confidential; exception</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Neither the Secretary, nor any other officer or employee of the Department of Commerce or bureau or agency thereof, or local government census liaison, may, except as provided in section 8 or 16 or chapter 10 of this title or section 210 of the Departments of Commerce, Justice, and State, the Judiciary, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1998 or section 2(f) of the Census of Agriculture Act of 1997—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> use the information furnished under the provisions of this title for any purpose other than the statistical purposes for which it is supplied; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> make any publication whereby the data furnished by any particular establishment or individual under this title can be identified; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> permit anyone other than the sworn officers and employees of the Department or bureau or agency thereof to examine the individual reports.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">No department, bureau, agency, officer, or employee of the Government, except the Secretary in carrying out the purposes of this title, shall require, for any reason, copies of census reports which have been retained by any such establishment or individual. Copies of census reports which have been so retained shall be immune from legal process, and shall not, without the consent of the individual or establishment concerned, be admitted as evidence or used for any purpose in any action, suit, or other judicial or administrative proceeding.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The provisions of subsection (a) of this section relating to the confidential treatment of data for particular individuals and establishments, shall not apply to the censuses of governments provided for by subchapter III of chapter 5 of this title, nor to interim current data provided for by subchapter IV of chapter 5 of this title as to the subjects covered by censuses of governments, with respect to any information obtained therefor that is compiled from, or customarily provided in, public rec­ords.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 31, 1954, ch. 1158</ref>, <ref>68 Stat. 1013</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–813</ref>, <date date="1962-10-15">Oct. 15, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 922</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–533, § 5(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-07">Nov. 7, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 2348</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–430, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-31">Oct. 31, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4394</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–113, § 4(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-21">Nov. 21, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 2276</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–119, title II, § 210(k)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-26">Nov. 26, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 2487</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 10.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 86–682, § 12(a)</ref>, <date date="1960-09-02">Sept. 2, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 708</ref>, eff. <date date="1960-09-01">Sept. 1, 1960</date>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated, out of the Treasury of the United States, such sums as may be necessary to carry out all provisions of this title.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 31, 1954, ch. 1158</ref>, <ref>68 Stat. 1014</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12.</num>
<heading> Mechanical and electronic development</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to have conducted mechanical and electronic development work as he determines is needed to further the functions and duties of carrying out the purposes of this title and may enter into such developmental contracts as he may determine to be in the best interest of the Government.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 85–207, § 5</ref>, <date date="1957-08-28">Aug. 28, 1957</date>, <ref>71 Stat. 481</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 13.</num>
<heading> Procurement of professional services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall have authority to contract with educational and other research organizations for the preparation of monographs and other reports and materials of a similar nature.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 85–207, § 5</ref>, <date date="1957-08-28">Aug. 28, 1957</date>, <ref>71 Stat. 481</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 14.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 89–473, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1966-06-29">June 29, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 221</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 15.</num>
<heading> Leases for 1980 decennial census</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The 15 percent limitation contained in section 322 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002010">1</ref> of the Act of <date date="1932-06-30">June 30, 1932</date> (<ref>47 Stat. 412</ref>) shall not apply to leases entered into by the Secretary for the purpose of carrying out the 1980 decennial census, but no lease may be entered into for such purpose at a rental in excess of 105 percent of the appraised fair annual rental of the leased premises, or a proportionate part of the appraised fair annual rental in the case of a lease for less than a year.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–52, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1979-08-13">Aug. 13, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 358</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–178, § 4(c)</ref>, <date date="2003-12-15">Dec. 15, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2641</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 16.</num>
<heading> Address information reviewed by States and local governments</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary, to assist efforts to ensure the accuracy of censuses and surveys under this title, shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> publish standards defining the content and structure of address information which States and local units of general purpose government may submit to the Secretary to be used in developing a national address list;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> develop and publish a timetable for the Bureau to receive, review, and respond to submissions of information under paragraph (1) before the decennial census date; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provide for a response by the Bureau with respect to such submissions in which the Bureau specifies its determinations regarding such information and the reasons for such determinations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> be subject to the review process developed under section 3 of the Census Address List Improvement Act of 1994 relating to responses pursuant to paragraph (2).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall provide officials who are designated as census liaisons by a local unit of general purpose government with access to census address information for the purpose of verifying the accuracy of the address information of the Bureau for census and survey purposes; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> together with such access, should provide an explanation of duties and obligations under this title.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Access under paragraph (1) shall be limited to address information concerning addresses within the local unit of general purpose government represented by the census liaison or an adjacent local unit of general purpose government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Bureau should respond to each recommendation made by a census liaison concerning the accuracy of address information, including the determination (and reasons therefor) of the Bureau regarding each such recommendation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> For the purposes of paragraph (1), in a case in which a local unit of general purpose government is within another local unit of general purpose government and is not independent of the enclosing unit, the census liaison shall be designated by the local unit of general purpose government which is within the enclosing local unit of general purpose government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> A census liaison may not use information made available under paragraph (1) for any purpose other than the purpose specified in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> For the purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “local unit of general purpose government” has the meaning given such term by <ref>section 184(1) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “State” includes the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, American Samoa, Guam, the Virgin Islands, and any other territory or possession of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–430, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-31">Oct. 31, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4393</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>OFFICERS AND EMPLOYEES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 21.</num>
<heading> Director of the Census; duties</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Appointment.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Bureau shall be headed by a Director of the Census, appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, without regard to political affiliation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Qualifications</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Such appointment shall be made from individuals who have a demonstrated ability in managing large organizations and experience in the collection, analysis, and use of statistical data.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Term of Office.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term of office of the Director shall be 5 years, and shall begin on <date date="2012-01-01">January 1, 2012</date>, and every fifth year thereafter. An individual may not serve more than 2 full terms as Director.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Vacancies</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any individual appointed to fill a vacancy in such position, occurring before the expiration of the term for which such individual’s predecessor was appointed, shall be appointed for the remainder of that term. The Director may serve after the end of the Director’s term until reappointed or until a successor has been appointed, but in no event longer than 1 year after the end of such term.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Removal</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An individual serving as Director may be removed from office by the President. The President shall communicate in writing the reasons for any such removal to both Houses of Congress not later than 60 days before the removal.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Personnel actions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided under paragraph (3), nothing in this subsection shall prohibit a personnel action otherwise authorized by law with respect to the Director of the Census, other than removal.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duties</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Director shall perform such duties as may be imposed upon the Director by law, regulations, or orders of the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 31, 1954, ch. 1158</ref>, <ref>68 Stat. 1014</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–166, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="2012-08-10">Aug. 10, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1291</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 22.</num>
<heading> Qualifications of permanent personnel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All permanent officers and employees of the Bureau shall be citizens of the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 31, 1954, ch. 1158</ref>, <ref>68 Stat. 1014</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–769, § 1</ref>, <date date="1960-09-13">Sept. 13, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 911</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 23.</num>
<heading> Additional officers and employees</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary may establish, at rates of compensation to be fixed by him without regard to the Classification Act of 1949, as many temporary positions as may be necessary to meet the requirements of the work provided for by law. Bureau employees who are transferred to any such temporary positions shall not lose their permanent civil service status by reason of the transfer. The Secretary may make appointments to such temporary positions in conformity with the civil service laws and rules.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> In addition to employees of the Department of Commerce, employees of other departments and independent offices of the Government may, with the consent of the head of the respective department or office, be employed and compensated for field work in connection with the work provided for by law without regard to section 301 of the Dual Compensation Act.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Secretary may utilize temporary staff, including employees of Federal, State, or local agencies or instrumentalities, and employees of private organizations to assist the Bureau in performing the work authorized by this title, but only if such temporary staff is sworn to observe the limitations imposed by <ref>section 9 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 31, 1954, ch. 1158</ref>, <ref>68 Stat. 1014</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–769, § 2</ref>, <date date="1960-09-13">Sept. 13, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 911</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–448, title IV, § 401(p)</ref>, <date date="1964-08-19">Aug. 19, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 492</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–521, § 12(b)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-17">Oct. 17, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2465</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 24.</num>
<heading> Special employment provisions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary may utilize the services of nontemporary employees of the Bureau (by assignment, promotion, appointment, detail, or otherwise) in temporary positions established for any census, for not to exceed the period during which appropriations are available for that census. Whenever the Secretary determines that the services of an employee which have been utilized under this section are no longer required in such a temporary position, he may, without regard to the provisions of any other law, return the employee to a continuing position, with rank and compensation not less than that which he held in his last permanent position in the Bureau: <i>Provided</i>, That no employee shall, by reason of his service in a temporary position under this subsection, lose the protection of any law or regulation with respect to his separation, suspension, furlough, or reduction in rank or compensation below the level held in his last permanent position in the Bureau. Service by a nontemporary employee in a temporary position under this subsection shall be creditable for step-increases (both periodic and longevity) under title VII of the Classification Act of 1949, as amended, as though it were a continuation of service in his last permanent position.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> As used in this title with respect to appointments or positions, “temporary” shall be construed to mean not in excess of one year, or not in excess of the specific period during which appropriations are available for the conduct of a particular census, whichever is longer. No employee of the Bureau who holds only a temporary appointment within the meaning of this section shall be considered as other than strictly temporary for purposes of any other provision of law relating to separations, suspensions, or reductions in rank or compensation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The enlisted men and officers of the uniformed services may be appointed and compensated for service in temporary enumerator positions for the enumeration of personnel of the uniformed services.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The Secretary may fix compensation on a piece-price basis without limitation as to the amount earned per diem, and payments may be made to enumerators for the use of private automobiles on official business without regard to section 4 of the Travel Expense Act of 1949, as amended (<ref>5 U.S.C. 837</ref>), but at rates not in excess of the rates provided by that Act.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> The Secretary may authorize the expenditure of necessary sums for travel expenses of persons selected for appointment for attendance at training courses held by the Department of Commerce with respect to any of the work provided for by law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law prohibiting the expenditure of public money for telephone service, the Secretary, under such regulations as he shall prescribe, may authorize reimbursement for tolls or charges for telephone service from private residences or private apartments to the extent such charges are determined by the Secretary to have been incurred to facilitate the collection of information in connection with the censuses and surveys authorized by this title.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 31, 1954, ch. 1158</ref>, <ref>68 Stat. 1015</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–769, § 3</ref>, <date date="1960-09-13">Sept. 13, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 911</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–535</ref>, <date date="1964-08-31">Aug. 31, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 744</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 25.</num>
<heading> Duties of supervisors, enumerators, and other employees</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Each supervisor shall perform the duties imposed upon him by the Secretary in the enforcement of chapter 5 of this title in accordance with the Secretary’s orders and instructions.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Each enumerator or other employee detailed to serve as enumerator shall be charged with the collection in his subdivision of the facts and statistics called for on such schedules as the Secretary determines shall be used by him in connection with any census or survey provided for by chapter 5 of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 31, 1954, ch. 1158</ref>, <ref>68 Stat. 1015</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–530</ref>, <date date="1964-08-31">Aug. 31, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 737</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 26.</num>
<heading> Transportation by contract</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may contract with field employees for the rental and use within the continental limits of the United States of means of transportation, other than motorcycle, automobile, or airplane, and for the rental and use outside of the continental United States of any means of transportation, which means may be owned by the field employee. Such rental contracts shall be made without regard to section 4 of the Travel Expense Act of 1949, as amended (<ref>5 U.S.C. 837</ref>). The rentals shall be at rates equivalent to the prevailing rental rates of the locality. The rental contracts within the continental United States may be entered into only when the use by the field employee of such other means of transportation is safer, more economical, or more advantageous to the Government than use of his motorcycle, automobile, or airplane in conducting the census.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 85–207, § 6</ref>, <date date="1957-08-28">Aug. 28, 1957</date>, <ref>71 Stat. 482</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>