<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 3—</num>
<heading>COLLECTION AND PUBLICATION OF STATISTICS</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>COTTON</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 41.</num>
<heading> Collection and publication</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall collect and publish statistics concerning the—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> amount of cotton ginned;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> quantity of raw cotton consumed in manufacturing establishments of every character;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> quantity of baled cotton on hand;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> number of active consuming cotton spindles;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> number of active spindle hours; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> quantity of cotton imported and exported, with the country of origin and destination.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 31, 1954, ch. 1158</ref>, <ref>68 Stat. 1016</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 42.</num>
<heading> Contents of reports; number of bales of linter; distribution; publication by Department of Agriculture</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The statistics of the quantity of cotton ginned shall show the quantity ginned from each crop prior to August 1, September 1, September 15, October 1, October 15, November 1, November 15, December 1, December 15, January 1, January 15, February 1, and March 1; but the Secretary may limit the canvasses of August 1 and September 1 to those sections of the cotton-growing States in which cotton has been ginned.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The quantity of cotton consumed in manufacturing establishments, the quantity of baled cotton on hand, the number of active consuming cotton spindles, the number of active spindle-hours, and the statistics of cotton imported and exported shall relate to each month, and shall be published as soon as possible after the close of the month.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> In collecting and publishing statistics of cotton on hand in warehouses and other storage establishments, and of cotton known as the “carry-over” in the United States, the Secretary shall ascertain and publish as a separate item in the report of cotton statistics the number of bales of linters as distinguished from the number of bales of cotton.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall furnish to the Department of Agriculture, immediately prior to the publication of each report of that Department regarding the cotton crop, the latest available statistics hereinbefore mentioned, and the Department of Agriculture shall publish the same in connection with each of its reports concerning cotton.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 31, 1954, ch. 1158</ref>, <ref>68 Stat. 1016</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–331, § 4</ref>, <date date="1972-06-30">June 30, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 400</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 43.</num>
<heading> Records and reports of cotton ginners</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Every cotton ginner shall keep a record of the county or parish in which each bale of cotton ginned by him is grown and report at the completion of the ginning season, but not later than the March canvass, of each year a segregation of the total number of bales ginned by counties or parishes in which grown.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 31, 1954, ch. 1158</ref>, <ref>68 Stat. 1016</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–143</ref>, <date date="1971-10-15">Oct. 15, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 393</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 44.</num>
<heading> Foreign cotton statistics</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In addition to the information regarding cotton in the United States provided for in this subchapter, the Secretary shall compile, by correspondence or the use of published reports and documents, any available information concerning the production, consumption, and stocks of cotton in foreign countries, and the number of cotton-consuming spindles in such countries. Each report published by the Department of Commerce or agency or bureau thereof regarding cotton shall contain an abstract of the latest available information obtained under the provisions of this section, and the Secretary shall furnish the same to the Department of Agriculture for publication in connection with the reports of that department concerning cotton in the same manner as in the case of statistics relating to the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 31, 1954, ch. 1158</ref>, <ref>68 Stat. 1016</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 45.</num>
<heading> Simultaneous publication of cotton reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The reports of cotton ginned to the dates as of which the Department of Agriculture is also required to issue cotton crop reports shall be issued simultaneously with the cotton crop reports of that department, the two reports to be issued from the same place at 3 o’clock postmeridian on or before the 12th day of the month to which the respective reports relate.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 31, 1954, ch. 1158</ref>, <ref>68 Stat. 1017</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–331, § 3</ref>, <date date="1972-06-30">June 30, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 400</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>OILSEEDS, NUTS, AND KERNELS; FATS, OILS, AND GREASES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 61.</num>
<heading> Collection and publication</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary shall collect, collate, and publish monthly statistics concerning—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the quantities of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> cotton seed, soybeans, peanuts, flaxseed, corn germs, copra, sesame seed, babassu nuts and kernels, and other oilseeds, nuts, and kernels received, crushed, and on hand at oil mills;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> crude and refined oils, cakes, and meals, and other primary products, by type or kind, of the seeds, nuts, and kernels referred to in clause (A) of this paragraph, manufactured, shipped out, and on hand at oil mills and processing establishments;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> crude and refined vegetable oils, by type or kind, used by class of product and held by manufacturers of vegetable short­ening, margarine, soap, and other principal products using large quantities of vegetable oils;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> crude and refined vegetable oils, by type or kind, held in warehouses and in transit to consuming establishments; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the quantities, by types or kinds, of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> animal fats and oils and greases produced;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> animal fats and oils and greases shipped and held by producers;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> animal fats and oils and greases, fish and marine mammal oils used by class of product and held by manufacturers of short­ening, margarine, soap, and other principal products which require the use of large quantities of animal fats and oils and greases, fish and marine mammal oils;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> animal fats and oils and greases, fish and marine mammal oils held in warehouses, cold storage, and in transit to consuming establishments.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall not be required to collect, more frequently than he deems necessary to provide reliable statistical reports, information from any person who produces, holds, or consumes fats and oils in inconsequential quantities.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 31, 1954, ch. 1158</ref>, <ref>68 Stat. 1017</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 62.</num>
<heading> Additional statistics</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This subchapter does not restrict or limit the Secretary in the collection and publication, under the general authority of the Secretary, of such statistics on fats and oils or products thereof not specifically required in this subchapter, as he deems to be in the public interest.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 31, 1954, ch. 1158</ref>, <ref>68 Stat. 1018</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 63.</num>
<heading> Duplicate collection of statistics prohibited; access to available statistics</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Statistics required under Federal law, as of the effective date of this title, to be collected by any other Federal department or agency in a manner comparable both as to form and period of time to the collection of statistics provided for by this subchapter shall not be collected by the Secretary under the authority of this subchapter. Immediately upon his request, the Secretary shall have access to any such statistics and shall include them in the publication required by this subchapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 31, 1954, ch. 1158</ref>, <ref>68 Stat. 1018</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>APPAREL AND TEXTILES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 81.</num>
<heading> Statistics on apparel and textile industries</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall collect and publish quarterly statistics relating to domestic apparel and textile industries.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–467, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-14">Oct. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1192</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>QUARTERLY FINANCIAL STATISTICS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 91.</num>
<heading> Collection and publication</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall collect and publish quarterly financial statistics of business operations, organization, practices, management, and relation to other businesses, including data on sales, expenses, profits, assets, liabilities, stockholders’ equity, and related accounts generally used by businesses in income statements, balance sheets, and other measures of financial condition.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Except to the extent determined otherwise by the Secretary on the basis of changed circumstances, the nature of statistics collected and published under this section, and the manner of the collection and publication of such statistics, shall conform to the quarterly financial reporting program carried out by the Federal Trade Commission before the effective date of this section under section 6(b) of the Federal Trade Commission Act.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> For purposes of section 6103(j)(1) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, the conducting of the quarterly financial report program under this section shall be considered as the conducting of a related statistical activity authorized by law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary shall not select an organization or entity for participation in a survey, if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> the organization or entity—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> has assets of less than $50,000,000;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> completed participation in a prior survey in the preceding 10-year period, as determined by the Secretary; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> was selected for that prior survey participation after <date date="1990-09-30">September 30, 1990</date>; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> the organization or entity—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> has assets of more than $50,000,000 and less than $100,000,000;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> completed participation in a prior survey in the preceding 2-year period, as determined by the Secretary; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> was selected for that prior survey participation after <date date="1995-09-30">September 30, 1995</date>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall furnish advice and similar assistance to ease the burden of a small business concern which is attempting to compile and furnish the business information required of organizations and entities participating in the survey.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> To facilitate the provision of the assistance under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall establish a toll-free telephone number.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall expand the use of statistical sampling techniques to select organizations and entities having assets less than $100,000,000 to participate in the survey.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary may undertake such additional paperwork burden reduction initiatives with respect to the conduct of the survey as may be deemed appropriate by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of this subsection:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The term “small business concern” means a business concern that meets the requirements of section 3(a) of the Small Business Act and the regulations promulgated pursuant thereto.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The term “survey” means the collection of information by the Secretary pursuant to this section for the purpose of preparing the publication entitled “Quarterly Financial Report for Manufacturing, Mining, and Trade Corporations”.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 97–454, § 1(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1983-01-12">Jan. 12, 1983</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2494</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 2095</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–13, § 3</ref>, <date date="1995-05-22">May 22, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 184</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER V—</num>
<heading>MISCELLANEOUS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 101.</num>
<heading> Defective, dependent, and delinquent classes; crime</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary may collect decennially statistics relating—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to the defective, dependent, and delinquent classes; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to crime, including judicial statistics pertaining thereto.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The statistics authorized by subsection (a) of this section shall include information upon the following questions, namely: age, sex, color, nativity, parentage, literacy by race, color, nativity, and parentage, and such other questions relating to such subjects as the Secretary deems proper.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> In addition to the decennial collections authorized by subsections (a) and (b) of this section, the Secretary may compile and publish annually statistics relating to crime and to the defective, dependent, and delinquent classes.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 31, 1954, ch. 1158</ref>, <ref>68 Stat. 1018</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 102.</num>
<heading> Religion</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may collect decennially statistics relating to religious bodies.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 31, 1954, ch. 1158</ref>, <ref>68 Stat. 1018</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 103.</num>
<heading> Designation of reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All reports covering any of the statistics collected under the provisions of this subchapter shall be designated as “Special Reports” followed by the name of whatever bureau or agency of the Department of Commerce is designated by the Secretary to collect and compile such statistics.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 31, 1954, ch. 1158</ref>, <ref>68 Stat. 1018</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>