<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 11—</num>
<heading>MINING CLAIMS ON LANDS SUBJECT TO MINERAL LEASING LAWS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 501.</num>
<heading> Mining claims located between <date date="1939-07-31">July 31, 1939</date>, and <date date="1953-01-01">January 1, 1953</date></heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Force and effect</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subject to the provisions of this chapter and to any valid intervening rights acquired under laws of the United States, any mining claim located under the mining laws of the United States subsequent to <date date="1939-07-31">July 31, 1939</date>, and prior to <date date="1953-01-01">January 1, 1953</date>, on lands of the United States which were, at the time of such location—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> included in a permit or lease issued under the mineral leasing laws; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> covered by an application or offer for a permit or lease which had been filed under the mineral leasing laws; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> known to be valuable for minerals subject to disposition under the mineral leasing laws;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be effective to the same extent as if such mining claim had been located on lands which were at the time of such location subject to location under the mining laws of the United States: <i>Provided, however</i>, That in order to obtain the benefits of this chapter, the owner of any such mining claim shall, not later than one hundred and twenty days after <date date="1953-08-12">August 12, 1953</date>, post on such claim in the manner required for posting notice of location of mining claims and file for record in the office where the notice or certificate of location of such claim is of record an amended notice of location of such claim, stating that such notice is filed pursuant to the provisions of this chapter and for the purpose of obtaining the benefits thereof.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Labor and improvement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Labor performed or improvements made upon or for the benefit of such mining claims after the original location thereof shall be recognized as applicable thereto for all purposes to the same extent as labor performed and improvements made upon or for the benefit of mining claims which are not affected by this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Withdrawal or reservation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any withdrawal or reservation made after the original location of such mining claim affecting land covered by such mining claim is modified and amended so that the effect thereof upon such mining claim shall be the same as if such mining claim had been located upon lands of the United States, which, subsequent to <date date="1939-07-31">July 31, 1939</date>, and prior to the date of such withdrawal, were subject to location under the mining laws of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 12, 1953, ch. 405, § 1</ref>, <ref>67 Stat. 539</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 502.</num>
<heading> Reservation of minerals to the United States; rights of entry, disposition and removal</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any mining claim given force and effect as provided in <ref>section 501 of this title</ref> shall be subject to the reservation to the United States of all minerals which, upon <date date="1953-08-12">August 12, 1953</date>, are provided in the mineral leasing laws to be disposed of thereunder, and the right of the United States, its lessees, permittees, and licensees, to enter upon the land covered by such mining claim to prospect for, mine, treat, store, and remove such minerals, and to use so much of the surface and subsurface of such mining claim as may be necessary for such purposes, and to enter upon such land whenever reasonably necessary for the purpose of prospecting for, mining, treating, storing, and removing such minerals on and from other lands of the United States; and any patent issued for any such mining claim shall contain such reservation.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 12, 1953, ch. 405, § 2</ref>, <ref>67 Stat. 539</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 503.</num>
<heading> Reservations required by law; atomic energy materials</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The rights under any mining claim given force and effect by this chapter shall also be subject to the reservation to the United States specified in section 5(b)(7) of the Atomic Energy Act of 1946, as amended, and, in addition, any reservation or reservations required by any other provision or provisions of law; and any patent issued for such mining claim shall contain such reservations.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 12, 1953, ch. 405, § 3</ref>, <ref>67 Stat. 540</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 504.</num>
<heading> Power to make arrangements respecting atomic energy materials as unaffected</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as this chapter provides for (a) validation of certain mining claims located on lands described in <ref>section 501 of this title</ref>, and (b) the modification and amendment of certain withdrawals or reservations of land, nothing in this chapter shall affect any power or authority duly vested in the Atomic Energy Commission or any other agency, department or officer of the United States to make leases, withdrawals, reservations or other arrangements with respect to source materials as defined in section 5(b)(1) of the Atomic Energy Act of 1946, as amended.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 12, 1953, ch. 405, § 4</ref>, <ref>67 Stat. 540</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 505.</num>
<heading> “Mineral leasing laws” defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As used in this chapter “mineral leasing laws” shall mean the Act of <date date="1914-10-20">October 20, 1914</date> (<ref>38 Stat. 741</ref>); the Act of <date date="1920-02-25">February 25, 1920</date> (<ref>41 Stat. 437</ref>) [<ref>30 U.S.C. 181</ref> et seq.]; the Act of <date date="1926-04-17">April 17, 1926</date> (<ref>44 Stat. 301</ref>) [<ref>30 U.S.C. 271</ref> et seq.]; the Act of <date date="1927-02-07">February 7, 1927</date> (<ref>44 Stat. 1057</ref>) [<ref>30 U.S.C. 281</ref> et seq.] and all Acts heretofore or hereafter enacted which are amendatory of or supplementary to any of the foregoing Acts.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 12, 1953, ch. 405, § 5</ref>, <ref>67 Stat. 540</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>