<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 14—</num>
<heading>ANTHRACITE MINE DRAINAGE AND FLOOD CONTROL</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 571.</num>
<heading> Declaration of policy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is hereby recognized that the presence of large volumes of water in anthracite coal formations involves serious wastage of the fuel resources of the Nation, and constitutes a menace to health and safety and national security. It is therefore declared to be the policy of the Congress to provide for the control and drainage of water in the anthracite coal formations and thereby conserve natural resources, promote national security, prevent injuries and loss of life, and preserve public and private property, and to seal abandoned coal mines and to fill voids in abandoned coal mines, in those instances where such work is in the interest of the public health or safety.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 15, 1955, ch. 369, § 1</ref>, <ref>69 Stat. 352</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–818, § 1(1)</ref>, <date date="1962-10-15">Oct. 15, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 934</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 572.</num>
<heading> United States contributions to Pennsylvania: authority, conditions, limitations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior is authorized, in order to carry out the purposes mentioned in <ref>section 571 of this title</ref>, to make financial contributions on the basis of programs or projects approved by the Secretary to the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania (hereinafter designated as the “Commonwealth”) to seal abandoned coal mines and to fill voids in abandoned coal mines, in those instances where such work is in the interest of the public health or safety, and for control and drainage of water which, if not so controlled or drained, will cause the flooding of anthracite coal formations, said contributions to be applied to the cost of drainage works, pumping plants, and related facilities but subject, however, to the following conditions and limitations:</chapeau>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contributions to be matched by Commonwealth</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The amounts authorized to be contributed by the Secretary of the Interior to the Commonwealth shall be equally matched by the Commonwealth;</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amount of contributions authorized</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The total amount of contributions by the Secretary of the Interior under the authority of this chapter shall not exceed $8,500,000, of which $1,500,000 of the unexpended balance remaining as of <date date="1962-07-31">July 31, 1962</date>, shall be reserved for the control and drainage of water;</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on use of contribution</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The amounts contributed by the Secretary of the Interior under the authority of this chapter and the equally matched amounts contributed by the Commonwealth shall not be used for operating and maintaining projects constructed pursuant to this chapter or for the purchase of culm, rock, or spoil banks;</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Commonwealth responsible for installation and operation of projects</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commonwealth shall have full responsibility for installing, operating, and maintaining projects constructed pursuant to this chapter, and shall give evidence, satisfactory to the Secretary of the Interior, that it will enforce effective installation, operation, and maintenance safeguards;</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Location and operation of projects</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Projects constructed pursuant to this chapter shall be so located, operated, and maintained as to provide the maximum conservation of anthracite coal resources or, in those instances where such work would be in the interest of the public health or safety, to seal abandoned coal mines and to fill voids in abandoned coal mines, and, where possible, to avoid creating inequities among those mines which may be affected by the waters to be controlled thereby; and</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Economic justification for abandoned coal mine projects</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Projects for the sealing of abandoned coal mines or the filling of voids in abandoned coal mines shall be determined by the Secretary of the Interior to be economically justified. The Secretary shall not find any project to be economically justified unless the potential benefits are estimated by him to exceed the estimated cost of the project.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 15, 1955, ch. 369, § 2</ref>, <ref>69 Stat. 353</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–818, § 1(2)</ref>–(7), <date date="1962-10-15">Oct. 15, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 934</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 573.</num>
<heading> Statement by Commonwealth for Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commonwealth shall furnish to the Secretary of the Interior a statement with respect to the project showing work done, the status of the project, expenditures and amounts obligated, at such times and in such detail as the Secretary of the Interior shall require for the purposes of this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 15, 1955, ch. 369, § 3</ref>, <ref>69 Stat. 353</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 574.</num>
<heading> Hearings; withholding payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever the Secretary of the Interior, after reasonable notice and opportunity for hearing, finds that there is a failure to expend funds in accordance with the terms and conditions governing the Federal contribution for such approved projects, he shall notify the Commonwealth that further payments will not be made to the Commonwealth from appropriations under this chapter until he is satisfied that there will no longer be any such failure. Until he is so satisfied the Secretary of the Interior shall withhold the payment of any financial contributions to the Commonwealth.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 15, 1955, ch. 369, § 4</ref>, <ref>69 Stat. 353</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 575.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 105–362, title IX, § 901(i)(1)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-10">Nov. 10, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3290</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 576.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is hereby authorized to be appropriated such amounts as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 15, 1955, ch. 369, § 5</ref>, formerly § 6, <ref>69 Stat. 353</ref>; renumbered § 5, <ref>Pub. L. 105–362, title IX, § 901(i)(2)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-10">Nov. 10, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3290</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>