<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 12A—</num>
<heading>ENTRY AND LOCATION ON COAL LANDS ON DISCOVERY OF SOURCE MATERIAL</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 541.</num>
<heading> Entry and location; filing of copy of notice of mining location; report and payment for lignite mined; mineral patents; reservation of minerals to United States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to the conditions and provisions of this chapter and to any valid intervening rights acquired under the laws of the United States, public lands of the United States classified as or known to be valuable for coal subject to disposition under the mineral leasing laws and which are open to location and entry subject to the conditions and provisions of chapter 12 of this title, unless embraced within a coal prospecting permit or lease, shall also be open to location and entry under the mining laws of the United States upon the discovery of a valuable source material occurring within any seam, bed, or deposit of lignite in such lands: <i>Provided</i>, That a copy of the notice of any mining location made for source material occurring in any such bed, seam, or deposit, shall be filed for record in the land office of the Bureau of Land Management for the State in which the claim is situated within ninety days after the date of its location: <i>Provided further</i>, That the claimant to any such mining location shall report annually to the Mining Supervisor of the Geological Survey the amount of lignite mined or stripped in the recovery of such valuable source material during each calendar year and tender payment to him of 10 cents per ton thereon. Any mineral patents issued hereunder shall be made subject to the recording and payment requirements of this section and shall contain a reservation to the United States of all Leasing Act minerals owned by the United States other than lignite containing valuable source material and lignite necessary to be stripped or mined in the recovery of such material. Mining claims located and mineral patents issued under the provisions of this chapter shall not include rights to lignite not containing valuable source material except to the extent it may be necessary to mine or strip such lignite in order to mine the source material and, with respect to lode claims, shall not include extralateral rights. For all purposes of this chapter “source material” and “lignite” shall have the meanings given in <ref>section 541e of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 11, 1955, ch. 795, § 1</ref>, <ref>69 Stat. 679</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 541a.</num>
<heading> Claims located prior to <date date="1955-05-25">May 25, 1955</date>; extra­lateral rights; amended notice of mining location</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any mining claim located in a manner prescribed by the mining laws of the United States upon lands of the character described in <ref>section 541 of this title</ref>, prior to <date date="1955-05-25">May 25, 1955</date>, if based upon a discovery of valuable source material contained in lignite shall be effective to the same extent as if such lands at the time of location, and at all times thereafter, had not been classified as or known to be valuable for coal subject to disposition under the mineral leasing laws, subject, however, to the provisions of <ref>section 541 of this title</ref>: <i>Provided</i>, That no extralateral rights shall attach to any mining location validated under this section: <i>And provided further</i>, That the locator or locators of such a mining claim shall, not later than one hundred and eighty days from and after <date date="1955-08-11">August 11, 1955</date>, post on the claim and file for record in the office where the notice or certificate of location is of record, an amended notice of the mining location stating that such amended notice is filed pursuant to the provisions of this chapter and for the purpose of obtaining the benefits thereof; and that a copy of said amended notice is, within the said one-hundred-and-eighty-day period, filed in the land office of the Bureau of Land Management for the State in which the mining location is situated, and the mining locator thereafter complies with the requirements of this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 11, 1955, ch. 795, § 2</ref>, <ref>69 Stat. 679</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 541b.</num>
<heading> Mining, removal, and disposal of lignite</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to the provisos of <ref>section 541a of this title</ref>, any mining location made under the mining laws of the United States, including chapter 12 of this title, on lands of the character described in <ref>section 541 of this title</ref>, except locations made for lands within the exterior boundaries of a prior coal prospecting permit or lease, if based upon a discovery of valuable source material in deposits other than deposits of Leasing Act minerals, shall include the right to mine, remove, and dispose of lignite containing valuable source material and lignite necessary to be stripped or mined in the recovery of source material contained in lignite, subject to the reporting and payment requirements of <ref>section 541 of this title</ref>, and subject to the provisions of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 [<ref>42 U.S.C. 2011</ref> et. seq.], and upon filing in the land office designated in <ref>section 541 of this title</ref>, an adequate description of his claim or claims containing such lignite: <i>Provided</i>, That nothing in this section shall be construed to limit or restrict the rights acquired by virtue of a mining claim heretofore or hereafter located, under the 1872 Mining Act, as amended, or to impose any additional obligation with respect to the mining and removal of source material which does not occur within any seam, bed, or deposit of lignite.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 11, 1955, ch. 795, § 3</ref>, <ref>69 Stat. 680</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 541c.</num>
<heading> Lands where coal deposits have been reserved to the United States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The entryman or owner of any land or the assignee of rights therein, including lands granted to States, with respect to which the coal deposits have been reserved to the United States pursuant to the provisions of <ref>section 81 of this title</ref> or sections 83 to 85 of this title, excepting lands embraced within a coal prospecting permit or lease, upon the discovery of valuable source material in lignite situated within such entered, granted, or patented lands, who, except for the reservation of coal to the United States would have the right to mine and remove such source material, shall have the exclusive right to mine, remove, and dispose of lignite containing such source material and lignite necessary to be stripped or mined in the recovery of such material, subject to the reporting and payment requirements of <ref>section 541 of this title</ref>, and subject to the provisions of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 [<ref>42 U.S.C. 2011</ref> et seq.], upon filing in the land office designated in <ref>section 541 of this title</ref>, an adequate description sufficient to identify the land containing such lignite.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 11, 1955, ch. 795, § 4</ref>, <ref>69 Stat. 680</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 541d.</num>
<heading> Location of source materials by holders of coal leases</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The holders of coal leases issued under the provision of the mineral leasing laws, including chapter 7 of this title, prior to <date date="1955-08-11">August 11, 1955</date>, or thereafter if based upon a prospecting permit issued prior to that date, upon the discovery during the term of such lease of valuable source material in any bed or deposit of lignite situated within the leased lands, shall have the exclusive right to locate such source material under the provisions of this chapter but the mining and disposal of such source material shall be subject to the operating provisions of the lease and to the provisions of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 [<ref>42 U.S.C. 2011</ref> et seq.]: <i>Provided</i>, That the provisions of this section shall not apply to coal prospecting, permits or leases on lands embraced within entered, granted or patented lands described in <ref>section 541c of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 11, 1955, ch. 795, § 5</ref>, <ref>69 Stat. 680</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 541e.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As used in this chapter “mineral leasing laws” shall mean the Act of <date date="1914-10-20">October 20, 1914</date> (<ref>38 Stat. 741</ref>); the Act of <date date="1920-02-25">February 25, 1920</date> (<ref>41 Stat. 437</ref>) [<ref>30 U.S.C. 181</ref> et seq.]; the Act of <date date="1926-04-17">April 17, 1926</date> (<ref>44 Stat. 301</ref>) [<ref>30 U.S.C. 271</ref> et seq.]; the Act of <date date="1927-02-07">February 7, 1927</date> (<ref>44 Stat. 1057</ref>) [<ref>30 U.S.C. 281</ref> et seq.]; and all Acts heretofore or hereafter enacted which are amendatory of or supplementary to any of the foregoing Acts; “Leasing Act minerals” shall mean all minerals which, upon <date date="1955-08-11">August 11, 1955</date>, are provided in the mineral leasing laws to be disposed of thereunder; “lignite” shall mean coal classified as ASTM designation: D 388–38, according to the standards established in the American Society for Testing Materials on Coal and Coke under standard specifications for Classification of Coals by Rank, contained in public-land deposits considered as valuable under the coal-land classification standards established by the Secretary of the Interior and prescribed in section 30, Code of Federal Regulations, part 201; and “source material” shall mean uranium, thorium, or any other material which is determined by the Atomic Energy Commission pursuant to the provisions of <ref>section 2091 of title 42</ref> to be source material.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 11, 1955, ch. 795, § 6</ref>, <ref>69 Stat. 680</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 541f.</num>
<heading> Disbursement of moneys</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All moneys received under the provisions of this chapter shall be paid into the Treasury of the United States and distributed in the same manner as provided in <ref>section 191 of this title</ref> and sections 437, 438, and 439 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002029">1</ref> of title 48.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 11, 1955, ch. 795, § 7</ref>, <ref>69 Stat. 681</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 541g.</num>
<heading> Rules and regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior is authorized to issue such rules and regulations as may be necessary or appropriate to effectuate the purposes of this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 11, 1955, ch. 795, § 8</ref>, <ref>69 Stat. 681</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 541h.</num>
<heading> Savings provision</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall be deemed to amend or repeal any provisions of chapter 12 of this title, or any right granted thereunder.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 11, 1955, ch. 795, § 9</ref>, <ref>69 Stat. 681</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 541i.</num>
<heading> Withdrawal of lands from entry; expiration of claims</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Twenty years after <date date="1955-08-11">August 11, 1955</date>, all lands subject to the provisions of <ref>section 541 of this title</ref> shall be withdrawn from all forms of entry under this chapter. All claims made pursuant to the provisions of this chapter shall expire at that time, except for (1) claims for which patent has already been issued, and (2) claims on which application for patent has already been made and on which patent is subsequently issued: <i>Provided</i>, That, if the President shall so provide by Executive order, the provisions of this section shall not become effective until thirty years after <date date="1955-08-11">August 11, 1955</date>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 11, 1955, ch. 795, § 10</ref>, <ref>69 Stat. 681</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>