<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 3—</num>
<heading>LANDS CONTAINING COAL, OIL, GAS, SALTS, ASPHALTIC MATERIALS, SODIUM, SULPHUR, AND BUILDING STONE</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>COAL LAND ENTRIES IN GENERAL</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 71.</num>
<heading> Entry of unappropriated or unreserved Federal coal lands; eligibility; application; acreage limitation; price per acre</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Every person above the age of twenty-one years, who is a citizen of the United States, or who has declared his intention to become such, or any association of persons severally qualified as above, shall, upon application to the register of the proper land office, have the right to enter, by legal subdivisions, any quantity of vacant coal lands of the United States not otherwise appropriated or reserved by competent authority, not exceeding one hundred and sixty acres to such individual person, or three hundred and twenty acres to such association, upon payment to the register of not less than $10 per acre for such lands, where the same shall be situated more than fifteen miles from any completed railroad, and not less than $20 per acre for such lands as shall be within fifteen miles of such road.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(R.S. § 2347; <ref>Mar. 3, 1925, ch. 462</ref>, <ref>43 Stat. 1145</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 72.</num>
<heading> Preference right of coal mine entry; acreage limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any person or association of persons severally qualified, as provided in <ref>section 71 of this title</ref>, who have opened and improved, or shall open and improve, any coal mine or mines upon the public lands, and shall be in actual possession of the same, shall be entitled to a preference right of entry, under <ref>section 71 of this title</ref>, of the mines so opened and improved: <i>Provided</i>, That when any association of not less than four persons, severally qualified as provided in <ref>section 71 of this title</ref>, shall have expended not less than $5,000 in working and improving any such mine or mines, such association may enter not exceeding six hundred and forty acres, including such mining improvements.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(R.S. § 2348.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 73.</num>
<heading> Presentation of claims</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All claims under <ref>section 72 of this title</ref> must be presented to the register of the proper land district within sixty days after the date of actual possession and the commencement of improvements on the land, by the filing of a declaratory statement therefor; but when the township plat is not on file at the date of such improvement, filing must be made within sixty days from the receipt of such plat at the district office.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(R.S. § 2349.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 74.</num>
<heading> Number of coal land entries; other entries upon noncompliance with conditions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Sections 71 to 73 of this title shall be held to authorize only one entry by the same person or association of persons; and no association of persons any member of which shall have taken the benefit of such sections, either as an individual or as a member of any other association, shall enter or hold any other lands under the provisions thereof; and no member of any association which shall have taken the benefit of such sections shall enter or hold any other lands under their provisions; and all persons claiming under <ref>section 72 of this title</ref> shall be required to prove their respective rights and pay for the lands filed upon within one year from the time prescribed for filing their respective claims; and upon failure to file the proper notice, or to pay for the land within the required period, the same shall be subject to entry by any other qualified applicant.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(R.S. § 2350.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 75.</num>
<heading> Conflicting claims upon coal lands; rules and regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In case of conflicting claims upon coal lands where the improvements shall be commenced, after the third day of March, 1873, priority of possession and improvement, followed by proper filing and continued good faith, shall determine the preference right to purchase. And also where improvements have already been made prior to the third day of March, 1873, division of the land claimed may be made by legal subdivisions, to include, as near as may be, the valuable improvements of the respective parties. The Director of the Bureau of Land Management is authorized to issue all needful rules and regulations for carrying into effect the provisions of this section and sections 71 to 74 of this title.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(R.S. § 2351; 1946 Reorg. Plan No. 3, § 403, eff. <date date="1946-07-16">July 16, 1946</date>, 11 F.R. 7876, <ref>60 Stat. 1100</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 76.</num>
<heading> Reservation of rights upon coal lands; sale of certain mining lands</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in sections 71 to 75 of this title shall be construed to destroy or impair any rights which may have attached prior to the third day of March, 1873, or to authorize the sale of lands valuable for mines of gold, silver, or copper.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(R.S. § 2352.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 77.</num>
<heading> Alabama coal lands; agricultural entry</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Unreserved public lands containing coal deposits in the State of Alabama which on <date date="1912-04-23">April 23, 1912</date>, were being withheld from homestead entry under the provisions of <ref>section 171 of this title</ref>, may be entered under the homestead laws of the United States subject to the provisions, terms, conditions, and limitations prescribed in sections 83 to 85 of this title.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Apr. 23, 1912, ch. 87</ref>, <ref>37 Stat. 90</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>COAL LAND ENTRIES UNDER NONMINERAL LAND LAWS WITH RESERVATION OF COAL TO UNITED STATES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 81.</num>
<heading> Rights of entrymen of lands subsequently classified as coal lands; disposal of coal deposits</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any person who has in good faith located, selected, or entered under the nonmineral land laws of the United States any lands which subsequently are classified, claimed, or reported as being valuable for coal, may, if he shall so elect, and upon making satisfactory proof of compliance with the laws under which such lands are claimed, receive a patent therefor, which shall contain a reservation to the United States of all coal in said lands, and the right to prospect for, mine, and remove the same. The coal deposits in such lands shall be subject to disposal by the United States in accordance with the provisions of the coal land laws in force at the time of such disposal, but no person shall enter upon said lands to prospect for, or mine and remove coal therefrom, without previous consent of the owner under such patent, except upon such conditions as to security for and payment of all damages to such owner caused thereby as may be determined by a court of competent jurisdiction. The owner under such patent shall have the right to mine coal for use on the land for domestic purposes prior to the disposal by the United States of the coal deposit. Nothing herein contained shall be held to affect or abridge the right of any locator, selector, or entryman to a hearing for the purpose of determining the character of the land located, selected, or entered by him. Such locator, selector, or entryman who has made or shall make final proof showing good faith and satisfactory compliance with the law under which his land is claimed shall be entitled to a patent without reservation unless at the time of such final proof and entry it shall be shown that the land is chiefly valuable for coal.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 3, 1909, ch. 270</ref>, <ref>35 Stat. 844</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 82.</num>
<heading> New or supplemental patents, in case of lands subsequently classified as noncoal</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior is authorized and directed in cases where patents for public lands have been issued to entrymen under the provisions of sections 81 and 83 to 85 of this title, reserving to the United States all coal deposits therein, and lands so patented are subsequently classified as noncoal in character, to issue new or supplemental patents without such reservation.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Apr. 14, 1914, ch. 55</ref>, <ref>38 Stat. 335</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 83.</num>
<heading> Homestead or desert-land and other entries</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Unreserved public lands of the United States exclusive of Alaska which have been withdrawn or classified as coal lands, or are valuable for coal, shall be subject to appropriate entry under the homestead laws by actual settlers only, the desert-land law, to selection under <ref>section 641 of title 43</ref>, and to withdrawal under the Act approved June seventeenth, nineteen hundred and two, known as the Reclamation Act, whenever such entry, selection, or withdrawal shall be made with a view of obtaining or passing title, with a reservation to the United States of the coal in such lands and of the right to prospect for, mine, and remove the same. But all homestead entries made hereunder shall be subject to the conditions, as to residence and cultivation, of entries under <ref>section 218 of title 43</ref>. Those who have initiated nonmineral entries, selections, or locations in good faith, prior to <date date="1910-06-22">June 22, 1910</date>, on lands withdrawn or classified as coal lands may perfect the same under the provisions of the laws under which said entries were made, but shall receive the limited patent provided for in sections 83 to 85 of this title.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 22, 1910, ch. 318, § 1</ref>, <ref>36 Stat. 583</ref>; <ref>June 16, 1955, ch. 145, § 1</ref>, <ref>69 Stat. 138</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 84.</num>
<heading> Applications for entry</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any person desiring to make entry under the homestead laws or the desert-land law, any State desiring to make selection under <ref>section 641 of title 43</ref>, and the Secretary of the Interior in withdrawing under the Reclamation Act lands classified as coal lands, or valuable for coal, with a view of securing or passing title to the same in accordance with the provisions of said Acts, shall state in the application for entry, selection, or notice of withdrawal that the same is made in accordance with and subject to the provisions and reservations of sections 83 to 85 of this title.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 22, 1910, ch. 318, § 2</ref>, <ref>36 Stat. 584</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 85.</num>
<heading> Patents for lands, with reservation of coal; disposal of coal deposits</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon satisfactory proof of full compliance with the provisions of the laws under which entry is made, and of sections 83 to 85 of this title, the entryman shall be entitled to a patent to the land entered by him, which patent shall contain a reservation to the United States of all the coal in the lands so patented, together with the right to prospect for, mine, and remove the same. The coal deposits in such lands shall be subject to disposal by the United States in accordance with the provisions of the coal-land laws in force at the time of such disposal. Any person qualified to acquire coal deposits or the right to mine and remove the coal under the laws of the United States shall have the right, at all times, to enter upon the lands selected, entered, or patented, as provided by sections 83 to 85 of this title, for the purpose of pros­pecting for coal thereon upon the approval by the Secretary of the Interior of a bond or undertaking to be filed with him as security for the payment of all damages to the crops and improvements on such lands by reason of such prospecting. Any person who has acquired from the United States the coal deposits in any such land, or the right to mine or remove the same, may reenter and occupy so much of the surface thereof as may be required for all purposes reasonably incident to the mining and removal of the coal therefrom, and mine and remove the coal, upon payment of the damages caused thereby to the owner thereof, or upon giving a good and sufficient bond or undertaking in an action instituted in any competent court to ascertain and fix said damages. The owner under such limited patent shall have the right to mine coal for use upon the land for domestic purposes at any time prior to the disposal by the United States of the coal deposits. Nothing herein contained shall be held to deny or abridge the right to present and have prompt consideration of applications to locate, enter, or select, under the land laws of the United States, lands which have been classified as coal lands with a view of disproving such classification and securing a patent without reservation.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 22, 1910, ch. 318, § 3</ref>, <ref>36 Stat. 584</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 86.</num>
<heading> Disposition of lands in Indian reservations with reservation of coal; examination and appraisal of lands</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In any Indian reservation opened to settlement and entry pursuant to a classification of the surplus lands therein as mineral and nonmineral, such surplus lands not otherwise reserved or disposed of, which have been or may be withdrawn or classified as coal lands or are valuable for coal deposits, shall be subject to the same disposition as is or may be prescribed by law for the nonmineral lands in such reservation whenever proper application shall be made with a view of obtaining title to such lands, with a reservation to the United States of the coal deposits therein and of the right to prospect for, mine, and remove the same. Such surplus lands, prior to any disposition hereunder, shall be examined, separated into classes the same as are the nonmineral lands in such reservations, and appraised, as to their value, exclusive of the coal deposits therein, under such rules and regulations as shall be prescribed by the Secretary of the Interior for that purpose.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Feb. 27, 1917, ch. 133, § 1</ref>, <ref>39 Stat. 944</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 87.</num>
<heading> Statements in application; patents</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any applicant for lands mentioned in <ref>section 86 of this title</ref> shall state in his application that the same is made in accordance with and subject to the provisions and reservations of sections 86 to 89 of this title, and upon submission of satisfactory proof of full compliance with the provisions of law under which application or entry is made and of sections 86 to 89 of this title shall be entitled to a patent to the lands applied for and entered by him, which patent shall contain a reservation to the United States of all the coal deposits in the lands so patented, together with the right to prospect for, mine, and remove the same.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Feb. 27, 1917, ch. 133, § 2</ref>, <ref>39 Stat. 945</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 88.</num>
<heading> Disposition of coal by United States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the coal-land laws have been or shall be extended over lands applied for, entered, or patented hereunder the coal deposits therein shall be subject to disposal by the United States in accordance with the provisions of the coal-land laws in force at the time of such disposal. Any person qualified to acquire coal deposits or the right to mine and remove the coal under the laws of the United States shall have the right at all times to enter upon the lands applied for, entered, or patented under sections 86 to 89 of this title, for the purpose of prospecting for coal thereon, if such coal deposits are then subject to disposition, upon the approval by the Secretary of the Interior of a bond or undertaking to be filed with him as security for the payment of all damages to the crops and improvements on such lands by reason of such prospecting. Any person who has acquired from the United States the coal deposits in any such lands, or the right to mine or remove the same, may reenter and occupy so much of the surface thereof as may be required for all purposes reasonably incident to the mining and removal of the coal therefrom, and mine and remove the coal, upon payment of the damages caused thereby to the owner thereof, or upon giving a good and sufficient bond or undertaking in an action instituted in any competent court to ascertain and fix said damages. The owner under such limited patent shall have the right to mine coal for personal use upon the land for domestic purposes at any time prior to the disposal by the United States of the coal deposits. Nothing herein contained shall be held to deny or abridge the right to present and have prompt consideration of applications made under the applicable land laws of the United States for any such surplus lands which have been or may be classified as coal lands with a view of disproving such classification and securing a patent without reservation.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Feb. 27, 1917, ch. 133, § 3</ref>, <ref>39 Stat. 945</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 89.</num>
<heading> Disposition of proceeds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The net proceeds derived from the sale and entry of surplus lands in conformity with the provisions of sections 86 to 89 of this title shall be paid into the Treasury of the United States to the credit of the same fund under the same conditions and limitations as are or may be prescribed by law for the disposition of the proceeds arising from the disposal of other surplus lands in such Indian reservation. The provisions of sections 86 to 89 of this title shall not apply to the lands of the Five Civilized Tribes of Indians in Oklahoma.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Feb. 27, 1917, ch. 133, § 4</ref>, <ref>39 Stat. 945</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 90.</num>
<heading> Selection of coal lands by States; sale in isolated or disconnected tracts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Unreserved public lands of the United States, exclusive of Alaska, which have been withdrawn or classified as coal lands or are valuable for coal shall, in addition to the classes of entries or filings described in sections 83 to 85 of this title be subject to selection by the several States within whose limits the lands are situate, under grants made by Congress, and to disposition, in the discretion of the Secretary of the Interior, under the laws providing for the sale of isolated or disconnected tracts of public lands, but there shall be a reservation to the United States of the coal in all such lands so selected or sold and of the right to prospect for, mine, and remove the same in accordance with the provisions of said sections, and such lands shall be subject to all the conditions and limitations of said sections.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Apr. 30, 1912, ch. 99</ref>, <ref>37 Stat. 105</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>PETROLEUM, OTHER MINERAL OIL, OR GAS LAND ENTRIES UNDER MINING LAWS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 101.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 102.</num>
<heading> Assessment work on contiguous oil lands, located as claims, of same owner</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Where oil lands are located under the provisions of sections 21, 22 to 24, 26 to 28, 29, 30, 33 to 48, 50 to 52, 71 to 76 of this title and <ref>section 661 of title 43</ref> as placer mining claims, the annual assessment labor upon such claims may be done upon any one of a group of claims lying contiguous and owned by the same person or corporation, not exceeding five claims in all, where such labor will tend to the development or to determine the oil-bearing character of such contiguous claims.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Feb. 12, 1903, ch. 548</ref>, <ref>32 Stat. 825</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 103.</num>
<heading> Patents for oil or gas lands not denied because of transfer before discovery of oil or gas; acreage limitation; nonapplication to withdraw lands</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In no case shall patent be denied to or for any lands located or claimed prior to <date date="1911-03-02">March 2, 1911</date>, under the mining laws of the United States containing petroleum, mineral oil, or gas solely because of any transfer or assignment thereof or of any interest or interests therein by the original locator or locators, or any of them, to any qualified persons or person or corporation, prior to discovery of oil or gas therein, but if such claim is in all other respects valid and regular, patent therefor not exceeding one hundred and sixty acres in any one claim shall issue to the holder or holders thereof, as in other cases. The above provisions shall not apply where such lands were at the time of inception of development on or under such claim withdrawn from mineral entry.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 2, 1911, ch. 201, § 1</ref>, <ref>36 Stat. 1015</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 104.</num>
<heading> Agreements with applicants for patents as to disposition of oil or gas, or proceeds thereof, pending determination of title; Navy Petroleum Fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Where applications for patents have been or may be offered for any oil or gas land included in an order of withdrawal upon which oil or gas had been discovered, or was being produced prior to <date date="1911-03-02">March 2, 1911</date>, or upon which drilling operations were in actual progress on <date date="1910-10-03">October 3, 1910</date>, and oil or gas is thereafter discovered thereon, and where there has been no final determination by the Secretary of the Interior upon such applications for patent, said Secretary, in his discretion, may enter into agreements, under such conditions as he may prescribe with such applicants for patents in possession of such land or any portions thereof, relative to the disposition of the oil or gas produced therefrom or the proceeds thereof, pending final determination of the title thereto by the Secretary of the Interior, or such other disposition of the same as may be authorized by law. Any money which may accrue to the United States under the provisions of sections 103 and 104 of this title from lands within the Naval Petroleum Reserves shall be set aside for the needs of the Navy and deposited in the Treasury to the credit of a fund to be known as the Navy Petroleum Fund, which fund shall be applied to the needs of the Navy as Congress may from time to time direct, by appropriation or otherwise.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 2, 1911, ch. 201, § 2</ref>, as added <ref>Aug. 25, 1914, ch. 287</ref>, <ref>38 Stat. 708</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>HOMESTEAD ENTRY OF LANDS IN UTAH, WITHDRAWN OR CLASSIFIED AS OIL LANDS</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 111 to 113.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Dec. 16, 1930, ch. 14, § 1</ref>, <ref>46 Stat. 1028</ref></heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER V—</num>
<heading>AGRICULTURAL ENTRY OF LANDS WITHDRAWN OR CLASSIFIED AS CONTAINING PHOSPHATE, NITRATE, POTASH, OIL, GAS, ASPHALTIC MINERALS, SODIUM, OR SULPHUR</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 121.</num>
<heading> Agricultural entry or purchase of lands withdrawn or classified as containing phosphate, nitrate, potash, oil, or gas; reservations to United States; application</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Lands withdrawn or classified as phosphate, nitrate, potash, oil, gas, or asphaltic minerals, or which are valuable for those deposits, shall be subject to appropriation, location, selection, entry, or purchase, if otherwise available, under the nonmineral land laws of the United States, whenever such location, selection, entry, or purchase shall be made with a view of obtaining or passing title with a reservation to the United States of the deposits on account of which the lands were withdrawn or classified or reported as valuable, together with the right to prospect for, mine, and remove the same. All applications to locate, select, enter, or purchase under this section shall state that the same are made in accordance with and subject to the provisions and reservations of sections 121 to 123 of this title.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 17, 1914, ch. 142, § 1</ref>, <ref>38 Stat. 509</ref>; <ref>June 16, 1955, ch. 145, § 2</ref>, <ref>69 Stat. 138</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 122.</num>
<heading> Patents; reservation in the United States of reserved deposits; acquisition of right to remove deposits; application for entry to disprove classification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon satisfactory proof of full compliance with the provisions of the laws under which the location, selection, entry, or purchase is made, the locator, selector, entryman, or purchaser shall be entitled to a patent to the land located, selected, entered, or purchased, which patent shall contain a reservation to the United States of the deposits on account of which the lands so patented were withdrawn or classified or reported as valuable, together with the right to prospect for, mine, and remove the same, such deposits to be subject to disposal by the United States only as shall be hereafter expressly directed by law: <i>Provided, however</i>, That all mineral deposits heretofore or hereafter reserved to the United States under sections 121 to 123 of this title which are subject, at the time of application for patent, to valid and subsisting rights acquired by discovery and location under the mining laws of the United States made prior to the date of the Mineral Leasing Act of <date date="1920-02-25">February 25, 1920</date> [<ref>30 U.S.C. 181</ref> et seq.], shall hereafter be subject to disposal to the holders of those valid and subsisting rights by patent under the mining laws of the United States in force at the time of such disposal. Any person qualified to acquire the reserved deposits may enter upon said lands with a view of prospecting for the same upon the approval by the Secretary of the Interior of a bond or undertaking to be filed with him as security for the payment of all damages to the crops and improvements on such lands by reason of such prospecting, the measure of any such damage to be fixed by agreement of parties or by a court of competent jurisdiction. Any person who has acquired from the United States the title to or the right to mine and remove the reserved deposits, should the United States dispose of the mineral deposits in lands, may reenter and occupy so much of the surface thereof as may be required for all purposes reasonably incident to the mining and removal of the minerals therefrom, and mine and remove such minerals, upon payment of damages caused thereby to the owner of the land, or upon giving a good and sufficient bond or undertaking therefor in an action instituted in any competent court to ascertain and fix said damages. Nothing herein contained shall be held to deny or abridge the right to present and have prompt consideration of applications to locate, select, enter, or purchase, under the land laws of the United States, lands which have been withdrawn or classified as phosphate, nitrate, potash, oil, gas, or asphaltic mineral lands, with a view of disproving such classification and securing patent without reservation, nor shall persons who have located, selected, entered, or purchased lands subsequently withdrawn, or classified as valuable for said mineral deposits, be debarred from the privilege of showing, at any time before final entry, purchase, or approval of selection or location, that the lands entered, selected, or located are in fact nonmineral in character.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 17, 1914, ch. 142, § 2</ref>, <ref>38 Stat. 509</ref>; <ref>July 20, 1956, ch. 652</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 592</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 123.</num>
<heading> Persons locating lands subsequently withdrawn or classified; patents to</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any person who has, in good faith, located, selected, entered, or purchased, or any person who shall locate, select, enter, or purchase, after <date date="1914-07-17">July 17, 1914</date>, under the nonmineral land laws of the United States, any lands which are subsequently withdrawn, classified, or reported as being valuable for phosphate, nitrate, potash, oil, gas, or asphaltic minerals, may, upon application therefor, and making satisfactory proof of compliance with the laws under which such lands are claimed, receive a patent therefor, which patent shall contain a reservation to the United States of all deposits on account of which the lands were withdrawn, classified, or reported as being valuable, together with the right to prospect for, mine, and remove the same.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 17, 1914, ch. 142, § 3</ref>, <ref>38 Stat. 510</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 124.</num>
<heading> Agricultural entry or purchase of lands withdrawn or classified as containing sodium or sulphur</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Lands withdrawn, classified, or reported as valuable for sodium and/or sulphur and subject to prospecting, leasing, or development under the General Leasing Act of <date date="1920-02-25">February 25, 1920</date>, or Acts amendatory thereof or supplementary thereto [<ref>30 U.S.C. 181</ref> et seq.], shall be subject to appropriation, location, selection, entry, or purchase if otherwise available in the form and manner and subject to the reservations, provisions, limitations, and conditions of the Act of Congress approved <date date="1914-07-17">July 17, 1914</date> (38 Stat. L. 509; U.S.C., title 30, sec. 123); <i>Provided, however</i>, That lands lying within the geologic structure of a field, or withdrawn, classified, or reported as valuable for any of the minerals named herein and/or in any of said sections, or upon which leases or prospecting permits have been applied for or granted, for the production of any of such minerals, shall not be subject to such appropriation, location, selection, entry, or purchase unless it shall be determined by the Secretary of the Interior that such disposal will not unreasonably interfere with operations under said sections.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 4, 1933, ch. 278</ref>, <ref>47 Stat. 1570</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 125.</num>
<heading> Patents in North Platte Reclamation Project; mineral rights; subrogation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Where reclamation homestead entry was made prior to <date date="1914-07-17">July 17, 1914</date>, pursuant to the Act of <date date="1902-06-17">June 17, 1902</date> (<ref>32 Stat. 389</ref>, 43 U.S.C., sec. 431), as amended and supplemented, for lands in the Northport Division or the Interstate Division of the North Platte Reclamation Project, and after such entry the lands have been or are hereafter withdrawn, classified, or reported as being valuable for any of the minerals named in sections 81 and 121 to 124 of this title, the patent shall not contain a reservation of such minerals. If any such mineral deposits on account of which the lands were withdrawn, classified or reported as being valuable have been leased by the United States, such patent shall be made subject to the rights of the lessee, but the patentee shall be subrogated to the rights of the United States under the lease.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Apr. 17, 1954, ch. 152</ref>, <ref>68 Stat. 56</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER VI—</num>
<heading>LOCATION OF PHOSPHATE ROCK LANDS UNDER PLACER-MINING LAWS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 131.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER VII—</num>
<heading>PERMITS TO PROSPECT FOR CHLORIDES, SULPHATES, CARBONATES, BORATES, SILICATES, OR NITRATES OF POTASSIUM</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 141 to 152.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Feb. 7, 1927, ch. 66, § 6</ref>, <ref>44 Stat. 1058</ref></heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER VIII—</num>
<heading>BUILDING STONE OR SALINE LAND ENTRIES UNDER PLACER-MINING LAWS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 161.</num>
<heading> Entry of building-stone lands; previous law unaffected</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any person authorized to enter lands under the mining laws of the United States may enter lands that are chiefly valuable for building stone under the provisions of the law in relation to placer mineral claims. Lands reserved for the benefit of the public schools or donated to any State shall not be subject to entry under this section. Nothing contained in this section shall be construed to repeal <ref>section 471 of title 16</ref> relating to the establishment of national forests.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 4, 1892, ch. 375</ref>, §§ 1, 3, <ref>27 Stat. 348</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 162.</num>
<heading> Entry of saline lands; limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All unoccupied public lands of the United States containing salt springs, or deposits of salt in any form, and chiefly valuable therefor, shall be subject to location and purchase under the provisions of the law relating to placer-mining claims. The same person shall not locate or enter more than one claim hereunder.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Jan. 31, 1901, ch. 186</ref>, <ref>31 Stat. 745</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IX—</num>
<heading>DISPOSAL OF ALABAMA LANDS AS AGRICULTURAL LANDS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 171.</num>
<heading> Disposal as agricultural lands</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided in chapter 3A of this title, all public lands within the State of Alabama, whether mineral or otherwise, shall be subject to disposal only as agricultural lands. All lands which had been reported to the General Land Office prior to <date date="1883-03-03">March 3, 1883</date>, as containing coal and iron shall first be offered at public sale.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 3, 1883, ch. 118</ref>, <ref>22 Stat. 487</ref>; <ref>Feb. 25, 1920, ch. 85, § 1</ref>, <ref>41 Stat. 437</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 172.</num>
<heading> Certain Alabama lands subject to homestead entry</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All lands designated as agricultural in the reclassification of the public lands of Alabama by the Secretary of the Interior under authority of Act <date date="1906-03-27">March 27, 1906</date> (chapter 1347, section 1, Thirty-fourth Statutes, page 88), shall be subject to homestead entry as such.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 27, 1906, ch. 1347, § 2</ref>, <ref>34 Stat. 88</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>