<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 9—</num>
<heading>RARE AND PRECIOUS METALS EXPERIMENT STATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 411.</num>
<heading> Establishment and operation of experimental plant</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior, acting through the United States Bureau of Mines, is authorized and directed to establish, equip, and maintain a research laboratory at Reno, Nevada, for research, investigation, and as a center for information and assistance in matters pertaining to the mining, preparation, metallurgy, use, and conservation of the rare and precious metals of the Sierra Nevada mining region, and pertaining to other problems affecting the mining industry of that region.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 21, 1950, ch. 338, § 1</ref>, <ref>64 Stat. 248</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–285, § 10(b)</ref>, <date date="1992-05-18">May 18, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 172</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 412.</num>
<heading> Acquisition of lands and interests; acceptance of money and property; disposition and use of money</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purposes of this chapter the Secretary, acting through the United States Bureau of Mines, is authorized to acquire land and interests therein; to receive and accept money and property, real or personal, or interests therein, and services as a gift, bequest, or contribution; and may conduct activities or projects in cooperation with any person, firm, agency, or organization, Federal, State, or private. Money so received shall be deposited in the Treasury of the United States in a special fund or funds for disbursement by the United States Bureau of Mines and shall remain available for the purposes for which received and accepted until expended.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 21, 1950, ch. 338, § 2</ref>, <ref>64 Stat. 248</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–285, § 10(b)</ref>, <date date="1992-05-18">May 18, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 172</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>