<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 32—</num>
<heading>METHANE HYDRATE RESEARCH AND DEVELOPMENT</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2001.</num>
<heading> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Congress finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in order to promote energy independence and meet the increasing demand for energy, the United States will require a diversified portfolio of substantially increased quantities of electricity, natural gas, and transportation fuels;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> according to the report submitted to Congress by the National Research Council entitled “Charting the Future of Methane Hydrate Research in the United States”, the total United States resources of gas hydrates have been estimated to be on the order of 200,000 trillion cubic feet;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> according to the report of the National Commission on Energy Policy entitled “Ending the Energy Stalemate—A Bipartisan Strategy to Meet America’s Energy Challenge”, and dated December 2004, the United States may be endowed with over one-fourth of the methane hydrate deposits in the world;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> according to the Energy Information Administration, a shortfall in natural gas supply from conventional and unconventional sources is expected to occur in or about 2020; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the National Academy of Sciences states that methane hydrate may have the potential to alleviate the projected shortfall in the natural gas supply.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–193, § 2</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 109–58, title IX, § 968(a)</ref>, <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 894</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2002.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contract</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “contract” means a procurement contract within the meaning of <ref>section 6303 of title 31</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cooperative agreement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “cooperative agreement” means a cooperative agreement within the meaning of <ref>section 6305 of title 31</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Director</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Director” means the Director of the National Science Foundation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grant</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “grant” means a grant awarded under a grant agreement (within the meaning of <ref>section 6304 of title 31</ref>).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Industrial enterprise</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “industrial enterprise” means a private, nongovernmental enterprise that has an expertise or capability that relates to methane hydrate research and development.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Institution of higher education</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “institution of higher education” means an institution of higher education (as defined in <ref>section 1002 of title 20</ref>).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Energy, acting through the Assistant Secretary for Fossil Energy.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary of Commerce</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Secretary of Commerce” means the Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary of Defense</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Secretary of Defense” means the Secretary of Defense, acting through the Secretary of the Navy.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(10)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary of the Interior</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Secretary of the Interior” means the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the United States Geological Survey, the Director of the Bureau of Land Management, and the Director of the Minerals Management Service.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–193, § 3</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 109–58, title IX, § 968(a)</ref>, <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 895</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2003.</num>
<heading> Methane hydrate research and development program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Commencement of program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 90 days after <date date="2005-08-08">August 8, 2005</date>, the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of the Interior, and the Director, shall commence a program of methane hydrate research and development in accordance with this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Designations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary, the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of the Interior, and the Director shall designate individuals to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The individual designated by the Secretary shall coordinate all activities within the Department of Energy relating to methane hydrate research and development.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Meetings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The individuals designated under paragraph (2) shall meet not later than 180 days after <date date="2005-08-08">August 8, 2005</date>, and not less frequently than every 180 days thereafter to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> review the progress of the program under paragraph (1); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> coordinate interagency research and partnership efforts in carrying out the program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grants, contracts, cooperative agreements, interagency funds transfer agreements, and field work proposals</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistance and coordination</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In carrying out the program of methane hydrate research and development authorized by this section, the Secretary may award grants to, or enter into contracts or cooperative agreements with, institutions of higher education, oceanographic institutions, and industrial enterprises to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> conduct basic and applied research to identify, explore, assess, and develop methane hydrate as a commercially viable source of energy;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> identify methane hydrate resources through remote sensing;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> acquire and reprocess seismic data suitable for characterizing methane hydrate accumulations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> assist in developing technologies required for efficient and environmentally sound development of methane hydrate resources;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> promote education and training in methane hydrate resource research and resource development through fellowships or other means for graduate education and training;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> conduct basic and applied research to assess and mitigate the environmental impact of hydrate degassing (including both natural degassing and degassing associated with commercial development);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> develop technologies to reduce the risks of drilling through methane hydrates; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> conduct exploratory drilling, well testing, and production testing operations on permafrost and non-permafrost gas hydrates in support of the activities authorized by this paragraph, including drilling of one or more full-scale production test wells.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Competitive peer review</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Funds made available under paragraph (1) shall be made available based on a competitive process using external scientific peer review of proposed research.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Methane hydrates advisory panel</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary shall establish an advisory panel (including the hiring of appropriate staff) consisting of representatives of industrial enterprises, institutions of higher education, oceanographic institutions, State agencies, and environmental organizations with knowledge and expertise in the natural gas hydrates field, to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> assist in developing recommendations and broad programmatic priorities for the methane hydrate research and development program carried out under subsection (a)(1);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provide scientific oversight for the methane hydrates program, including assessing progress toward program goals, evaluating program balance, and providing recommendations to enhance the quality of the program over time; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> not later than 2 years after <date date="2005-08-08">August 8, 2005</date>, and at such later dates as the panel considers advisable, submit to Congress—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an assessment of the methane hydrate research program; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> an assessment of the 5-year research plan of the Department of Energy.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conflicts of interest</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In appointing each member of the advisory panel established under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall ensure, to the maximum extent practicable, that the appointment of the member does not pose a conflict of interest with respect to the duties of the member under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Meetings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The advisory panel shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> hold the initial meeting of the advisory panel not later than 180 days after the date of establishment of the advisory panel; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> meet biennially thereafter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The advisory panel shall coordinate activities of the advisory panel with program managers of the Department of Energy at appropriate National Laboratories.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Construction costs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">None of the funds made available to carry out this section may be used for the construction of a new building or the acquisition, expansion, remodeling, or alteration of an existing building (including site grading and improvement and architect fees).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Responsibilities of the Secretary</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In carrying out subsection (b)(1), the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> facilitate and develop partnerships among government, industrial enterprises, and institutions of higher education to research, identify, assess, and explore methane hydrate resources;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> undertake programs to develop basic information necessary for promoting long-term interest in methane hydrate resources as an energy source;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> ensure that the data and information developed through the program are accessible and widely disseminated as needed and appropriate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> promote cooperation among agencies that are developing technologies that may hold promise for methane hydrate resource development;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> report annually to Congress on the results of actions taken to carry out this chapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> ensure, to the maximum extent practicable, greater participation by the Department of Energy in international cooperative efforts.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–193, § 4</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 109–58, title IX, § 968(a)</ref>, <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 895</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2004.</num>
<heading> National Research Council study</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agreement for Study</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall offer to enter into an agreement with the National Research Council under which the National Research Council shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> conduct a study of the progress made under the methane hydrate research and development program implemented under this chapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> make recommendations for future methane hydrate research and development needs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than <date date="2009-09-30">September 30, 2009</date>, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report containing the findings and recommendations of the National Research Council under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–193, § 5</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 109–58, title IX, § 968(a)</ref>, <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 898</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2005.</num>
<heading> Reports and studies for Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall provide to the Committee on Science of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate copies of any report or study that the Department of Energy prepares at the direction of any committee of Congress relating to the methane hydrate research and development program implemented under this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–193, § 6</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 109–58, title IX, § 968(a)</ref>, <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 898</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2006.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this chapter, to remain available until expended—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> $15,000,000 for fiscal year 2006;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> $20,000,000 for fiscal year 2007;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> $30,000,000 for fiscal year 2008;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> $40,000,000 for fiscal year 2009; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> $50,000,000 for fiscal year 2010.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–193, § 7</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 109–58, title IX, § 968(a)</ref>, <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 898</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>