<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 23—</num>
<heading>GEOTHERMAL RESOURCES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1001.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this chapter, the term—</chapeau>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> “Secretary” means the Secretary of the Interior;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> “geothermal lease” means a lease issued under authority of this chapter;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> “geothermal resources” means (i) all products of geothermal processes, embracing indigenous steam, hot water and hot brines; (ii) steam and other gases, hot water and hot brines resulting from water, gas, or other fluids artificially introduced into geothermal formations; (iii) heat or other associated energy found in geothermal formations; and (iv) any byproduct derived from them;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> “byproduct” means any mineral or minerals (exclusive of oil, hydrocarbon gas, and helium) which are found in solution or in association with geothermal steam and which have a value of less than 75 per centum of the value of the geothermal steam or are not, because of quantity, quality, or technical difficulties in extraction and production, of sufficient value to warrant extraction and production by themselves;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> “known geothermal resources area” means an area in which the geology, nearby discoveries, competitive interests, or other indicia would, in the opinion of the Secretary, engender a belief in men who are experienced in the subject matter that the prospects for extraction of geothermal steam or associated geothermal resources are good enough to warrant expenditures of money for that purpose.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(f)</num>
<chapeau> “Significant <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002052">1</ref> thermal features within units of the National Park System” shall include, but not be limited to, the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent2">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Thermal features within units of the National Park System listed in Section <sup>1</sup> 1026(a)(1) of this title and designated as significant in the Federal Register notice of <date date="1987-08-03">August 3, 1987</date> (Vol. 52, No. 148 Fed. Reg. 28790).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Crater Lake National Park.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Thermal features within Big Bend National Park and Lake Mead National Recreation Area proposed as significant in the Federal Register notice of <date date="1987-02-13">February 13, 1987</date> (Vol. 52, No. 30 Fed. Reg. 4700).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Thermal features within units of the National Park System added to the significant thermal features list pursuant to <ref>section 1026(a)(2) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> “direct use” means utilization of geothermal resources for commercial, residential, agricultural, public facilities, or other energy needs other than the commercial production of electricity; and <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002053">2</ref></content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–581, § 2</ref>, <date date="1970-12-24">Dec. 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1566</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–443, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-22">Sept. 22, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1766</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–58, title II, § 236(1)</ref>, (2), (5), <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 671</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1002.</num>
<heading> Lands subject to geothermal leasing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to the provisions of <ref>section 1014 of this title</ref>, the Secretary of the Interior may issue leases for the development and utilization of geothermal resources (1) in lands administered by him, including public, withdrawn, and acquired lands, (2) in any national forest or other lands administered by the Department of Agriculture through the Forest Service, including public, withdrawn, and acquired lands, and (3) in lands which have been conveyed by the United States subject to a reservation to the United States of the geothermal resources therein.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–581, § 3</ref>, <date date="1970-12-24">Dec. 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1566</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–58, title II, § 236(1)</ref>, (6), <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 671</ref>, 672.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1002a.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 97–214, § 7(16)</ref>, <date date="1982-07-12">July 12, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 174</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1003.</num>
<heading> Leasing procedures</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nominations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall accept nominations of land to be leased at any time from qualified companies and individuals under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Competitive lease sale required</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as otherwise specifically provided by this chapter, all land to be leased that is not subject to leasing under subsection (c) shall be leased as provided in this subsection to the highest responsible qualified bidder, as determined by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Competitive lease sales</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall hold a competitive lease sale at least once every 2 years for land in a State that has nominations pending under subsection (a) if the land is otherwise available for leasing.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Lands subject to mining claims</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Lands that are subject to a mining claim for which a plan of operations has been approved by the relevant Federal land management agency may be available for noncompetitive leasing under this section to the mining claim holder.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Land subject to oil and gas lease</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Land under an oil and gas lease issued pursuant to the Mineral Leasing Act (<ref>30 U.S.C. 181</ref> et seq.) or the Mineral Leasing Act for Acquired Lands (<ref>30 U.S.C. 351</ref> et seq.) that is subject to an approved application for permit to drill and from which oil and gas production is occurring may be available for noncompetitive leasing under subsection (c) by the holder of the oil and gas lease—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> on a determination that geothermal energy will be produced from a well producing or capable of producing oil and gas; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to provide for the coproduction of geothermal energy with oil and gas.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Noncompetitive leasing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall make available for a period of 2 years for noncompetitive leasing any tract for which a competitive lease sale is held, but for which the Secretary does not receive any bids in a competitive lease sale.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Pending lease applications</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">It shall be a priority for the Secretary, and for the Secretary of Agriculture with respect to National Forest Systems land, to ensure timely completion of administrative actions, including amendments to applicable forest plans and resource management plans, necessary to process applications for geothermal leasing pending on <date date="2005-08-08">August 8, 2005</date>.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002054">1</ref> All future forest plans and resource management plans for areas with high geothermal resource potential shall consider geothermal leasing and development.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administration</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">An application described in paragraph (1) and any lease issued pursuant to the application—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> except as provided in subparagraph (B), shall be subject to this section as in effect on the day before <date date="2005-08-08">August 8, 2005</date>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> at the election of the applicant, shall be subject to this section as in effect on <date date="2005-08-08">August 8, 2005</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Leases sold as a block</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If information is available to the Secretary indicating a geothermal resource that could be produced as 1 unit can reasonably be expected to underlie more than 1 parcel to be offered in a competitive lease sale, the parcels for such a resource may be offered for bidding as a block in the competitive lease sale.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Leasing for direct use of geothermal resources</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Notwithstanding subsection (b), the Secretary may identify areas in which the land to be leased under this chapter exclusively for direct use of geothermal resources, without sale for purposes other than commercial generation of electricity, may be leased to any qualified applicant that first applies for such a lease under regulations issued by the Secretary, if the Secretary—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> publishes a notice of the land proposed for leasing not later than 90 days before the date of the issuance of the lease;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> does not receive during the 90-day period beginning on the date of the publication any nomination to include the land concerned in the next competitive lease sale; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> determines there is no competitive interest in the geothermal resources in the land to be leased.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Area subject to lease for direct use</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subject to paragraph (2), a geothermal lease for the direct use of geothermal resources shall cover not more than the quantity of acreage determined by the Secretary to be reasonably necessary for the proposed use.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The quantity of acreage covered by the lease shall not exceed the limitations established under <ref>section 1006 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–581, § 4</ref>, <date date="1970-12-24">Dec. 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1566</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–58, title II</ref>, §§ 222, 223(b), <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 660</ref>, 662; <ref>Pub. L. 116–260, div. Z, title III, § 3105</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 2516</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1004.</num>
<heading> Rents and royalties</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Geothermal leases shall provide for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> a royalty on electricity produced using geothermal resources, other than direct use of geothermal resources, that shall be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> not less than 1 percent and not more than 2.5 percent of the gross proceeds from the sale of electricity produced from such resources during the first 10 years of production under the lease; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> not less than 2 and not more than 5 percent of the gross proceeds from the sale of electricity produced from such resources during each year after such 10-year period;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a royalty on any byproduct that is a mineral specified in the first section of the Mineral Leasing Act (<ref>30 U.S.C. 181</ref>), and that is derived from production under the lease, at the rate of the royalty that applies under that Act [<ref>30 U.S.C. 181</ref> et seq.] to production of the mineral under a lease under that Act; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> payment in advance of an annual rental of not less than—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> for each of the 1st through 10th years of the lease—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> in the case of a lease awarded in a noncompetitive lease sale, $1 per acre or fraction thereof; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in the case of a lease awarded in a competitive lease sale, $2 per acre or fraction thereof for the 1st year and $3 per acre or fraction thereof for each of the 2nd through 10th years; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for each year after the 10th year of the lease, $5 per acre or fraction thereof; <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002055">1</ref></content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Direct use</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Notwithstanding subsection (a)(1), the Secretary shall establish a schedule of fees, in lieu of royalties for geothermal resources, that a lessee or its affiliate—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> uses for a purpose other than the commercial generation of electricity; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> does not sell.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Schedule of fees</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The schedule of fees—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> may be based on the quantity or thermal content, or both, of geothermal resources used;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> shall ensure a fair return to the United States for use of the resource; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> shall encourage development of the resource.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State, tribal, or local governments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If a State, tribal, or local government is the lessee and uses geothermal resources without sale and for public purposes other than commercial generation of electricity, the Secretary shall charge only a nominal fee for use of the resource.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Final regulation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In issuing any final regulation establishing a schedule of fees under this subsection, the Secretary shall seek—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to provide lessees with a simplified administrative system;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to facilitate development of direct use of geothermal resources; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to contribute to sustainable economic development opportunities in the area.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Final regulation establishing royalty rates</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In issuing any final regulation establishing royalty rates under this section, the Secretary shall seek—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to provide lessees a simplified administrative system;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to encourage new development; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to achieve the same level of royalty revenues over a 10-year period as the regulation in effect on <date date="2005-08-08">August 8, 2005</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Credits for in-kind payments of electricity</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary may provide to a lessee a credit against royalties owed under this chapter, in an amount equal to the value of electricity provided under contract to a State or county government that is entitled to a portion of such royalties under <ref>section 1019 of this title</ref>, section 35 of the Mineral Leasing Act (<ref>30 U.S.C. 191</ref>), except as otherwise provided by this section, or <ref>section 355 of this title</ref>, if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Secretary has approved in advance the contract between the lessee and the State or county government for such in-kind payments;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the contract establishes a specific methodology to determine the value of such credits; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the maximum credit will be equal to the royalty value owed to the State or county that is a party to the contract and the electricity received will serve as the royalty payment from the Federal Government to that entity.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Crediting of rental toward royalty</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any annual rental under this section that is paid with respect to a lease before the first day of the year for which the annual rental is owed shall be credited to the amount of royalty that is required to be paid under the lease for that year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Advanced royalties required for cessation of production</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subject to paragraphs (2) and (3), if, at any time after commercial production under a lease is achieved, production ceases for any reason, the lease shall remain in full force and effect for a period of not more than an aggregate number of 10 years beginning on the date production ceases, if, during the period in which production is ceased, the lessee pays royalties in advance at the monthly average rate at which the royalty was paid during the period of production.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reduction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The amount of any production royalty paid for any year shall be reduced (but not below 0) by the amount of any advanced royalties paid under the lease to the extent that the advance royalties have not been used to reduce production royalties for a prior year.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Paragraph (1) shall not apply if the cessation in production is required or otherwise caused by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Secretary;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Secretary of the Air Force;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Secretary of the Army;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Secretary of the Navy;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> a State or a political subdivision of a State; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> a force majeure.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination of lease for failure to pay rental</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall terminate any lease with respect to which rental is not paid in accordance with this chapter and the terms of the lease under which the rental is required, on the expiration of the 45-day period beginning on the date of the failure to pay the rental.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall promptly notify a lessee that has not paid rental required under the lease that the lease will be terminated at the end of the period referred to in paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reinstatement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A lease that would otherwise terminate under paragraph (1) shall not terminate under that paragraph if the lessee pays to the Secretary, before the end of the period referred to in paragraph (1), the amount of rental due plus a late fee equal to 10 percent of the amount.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–581, § 5</ref>, <date date="1970-12-24">Dec. 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1567</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–58, title II</ref>, §§ 223(a), 224(a), 228, 230, 232, 233, 236(7), <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 661</ref>, 662, 667–670, 672.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1005.</num>
<heading> Lease term and work commitment requirements</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Primary term</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A geothermal lease shall be for a primary term of 10 years.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initial extension</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary shall extend the primary term of a geothermal lease for 5 years if, for each year after the 10th year of the lease—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Secretary determined under subsection (b) that the lessee satisfied the work commitment requirements that applied to the lease for that year; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the lessee paid in annual payments accordance with subsection (c).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional extension</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall extend the primary term of a geothermal lease (after an initial extension under paragraph (2)) for an additional 5 years if, for each year of the initial extension under paragraph (2), the Secretary determined under subsection (b) that the lessee satisfied the minimum work requirements that applied to the lease for that year.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement to satisfy annual minimum work requirement</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The lessee for a geothermal lease shall, for each year after the 10th year of the lease, satisfy minimum work requirements prescribed by the Secretary that apply to the lease for that year.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prescription of minimum work requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary shall issue regulations prescribing minimum work requirements for geothermal leases, that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> establish a geothermal potential; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> if a geothermal potential has been established, confirm the existence of producible geothermal resources.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payments in lieu of minimum work requirements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In lieu of the minimum work requirements set forth in subsection (b)(2), the Secretary shall by regulation establish minimum annual payments which may be made by the lessee for a limited number of years that the Secretary determines will not impair achieving diligent development of the geothermal resource, but in no event shall the number of years exceed the duration of the extension period provided in subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transition rules for leases issued prior to <date date="2005-08-08">August 8, 2005</date></heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall by regulation establish transition rules for leases issued before <date date="2005-08-08">August 8, 2005</date>, including terms under which a lease that is near the end of its term on <date date="2005-08-08">August 8, 2005</date>, may be extended for up to 2 years—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to allow achievement of production under the lease; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to allow the lease to be included in a producing unit.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Geothermal lease overlying mining claim</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exemption</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The lessee for a geothermal lease of an area overlying an area subject to a mining claim for which a plan of operations has been approved by the relevant Federal land management agency is exempt from annual work requirements established under this chapter, if development of the geothermal resource subject to the lease would interfere with the mining operations under such claim.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination of exemption</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">An exemption under this paragraph expires upon the termination of the mining operations.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination of application of requirements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Minimum work requirements prescribed under this section shall not apply to a geothermal lease after the date on which the geothermal resource is utilized under the lease in commercial quantities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cooperative or unit plan for drilling operations; extension of term; renewal</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any lease for land on which, or for which under an approved cooperative or unit plan of development or operation, actual drilling operations were commenced prior to the end of its primary term and are being diligently prosecuted at that time shall be extended for five years and so long thereafter, but not more than thirty-five years, as geothermal steam is produced or utilized in commercial quantities. If, at the end of such extended term, steam is being produced or utilized in commercial quantities and the lands are not needed for other purposes, the lessee shall have a preferential right to a renewal of such lease for a second term in accordance with such terms and conditions as the Secretary deems appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> “Produced or utilized in commercial quantities” defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided for in this section, for purposes of this section the term “produced or utilized in commercial quantities” means the completion of a well producing geothermal steam in commercial quantities. Such term shall also include the completion of a well capable of producing geothermal steam in commercial quantities so long as the Secretary determines that diligent efforts are being made toward the utilization of the geothermal steam.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Principles for location of minerals under mining laws when minerals are not associated with geothermal resources</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Minerals locatable under the mining laws of the United States in lands subject to a geothermal lease issued under the provisions of this chapter which are not associated with the geothermal resources of such lands as defined in <ref>section 1001(c) of this title</ref> shall be locatable under said mining laws in accordance with the principles of the Multiple Mineral Development Act (<ref>68 Stat. 708</ref>; found in <ref>30 U.S.C. 521</ref> et seq.).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–581, § 6</ref>, <date date="1970-12-24">Dec. 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1568</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–443</ref>, §§ 2(b), 3, <date date="1988-09-22">Sept. 22, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1766</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–58, title II</ref>, §§ 231, 236(1), <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 668</ref>, 671.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1006.</num>
<heading> Acreage limitations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A geothermal lease shall embrace a reasonably compact area of not more than 5,120 acres, except where a departure therefrom is occasioned by an irregular subdivision or subdivisions. No person, association, or corporation, except as otherwise provided in this chapter, shall take, hold, own, or control at one time, whether acquired directly from the Secretary under this chapter or otherwise, any direct or indirect interest in Federal geothermal leases in any one State exceeding 51,200 acres, including leases acquired under the provisions of <ref>section 1003 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–581, § 7</ref>, <date date="1970-12-24">Dec. 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1569</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–58, title II, § 235</ref>, <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 671</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1007.</num>
<heading> Readjustment of lease terms and conditions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initial readjustment; periodic intervals; notice; objections, relinquishment, and termination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may readjust the terms and conditions, except as otherwise provided herein, of any geothermal lease issued under this chapter at not less than ten-year intervals beginning ten years after the date the geothermal steam is produced, as determined by the Secretary. Each geothermal lease issued under this chapter shall provide for such readjustment. The Secretary shall give notice of any proposed readjustment of terms and conditions, and, unless the lessee files with the Secretary objection to the proposed terms or relinquishes the lease within thirty days after receipt of such notice, the lessee shall conclusively be deemed to have agreed with such terms and conditions. If the lessee files objections, and no agreement can be reached between the Secretary and the lessee within a period of not less than sixty days, the lease may be terminated by either party.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rentals and royalties; initial readjustment; periodic intervals; limitation on increases and on royalties; notice; objections, relinquishment, and termination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may readjust the rentals and royalties of any geothermal lease issued under this chapter at not less than twenty-year intervals beginning thirty-five years after the date geothermal steam is produced, as determined by the Secretary. In the event of any such readjustment neither the rental nor royalty may be increased by more than 50 per centum over the rental or royalty paid during the preceding period. Each geothermal lease issue <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002056">1</ref> under this chapter shall provide for such readjustment. The Secretary shall give notice of any proposed readjustment of rentals and royalties, and, unless the lessee files with the Secretary objection to the proposed rentals and royalties or relinquishes the lease within thirty days after receipt of such notice, the lessee shall conclusively be deemed to have agreed with such terms and conditions. If the lessee files objections, and no agreement can be reached between the Secretary and the lessee within a period of not less than sixty days, the lease may be terminated by either party.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Surface use, protection, or restoration of lands withdrawn or acquired for Federal agency; notice; approval of agency</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any readjustment of the terms and conditions as to use, protection, or restoration of the surface of any lease of lands withdrawn or acquired in aid of a function of a Federal department or agency other than the Department of the Interior may be made only upon notice to, and with the approval of, such department or agency.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–581, § 8</ref>, <date date="1970-12-24">Dec. 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1569</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–58, title II</ref>, §§ 229, 236(8), <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 668</ref>, 672.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1008.</num>
<heading> Byproducts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the production, use, or conversion of geothermal steam is susceptible of producing a valuable byproduct or byproducts, including commercially demineralized water for beneficial uses in accordance with applicable State water laws, the Secretary shall require substantial beneficial production or use thereof unless, in individual circumstances he modifies or waives this requirement in the interest of conservation of natural resources or for other reasons satisfactory to him. However, the production or use of such byproducts shall be subject to the rights of the holders of preexisting leases, claims, or permits covering the same land or the same minerals, if any.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–581, § 9</ref>, <date date="1970-12-24">Dec. 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1570</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–58, title II, § 236(9)</ref>, <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 672</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1009.</num>
<heading> Relinquishment of geothermal rights</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The holder of any geothermal lease at any time may make and file in the appropriate land office a written relinquishment of all rights under such lease or of any legal subdivision of the area covered by such lease. Such relinquishment shall be effective as of the date of its filing. Thereupon the lessee shall be released of all obligations thereafter accruing under said lease with respect to the lands relinquished, but no such relinquishment shall release such lessee, or his surety or bond, from any liability for breach of any obligation of the lease, other than an obligation to drill, accrued at the date of the relinquishment, or from the continued obligation, in accordance with the applicable lease terms and regulations, (1) to make payment of all accrued rentals and royalties, (2) to place all wells on the relinquished lands in condition for suspension or abandonment, and (3) to protect or restore substantially the surface and surface resources.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–581, § 10</ref>, <date date="1970-12-24">Dec. 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1570</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–58, title II, § 236(10)</ref>, <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 672</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1010.</num>
<heading> Suspension of operations and production</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary, upon application by the lessee, may authorize the lessee to suspend operations and production on a producing lease and he may, on his own motion, in the interest of conservation suspend operations on any lease but in either case he may extend the lease term for the period of any suspension, and he may waive, suspend, or reduce the rental or royalty required in such lease.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–581, § 11</ref>, <date date="1970-12-24">Dec. 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1570</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–58, title II, § 236(11)</ref>, <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 672</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1011.</num>
<heading> Termination of leases</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Leases may be terminated by the Secretary for any violation of the regulations or lease terms after thirty days notice provided that such violation is not corrected within the notice period, or in the event the violation is such that it cannot be corrected within the notice period then provided that lessee has not commenced in good faith within said notice period to correct such violation and thereafter to proceed diligently to correct such violation. Lessee shall be entitled to a hearing on the matter of such claimed violation or proposed termination of lease if request for a hearing is made to the Secretary within the thirty-day period after notice. The period for correction of violation or commencement to correct such violation of regulations or of lease terms, as aforesaid, shall be extended to thirty days after the Secretary’s decision after such hearing if the Secretary shall find that a violation exists.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–581, § 12</ref>, <date date="1970-12-24">Dec. 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1570</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–58, title II, § 236(12)</ref>, <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 672</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1012.</num>
<heading> Waiver, suspension, or reduction of rental or royalty</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may waive, suspend, or reduce the rental or royalty for any lease or portion thereof in the interests of conservation and to encourage the greatest ultimate recovery of geothermal resources, if he determines that this is necessary to promote development or that the lease cannot be successfully operated under the lease terms.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–581, § 13</ref>, <date date="1970-12-24">Dec. 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1570</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–58, title II, § 236(13)</ref>, <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 672</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1013.</num>
<heading> Surface land use</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to the other provisions of this chapter, a lessee shall be entitled to use so much of the surface of the land covered by his geothermal lease as may be found by the Secretary to be necessary for the production, utilization, and conservation of geothermal resources.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–581, § 14</ref>, <date date="1970-12-24">Dec. 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1571</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–58, title II, § 236(14)</ref>, <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 672</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1014.</num>
<heading> Lands subject to geothermal leasing</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Terms and conditions for lands withdrawn or acquired for Department of the Interior</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Geothermal leases for lands withdrawn or acquired in aid of functions of the Department of the Interior may be issued only under such terms and conditions as the Secretary may prescribe to insure adequate utilization of the lands for the purposes for which they were withdrawn or acquired.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consent and terms and conditions for lands withdrawn or acquired for Department of Agriculture or for lands for power and related purposes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Geothermal leases for lands withdrawn or acquired in aid of functions of the Department of Agriculture may be issued only with the consent of, and subject to such terms and conditions as may be prescribed by, the head of that Department to insure adequate utilization of the lands for the purposes for which they were withdrawn or acquired. Geothermal leases for lands to which <ref>section 818 of title 16</ref> is applicable, may be issued only with the consent of, and subject to, such terms and conditions as the Secretary of Energy may prescribe to insure adequate utilization of such lands for power and related purposes.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exemption of certain Federal lands</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Geothermal leases under this chapter shall not be issued for lands administered in accordance with (1) the Act of <date date="1916-08-25">August 25, 1916</date> (<ref>39 Stat. 535</ref>),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002057">1</ref> as amended or supplemented, (2) for lands within a national recreation area, (3) for lands in a fish hatchery administered by the Secretary, wildlife refuge, wildlife range, game range, wildlife management area, waterfowl production area, or for lands acquired or reserved for the protection and conservation of fish and wildlife that are threatened with extinction, (4) for tribally or individually owned Indian trust or restricted lands, within or without the boundaries of Indian reservations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–581, § 15</ref>, <date date="1970-12-24">Dec. 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1571</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–91, title III, § 301(b)</ref>, title VII, §§ 703, 707, <date date="1977-08-04">Aug. 4, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 578</ref>, 606, 607; <ref>Pub. L. 109–58, title II, § 236(15)</ref>, <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 672</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1015.</num>
<heading> Requirement for lessees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Leases under this chapter may be issued only to citizens of the United States, associations of such citizens, corporations organized under the laws of the United States or of any State or the District of Columbia, or governmental units, including, without limitation, municipalities.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–581, § 16</ref>, <date date="1970-12-24">Dec. 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1571</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–58, title II, § 236(16)</ref>, <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 672</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1016.</num>
<heading> Administration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Administration of this chapter shall be under the principles of multiple use of lands and resources, and geothermal leases shall, insofar as feasible, allow for coexistence of other leases of the same lands for deposits of minerals under the laws applicable to them, for the location and production of claims under the mining laws, and for other uses of the areas covered by them. Operations under such other leases or for such other uses, however, shall not unreasonably interfere with or endanger operations under any lease issued pursuant to this chapter, nor shall operations under leases so issued unreasonably interfere with or endanger operations under any lease, license, claim, or permit issued pursuant to the provisions of any other Act.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–581, § 17</ref>, <date date="1970-12-24">Dec. 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1571</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–58, title II, § 236(17)</ref>, <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 672</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1017.</num>
<heading> Unit and communitization agreements</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adoption of units by lessees</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For the purpose of more properly conserving the natural resources of any geothermal reservoir, field, or like area, or any part thereof (whether or not any part of the geothermal reservoir, field, or like area, is subject to any cooperative plan of development or operation (referred to in this section as a “unit agreement”)), lessees thereof and their representatives may unite with each other, or jointly or separately with others, in collectively adopting and operating under a unit agreement for the reservoir, field, or like area, or any part thereof, including direct use resources, if determined and certified by the Secretary to be necessary or advisable in the public interest.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Majority interest of single leases</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A majority interest of owners of any single lease shall have the authority to commit the lease to a unit agreement.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initiative of Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may also initiate the formation of a unit agreement, or require an existing Federal lease to commit to a unit agreement, if in the public interest.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Modification of lease requirements by Secretary</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary may, in the discretion of the Secretary and with the consent of the holders of leases involved, establish, alter, change, or revoke rates of operations (including drilling, operations, production, and other requirements) of the leases and make conditions with respect to the leases, with the consent of the lessees, in connection with the creation and operation of any such unit agreement as the Secretary may consider necessary or advisable to secure the protection of the public interest.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Unlike terms or rates</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Leases with unlike lease terms or royalty rates shall not be required to be modified to be in the same unit.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement of plans under new leases</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provide that geothermal leases issued under this chapter shall contain a provision requiring the lessee to operate under a unit agreement; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> prescribe the unit agreement under which the lessee shall operate, which shall adequately protect the rights of all parties in interest, including the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Modification of rate of prospecting, development, and production</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may require that any unit agreement authorized by this section that applies to land owned by the United States contain a provision under which authority is vested in the Secretary, or any person, committee, or State or Federal officer or agency as may be designated in the unit agreement to alter or modify, from time to time, the rate of prospecting and development and the quantity and rate of production under the unit agreement.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exclusion from determination of holding or control</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any land that is subject to a unit agreement approved or prescribed by the Secretary under this section shall not be considered in determining holdings or control under <ref>section 1006 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Pooling of certain land</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">If separate tracts of land cannot be independently developed and operated to use geothermal resources pursuant to any section of this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the land, or a portion of the land, may be pooled with other land, whether or not owned by the United States, for purposes of development and operation under a communitization agreement providing for an apportionment of production or royalties among the separate tracts of land comprising the production unit, if the pooling is determined by the Secretary to be in the public interest; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> operation or production pursuant to the communitization agreement shall be treated as operation or production with respect to each tract of land that is subject to the communitization agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Unit agreement review</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 5 years after the date of approval of any unit agreement and at least every 5 years thereafter, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> review each unit agreement; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> after notice and opportunity for comment, eliminate from inclusion in the unit agreement any land that the Secretary determines is not reasonably necessary for unit operations under the unit agreement.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Basis for elimination</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The elimination shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> be based on scientific evidence; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> occur only if the elimination is determined by the Secretary to be for the purpose of conserving and properly managing the geothermal resource.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Extension</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any land eliminated under this subsection shall be eligible for an extension under <ref>section 1005(g) of this title</ref> if the land meets the requirements for the extension.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Drilling or development contracts</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may, on such conditions as the Secretary may prescribe, approve drilling or development contracts made by one or more lessees of geothermal leases, with one or more persons, associations, or corporations if, in the discretion of the Secretary, the conservation of natural resources or the public convenience or necessity may require or the interests of the United States may be best served by the approval.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Holdings or control</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Each lease operated under an approved drilling or development contract, and interest under the contract, shall be excepted in determining holdings or control under <ref>section 1006 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination with State governments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall coordinate unitization and pooling activities with appropriate State agencies.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–581, § 18</ref>, <date date="1970-12-24">Dec. 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1571</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–443, § 4</ref>, <date date="1988-09-22">Sept. 22, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1768</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–58, title II, § 227</ref>, <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 666</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1018.</num>
<heading> Data from Federal agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon request of the Secretary, other Federal departments and agencies shall furnish him with any relevant data then in their possession or knowledge concerning or having bearing upon fair and adequate charges to be made for geothermal steam produced or to be produced for conversion to electric power or other purposes. Data given to any department or agency as confidential under law shall not be furnished in any fashion which identifies or tends to identify the business entity whose activities are the subject of such data or the person or persons who furnished such information.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–581, § 19</ref>, <date date="1970-12-24">Dec. 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1572</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–58, title II, § 236(18)</ref>, <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 673</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1019.</num>
<heading> Disposal of moneys from sales, bonuses, rentals, and royalties</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except with respect to lands in the State of Alaska, all monies received by the United States from sales, bonuses, rentals, and royalties under this chapter shall be paid into the Treasury of the United States. Of amounts deposited under this subsection, subject to the provisions of subsection (b) of <ref>section 191 of this title</ref> and <ref>section 1004(a)(2) of this title</ref>—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> 50 percent shall be paid to the State within the boundaries of which the leased lands or geothermal resources are or were located; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> 25 percent shall be paid to the county within the boundaries of which the leased lands or geothermal resources are or were located.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Amounts paid to a State or county under subsection (a) shall be used consistent with the terms of <ref>section 191 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–581, § 20</ref>, <date date="1970-12-24">Dec. 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1572</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–443, § 5(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-22">Sept. 22, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1768</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–66, title X, § 10202(b)</ref>, <date date="1993-08-10">Aug. 10, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 408</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–58, title II, § 224(b)</ref>, <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 663</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1020.</num>
<heading> Publication in Federal Register; reservation of mineral rights</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Geothermal resources in lands the surface of which has passed from Federal ownership but in which the minerals have been reserved to the United States shall not be developed or produced except under geothermal leases made pursuant to this chapter. If the Secretary of the Interior finds that such development is imminent, or that production from a well heretofore drilled on such lands is imminent, he shall so report to the Attorney General, and the Attorney General is authorized and directed to institute an appropriate proceeding in the United States district court of the district in which such lands are located, to quiet the title of the United States in such resources, and if the court determines that the reservation of minerals to the United States in the lands involved included the geothermal resources, to enjoin their production otherwise than under the terms of this chapter: <i>Provided</i>, That upon an authoritative judicial determination that Federal mineral reservation does not include geothermal resources the duties of the Secretary of the Interior to report and of the Attorney General to institute proceedings, as hereinbefore set forth, shall cease.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–581, § 21</ref>, <date date="1970-12-24">Dec. 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1572</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–58, title II, § 236(1)</ref>, (3), (19), <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 671</ref>, 673.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1021.</num>
<heading> Federal exemption from State water laws</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall constitute an express or implied claim or denial on the part of the Federal Government as to its exemption from State water laws.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–581, § 22</ref>, <date date="1970-12-24">Dec. 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1573</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–58, title II, § 236(20)</ref>, <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 673</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1022.</num>
<heading> Prevention of waste; exclusivity</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> All leases under this chapter shall be subject to the condition that the lessee will, in conducting his exploration, development, and producing operations, use all reasonable precautions to prevent waste of geothermal resources developed in the lands leased.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Rights to develop and utilize geothermal resources underlying lands owned by the United States may be acquired solely in accordance with the provisions of this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–581, § 23</ref>, <date date="1970-12-24">Dec. 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1573</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–58, title II, § 236(1)</ref>, (21), <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 671</ref>, 673.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1023.</num>
<heading> Rules and regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall prescribe such rules and regulations as he may deem appropriate to carry out the provisions of this chapter. Such regulations may include, without limitation, provisions for (a) the prevention of waste, (b) development and conservation of geothermal and other natural resources, (c) the protection of the public interest, (d) assignment, segregation, extension of terms, relinquishment of leases, development contracts, unitization, pooling, and drilling agreements, (e) compensatory royalty agreements, suspension of operations or production, and suspension or reduction of rentals or royalties, (f) the filing of surety bonds to assure compliance with the terms of the lease and to protect surface use and resources, (g) use of the surface by a lessee of the lands embraced in his lease, (h) the maintenance by the lessee of an active development program, and (i) protection of water quality and other environmental qualities.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–581, § 24</ref>, <date date="1970-12-24">Dec. 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1573</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–58, title II, § 236(22)</ref>, <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 673</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1024.</num>
<heading> Inclusion of geothermal leasing under certain other laws</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As to any land subject to geothermal leasing under <ref>section 1002 of this title</ref>, all laws which either (a) provide for the disposal of land by patent or other form of conveyance or by grant or by operation of law subject to a reservation of any mineral or (b) prevent or restrict the disposal of such land because of the mineral character of the land, shall hereafter be deemed to embrace geothermal resources as a substance which either must be reserved or must prevent or restrict the disposal of such land, as the case may be. This section shall not be construed to affect grants, patents, or other forms of conveyances made prior to <date date="1970-12-24">December 24, 1970</date>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–581, § 25</ref>, <date date="1970-12-24">Dec. 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1573</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–58, title II, § 236(1)</ref>, (23), <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 671</ref>, 673.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1025.</num>
<heading> Federal reservation of certain mineral rights</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The United States reserves the ownership of and the right to extract under such rules and regulations as the Secretary may prescribe oil, hydrocarbon gas, and helium from all geothermal resources produced from lands leased under this chapter in accordance with presently applicable laws: <i>Provided</i>, That whenever the right to extract oil, hydrocarbon gas, and helium from geothermal resources produced from such lands is exercised pursuant to this section, it shall be exercised so as to cause no substantial interference with the production of geothermal resources from such lands.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–581, § 27</ref>, <date date="1970-12-24">Dec. 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1574</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–58, title II, § 236(1)</ref>, (25), <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 671</ref>, 673.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1026.</num>
<heading> Significant thermal features</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Units of National Park System</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary shall maintain a list of significant thermal features, as defined in <ref>section 1001(f) of this title</ref>, within units of the National Park System, including but not limited to the following units:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Mount Rainier National Park.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Crater Lake National Park.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Yellowstone National Park.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Memorial Parkway.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Bering Land Bridge National Preserve.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Gates of the Arctic National Park and Preserve.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> Katmai National Park.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> Aniakchak National Monument and Preserve.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> Wrangell-St. Elias National Park and Preserve.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> Lake Clark National Park and Preserve.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> Hot Springs National Park.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(L)</num>
<content> Big Bend National Park (including that portion of the Rio Grande National Wild Scenic River within the boundaries of Big Bend National Park).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(M)</num>
<content> Lassen Volcanic National Park.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(N)</num>
<content> Hawaiʻi Volcanoes National Park.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(O)</num>
<content> Haleakala̅ National Park.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(P)</num>
<content> Lake Mead National Recreation Area.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary may, after notice and public comment, add significant thermal features within units of the National Park System to the significant thermal features list.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary shall consider the following criteria in determining the significance of thermal features:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Size, extent and uniqueness.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Scientific and geologic significance.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The extent to which such features remain in a natural, undisturbed condition.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Significance of thermal features to the authorized purposes for which the National Park System unit was established.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Monitoring program</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall maintain a monitoring program for significant thermal features within units of the National Park System.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> As part of the monitoring program required by paragraph (1), the Secretary shall establish a research program to collect and assess data on the geothermal resources within units of the National Park System with significant thermal features. Such program shall be carried out by the National Park Service in cooperation with the U.S. Geological Survey and shall begin with the collection and assessment of data for significant thermal features near current or proposed geothermal development and shall also include such features near areas of potential geothermal development.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Lease application; adverse effect</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Upon receipt of an application for a lease under this chapter, the Secretary shall determine on the basis of scientific evidence if exploration, development or utilization of the lands subject to the lease application is reasonably likely to result in a significant adverse effect on a significant thermal feature within a unit of the National Park System. Such determination shall be subject to notice and public comment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If the Secretary determines that the exploration, development or utilization of the land subject to the lease application is reasonably likely to result in a significant adverse effect on a significant thermal feature within a unit of the National Park System, the Secretary shall not issue such lease.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall not issue any lease under this chapter for those lands, or portions thereof, which are the subject of a determination made pursuant to subparagraph (2).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Lease stipulations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">With respect to all leases or drilling permits issued, extended, renewed or modified under this chapter, the Secretary shall include stipulations in such leases and permits necessary to protect significant thermal features within units of the National Park System where the Secretary determines that, based on scientific evidence, the exploration, development or utilization of the land subject to the lease or drilling permit is reasonably likely to adversely affect any such significant thermal feature. Stipulations shall include, but not be limited to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> requiring the lessee to reinject geothermal fluids into the rock formations from which they originate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> requiring the lessee to report annually to the Secretary on activities taken on the lease;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> requiring the lessee to continuously monitor geothermal resources production and injection wells; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> requiring the lessee to suspend activity on the lease if the Secretary determines that ongoing exploration, development or utilization activities are having a significant adverse effect on a significant thermal feature within a unit of the National Park System until such time as the significant adverse effect is eliminated. The stipulation shall provide for the termination of the lease by the Secretary if the significant adverse effect cannot be eliminated within a reasonable period of time.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Lands administered by Department of Agriculture</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture shall consider the effects on significant thermal features within units of the National Park System in determining whether to consent to leasing under this chapter on national forest lands or other lands administered by the Department of Agriculture available for leasing under this chapter, including public, withdrawn, and acquired lands.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall affect the ban on leasing under this chapter with respect to the Island Park Geothermal Area, as designated by the map in the “Final Environmental Impact Statement of the Island Park Geothermal Area” (<date date="1980-01-15">January 15, 1980</date>, p. XI), and provided for in <ref>Public Law 98–473</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–581, § 28</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 100–443, § 6</ref>, <date date="1988-09-22">Sept. 22, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1769</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–510, § 3(a)(2)</ref>, (b)(2), <date date="2000-11-13">Nov. 13, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2363</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–58, title II, § 236(1)</ref>, (26), <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 671</ref>, 673.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1027.</num>
<heading> Land subject to prohibition on leasing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall not issue any lease under this chapter on those lands subject to the prohibition provided under <ref>section 226–3 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–581, § 29</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 100–443, § 5(d)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-22">Sept. 22, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1769</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 109–58, title II, § 236(27)</ref>, <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 673</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1028.</num>
<heading> Hot dry rock geothermal energy</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition of enhanced geothermal systems</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this section, the term “enhanced geothermal systems” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 17191 of title 42</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> USGS program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior, acting through the United States Geological Survey, and in consultation with the Secretary of Energy, shall establish a cooperative Government-private sector program with respect to hot dry rock geothermal energy resources on public lands (as such term is defined in <ref>section 1702(e) of title 43</ref>) and lands managed by the Department of Agriculture, other than any such public or other lands that are withdrawn from geothermal leasing. Such program shall include, but shall not be limited to, activities to identify, select, and classify those areas throughout the United States that have a high potential for hot dry rock geothermal energy production and activities to develop and disseminate information regarding the utilization of such areas for hot dry rock energy production. Such information may include information regarding field test processes and techniques for assuring that hot dry rock geothermal energy development projects are developed in an economically feasible manner without adverse environmental consequences. Utilizing the information developed by the Secretary, together with information developed in connection with other related programs carried out by other Federal agencies, the Secretary, acting through the United States Geological Survey, may also enter into contracts and cooperative agreements with any public or private entity to provide assistance to any such entity to enable such entity to carry out additional projects with respect to the utilization of hot dry rock geothermal energy resources which will further the purposes of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Update to geothermal resource assessment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior, acting through the United States Geological Survey, and in consultation with the Secretary of Energy, shall update the 2008 United States geothermal resource assessment carried out by the United States Geological Survey, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> with respect to areas previously identified by the Department of Energy or the United States Geological Survey as having significant potential for hydrothermal energy or enhanced geothermal systems energy, by focusing on—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> improving the resolution of resource potential at systematic temperatures and depths, including temperatures and depths appropriate for power generation and direct use applications;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> quantifying the total potential to coproduce geothermal energy and minerals;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> incorporating data relevant to underground thermal energy storage and exchange, such as aquifer and soil properties; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> producing high resolution maps, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> maps that indicate key subsurface parameters for electric and direct use resources; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> risk maps for induced seismicity based on geologic, geographic, and operational parameters; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to the maximum extent practicable, by coordinating with relevant State officials and institutions of higher education to expand geothermal assessments, including enhanced geothermal systems assessments, to include assessments for the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico and the States of Alaska and Hawaii.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–486, title XXV, § 2501</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 3101</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–260, div. Z, title III, § 3002(m)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 2496</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>