<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 31—</num>
<heading>MARINE MINERAL RESOURCES RESEARCH</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1901.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “contract” has the same meaning as “procurement contract” in <ref>section 6303 of title 31</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “cooperative agreement” has the same meaning as in <ref>section 6305 of title 31</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The term “eligible entity” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a research or educational entity chartered or incorporated under Federal or State law;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an individual who is a United States citizen; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a State or regional agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “grant” has the same meaning as “grant agreement” in <ref>section 6304 of title 31</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The term “in-kind contribution” means a noncash contribution provided by a non-Federal entity that directly benefits and is related to a specific project or program. An in-kind contribution may include real property, equipment, supplies, other expendable property, goods, and services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> The term “marine mineral resource” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> sand and aggregates;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> placers;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> phosphates;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> manganese nodules;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> cobalt crusts;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> metal sulfides;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> for purposes of this section and sections 1902 through 1905 of this title only, methane hydrate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<chapeau> other marine resources that are not—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> oil and gas;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> fisheries; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> marine mammals.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<chapeau> The term “methane hydrate” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a methane clathrate that is in the form of a methane-water ice-like crystalline material and is stable and occurs naturally in deep-ocean and permafrost areas; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> other natural gas hydrates found in association with deep-ocean and permafrost deposits of methane hydrate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of the Interior.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–631, title II, § 201</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 104–325, § 2(3)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3994</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–193, § 4</ref>, <date date="2000-05-02">May 2, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 236</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1902.</num>
<heading> Research program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish and carry out a program of research on marine mineral resources.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program goal</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The goal of the program shall be to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> promote research, identification, assessment, and exploration of marine mineral resources in an environmentally responsible manner;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> assist in developing domestic technologies required for efficient and environmentally sound development of marine mineral resources;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> coordinate and promote the use of technologies developed with Federal assistance, and the use of available Federal assets, for research, identification, assessment, exploration, and development of marine mineral resources; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> encourage academia and industry to conduct basic and applied research, on a joint basis, through grants, cooperative agreements, or contracts with the Federal Government.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Responsibilities of Secretary</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In carrying out the program, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> promote and coordinate partnerships between industry, government, and academia to research, identify, assess, and explore marine mineral resources in an environmentally sound manner;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> undertake programs to develop the basic information necessary to the long-term national interest in marine mineral resources (including seabed mapping) and to ensure that data and information are accessible and widely disseminated as needed and appropriate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> identify, and promote cooperation among agency programs that are developing, technologies developed by other Federal programs that may hold promise for facilitating undersea applications related to marine mineral resources, including technologies related to vessels and other platforms, underwater vehicles, survey and mapping systems, remote power sources, data collection and transmission systems, and various seabed research systems; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> foster communication and coordination between Federal and State agencies, universities, and private entities concerning marine mineral research on seabeds of the continental shelf, ocean basins, and arctic and cold water areas.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">In carrying out these responsibilities, the Secretary shall ensure the participation of non-Federal users of technologies and data related to marine mineral resources in planning and priority setting.</continuation>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–631, title II, § 202</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 104–325, § 2(3)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3995</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1903.</num>
<heading> Grants, contracts, and cooperative agreements</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistance and coordination</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary shall award grants or contracts to, or enter into cooperative agreements with, eligible entities to support research for the development or utilization of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> methods, equipment, systems, and components necessary for the identification, assessment, and exploration of marine mineral resources in an environmentally responsible manner;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> methods of detecting, monitoring, and predicting the presence of adverse environmental effects in the marine environment and remediating the environmental effects of marine mineral resource exploration, development, and production; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> education and training material in marine mineral research and resource management.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cost-sharing for contracts or cooperative agreements</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal share</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Except as provided in subparagraph (B)(ii), the Federal share of the cost of a contract or cooperative agreement carried out under this subsection shall not be greater than 80 percent of the total cost of the project.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Non-Federal share</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The remaining non-Federal share of the cost of a project carried out under this section may be—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> in the form of cash or in-kind contributions, or both; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> comprised of funds made available under other Federal programs, except that non-Federal funds shall be used to defray at least 10 percent of the total cost of the project.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Not later than 180 days after <date date="1996-10-19">October 19, 1996</date>, the Secretary shall establish, after consultation with other Federal agencies, terms and conditions under which Federal funding will be provided under this subsection that are consistent with the Agreement on Subsidies and Countervailing Measures referred to in <ref>section 3511(d)(12) of title 19</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Competitive review</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">An entity shall not be eligible to receive a grant or contract, or participate in a cooperative agreement, under subsection (a) unless—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the entity submits a proposal to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and accompanied by such information as the Secretary may reasonably require; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the proposal has been evaluated by a competitive review panel under paragraph (3).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Competitive review panels</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Composition</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">A competitive review panel shall be chaired by the Secretary or by the Secretary’s designee and shall be composed of members who meet the following criteria:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The members shall be appointed by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Experience</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Not less than 50 percent of the members shall represent or be employed by private marine resource companies that are involved in exploration of the marine environment or development of marine mineral resources.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interest</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">None of the members may have an interest in a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement being evaluated by the panel.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> No compensation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A review panel member who is not otherwise a Federal employee shall receive no compensation for performing duties under this section, except that, while engaged in the performance of duties away from the home or regular place of business of the member, the member may be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, in the same manner as a person employed intermittently in the Government service under <ref>section 5703 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Evaluation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A competitive review panel shall base an evaluation of a proposal on criteria developed by the Secretary that shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the merits of the proposal;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the research methodology and costs of the proposal;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the capability of the entity submitting the proposal and any other participating entity to perform the proposed work and provide in-kind contributions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the amount of matching funds provided by the entity submitting the proposal or provided by other Federal, State, or private entities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the extent of collaboration with other Federal, State, or private entities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> in the case of a noncommercial entity, the existence of a cooperative agreement with a commercial entity that provides for collaboration in the proposed research;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> whether the proposal promotes responsible environmental stewardship; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> such other factors as the Secretary considers appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrative expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not more than 10 percent of the amount made available to carry out this section during a fiscal year may be used by the Secretary for expenses associated with administration of the program authorized by this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Construction costs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">None of the funds made available under this section may be used for the construction of a new building or the acquisition, expansion, remodeling, or alteration of an existing building (including site grading and improvement and architect fees).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">An eligible entity that receives a grant or contract or enters into a cooperative agreement under this section shall submit an annual progress report and a final technical report to the Secretary that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> describes project activities, implications of the project, the significance of the project to marine mineral research, identification, assessment, and exploration, and potential commercial and economic benefits and effects of the project; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in the case of an annual progress report, includes a project plan for the subsequent year.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–631, title II, § 203</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 104–325, § 2(3)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3995</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1904.</num>
<heading> Marine mineral research centers</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No later than 90 days after <date date="1996-10-19">October 19, 1996</date>, the Secretary shall designate 3 centers for marine mineral research and related activities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Concentration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">One center shall concentrate primarily on research in the continental shelf regions of the United States, 1 center shall concentrate primarily on research in deep seabed and near-shore environments of islands, and 1 center shall concentrate primarily on research in arctic and cold water regions.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Criteria</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In designating a center under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to a university that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> administers a federally funded center for marine minerals research;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> matriculates students for advanced degrees in marine geological sciences, nonenergy natural resources, and related fields of science and engineering;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> is a United States university with established programs and facilities that primarily focus on marine mineral resources;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> has engaged in collaboration and cooperation with industry, governmental agencies, and other universities in the field of marine mineral resources;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> has demonstrated significant engineering, development, and design experience in two or more of the following areas; <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002110">1</ref></chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> seabed exploration systems;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> marine mining systems; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> marine mineral processing systems; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> has been designated by the Secretary as a State Mining and Mineral Resources Research Institute.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Center activities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A center shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provide technical assistance to the Secretary concerning marine mineral resources;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> advise the Secretary on pertinent international activities in marine mineral resources development;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> engage in research, training, and education transfer associated with the characterization and utilization of marine mineral resources; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> promote the efficient identification, assessment, exploration, and management of marine mineral resources in an environmentally sound manner.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Allocation of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In distributing funds to the centers designated under subsection (a), the Secretary shall, to the extent practicable, allocate an equal amount to each center.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrative expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not more than 5 percent of the amount made available to carry out this section during a fiscal year may be used by the Secretary for expenses associated with administration of the program authorized by this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Construction costs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">None of the funds made available under this section may be used for the construction of a new building or the acquisition, expansion, remodeling, or alteration of an existing building (including site grading and improvement and architect fees).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–631, title II, § 204</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 104–325, § 2(3)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3998</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1905.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated such sums as are necessary to carry out this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–631, title II, § 205</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 104–325, § 2(3)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3999</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>