<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 879—</num>
<heading>SHIPS’ STORES AND COMMISSARY STORES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 8801.</num>
<heading> Sales: members of the naval service and Coast Guard; widows and widowers; civilian employees and other persons</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Such stores as the Secretary of the Navy designates may be procured and sold to members of the naval service, members of the Coast Guard, and widows and widowers of such members.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary may, by regulation, provide for the procurement and sale of stores designated by him to such civilian officers and employees of the United States, and such other persons, as he considers proper—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> at military installations outside the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> at military installations inside the United States where he determines that it is impracticable for those civilian officers, employees, and persons to obtain those stores from private agencies without impairing the efficient operation of naval activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">However, sales to civilian officers and employees inside the United States may be made only to those residing within military installations.</continuation>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 470</ref>, § 7601; <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title XIII, § 1301(c)(3)(A)</ref>, (B), <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 736</ref>; renumbered § 8801, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(d)(9)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1837</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8802.</num>
<heading> Sales: members of Army, Air Force, and Space Force; prices</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Navy and the Marine Corps shall sell subsistence supplies to any member of the Army, the Air Force, or the Space Force at prices charged members of the naval service.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 471</ref>, § 7602; renumbered § 8802, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(d)(9)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1837</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 924(d)(2)(A)</ref>, (B), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3826</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8803.</num>
<heading> Sales: veterans under treatment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A person who has been separated honorably or under honorable conditions from the Army, the Navy, the Air Force, the Marine Corps, the Space Force, or the Coast Guard and who is receiving care and medical treatment from the Public Health Service or the Department of Veterans Affairs may buy subsistence supplies and other supplies, except articles of uniform, from the Navy and the Marine Corps at prices charged members of the naval service.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 471</ref>, § 7603; <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title XVI, § 1621(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1602</ref>; renumbered § 8803, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(d)(9)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1837</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 924(d)(3)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3826</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title VI, § 642</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1938</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8804.</num>
<heading> Ships’ stores: sale of goods and services</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Under such regulations and at such prices as the Secretary of the Navy may prescribe, the Secretary may provide for the sale of goods and services from ships’ stores to members of the naval service and to such other persons as provided by law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Incidental Services</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the Navy may provide financial services, space, utilities, and labor to ships’ stores on a nonreimbursable basis.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Items Sold</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Merchandise sold by ship stores afloat may include items in the following categories:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Health, beauty, and barber items.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Prerecorded music and videos.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Photographic batteries and related supplies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Appliances and accessories.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Uniform items, emblematic and athletic clothing, and equipment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Luggage and leather goods.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Stationery, magazines, books, and supplies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Sundry, games, and souvenirs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> Beverages and related food and snacks.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> Laundry, tailor, and cleaning supplies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> Tobacco products.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title III, § 329(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1534</ref>, § 7604; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title III, § 371(a)</ref>, formerly § 371(c), <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1635</ref>, renumbered § 371(a), <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title III, § 340(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 265</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title VI, § 641</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1466</ref>; renumbered § 8804, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(d)(9)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1837</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8805.</num>
<heading> Acceptance of Government checks outside the United States</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Notwithstanding <ref>section 3302(a) of title 31</ref>, the Secretary of the Navy may authorize the officer in charge of any commissary store or ship’s store ashore located outside the United States to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> accept any Government check tendered by a retired member of the Navy or the Marine Corps, a member of the Navy Reserve or the Marine Corps Reserve, or a member of the Fleet Reserve or the Fleet Marine Corps Reserve, if the member is the payee of the check and the check is tendered in payment of amounts due from the member to the store; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> refund in cash any difference between the amount due and the amount of the tendered check.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 471</ref>, § 7605; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 513(42)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2935</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–258, § 3(b)(10)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1064</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title V, § 515(b)(1)(V)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3233</ref>; renumbered § 8805, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(d)(9)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1837</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8806.</num>
<heading> Subsistence and other supplies: members of armed forces; veterans; executive or military departments and employees; prices</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of the Navy shall procure and sell, for cash or credit—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> articles designated by the Secretary to members of the Navy and Marine Corps; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> items of individual clothing and equipment to members of the Navy and Marine Corps, under such restrictions as the Secretary may prescribe.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> An account of sales on credit shall be kept and the amount due reported to the Secretary. Except for articles and items acquired through the use of working capital funds under <ref>section 2208 of this title</ref>, sales of articles shall be at cost, and sales of individual clothing and equipment shall be at average current prices, including overhead, as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall sell subsistence supplies to members of other armed forces at the prices at which like property is sold to members of the Navy and Marine Corps.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Secretary may sell serviceable supplies, other than subsistence supplies, to members of other armed forces for the buyers’ use in the service. The prices at which the supplies are sold shall be the same prices at which like property is sold to members of the Navy and Marine Corps.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> A person who has been discharged honorably or under honorable conditions from the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, or Space Force and who is receiving care and medical treatment from the Public Health Service or the Department of Veterans Affairs may buy subsistence supplies and other supplies, except articles of uniform, at the prices at which like property is sold to members of the Navy and Marine Corps.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> Under such conditions as the Secretary may prescribe, exterior articles of uniform may be sold to a person who has been discharged honorably or under honorable conditions from the Navy or Marine Corps, at the prices at which like articles are sold to members of the Navy or Marine Corps. This subsection does not modify section 772 or 773 of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, payment for subsistence supplies shall be made in cash or by commercial credit.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary may provide for the procurement and sale of stores designated by the Secretary to such civilian officers and employees of the United States, and such other persons, as the Secretary considers proper—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> at military installations outside the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> subject to paragraph (2), at military installations inside the United States where the Secretary determines that it is impracticable for those civilian officers, employees, and persons to obtain such stores from commercial enterprises without impairing the efficient operation of military activities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Sales to civilian officers and employees inside the United States may be made under paragraph (1) only to civilian officers and employees residing within military installations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<content> Appropriations for subsistence of the Navy or Marine Corps may be applied to the purchase of subsistence supplies for sale to members of the Navy and Marine Corps on active duty for the use of such members and their families.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title III, § 375(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 281</ref>, § 7606; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title X, § 1073(a)(63)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1903</ref>; renumbered § 8806, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(d)(9)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1837</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 924(d)(4)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3826</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>