<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 973—</num>
<heading>DISPOSAL OF OBSOLETE OR SURPLUS MATERIAL</heading>
<section>
<num>[§ 9681.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1253(a)(1)(D)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2532</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9682.</num>
<heading> Obsolete or excess material: sale to National Council of Boy Scouts of America</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to regulations under <ref>section 121 of title 40</ref>, the Secretary of the Air Force, under such conditions as he may prescribe, may sell obsolete or excess material to the National Council of the Boy Scouts of America. Sales under this section shall be at fair value to the Department of the Air Force, including packing, handling, and transportation.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 583</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 514(18)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2936</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–217, § 3(b)(37)</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1298</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9684.</num>
<heading> Surplus obsolete ordnance: sale to patriotic organizations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subject to regulations under <ref>section 121 of title 40</ref>, the Secretary of the Air Force may sell, without advertisement and at prices that he considers reasonable—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> surplus obsolete small arms and ammunition and equipment for them, to any patriotic organization for military purposes; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> surplus obsolete brass or bronze cannons, carriages, and cannon balls, for public parks, public buildings, and soldiers’ monuments.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 583</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 514(18)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2936</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–217, § 3(b)(38)</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1298</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9685.</num>
<heading> Obsolete ordnance: loan to educational institutions and State soldiers’ and sailors’ orphans’ homes</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Upon the recommendation of the Governor of the State concerned or Guam or the Virgin Islands, the Secretary of the Air Force, under regulations to be prescribed by him and without cost to the United States for transportation, may lend obsolete ordnance and ordnance stores to State, Guam, and the Virgin Islands educational institutions and to State soldiers’ and sailors’ orphans’ homes, for drill and instruction. However, no loan may be made under this subsection to an institution to which ordnance or ordnance stores may be issued under any law that was in effect on <date date="1906-06-30">June 30, 1906</date>, and is still in effect.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall require a bond from each institution or home to which property is lent under subsection (a), in double the value of the property lent, for the care and safekeeping of that property and, except for property properly expended, for its return when required.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 584</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title X, § 1057(a)(10)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3441</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9686.</num>
<heading> Obsolete ordnance: gift to State homes for soldiers and sailors</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to regulations under <ref>section 121 of title 40</ref>, the Secretary of the Air Force may give not more than two obsolete bronze or iron cannons suitable for firing salutes to any home for soldiers or sailors established and maintained under State authority.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 584</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 514(18)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2936</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–217, § 3(b)(39)</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1298</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>