<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 1607—</num>
<heading>EDUCATIONAL ASSISTANCE FOR RESERVE COMPONENT MEMBERS SUPPORTING CONTINGENCY OPERATIONS AND CERTAIN OTHER OPERATIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 16161.</num>
<heading> Purpose</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The purpose of this chapter is to provide educational assistance to members of the reserve components called or ordered to active service in response to a war or national emergency declared by the President or the Congress, in recognition of the sacrifices that those members make in answering the call to duty.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title V, § 527(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1890</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 16162.</num>
<heading> Educational assistance program</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Program Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of each military department, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, and the Secretary of Homeland Security with respect to the Coast Guard when it is not operating as a service in the Navy, shall establish and maintain a program as prescribed in this chapter to provide educational assistance to members of the Ready Reserve of the armed forces under the jurisdiction of the Secretary concerned.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authorized Education Programs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Educational assistance may be provided under this chapter for pursuit of any program of education that is an approved program of education for purposes of chapter 30 of title 38.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Benefit Amount</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The educational assistance program established under subsection (a) shall provide for payment by the Secretary concerned, through the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, an educational assistance allowance to each member entitled to educational assistance under this chapter who is pursuing a program of education authorized under subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The educational assistance allowance provided under this chapter shall be based on the applicable percent under paragraph (4) to the applicable rate provided under <ref>section 3015 of title 38</ref> for a member whose entitlement is based on completion of an obligated period of active duty of three years.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The educational assistance allowance provided under this section for a person who is undertaking a program for which a reduced rate is specified in chapter 30 of title 38, that rate shall be further adjusted by the applicable percent specified in paragraph (4).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> The adjusted educational assistance allowance under paragraph (2) or (3), as applicable, shall be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> 40 percent in the case of a member of a reserve component who performed active service for 90 consecutive days but less than one continuous year;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> 60 percent in the case of a member of a reserve component who performed active service for one continuous year but less than two continuous years; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> 80 percent in the case of a member of a reserve component who performed active service for—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> two continuous years or more; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> an aggregate of three years or more.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Maximum Months of Assistance</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Subject to <ref>section 3695 of title 38</ref>, the maximum number of months of educational assistance that may be provided to any member under this chapter is 36 (or the equivalent thereof in part-time educational assistance).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter or chapter 36 of title 38, any payment of an educational assistance allowance described in subparagraph (B) shall not—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> be charged against the entitlement of any individual under this chapter; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> be counted toward the aggregate period for which <ref>section 3695 of title 38</ref> limits an individual’s receipt of assistance.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> The payment of the educational assistance allowance referred to in subparagraph (A) is the payment of such an allowance to the individual for pursuit of a course or courses under this chapter if the Secretary of Veterans Affairs finds that the individual—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> had to discontinue such course pursuit as a result of being ordered to serve on active duty under section 12301(a), 12301(d), 12301(g), 12302, or 12304 of this title; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> failed to receive credit or training time toward completion of the individual’s approved educational, professional, or vocational objective as a result of having to discontinue, as described in clause (i), the individual’s course pursuit.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The period for which, by reason of this subsection, an educational assistance allowance is not charged against entitlement or counted toward the applicable aggregate period under <ref>section 3695 of title 38</ref> shall not exceed the portion of the period of enrollment in the course or courses for which the individual failed to receive credit or with respect to which the individual lost training time, as determined under subparagraph (B)(ii).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Availability of Assistance for Licensing and Certification Tests</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The provisions of <ref>section 16131(j) of this title</ref> shall apply to the provision of educational assistance under this chapter, except that, in applying such section under this chapter, the reference to subsection (b) in paragraph (2) of such section is deemed to be a reference to subsection (c) of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contributions for Increased Amount of Educational Assistance</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Any individual eligible for educational assistance under this section may contribute amounts for purposes of receiving an increased amount of educational assistance as provided for in paragraph (2).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> An individual covered by subparagraph (A) may make the contributions authorized by that subparagraph at any time while a member of a reserve component, but not more frequently than monthly.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The total amount of the contributions made by an individual under subparagraph (A) may not exceed $600. Such contributions shall be made in multiples of $20.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Contributions under this subsection shall be made to the Secretary concerned. Such Secretary shall deposit any amounts received as contributions under this subsection into the Treasury as miscellaneous receipts.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Effective as of the first day of the enrollment period following the enrollment period in which an individual makes contributions under paragraph (1), the monthly amount of educational assistance allowance applicable to such individual under this section shall be the monthly rate otherwise provided for under subsection (c) increased by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an amount equal to $5 for each $20 contributed by such individual under paragraph (1) for an approved program of education pursued on a full-time basis; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an appropriately reduced amount based on the amount so contributed as determined under regulations that the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall prescribe, for an approved program of education pursued on less than a full-time basis.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title V, § 527(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1890</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title V, § 539(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3250</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title V, § 528(c)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 109</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 16162a.</num>
<heading> Accelerated payment of educational assistance</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Payment on Accelerated Basis</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The educational assistance allowance payable under <ref>section 16162 of this title</ref> with respect to an eligible member described in subsection (b) may, upon the election of such eligible member, be paid on an accelerated basis in accordance with this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Eligible Members</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An eligible member described in this subsection is a member of a reserve component entitled to educational assistance under this chapter who is—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> enrolled in an approved program of education not exceeding two years in duration and not leading to an associate, bachelors, masters, or other degree, subject to subsection (g); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> charged tuition and fees for the program of education that, when divided by the number of months (and fractions thereof) in the enrollment period, exceeds the amount equal to 200 percent of the monthly rate of educational assistance allowance otherwise payable with respect to the member under <ref>section 16162 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Amount of Accelerated Payment</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The amount of the accelerated payment of educational assistance payable with respect to an eligible member making an election under subsection (a) for a program of education shall be the lesser of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the amount equal to 60 percent of the established charges for the program of education; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the aggregate amount of educational assistance allowance to which the member remains entitled under this chapter at the time of the payment.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> In this subsection, except as provided in subparagraph (B), the term “established charges”, in the case of a program of education, means the actual charges (as determined pursuant to regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs) for tuition and fees which similarly circumstanced individuals who are not eligible for benefits under this chapter and who are enrolled in the program of education would be required to pay. Established charges shall be determined on the following basis:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> In the case of an individual enrolled in a program of education offered on a term, quarter, or semester basis, the tuition and fees charged the individual for the term, quarter, or semester.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> In the case of an individual enrolled in a program of education not offered on a term, quarter, or semester basis, the tuition and fees charged the individual for the entire program of education.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> In this subsection, the term “established charges” does not include any fees or payments attributable to the purchase of a vehicle.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The educational institution providing the program of education for which an accelerated payment of educational assistance allowance is elected by an eligible member under subsection (a) shall certify to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs the amount of the established charges for the program of education.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Time of Payment</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An accelerated payment of educational assistance allowance made with respect to an eligible member under this section for a program of education shall be made not later than the last day of the month immediately following the month in which the Secretary of Veterans Affairs receives a certification from the educational institution regarding—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the member’s enrollment in and pursuit of the program of education; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the amount of the established charges for the program of education.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Charge Against Entitlement</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraph (2), for each accelerated payment of educational assistance allowance made with respect to an eligible member under this section, the member’s entitlement to educational assistance under this chapter shall be charged the number of months (and any fraction thereof) determined by dividing the amount of the accelerated payment by the full-time monthly rate of educational assistance allowance otherwise payable with respect to the member under <ref>section 16162 of this title</ref> as of the beginning date of the enrollment period for the program of education for which the accelerated payment is made.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If the monthly rate of educational assistance allowance otherwise payable with respect to an eligible member under <ref>section 16162 of this title</ref> increases during the enrollment period of a program of education for which an accelerated payment of educational assistance allowance is made under this section, the charge to the member’s entitlement to educational assistance under this chapter shall be determined by prorating the entitlement chargeable, in the manner provided for under paragraph (1), for the periods covered by the initial rate and increased rate, respectively, in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall prescribe regulations to carry out this section. The regulations shall include requirements, conditions, and methods for the request, issuance, delivery, certification of receipt and use, and recovery of overpayment of an accelerated payment of educational assistance allowance under this section. The regulations may include such elements of the regulations prescribed under <ref>section 3014A of title 38</ref> as the Secretary of Veterans Affairs considers appropriate for purposes of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The aggregate amount of educational assistance payable under this section in any fiscal year for enrollments covered by subsection (b)(1) may not exceed $3,000,000.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title V, § 528(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 107</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 16163.</num>
<heading> Eligibility for educational assistance</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Eligibility</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>On or after <date date="2001-09-11">September 11, 2001</date>, a member of a reserve component is entitled to educational assistance under this chapter if the member—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> served on active duty in support of a contingency operation for 90 consecutive days or more; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in the case of a member of the Army National Guard of the United States or Air National Guard of the United States, performed full time National Guard duty under <ref>section 502(f) of title 32</ref> for 90 consecutive days or more when authorized by the President or Secretary of Defense for the purpose of responding to a national emergency declared by the President and supported by Federal funds.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Disabled Members</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding the eligibility requirements in subsection (a), a member who was ordered to active service as prescribed under subsection (a)(1) or (a)(2) but is released from duty before completing 90 consecutive days because of an injury, illness or disease incurred or aggravated in the line of duty shall be entitled to educational assistance under this chapter at the rate prescribed in <ref>section 16162(c)(4)(A) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Written Notification</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Each member who becomes entitled to educational assistance under subsection (a) shall be given a statement in writing prior to release from active service that summarizes the provisions of this chapter and stating clearly and prominently the substance of <ref>section 16165 of this title</ref> as such section may apply to the member.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> At the request of the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, the Secretary concerned shall transmit a notice of entitlement for each such member to that Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Bar From Dual Eligibility</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A member who qualifies for educational assistance under this chapter may not receive credit for such service under both the program established by chapter 30 of title 38 and the program established by this chapter but shall make an irrevocable election (in such form and manner as the Secretary of Veterans Affairs may prescribe) as to the program to which such service is to be credited.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Bar From Duplication of Educational Assistance Allowance</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraph (2), an individual entitled to educational assistance under this chapter who is also eligible for educational assistance under chapter 1606 of this title, chapter 30, 31, 32, 33, or 35 of title 38, or under the Hostage Relief Act of 1980 (<ref>Public Law 96–449</ref>; <ref>5 U.S.C. 5561</ref> note) may not receive assistance under more than one such program and shall elect (in such form and manner as the Secretary of Veterans Affairs may prescribe) under which program the member elects to receive educational assistance.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The restriction on duplication of educational assistance under paragraph (1) does not apply to the entitlement of educational assistance under <ref>section 16131(i) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title V, § 527(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1892</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title V, § 540(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3251</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–252, title V, § 5003(b)(1)(C)</ref>, <date date="2008-06-30">June 30, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2375</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title X, § 1073(a)(36)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2474</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 16163a.</num>
<heading> Authority to transfer unused education benefits to family members</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to the provisions of this section, the Secretary concerned may permit, at such Secretary’s sole discretion, a member described in subsection (b) who is entitled to basic educational assistance under this chapter to elect to transfer to one or more of the dependents specified in subsection (c) a portion of such member’s entitlement to such assistance, subject to the limitation under subsection (d).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Eligible Members</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A member referred to in subsection (a) is a member of the armed forces who, at the time of the approval of the member’s request to transfer entitlement to basic educational assistance under this section, has completed at least—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> six years of service in the armed forces and enters into an agreement to serve at least four more years as a member of the armed forces; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the years of service as determined in regulations pursuant to subsection (j).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Eligible Dependents</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A member approved to transfer an entitlement to basic educational assistance under this section may transfer the member’s entitlement as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> To the member’s spouse.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> To one or more of the member’s children.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> To a combination of the individuals referred to in paragraphs (1) and (2).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Months of Transfer</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The total number of months of entitlement transferred by a member under this section may not exceed 36 months. The Secretary of Defense may prescribe regulations that would limit the months of entitlement that may be transferred under this section to no less than 18 months.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designation of Transferee</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A member transferring an entitlement to basic educational assistance under this section shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> designate the dependent or dependents to whom such entitlement is being transferred;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> designate the number of months of such entitlement to be transferred to each such dependent; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> specify the period for which the transfer shall be effective for each dependent designated under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Time for Transfer; Revocation and Modification</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Subject to the time limitation for use of entitlement under section 16164, a member approved to transfer entitlement to basic educational assistance under this section may transfer such entitlement only while serving as a member of the armed forces when the transfer is executed.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A member transferring entitlement under this section may modify or revoke at any time the transfer of any unused portion of the entitlement so transferred. The modification or revocation of the transfer of entitlement under this paragraph shall be made by the submittal of written notice of the action to both the Secretary concerned and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Entitlement transferred under this section may not be treated as marital property, or the asset of a marital estate, subject to division in a divorce or other civil proceeding.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Commencement of Use</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A dependent to whom entitlement to basic educational assistance is transferred under this section may not commence the use of the transferred entitlement until—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> in the case of entitlement transferred to a spouse, the completion by the member making the transfer of at least—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> six years of service in the armed forces; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the years of service as determined in regulations pursuant to subsection (j); or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> in the case of entitlement transferred to a child, both—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> the completion by the member making the transfer of at least—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> ten years of service in the armed forces; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the years of service as determined in regulations pursuant to subsection (j); and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> either—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the completion by the child of the requirements of a secondary school diploma (or equivalency certificate); or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the attainment by the child of 18 years of age.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Additional Administrative Matters</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The use of any entitlement to basic educational assistance transferred under this section shall be charged against the entitlement of the member making the transfer at the rate of one month for each month of transferred entitlement that is used.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Except as provided under subsection (e)(2) and subject to paragraphs (5) and (6), a dependent to whom entitlement is transferred under this section is entitled to basic educational assistance under this chapter in the same manner as the member from whom the entitlement was transferred.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The monthly rate of educational assistance payable to a dependent to whom entitlement is transferred under this section shall be the monthly amount payable under sections 16162 and 16162a to the member making the transfer.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The death of a member transferring an entitlement under this section shall not affect the use of the entitlement by the dependent to whom the entitlement is transferred.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding section 16164(a)(2), a child to whom entitlement is transferred under this section may use the benefit without regard to the 10-year delimiting date, but may not use any entitlement so transferred after attaining the age of 26 years.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The administrative provisions of this chapter shall apply to the use of entitlement transferred under this section, except that the dependent to whom the entitlement is transferred shall be treated as the eligible member for purposes of such provisions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The purposes for which a dependent to whom entitlement is transferred under this section may use such entitlement shall include the pursuit and completion of the requirements of a secondary school diploma (or equivalency certificate).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Overpayment.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Joint and several liability</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In the event of an overpayment of basic educational assistance with respect to a dependent to whom entitlement is transferred under this section, the dependent and the member making the transfer shall be jointly and severally liable to the United States for the amount of the overpayment for purposes of <ref>section 3685 of title 38</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Failure to complete service agreement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in paragraph (3), if an individual transferring entitlement under this section fails to complete the service agreed to by the individual under subsection (b)(1) in accordance with the terms of the agreement of the individual under that subsection, the amount of any transferred entitlement under this section that is used by a dependent of the individual as of the date of such failure shall be treated as an overpayment of educational assistance under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> Paragraph (2) shall not apply in the case of an individual who fails to complete service agreed to by the individual—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> by reason of the death of the individual; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for a reason referred to in section 16133(b).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, shall prescribe regulations for purposes of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Such regulations shall specify—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the manner of authorizing the transfer of entitlements under this section;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the eligibility criteria in accordance with subsection (b); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the manner and effect of an election to modify or revoke a transfer of entitlement under subsection (f)(2).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(k)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Secretary Concerned Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of this section, the term “Secretary concerned” has the meaning given in section 101(a)(9) in the case of a member of the armed forces.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–252, title V, § 5006(c)</ref>, <date date="2008-06-30">June 30, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2383</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title X, § 1075(b)(56)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4372</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 16164.</num>
<heading> Time limitation for use of entitlement</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duration of Entitlement</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Except as provided in subsection (b), a member remains entitled to educational assistance under this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> while the member is serving—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the Selected Reserve of the Ready Reserve, in the case of a member called or ordered to active service while serving in the Selected Reserve; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the Ready Reserve, in the case of a member ordered to active duty while serving in the Ready Reserve (other than the Selected Reserve); and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in the case of a person who separates from the Selected Reserve of the Ready Reserve after completion of a period of active service described in <ref>section 16163 of this title</ref> and completion of a service contract under honorable conditions, during the 10-year period beginning on the date on which the person separates from the Selected Reserve.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duration of Entitlement for Disabled Members</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In the case of a person who is separated from the Ready Reserve because of a disability which was not the result of the individual’s own willful misconduct incurred on or after the date on which such person became entitled to educational assistance under this chapter, such person’s entitlement to educational assistance expires at the end of the 10-year period beginning on the date on which such person became entitled to such assistance.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The provisions of subsections (d) and (f) of <ref>section 3031 of title 38</ref> shall apply to the period of entitlement prescribed by paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title V, § 527(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1892</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title V, § 530(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 110</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title V, § 546(a), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4466</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 16165.</num>
<heading> Termination of assistance</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Except as provided in subsection (b), educational assistance may not be provided under this chapter, or if being provided under this chapter, shall be terminated—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> if the member is receiving financial assistance under <ref>section 2107 of this title</ref> as a member of the Senior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps program; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> when the member separates from the Ready Reserve as provided in <ref>section 16164(a)(1) of this title</ref>, or upon completion of the period provided for in <ref>section 16164(a)(2) of this title</ref>, as applicable.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, educational assistance may be provided under this chapter to a member of the Selected Reserve of the Ready Reserve who incurs a break in service in the Selected Reserve if the member continues to serve in the Ready Reserve during and after such break in service.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title V, § 527(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1893</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title V, § 540(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3251</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title V, § 530(a)(2)</ref>, (b), <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 110</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 16166.</num>
<heading> Administration of program</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Administration</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Educational assistance under this chapter shall be provided through the Department of Veterans Affairs, under agreements to be entered into by the Secretary of Defense, and by the Secretary of Homeland Security, with the Secretary of Veterans Affairs. Such agreements shall include administrative procedures to ensure the prompt and timely transfer of funds from the Secretary concerned to the Department of Veterans Affairs for the making of payments under this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Program Management</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as otherwise provided in this chapter, the provisions of sections 503, 511, 3470, 3471, 3474, 3476, 3482(g), 3483, and 3485 of title 38 and the provisions of subchapters I and II of chapter 36 of such title (with the exception of sections 3686(a), 3687, and 3692) shall be applicable to the provision of educational assistance under this chapter. The term “eligible veteran” and the term “person”, as used in those provisions, shall be deemed for the purpose of the application of those provisions to this chapter to refer to a person eligible for educational assistance under this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Flight Training</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs may approve the pursuit of flight training (in addition to a course of flight training that may be approved under <ref>section 3680A(b) of title 38</ref>) by an individual entitled to educational assistance under this chapter if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> such training is generally accepted as necessary for the attainment of a recognized vocational objective in the field of aviation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the individual possesses a valid private pilot certificate and meets, on the day the member begins a course of flight training, the medical requirements necessary for a commercial pilot certificate; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the flight school courses meet Federal Aviation Administration standards for such courses and are approved by the Federal Aviation Administration and the State approving agency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Trust Fund</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Amounts for payments for benefits under this chapter shall be derived from the Department of Defense Education Benefits Fund under <ref>section 2006 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title V, § 527(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1893</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 16167.</num>
<heading> Sunset</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Sunset</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The authority to provide educational assistance under this chapter shall terminate on the date that is four years after the date of the enactment of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2016.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Provision of Assistance Pending Sunset</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, during the period beginning on the date of the enactment of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2016 and ending on the date that is four years after the date of the enactment of that Act, educational assistance may be provided under this chapter only to a member otherwise eligible for educational assistance under this chapter who received educational assistance under this chapter for a course of study at an educational institution for the enrollment period at the educational institution that immediately preceded the date of the enactment of that Act.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Eligibility for Post-</inline>9/11<inline class="small-caps"> Educational Assistance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A member who loses eligibility for benefits under this chapter pursuant to subsection (b) shall be allowed to elect (in such form and manner as the Secretary of Veterans Affairs may prescribe) to have such service previously credited toward this chapter credited towards establishing eligibility for educational assistance under chapter 33 of title 38, notwithstanding the provisions of <ref>section 16163(e) of this title</ref> or <ref>section 3322(h)(1) of title 38</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title V, § 555(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 824</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–48, title I, § 106(a)</ref>, <date date="2017-08-16">Aug. 16, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 977</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>