<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 20—</num>
<heading>HUMANITARIAN AND OTHER ASSISTANCE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 401.</num>
<heading> Humanitarian and civic assistance provided in conjunction with military operations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of a military department may carry out humanitarian and civic assistance activities in conjunction with authorized military operations of the armed forces in a country if the Secretary concerned determines that the activities will promote—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the security interests of both the United States and the country in which the activities are to be carried out; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the specific operational readiness skills of the members of the armed forces who participate in the activities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Humanitarian and civic assistance activities carried out under this section shall complement, and may not duplicate, any other form of social or economic assistance which may be provided to the country concerned by any other department or agency of the United States. Such activities shall serve the basic economic and social needs of the people of the country concerned.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Humanitarian and civic assistance may not be provided under this section (directly or indirectly) to any individual, group, or organization engaged in military or paramilitary activity.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Humanitarian and civic assistance may not be provided under this section to any foreign country unless the Secretary of State specifically approves the provision of such assistance.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Expenses incurred as a direct result of providing humanitarian and civic assistance under this section to a foreign country shall be paid for out of funds specifically appropriated for such purpose.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>[(2)</num>
<content>, (3) Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title XII, § 1203(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2413</ref>.]</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Nothing in this section may be interpreted to preclude the incurring of minimal expenditures by the Department of Defense for purposes of humanitarian and civic assistance out of funds other than funds appropriated pursuant to paragraph (1), except that funds appropriated to the Department of Defense for operation and maintenance (other than funds appropriated pursuant to such paragraph) may be obligated for humanitarian and civic assistance under this section only for incidental costs of carrying out such assistance.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives a report, not later than March 1 of each year, on activities carried out under this section during the preceding fiscal year. The Secretary shall include in each such report—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a list of the countries in which humanitarian and civic assistance activities were carried out during the preceding fiscal year;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the type and description of such activities carried out in each country during the preceding fiscal year; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the amount expended in carrying out each such activity in each such country during the preceding fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<chapeau> In this section, the term “humanitarian and civic assistance” means any of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Medical, surgical, dental, and veterinary care provided in areas of a country that are rural or are underserved by medical, surgical, dental, and veterinary professionals, respectively, including education, training, and technical assistance related to the care provided.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Construction of rudimentary surface transportation systems.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Well drilling and construction of basic sanitation facilities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Rudimentary construction and repair of public facilities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title III, § 333(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3857</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–180, div. A, title III, § 332(b)(1)</ref>–(5), <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1080</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–456, div. A, title XII, § 1233(g)(1)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2058</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title XI, § 1182(a)(1)</ref>, title XV, § 1504(b), <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1771</ref>, 1839; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XIII, § 1313(a)</ref>, (b), title XV, § 1502(a)(8), <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 474</ref>, 475, 503; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title X, § 1074(a)(2)</ref>, title XIII, § 1304, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2658</ref>, 2704; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1067(1)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 774</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title XII, § 1235], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–331; <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title XII, § 1221</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2089</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title XII, § 1201</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3455</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title XII, § 1203(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2413</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title X, § 1076(f)(7)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1952</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 402.</num>
<heading> Transportation of humanitarian relief supplies to foreign countries</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, and subject to subsection (b), the Secretary of Defense may transport to any country, without charge, supplies which have been furnished by a nongovernmental source and which are intended for humanitarian assistance. Such supplies may be transported only on a space available basis.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary may not transport supplies under subsection (a) unless the Secretary determines that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the transportation of such supplies is consistent with the foreign policy of the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the supplies to be transported are suitable for humanitarian purposes and are in usable condition;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> there is a legitimate humanitarian need for such supplies by the people or entity for whom they are intended;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the supplies will in fact be used for humanitarian purposes; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> adequate arrangements have been made for the distribution or use of such supplies in the destination country.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The President shall establish procedures for making the determinations required under paragraph (1). Such procedures shall include inspection of supplies before acceptance for transport.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> It shall be the responsibility of the entity requesting the transport of supplies under this section to ensure that the supplies are suitable for transport.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Supplies transported under this section may be distributed by an agency of the United States Government, a foreign government, an international organization, or a private nonprofit relief organization.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Supplies transported under this section may not be distributed, directly or indirectly, to any individual, group, or organization engaged in a military or paramilitary activity.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may use the authority provided by subsection (a) to transport supplies intended for use to respond to, or mitigate the effects of, an event or condition, such as an oil spill, that threatens serious harm to the environment, but only if other sources to provide such transportation are not readily available.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding subsection (a), the Secretary of Defense may require reimbursement for costs incurred by the Department of Defense to transport supplies under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> Not later than July 31 each year, the Secretary of State shall submit to the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on International Relations of the House of Representatives a report identifying the origin, contents, destination, and disposition of all supplies transported under this section during the 12-month period ending on the preceding June 30.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–180, div. A, title III, § 332(a)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1079</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XIII, § 1311(2)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1669</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1502(a)(8)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 503</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1067(1)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 774</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title III, § 312(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1429</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 403.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title X, § 1061(g)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 443</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 404.</num>
<heading> Foreign disaster assistance</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The President may direct the Secretary of Defense to provide disaster assistance outside the United States to respond to manmade or natural disasters when necessary to prevent loss of lives or serious harm to the environment.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Forms of Assistance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Assistance provided under this section may include transportation, supplies, services, and equipment.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notification Required</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not later than 48 hours after the commencement of disaster assistance activities to provide assistance under this section, the President shall transmit to Congress a report containing notification of the assistance provided, and proposed to be provided, under this section and a description of so much of the following as is then available:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The manmade or natural disaster for which disaster assistance is necessary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The threat to human lives or the environment presented by the disaster.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The United States military personnel and material resources that are involved or expected to be involved.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The disaster assistance that is being provided or is expected to be provided by other nations or public or private relief organizations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The anticipated duration of the disaster assistance activities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Organizing Policies and Programs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Amounts appropriated to the Department of Defense for any fiscal year for Overseas Humanitarian, Disaster, and Civic Aid (OHDACA) programs of the Department shall be available for organizing general policies and programs for disaster relief programs for disasters occurring outside the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Transportation Assistance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Transportation services authorized under subsection (b) may be provided in response to a manmade or natural disaster to prevent serious harm to the environment, when human lives are not at risk, only if other sources to provide such transportation are not readily available.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XIV, § 1412(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2912</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title III, § 312(c)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1430</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 405.</num>
<heading> Use of Department of Defense funds for United States share of costs of United Nations peacekeeping activities: limitation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition on Use of Funds</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Funds available to the Department of Defense may not be used to make a financial contribution (directly or through another department or agency of the United States) to the United Nations—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> for the costs of a United Nations peacekeeping activity; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> for any United States arrearage to the United Nations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Application of Prohibition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The prohibition in subsection (a) applies to voluntary contributions, as well as to contributions pursuant to assessment by the United Nations for the United States share of the costs of a peacekeeping activity.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XIII, § 1301(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 473</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 406.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 401(f)]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 407.</num>
<heading> Humanitarian demining assistance and stockpiled conventional munitions assistance: authority; limitations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of a military department may provide humanitarian demining assistance and stockpiled conventional munitions assistance to a country if the Secretary concerned determines that the assistance will promote either—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the security interests of both the United States and the country to which the assistance is to be provided; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the specific operational readiness skills of the members of the armed forces who participate in the activities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Humanitarian demining assistance and stockpiled conventional munitions assistance under this section shall complement, and may not duplicate, any other form of social or economic assistance which may be provided to the country concerned by any other department or agency of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that no member of the armed forces, while providing humanitarian demining assistance under this section—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> engages in the physical detection, lifting, or destroying of landmines, unexploded explosive ordnance, or other explosive remnants of war (unless the member does so for the concurrent purpose of supporting a United States military operation); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provides such assistance as part of a military operation that does not involve the armed forces.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitations</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Humanitarian demining assistance and stockpiled conventional munitions assistance may not be provided under this section unless the Secretary of State specifically approves the provision of such assistance.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any authority provided under any other provision of law to provide humanitarian demining assistance or stockpiled conventional munitions assistance to a foreign country shall be carried out in accordance with, and subject to, the limitations prescribed in this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Expenses</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Expenses incurred as a direct result of providing humanitarian demining assistance or stockpiled conventional munitions assistance under this section to a foreign country shall be paid for out of funds specifically appropriated for the purpose of the provision by the Department of Defense of overseas humanitarian assistance.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Expenses covered by paragraph (1) include the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Travel, transportation, and subsistence expenses of Department of Defense personnel providing such assistance.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The cost of any equipment, services, or supplies acquired for the purpose of carrying out or supporting humanitarian demining activities or stockpiled conventional munitions activities, including any nonlethal, individual, or small-team equipment or supplies for clearing landmines or other explosive remnants of war, or stockpiled conventional munitions, as applicable, that are to be transferred or otherwise furnished to a foreign country in furtherance of the provision of assistance under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Travel, transportation, and subsistence expenses of foreign personnel to attend training provided by the Department of Defense under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Report</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on activities carried out under this section during the preceding fiscal year, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a list of the countries to which humanitarian demining assistance or stockpiled conventional munitions assistance was provided during the preceding fiscal year;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the type and description of humanitarian demining assistance or stockpiled conventional munitions assistance provided to each country during the preceding fiscal year, as specified in paragraph (1), and whether such assistance was primarily related to the humanitarian demining efforts or stockpiled conventional munitions assistance;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a list of countries to which humanitarian demining assistance or stockpiled conventional munitions assistance could not be provided during the preceding fiscal year due to insufficient numbers of Department of Defense personnel to carry out such activities or insufficient funding;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the amount expended in providing such assistance to each such country during the preceding fiscal year; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> a description of interagency efforts to coordinate and improve research, development, test, and evaluation for humanitarian demining technology and mechanical clearance methods, including the transfer of relevant counter-improvised explosive device technology with potential humanitarian demining applications.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “humanitarian demining assistance”, as it relates to training and support, means detection and clearance of landmines, unexploded explosive ordnance, and other explosive remnants of war, and includes activities related to the furnishing of education, training, and technical assistance with respect to explosive safety, the detection and clearance of landmines, unexploded explosive ordnance, and other explosive remnants of war.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “stockpiled conventional munitions assistance”, as it relates to the support of humanitarian assistance efforts, means training and support in the disposal, demilitarization, physical security, and stockpile management of potentially dangerous stockpiles of explosive ordnance, small arms, and light weapons, including man-portable air-defense systems. Such term includes activities related to the furnishing of education, training, and technical assistance with respect to explosive safety and the disposal, demilitarization, physical security, and stockpile management of potentially dangerous stockpiles of explosive ordnance, small arms, and light weapons, including man-portable air-defense systems.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title XII, § 1203(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2413</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title X, § 1092(a)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1605</ref>, 1606; <ref>Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title X, § 1083</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 871</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title X</ref>, §§ 1041, 1071(f)(5), <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3492</ref>, 3510; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title X, § 1082</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2420</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title X, § 1043</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1554</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title X, § 1043</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2770</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 408.</num>
<heading> Assistance in support of Department of Defense accounting for missing United States Government personnel</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may provide assistance to any foreign nation to assist the Department of Defense with recovery of and accounting for missing United States Government personnel.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Types of Assistance</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The assistance provided under subsection (a) may include the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Equipment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Supplies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Training of personnel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Funds.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Approval by Secretary of State</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Assistance may not be provided under this section to any foreign nation unless the Secretary of State specifically approves the provision of such assistance.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitations</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraph (2), the amount of assistance provided under this section in any fiscal year may not exceed $5,000,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary may waive the limitation under paragraph (1) if the Secretary submits to the congressional defense committees notice of the waiver together with the reasons why the waiver is necessary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> No assistance may be provided under this section to a foreign nation the government of which the Secretary of State determines has repeatedly provided support for international terrorism pursuant to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> section 1754(c)(1)(A) of the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 4813(c)(1)(A)</ref>);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> section 620A of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2371</ref>); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> section 40 of the Arms Export Control Act (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2780</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Construction With Other Assistance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The authority to provide assistance under this section is in addition to any other authority to provide assistance to foreign nations under law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Report</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than December 31 of each year, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report on the assistance provided under this section during the preceding fiscal year.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title XII, § 1207(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 367</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title X, § 1064(5)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1587</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title X, § 1042(a)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 388</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 409.</num>
<heading> Center for Complex Operations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Center Authorized</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may establish a center to be known as the “Center for Complex Operations” (in this section referred to as the “Center”).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Purposes</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The purposes of the Center established under subsection (a) shall be the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> To provide for effective coordination in the preparation of Department of Defense personnel and other United States Government personnel for complex operations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> To foster unity of effort during complex operations among—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the departments and agencies of the United States Government;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> foreign governments and militaries;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> international organizations and international nongovernmental organizations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> domestic nongovernmental organizations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> To conduct research; collect, analyze, and distribute lessons learned; and compile best practices in matters relating to complex operations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> To identify gaps in the education and training of Department of Defense personnel, and other relevant United States Government personnel, relating to complex operations, and to facilitate efforts to fill such gaps.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Concurrence of the Secretary of State</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall seek the concurrence of the Secretary of State to the extent the efforts and activities of the Center involve the entities referred to in subparagraphs (B) and (C) of subsection (b)(2).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Support From Other United States Government Departments or Agencies</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The head of any non-Department of Defense department or agency of the United States Government may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provide to the Secretary of Defense services, including personnel support, to support the operations of the Center; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> transfer funds to the Secretary of Defense to support the operations of the Center.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Acceptance of Gifts and Donations</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Subject to paragraph (3), the Secretary of Defense may accept from any source specified in paragraph (2) any gift or donation for purposes of defraying the costs or enhancing the operations of the Center.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The sources specified in this paragraph are the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The government of a State or a political subdivision of a State.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The government of a foreign country.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> A foundation or other charitable organization, including a foundation or charitable organization that is organized or operates under the laws of a foreign country.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Any source in the private sector of the United States or a foreign country.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary may not accept a gift or donation under this subsection if acceptance of the gift or donation would compromise or appear to compromise—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the ability of the Department of Defense, any employee of the Department, or any member of the armed forces to carry out the responsibility or duty of the Department in a fair and objective manner; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the integrity of any program of the Department or of any person involved in such a program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall provide written guidance setting forth the criteria to be used in determining the applicability of paragraph (3) to any proposed gift or donation under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Crediting of Funds Transferred or Accepted</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Funds transferred to or accepted by the Secretary of Defense under this section shall be credited to appropriations available to the Department of Defense for the Center, and shall be available for the same purposes, and subject to the same conditions and limitations, as the appropriations with which merged. Any funds so transferred or accepted shall remain available until expended.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The term “complex operation” means an operation as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A stability operation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A security operation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> A transition and reconstruction operation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> A counterinsurgency operation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> An operation consisting of irregular warfare.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “gift or donation” means any gift or donation of funds, materials (including research materials), real or personal property, or services (including lecture services and faculty services).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title X, § 1031(a), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4589</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 410.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title V, § 571(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 353</ref>]</heading>
</section>
</chapter>