<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 223—</num>
<heading>OTHER PROVISIONS RELATING TO PLANNING AND SOLICITATION GENERALLY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3241.</num>
<heading> Design-build selection procedures</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authorization</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Unless the traditional acquisition approach of design-bid-build established under chapter 11 of title 40 is used or another acquisition procedure authorized by law is used, the head of an agency shall use the two-phase selection procedures authorized in this section for entering into a contract for the design and construction of a public building, facility, or work when a determination is made under subsection (b) that the procedures are appropriate for use.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Criteria for Use</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A contracting officer shall make a determination whether two-phase selection procedures are appropriate for use for entering into a contract for the design and construction of a public building, facility, or work when—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the contracting officer anticipates that three or more offers will be received for such contract;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> design work must be performed before an offeror can develop a price or cost proposal for such contract;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the offeror will incur a substantial amount of expense in preparing the offer; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> the contracting officer has considered information such as the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The extent to which the project requirements have been adequately defined.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The time constraints for delivery of the project.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The capability and experience of potential contractors.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The suitability of the project for use of the two-phase selection procedures.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The capability of the agency to manage the two-phase selection process.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Other criteria established by the agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Procedures Described</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Two-phase selection procedures consist of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Development of scope of work statement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The agency develops, either in-house or by contract, a scope of work statement for inclusion in the solicitation that defines the project and provides prospective offerors with sufficient information regarding the Government’s requirements (which may include criteria and preliminary design, budget parameters, and schedule or delivery requirements) to enable the offerors to submit proposals which meet the Government’s needs. If the agency contracts for development of the scope of work statement, the agency shall contract for architectural and engineering services as defined by and in accordance with chapter 11 of title 40.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Solicitation of phase-one proposals</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The contracting officer solicits phase-one proposals that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> include information on the offeror’s—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> technical approach; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> technical qualifications; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> do not include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> detailed design information; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> cost or price information.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Evaluation factors.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Evaluation factors to be used</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The evaluation factors to be used in evaluating phase-one proposals are stated in the solicitation and include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> specialized experience and technical competence;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> capability to perform;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> past performance of the offeror’s team (including the architect-engineer and construction members of the team); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> other appropriate factors, except that cost-related or price-related evaluation factors are not permitted.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Relative importance of evaluation factors and subfactors</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each solicitation establishes the relative importance assigned to the evaluation factors and subfactors that must be considered in the evaluation of phase-one proposals.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Evaluation of proposals</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The agency evaluates phase-one proposals on the basis of the phase-one evaluation factors set forth in the solicitation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Selection by contracting officer.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Number of offerors selected and what is to be evaluated</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The contracting officer selects as the most highly qualified the number of offerors specified in the solicitation to provide the property or services under the contract and requests the selected offerors to submit phase-two competitive proposals that include technical proposals and cost or price information. Each solicitation establishes with respect to phase two—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the technical submission for the proposal, including design concepts or proposed solutions to requirements addressed within the scope of work (or both), and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the evaluation factors and subfactors, including cost or price, that must be considered in the evaluations of proposals in accordance with subsections (b), (c), and (d) of <ref>section 3206 of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The contracting officer separately evaluates the submissions described in clauses (i) and (ii) of subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Awarding of contract</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The agency awards the contract in accordance with <ref>section 3303 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Solicitation to State Number of Offerors To Be Selected for Phase Two Requests for Competitive Proposals</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A solicitation issued pursuant to the procedures described in subsection (c) shall state the maximum number of offerors that are to be selected to submit competitive proposals pursuant to subsection (c)(4). If the contract value exceeds $4,000,000, the maximum number specified in the solicitation shall not exceed 5 unless—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the solicitation is issued pursuant to an indefinite delivery-indefinite quantity contract for design-build construction; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the head of the contracting activity, delegable to a level no lower than the senior contracting official within the contracting activity, approves the contracting officer’s justification with respect to an individual solicitation that a maximum number greater than 5 is in the interest of the Federal Government; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the contracting officer provides written documentation of how a maximum number greater than 5 is consistent with the purposes and objectives of the two-phase selection procedures.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirement for Guidance and Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Federal Acquisition Regulation shall include guidance—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> regarding the factors that may be considered in determining whether the two-phase contracting procedures authorized by subsection (a) are appropriate for use in individual contracting situations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> regarding the factors that may be used in selecting contractors; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> providing for a uniform approach to be used Government-wide.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Special Authority for Military Construction Projects</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of a military department may use funds available to the Secretary under section 2807(a) or 18233(e) of this title to accelerate the design effort in connection with a military construction project for which the two-phase selection procedures described in subsection (c) are used to select the contractor for both the design and construction portion of the project before the project is specifically authorized by law and before funds are appropriated for the construction portion of the project. Notwithstanding the limitations contained in such sections, use of such funds for the design portion of a military construction project may continue despite the subsequent authorization of the project. The advance notice requirement of <ref>section 2807(b) of this title</ref> shall continue to apply whenever the estimated cost of the design portion of the project exceeds the amount specified in such section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any military construction contract that provides for an accelerated design effort, as authorized by paragraph (1), shall include as a condition of the contract that the liability of the United States in a termination for convenience before funds are first made available for construction may not exceed an amount attributable to the final design of the project.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> For each fiscal year during which the authority provided by this subsection is in effect, the Secretary of a military department may select not more than two military construction projects to include the accelerated design effort authorized by paragraph (1) for each armed force under the jurisdiction of the Secretary. To be eligible for selection under this subsection, a request for the authorization of the project, and for the authorization of appropriations for the project, must have been included in the annual budget of the President for a fiscal year submitted to Congress under <ref>section 1105(a) of title 31</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Not later than <date date="2008-03-01">March 1, 2008</date>, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report evaluating the usefulness of the authority provided by this subsection in expediting the design and construction of military construction projects. The authority provided by this subsection expires <date date="2008-09-30">September 30, 2008</date>, except that, if the report required by this paragraph is not submitted by <date date="2008-03-01">March 1, 2008</date>, the authority shall expire on that date.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. D, title XLI, § 4105(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 645</ref>, § 2305a; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title X, § 1073(a)(44)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1902</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–217, § 3(b)(4)</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1295</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–178, § 4(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="2003-12-15">Dec. 15, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2641</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2807</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2123</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2807</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3508</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title VIII, § 814</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3430</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title VIII, § 823</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1465</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title XVII, § 1731(a)(38)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1814</ref>; renumbered § 3241 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1813(b)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4177</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3242.</num>
<heading> Supplies: economic order quantities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Quantity to Procure.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> An agency referred to in <ref>section 3063 of this title</ref> shall procure supplies in such quantity as—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> will result in the total cost and unit cost most advantageous to the United States, where practicable; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> does not exceed the quantity reasonably expected to be required by the agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall take paragraph (1) into account in approving rates of obligation of appropriations under <ref>section 2204 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Opinion of Offeror With Respect to Quantity to Be Procured</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each solicitation for a contract for supplies shall, if practicable, include a provision inviting each offeror responding to the solicitation to state an opinion on whether the quantity of the supplies proposed to be procured is economically advantageous to the United States and, if applicable, to recommend a quantity or quantities which would be more economically advantageous to the United States. Each such recommendation shall include a quotation of the total price and the unit price for supplies procured in each recommended quantity.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 98–525, title XII, § 1233(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2600</ref>, § 2384a; renumbered § 3242 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1813(c)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4179</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(b)(5)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2133</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3243.</num>
<heading> Encouragement of new competitors: qualification requirement</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Qualification Requirement Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “qualification requirement” means a requirement for testing or other quality assurance demonstration that must be completed by an offeror before award of a contract.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Actions Before Establishing Qualification Requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Except as provided in subsection (c), the head of the agency shall, before establishing a qualification requirement—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> prepare a written justification stating the necessity for establishing the qualification requirement and specify why the qualification requirement must be demonstrated before contract award;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> specify in writing and make available to a potential offeror upon request all requirements which a prospective offeror, or its product, must satisfy in order to become qualified, such requirements to be limited to those least restrictive to meet the purposes necessitating the establishment of the qualification requirement;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> specify an estimate of the costs of testing and evaluation likely to be incurred by a potential offeror in order to become qualified;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> ensure that a potential offeror is provided, upon request and on a reimbursable basis, a prompt opportunity to demonstrate its ability to meet the standards specified for qualification using qualified personnel and facilities of the agency concerned or of another agency obtained through interagency agreement, or under contract, or other methods approved by the agency (including use of approved testing and evaluation services not provided under contract to the agency);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> if testing and evaluation services are provided under contract to the agency for the purposes of paragraph (4), provide to the extent possible that such services be provided by a contractor who is not expected to benefit from an absence of additional qualified sources and who shall be required in such contract to adhere to any restriction on technical data asserted by the potential offeror seeking qualification; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> ensure that a potential offeror seeking qualification is promptly informed as to whether qualification is attained and, in the event qualification is not attained, is promptly furnished specific information why qualification was not attained.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Applicability, Waiver Authority, and Referral of Offers.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Applicability</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subsection (b) does not apply with respect to a qualification requirement established by statute or administrative action before <date date="1984-10-19">October 19, 1984</date>, unless such requirement is a qualified products list.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Waiver Authority.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Submission of determination of unreasonableness</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in subparagraph (C), if it is unreasonable to specify the standards for qualification which a prospective offeror or its product must satisfy, a determination to that effect shall be submitted to the advocate for competition of the procuring activity responsible for the purchase of the item subject to the qualification requirement.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority to grant waiver</inline>.—</heading>
<content>After considering any comments of the advocate for competition reviewing such determination, the head of the purchasing office may waive the requirements of clauses (2) through (6) of subsection (b) for up to two years with respect to the item subject to the qualification requirement.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inapplicability to qualified products list</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The waiver authority provided in this paragraph does not apply with respect to a qualified products list.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Submission and consideration of offer not to be denied in certain cases</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A potential offeror may not be denied the opportunity to submit and have considered an offer for a contract solely because the potential offeror (A) is not on a qualified bidders list, qualified manufacturers list, or qualified products list, or (B) has not been identified as meeting a qualification requirement established after <date date="1984-10-19">October 19, 1984</date>, if the potential offeror can demonstrate to the satisfaction of the contracting officer (or, in the case of a contract for the procurement of an aviation critical safety item or ship critical safety item, the head of the design control activity for such item) that the potential offeror or its product meets the standards established for qualification or can meet such standards before the date specified for award of the contract.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Referral to small business administration</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing contained in this subsection requires the referral of an offer to the Small Business Administration pursuant to section 8(b)(7) of the Small Business Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 637(b)(7)</ref>) if the basis for the referral is a challenge by the offeror to either the validity of the qualification requirement or the offeror’s compliance with such requirement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Delay of procurement not required</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The head of an agency need not delay a proposed procurement in order to comply with subsection (b) or in order to provide a potential offeror with an opportunity to demonstrate its ability to meet the standards specified for qualification.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirements before enforcement of certain lists</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The requirements of subsection (b) also apply before enforcement of any qualified products list, qualified manufacturers list, or qualified bidders list.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Fewer Than</inline> 2 <inline class="small-caps">Actual Manufacturers.—</inline></heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Solicitation and testing of additional sources or products</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>If the number of qualified sources or qualified products available to compete actively for an anticipated future requirement is fewer than two actual manufacturers or the products of two actual manufacturers, respectively, the head of the agency concerned shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> periodically publish notice in the Commerce Business Daily soliciting additional sources or products to seek qualification, unless the contracting officer determines that such publication would compromise national security; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> subject to paragraph (2), bear the cost of conducting the specified testing and evaluation (excluding the costs associated with producing the item or establishing the production, quality control, or other system to be tested and evaluated) for a small business concern or a product manufactured by a small business concern which has met the standards specified for qualification and which could reasonably be expected to compete for a contract for that requirement.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Certification when agency may bear cost</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Costs may be borne under paragraph (1)(B) only if the head of the agency determines that such additional qualified sources or products are likely to result in cost savings from increased competition for future requirements sufficient to amortize the costs incurred by the agency within a reasonable period of time considering the duration and dollar value of anticipated future requirements.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Certification required</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The head of an agency shall require a prospective contractor requesting the United States to bear testing and evaluation costs under paragraph (1)(B) to certify as to its status as a small business concern under section 3 of the Small Business Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 632</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Examination and Revalidation of Qualification Requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Within seven years after the establishment of a qualification requirement under subsection (b) or within seven years following an agency’s enforcement of a qualified products list, qualified manufacturers list, or qualified bidders list, any such qualification requirement shall be examined and revalidated in accordance with the requirements of subsection (b). The preceding sentence does not apply in the case of a qualification requirement for which a waiver is in effect under subsection (c)(2).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Restriction on Enforcement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except in an emergency as determined by the head of the agency, whenever the head of the agency determines not to enforce a qualification requirement for a solicitation, the agency may not thereafter enforce that qualification requirement unless the agency complies with the requirements of subsection (b).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “aviation critical safety item” means a part, an assembly, installation equipment, launch equipment, recovery equipment, or support equipment for an aircraft or aviation weapon system if the part, assembly, or equipment contains a characteristic any failure, malfunction, or absence of which could cause a catastrophic or critical failure resulting in the loss of or serious damage to the aircraft or weapon system, an unacceptable risk of personal injury or loss of life, or an uncommanded engine shutdown that jeopardizes safety.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “ship critical safety item” means any ship part, assembly, or support equipment containing a characteristic the failure, malfunction, or absence of which could cause a catastrophic or critical failure resulting in loss of or serious damage to the ship or unacceptable risk of personal injury or loss of life.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “design control activity”, with respect to an aviation critical safety item or ship critical safety item, means the systems command of a military department that is specifically responsible for ensuring the airworthiness of an aviation system or equipment, or the seaworthiness of a ship or ship equipment, in which such item is to be used.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 98–525, title XII, § 1216(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2593</ref>, § 2319; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–26, § 7(d)(5)</ref>, (i)(4), (k)(3), <date date="1987-04-21">Apr. 21, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 281</ref>, 282, 284; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title VIII, § 802(d)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1541</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title I, § 130(d)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2110</ref>; renumbered § 3243 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1813(d)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4179</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3247.</num>
<heading> Contracts: regulations for bids</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Defense may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> prescribe regulations for the preparation, submission, and opening of bids for contracts; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> require that a bid be accompanied by a written guaranty, signed by one or more responsible persons, undertaking that the bidder, if his bid is accepted, will, within the time prescribed by the Secretary or other officer authorized to make the contract, make a contract and furnish a bond with good and sufficient sureties for the performance of the contract.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> If a bidder, after being notified of the acceptance of his bid, fails within the time prescribed under subsection (a)(2) to enter into a contract and furnish the prescribed bond, the Secretary concerned or other authorized officer shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> contract with another person; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> charge against the defaulting bidder and his guarantors the difference between the amount specified by the bidder in his bid and the amount for which a contract is made with the other person, this difference being immediately recoverable by the United States for the use of the military department concerned in an action against the bidder and his guarantors, jointly or severally.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Proceedings under this section are subject to regulations under <ref>section 121 of title 40</ref>, unless exempted therefrom under <ref>section 501(a)(2) of title 40</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 136</ref>, § 2381; <ref>Pub. L. 98–525, title XIV, § 1405(35)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2624</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–355, title I, § 1507</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3298</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–217, § 3(b)(6)</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1295</ref>; renumbered § 3247, <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1813(e)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4181</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3249.</num>
<heading> Advocates for competition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each advocate for competition designated pursuant to <ref>section 1705(a) of title 41</ref> for an agency named in <ref>section 3063 of this title</ref> shall be a general or flag officer if a member of the armed forces or in a position classified above GS–15 pursuant to <ref>section 5108 of title 5</ref>, if a civilian employee and shall be designated to serve for a minimum of two years.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 98–525, title XII, § 1216(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2593</ref>, § 2318; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–26, § 7(d)(4)</ref>, <date date="1987-04-21">Apr. 21, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 281</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–25, title VII, § 701(f)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-04-06">Apr. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 115</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–355, title I, § 1031</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3260</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 5(b)(17)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3843</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title X, § 1076(f)(24)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1953</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 811(d)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1845</ref>; renumbered § 3249 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1813(f)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4181</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3252.</num>
<heading> Requirements for information relating to supply chain risk</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subject to subsection (b), the head of a covered agency may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> carry out a covered procurement action; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> limit, notwithstanding any other provision of law, in whole or in part, the disclosure of information relating to the basis for carrying out a covered procurement action.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Determination and Notification</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The head of a covered agency may exercise the authority provided in subsection (a) only after—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> consulting with procurement or other relevant officials of the covered agency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> making a determination in writing, in unclassified or classified form, that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> use of the authority in subsection (a)(1) is necessary to protect national security by reducing supply chain risk;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> less intrusive measures are not reasonably available to reduce such supply chain risk; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> in a case where the head of the covered agency plans to limit disclosure of information under subsection (a)(2), the risk to national security due to the disclosure of such information outweighs the risk due to not disclosing such information; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> providing a classified or unclassified notice of the determination made under paragraph (2) to the appropriate congressional committees, which notice shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a summary of the risk assessment that serves as the basis for the written determination required by paragraph (2); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a summary of the basis for the determination, including a discussion of less intrusive measures that were considered and why they were not reasonably available to reduce supply chain risk.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Disclosure</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>If the head of a covered agency has exercised the authority provided in subsection (a)(2) to limit disclosure of information—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> no action undertaken by the agency head under such authority shall be subject to review in a bid protest before the Government Accountability Office or in any Federal court; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the agency head shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> notify appropriate parties of a covered procurement action and the basis for such action only to the extent necessary to effectuate the covered procurement action;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> notify other Department of Defense components or other Federal agencies responsible for procurements that may be subject to the same or similar supply chain risk, in a manner and to the extent consistent with the requirements of national security; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> ensure the confidentiality of any such notifications.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Head of a covered agency</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “head of a covered agency” means each of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Army.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Navy.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Air Force.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered procurement action</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “covered procurement action” means any of the following actions, if the action takes place in the course of conducting a covered procurement:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The exclusion of a source that fails to meet qualification standards established in accordance with the requirements of <ref>section 3243 of this title</ref> for the purpose of reducing supply chain risk in the acquisition of covered systems.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The exclusion of a source that fails to achieve an acceptable rating with regard to an evaluation factor providing for the consideration of supply chain risk in the evaluation of proposals for the award of a contract or the issuance of a task or delivery order.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The decision to withhold consent for a contractor to subcontract with a particular source or to direct a contractor for a covered system to exclude a particular source from consideration for a subcontract under the contract.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered procurement</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “covered procurement” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a source selection for a covered system or a covered item of supply involving either a performance specification, as provided in <ref>section 3206(a)(3)(B) of this title</ref>, or an evaluation factor, as provided in <ref>section 3206(b)(1) of this title</ref>, relating to supply chain risk;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the consideration of proposals for and issuance of a task or delivery order for a covered system or a covered item of supply, as provided in <ref>section 3406(d)(3) of this title</ref>, where the task or delivery order contract concerned includes a contract clause establishing a requirement relating to supply chain risk; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any contract action involving a contract for a covered system or a covered item of supply where such contract includes a clause establishing requirements relating to supply chain risk.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Supply chain risk</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “supply chain risk” means the risk that an adversary may sabotage, maliciously introduce unwanted function, or otherwise subvert the design, integrity, manufacturing, production, distribution, installation, operation, or maintenance of a covered system so as to surveil, deny, disrupt, or otherwise degrade the function, use, or operation of such system.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered system</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “covered system” means a national security system, as that term is defined in <ref>section 3552(b)(6) of title 44</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered item of supply</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “covered item of supply” means an item of information technology (as that term is defined in <ref>section 11101 of title 40</ref>) that is purchased for inclusion in a covered system, and the loss of integrity of which could result in a supply chain risk for a covered system.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appropriate congressional committees</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “appropriate congressional committees” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the case of a covered system included in the National Intelligence Program or the Military Intelligence Program, the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate, the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives, and the congressional defense committees; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of a covered system not otherwise included in subparagraph (A), the congressional defense committees.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 881(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1910</ref>, § 2339a; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title XVII, § 1731(a)(43)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1814</ref>; renumbered § 3252 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title X, § 1081(a)(36)</ref>, title XVIII, § 1813(g), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3872</ref>, 4181; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title VIII, § 841</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1990</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>