<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 823—</num>
<heading>SPECIAL ASSIGNMENTS AND DETAILS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 8183.</num>
<heading> State Department: assignment of enlisted members as custodians of buildings in foreign countries</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon the request of the Secretary of State, the Secretary of the Navy may assign enlisted members of the naval service to serve as custodians under the supervision of the principal officer at any embassy, legation, or consulate.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 374</ref>, § 5983; renumbered § 8183, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(b)(6)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1834</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8185.</num>
<heading> Nautical Schools: detail of naval officers as superintendents or instructors</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President may detail officers of the Navy as superintendents or instructors of institutions receiving benefits under chapter 515 of title 46 when in his opinion it can be done without detriment to the naval service. Officers so detailed shall be recalled from an institution if it is discontinued or if the good of the naval service requires.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 374</ref>, § 5985; <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title XIII, § 1303(a)(21)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 739</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 17(a)(5)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1706</ref>; renumbered § 8185, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(b)(6)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1834</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8186.</num>
<heading> Technical institutions: detail of naval officers to promote knowledge of naval engineering and naval architecture</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> To promote a knowledge of naval engineering and naval architecture, the President, upon the application of any established scientific school or college in the United States, the Commonwealths or possessions, may detail a qualified officer of the Navy as a professor in that school or college. The number of officers detailed under this section may not exceed 25 at any one time.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The President may prescribe regulations for detailing such officers and may recall them when the public interest requires.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 374</ref>, § 5986; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title X, § 1057(a)(5)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3440</ref>; renumbered § 8186, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(b)(6)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1834</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>