<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 1409—</num>
<heading>CONTINUATION OF OFFICERS ON THE RESERVE ACTIVE-STATUS LIST AND SELECTIVE EARLY REMOVAL</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 14701.</num>
<heading> Selection of officers for continuation on the reserve active-status list</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consideration for Continuation</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A reserve officer of the Army, Navy, Air Force, or Marine Corps described in subparagraph (B) who is required to be removed from the reserve active-status list under <ref>section 14504 of this title</ref>, or a reserve officer of the Army, Navy, Air Force, or Marine Corps who is required to be removed from the reserve active-status list under section 14505, 14506, or 14507 of this title, may be considered for continuation on the reserve active-status list under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> A reserve officer covered by this subparagraph is a reserve officer of the Army, Air Force, or Marine Corps who holds the grade of first lieutenant, or a reserve officer of the Navy who holds the grade of lieutenant (junior grade), and who—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is a health professions officer; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> is actively pursuing an undergraduate program of education leading to a baccalaureate degree.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The consideration of a reserve officer for continuation on the reserve active-status list pursuant to this paragraph is subject to the needs of the service and to <ref>section 14509 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A reserve officer who holds the grade of captain in the Army, Air Force, or Marine Corps or the grade of lieutenant in the Navy and who is subject to separation under <ref>section 14513 of this title</ref> may not be continued on the reserve active-status list under this subsection for a period which extends beyond the last day of the month in which the officer completes 20 years of commissioned service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A reserve officer who holds the grade of major or lieutenant commander and who is subject to separation under <ref>section 14513 of this title</ref> may not be continued on the reserve active-status list under this subsection for a period which extends beyond the last day of the month in which the officer completes 24 years of commissioned service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> A reserve officer who holds the grade of lieutenant colonel or commander and who is subject to separation under <ref>section 14514 of this title</ref> may not be continued on the reserve active-status list under this subsection for a period which extends beyond the last day of the month in which the officer completes 33 years of commissioned service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> A reserve officer who holds the grade of colonel in the Army, Air Force, or Marine Corps or the grade of captain in the Navy and who is subject to separation under <ref>section 14514 of this title</ref> may not be continued on the reserve active-status list under this subsection for a period which extends beyond the last day of the month in which the officer completes 35 years of commissioned service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> An officer who is selected for continuation on the reserve active-status list under regulations prescribed under paragraph (1) but who declines to continue on that list shall be separated in accordance with section 14513 or 14514 of this title, as the case may be.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Each officer who is continued on the reserve active-status list under this section, who is not subsequently promoted or continued on the active-status list, and whose name is not on a list of officers recommended for promotion to the next higher grade shall (unless sooner separated under another provision of law) be separated in accordance with section 14513 or 14514 of this title, as appropriate, upon the expiration of the period for which the officer was continued on the reserve active-status list.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Continuation of Health Professions Officers</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding subsection (a)(6), a health professions officer obligated to a period of service incurred under <ref>section 16201 of this title</ref> who is required to be removed from the reserve active-status list under section 14504, 14505, 14506, or 14507 of this title and who has not completed a service obligation incurred under <ref>section 16201 of this title</ref> shall be retained on the reserve active-status list until the completion of such service obligation and then discharged, unless sooner retired or discharged under another provision of law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned may waive the applicability of paragraph (1) to any officer if the Secretary determines that completion of the service obligation of that officer is not in the best interest of the service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A health professions officer who is continued on the reserve active-status list under this subsection who is subsequently promoted or whose name is on a list of officers recommended for promotion to the next higher grade is not required to be discharged or retired upon completion of the officer’s service obligation. Such officer may continue on the reserve active-status list as other officers of the same grade unless separated under another provision of law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations for the administration of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1611</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2954</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title V, § 522], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–108; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title V, § 511(a)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1459</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title V, § 511</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3357</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 14701a.</num>
<heading> Continuation on reserve active-status list: officers in certain military specialties and career tracks</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the military department concerned may authorize a reserve commissioned officer in a grade above O-2 to remain on the reserve active-status list after the date otherwise provided for the separation or retirement of the officer under section 14505, 14506, or 14507 of this title, as applicable, if the officer has a military occupational specialty, rating, or specialty code in a military specialty designated pursuant to subsection (b).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Military Specialties</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of a military department shall designate the military specialties in which a military occupational specialty, rating, or specialty code, as applicable, assigned to members of the armed forces under the jurisdiction of such Secretary authorizes the members to be eligible for continuation on the reserve active-status list as provided in subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duration of Continuation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An officer continued on the reserve active-status list pursuant to this section shall, if not earlier retired, transferred to the Retired Reserve, or discharged, be separated in accordance with section 14513 or 14514 of this title, as applicable, on the first day of the month after the month in which the officer completes 40 years of commissioned service.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretaries of the military departments shall carry out this section in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense. The regulations shall specify the criteria to be used by the Secretaries of the military departments in designating military specialties for purposes of subsection (b).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title V, § 513(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1876</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 14702.</num>
<heading> Retention on reserve active-status list of certain officers in the grade of major, lieutenant colonel, colonel, or brigadier general</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Retention</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Notwithstanding the provisions of section 14506, 14507, or 14508 of this title, the Secretary of the military department concerned may, with the officer’s consent, retain on the reserve active-status list an officer in the grade of major, lieutenant colonel, colonel, or brigadier general who is—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an officer of the Army National Guard of the United States and assigned to a headquarters or headquarters detachment of a State; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a reserve officer of the Army or Air Force who, as a condition of continued employment as a National Guard or Reserve technician is required by the Secretary concerned to maintain membership in a Selected Reserve unit or organization.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Separation for Age</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An officer may be retained under this section only so long as the officer continues to meet the conditions of paragraph (1) or (2) of subsection (a). An officer described in paragraph (1) of such subsection may not be retained under this section after the last day of the month in which the officer becomes 62 years of age. An officer described in paragraph (2) of such subsection may not be retained under this section after the last day of the month in which the officer becomes 62 years of age.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1611</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2955</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title V, § 521(a)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1734</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title V, § 514(b), (c)(1), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4441</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title V, § 511(b)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1875</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 14703.</num>
<heading> Authority to retain chaplains and officers in medical specialties until specified age</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Retention</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Notwithstanding any provision of chapter 1407 of this title and except for officers referred to in sections 14503, 14504, 14505, and 14506 of this title and under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Secretary of the Army may, with the officer’s consent, retain in an active status any reserve officer assigned to the Medical Corps, the Dental Corps, the Veterinary Corps, the Medical Services Corps (if the officer has been designated as allied health officer or biomedical sciences officer in that Corps), the Optometry Section of the Medical Services Corps, the Chaplains, the Army Nurse Corps, or the Army Medical Specialists Corps;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Secretary of the Navy may, with the officer’s consent, retain in an active status any reserve officer appointed in the Medical Corps, Dental Corps, Nurse Corps, or Chaplain Corps or appointed in the Medical Services Corps and designated to perform as a veterinarian, optometrist, podiatrist, allied health officer, or biomedical sciences officer; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the Secretary of the Air Force may, with the officer’s consent, retain in an active status any reserve officer who is designated as a medical officer, dental officer, Air Force nurse, Medical Service Corps officer, biomedical sciences officer, or chaplain.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Separation at Specified Age</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Subject to paragraph (2), an officer may not be retained in active status under this section later than the date on which the officer becomes 68 years of age.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned may, with the consent of the officer, retain in an active status an officer in a medical specialty described in subsection (a) beyond the date described in paragraph (1) of this subsection if the Secretary concerned determines that such retention is necessary to the military department concerned. Each such retention shall be made on a case-by-case basis and for such period as the Secretary concerned determines appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1611</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2956</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title V, § 516</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 594</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title V, § 523], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–108; <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title V, § 516(a), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4442</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title V, § 516</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1349</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 14704.</num>
<heading> Selective early removal from the reserve active-status list</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Boards To Recommend Officers for Removal From Reserve Active-Status List</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Whenever the Secretary of the military department concerned determines that there are in any reserve component under the jurisdiction of the Secretary too many officers in any grade and competitive category who have at least 30 years of service computed under <ref>section 14706 of this title</ref> or at least 20 years of service computed under <ref>section 12732 of this title</ref>, the Secretary may convene a selection board under <ref>section 14101(b) of this title</ref> to consider officers on the reserve active-status list who are in that grade and competitive category, and who have that amount of service, for the purpose of recommending officers by name for removal from that list.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Except as provided in paragraph (3), the list of officers in a reserve component whose names are submitted to a board under paragraph (1) shall include each officer on the reserve active-status list for that reserve component in the same grade and competitive category whose position on the reserve active-status list is between—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> that of the most junior officer in that grade and competitive category whose name is submitted to the board; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> that of the most senior officer in that grade and competitive category whose name is submitted to the board.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> A list submitted to a board under paragraph (1) may not include an officer who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> has been approved for voluntary retirement; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is to be involuntarily retired under any provision of law during the fiscal year in which the board is convened or during the following fiscal year.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Specification of Number of Officers Who May Be Recommended for Separation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the military department concerned shall specify the number of officers described in subsection (a)(1) that a board may recommend for separation under subsection (c).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Separation of Officers Selected</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In the case of an officer recommended for separation in the report of a board under subsection (a), the Secretary may separate the officer in accordance with <ref>section 14514 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the military department concerned shall prescribe regulations for the administration of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1611</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2956</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title V, § 503(b)</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 750</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 14705.</num>
<heading> Selective early retirement: reserve general and flag officers of the Navy and Marine Corps</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority To Consider</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An officer in the Navy Reserve in an active status serving in the grade of rear admiral (lower half) or rear admiral and an officer in the Marine Corps Reserve in an active status serving in the grade of brigadier general or major general may be considered for early retirement whenever the Secretary of the Navy determines that such action is necessary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Boards</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> If the Secretary of the Navy determines that consideration of officers for early retirement under this section is necessary, the Secretary shall convene a selection board under <ref>section 14101(b) of this title</ref> to recommend an appropriate number of officers for early retirement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> In the case of such a board convened to consider officers in the grade of rear admiral or major general, the Secretary of the Navy may appoint the board without regard to <ref>section 14102(b) of this title</ref>. In doing so, however, the Secretary shall ensure that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> each regular commissioned officer appointed to the board holds a grade higher than the grade of rear admiral or major general; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> at least one member of the board is a reserve officer who holds the grade of rear admiral or major general.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Separation Under Section</inline> 14514.—</heading>
<content>An officer selected for early retirement under this section shall be separated in accordance with <ref>section 14514 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1611</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2957</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title V, § 515</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2008</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title V, § 511(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1459</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title V, § 515(b)(1)(VV)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3234</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 14706.</num>
<heading> Computation of total years of service</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> For the purpose of this chapter and chapter 1407 of this title, a Reserve officer’s years of service include all service of the officer as a commissioned officer of a uniformed service other than the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Service as a warrant officer.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Constructive service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Service after appointment as a commissioned officer of a reserve component while in a program of advanced education to obtain the first professional degree required for appointment, designation, or assignment to a professional specialty, but only if that service occurs before the officer commences initial service on active duty or initial service in the Ready Reserve in the specialty that results from such a degree.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The exclusion under subsection (a)(3) does not apply to service performed by an officer who previously served on active duty or participated as a member of the Ready Reserve in other than a student status for the period of service preceding the member’s service in a student status.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> For purposes of subsection (a)(3), an officer shall be considered to be in a professional specialty if the officer is appointed or assigned to the Medical Corps, the Dental Corps, the Veterinary Corps, the Medical Service Corps, the Nurse Corps, or the Army Medical Specialists Corps or is designated as a chaplain or judge advocate.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1611</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2957</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title V, § 515</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 594</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>