<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 105—</num>
<heading>ARMED FORCES HEALTH PROFESSIONS FINANCIAL ASSISTANCE PROGRAMS</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>HEALTH PROFESSIONS SCHOLARSHIP AND FINANCIAL ASSISTANCE PROGRAM FOR ACTIVE SERVICE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2120.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this subchapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “program” means the Armed Forces Health Professions Scholarship and Financial Assistance program provided for in this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “member of the program” means a person appointed a commissioned officer in a reserve component of the armed forces who is enrolled in the Armed Forces Health Professions Scholarship and Financial Assistance program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “course of study” means education received at an accredited college, university, or institution in medicine, dentistry, or other health profession, leading, respectively, to a degree related to the health professions as determined under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “specialized training” means advanced training in a health professions specialty received in an accredited program that is beyond the basic education required for appointment as a commissioned officer with a designation as a health professional.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 92–426, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1972-09-21">Sept. 21, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 717</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–94, title XII, § 1268(13)</ref>, <date date="1983-09-24">Sept. 24, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 706</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–26, § 7(k)(2)</ref>, <date date="1987-04-21">Apr. 21, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 284</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–180, div. A, title VII, § 711(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1108</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title VII, § 725(a)</ref>, (h)(1), <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1478</ref>, 1480.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2121.</num>
<heading> Establishment</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> For the purpose of obtaining adequate numbers of commissioned officers on active duty who are qualified (A) in the various health professions or (B) as a health professional with specific skills to assist in providing mental health care to members of the armed forces, the Secretary of each military department, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, may establish and maintain a health professions scholarship and financial assistance program for his department.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Under the program of a military department, the Secretary of that military department shall allocate a portion of the total number of scholarships to members of the program described in paragraph (1)(B) for the purpose of assisting such members to pursue a degree at the masters and doctoral level in any of the following disciplines:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Social work.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Clinical psychology.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Psychiatry.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Other disciplines that contribute to mental health care programs in that military department.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The program shall consist of courses of study and specialized training in designated health professions, with obligatory periods of military training.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Persons participating in the program shall be commissioned officers in reserve components of the armed forces. Members pursuing a course of study shall serve on active duty in pay grade O–1 with full pay and allowances of that grade for a period of 45 days during each year of participation in the program. Members pursuing specialized training shall serve on active duty in a pay grade commensurate with their educational level, as determined by appointment under <ref>section 12207 of this title</ref>, with full pay and allowances of that grade for a period of 14 days during each year of participation in the program. They shall be detailed as students at accredited civilian institutions, located in the United States or Puerto Rico, for the purpose of acquiring knowledge or training in a designated health profession. In addition, members of the program shall, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, receive military and professional training and instruction.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If a member of the uniformed services selected to participate in the program as a medical student has prior active service in a pay grade and with years of service credited for pay that would entitle the member, if the member remained in the former grade, to a rate of basic pay in excess of the rate of basic pay for regular officers in the grade of second lieutenant or ensign, the member shall be paid basic pay based on the former grade and years of service credited for pay. The amount of such basic pay for the member shall be increased on January 1 of each year by the percentage by which basic pay is increased on average on that date for that year, and the member shall continue to receive basic pay based on the former grade and years of service until the date, whether occurring before or after the conclusion of such participation, on which the basic pay for the member in the member’s actual grade and years of service credited for pay exceeds the amount of basic pay to which the member is entitled based on the member’s former grade and years of service.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> Except when serving on active duty pursuant to subsection (c), a member of the program shall be entitled to a stipend at a monthly rate established by the Secretary of Defense, but not to exceed a total of $50,000 per year. The maximum annual amount of the stipend shall be increased annually by the Secretary of Defense effective on July 1 of each year by an amount (rounded to the next highest multiple of $1) equal to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the amount of such stipend (as previously adjusted (if at all)), multiplied by</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the overall percentage of the adjustment (if such adjustment is an increase) in the rates of basic pay for members of the uniformed services made effective for the fiscal year in which the school year ends.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 92–426, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1972-09-21">Sept. 21, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 717</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 96–107, title VIII, § 804(a)</ref>, <date date="1979-11-09">Nov. 9, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 812</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–94, title IX, § 935(a)</ref>, <date date="1983-09-24">Sept. 24, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 652</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title VII, § 725(b)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1479</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XIV, § 1484(k)(7)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1719</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1501(c)(22)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 499</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title V, § 538(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2209</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title V, § 524(b)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 103</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title V, § 524(a)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2285</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title VII, § 712</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 302</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2122.</num>
<heading> Eligibility for participation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> To be eligible for participation as a member of the program, a person must be a citizen of the United States and must—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> be accepted for admission to, or enrolled in, an institution in a course of study or selected to receive specialized training;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> sign an agreement that unless sooner separated he will—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> complete the educational phase of the program;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> accept an appropriate reappointment or designation within his military service, if tendered, based upon his health profession, following satisfactory completion of the program;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> participate in the intern program of his service if selected for such participation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> participate in the residency program of his service, if selected, or be released from active duty for the period required to undergo civilian residency if selected for such training; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> because of his sincere motivation and dedication to a career in the uniformed services, participate in military training while he is in the program, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> meet the requirements for appointment as a commissioned officer.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may require, as part of the agreement under subsection (a)(2), that a person must agree to accept, if offered, residency training in a health profession skill which has been designated by the Secretary as a critically needed wartime skill.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 92–426, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1972-09-21">Sept. 21, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 717</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–180, div. A, title VII, § 712(a)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1112</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title VII, § 725(c)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1479</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2123.</num>
<heading> Members of the program: active duty obligation; failure to complete training; release from program</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> A member of the program incurs an active duty obligation. The amount of his obligation shall be determined under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, but those regulations may not provide for a period of obligation of less than one year for each year of participation in the program.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> A period of time spent in military intern or residency training shall not be creditable in satisfying an active duty obligation imposed by this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> A member of the program who, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, is dropped from the program for deficiency in conduct or studies, or for other reasons, may be required to perform active duty in an appropriate military capacity in accordance with the active duty obligation imposed by this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The Secretary of a military department, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, may relieve a member of the program who is dropped from the program from an active duty obligation imposed by this section, but such relief shall not relieve him from any military obligation imposed by any other law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> A member of the program who is relieved of the member’s active duty obligation under this subchapter before the completion of that active duty obligation may be given, with or without the consent of the member, any of the following alternative obligations, as determined by the Secretary of the military department concerned:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A service obligation in another armed force for a period of time not less than the member’s remaining active duty service obligation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A service obligation in a component of the Selected Reserve for a period not less than twice as long as the member’s remaining active duty service obligation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Repayment to the Secretary of Defense of a percentage of the total cost incurred by the Secretary under this subchapter on behalf of the member pursuant to the repayment provisions of section 303a(e) or 373 of title 37.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In addition to the alternative obligations specified in paragraph (1), if the member is relieved of an active duty obligation by reason of the separation of the member because of a physical disability, the Secretary of the military department concerned may give the member a service obligation as a civilian employee employed as a health care professional in a facility of the uniformed services for a period of time equal to the member’s remaining active duty service obligation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations describing the manner in which an alternative obligation may be given under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 92–426, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1972-09-21">Sept. 21, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 718</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 511(67)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2926</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–180, div. A, title VII, § 711(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1108</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–597, title IV, § 401(b)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3035</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title VII, § 741(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2599</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title VI, § 687(c)(5)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3334</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title VI, § 618(a)(1)(E)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1426</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2124.</num>
<heading> Members of the program: numbers appointed</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authorized Number of Members of the Program</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The number of persons who may be designated as members of the program for training in each health profession shall be as prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, except that the total number of persons so designated may not, at any time, exceed 6,300.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Mental Health Professionals</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Of the number of persons designated as members of the program at any time, 300 may be members of the program described in <ref>section 2121(a)(1)(B) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 92–426, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1972-09-21">Sept. 21, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 718</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title VI, § 672(i)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 664</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–180, div. A, title VII</ref>, §§ 711(a)(2), 712(b)(1), <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1108</ref>, 1112; <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title VII, § 725(g)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1480</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title VII, § 717</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1404</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title V, § 524(b)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2285</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2125.</num>
<heading> Members of the program: exclusion from authorized strengths</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, members of the program shall not be counted against any prescribed military strengths.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 92–426, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1972-09-21">Sept. 21, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 718</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2126.</num>
<heading> Members of the program: service credit</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Service Not Creditable</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Except as provided in subsection (b), service performed while a member of the program shall not be counted—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in determining eligibility for retirement other than by reason of a physical disability incurred while on active duty as a member of the program; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in computing years of service creditable under <ref>section 205 of title 37</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Service Creditable for Certain Purposes</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary concerned may authorize service performed by a member of the program in pursuit of a course of study under this subchapter to be counted in accordance with this subsection if the member—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> completes the course of study;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> completes the active duty obligation imposed under <ref>section 2123(a) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> possesses a specialty designated by the Secretary concerned as critically needed in wartime.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Service credited under paragraph (1) counts only for the award of retirement points for computation of years of service under <ref>section 12732 of this title</ref> and for computation of retired pay under <ref>section 12733 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The number of points credited to a member under paragraph (1) for a year of participation in a course of study is 50. The points shall be credited to the member for one of the years of that participation at the end of each year after the completion of the course of study that the member serves in the Selected Reserve and is credited under <ref>section 12732(a)(2) of this title</ref> with at least 50 points. The points credited for the participation shall be recorded in the member’s records as having been earned in the year of the participation in the course of study.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Service may not be counted under paragraph (1) for more than four years of participation in a course of study as a member of the program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> A member of the Selected Reserve may be considered to be in an active status while pursuing a course of study under this subchapter only for purposes of sections 12732(a) and 12733(3) of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> A member is not entitled to any retroactive award of, or increase in, pay or allowances under title 37 by reason of an award of service credit under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 92–426, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1972-09-21">Sept. 21, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 718</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 501(22)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2908</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title V, § 543(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2521</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title V, § 544</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 608</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2127.</num>
<heading> Scholarships and financial assistance: payments</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may provide for the payment of all educational expenses incurred by a member of the program, including tuition, fees, books, and laboratory expenses. Such payments, however, shall be limited to those educational expenses normally incurred by students at the institution and in the health profession concerned who are not members of the program.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may contract with an accredited civilian educational institution for the payment of tuition and other educational expenses of members of the program authorized by this subchapter. Payment to such institutions may be made without regard to subsections (a) and (b) of <ref>section 3324 of title 31</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Payments made under subsection (b) shall not cover any expenses other than those covered by subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> When the Secretary of Defense determines, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Health and Human Services, that an accredited civilian educational institution has increased its total enrollment for the sole purpose of accepting members of the program covered by this subchapter, he may provide under a contract with such an institution for additional payments to cover the portion of the increased costs of the additional enrollment which are not covered by the institution’s normal tuition and fees.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> A person participating as a member of the program in specialized training shall be paid an annual grant in an amount not to exceed $45,000 in addition to the stipend under <ref>section 2121(d) of this title</ref>. The maximum amount of the grant shall be increased annually by the Secretary of Defense, effective July 1 of each year, in the same manner as provided for stipends.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 92–426, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1972-09-21">Sept. 21, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 718</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 511(67)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2926</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–258, § 3(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1063</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–525, title XIV, § 1405(56)(A)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2626</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–180, div. A, title VII, § 711(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1108</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title VII, § 725(d)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1479</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title V, § 538(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2209</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title X, § 1073(a)(19)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2473</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2128.</num>
<heading> Accession bonus for members of the program</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Availability of Bonus</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may offer a person who enters into an agreement under <ref>section 2122(a)(2) of this title</ref> an accession bonus of not more than $100,000 as part of the agreement.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Relation to Other Payments</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An accession bonus paid a person under this section is in addition to any other amounts payable to the person under this subchapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Repayment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A person who receives an accession bonus under this section, but fails to comply with the agreement under <ref>section 2122(a)(2) of this title</ref> or to commence or complete the active duty obligation imposed by <ref>section 2123 of this title</ref>, shall be subject to the repayment provisions of section 303a(e) or 373 of title 37.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title VI, § 623(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 152</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title VI, § 618(a)(1)(F)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1426</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title VI, § 612</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1933</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>NURSE OFFICER CANDIDATE ACCESSION PROGRAM</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2130a.</num>
<heading> Financial assistance: nurse officer candidates</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Bonus Authorized</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A person described in subsection (b) who, during the period beginning on <date date="1989-11-29">November 29, 1989</date>, and ending on <date date="2025-12-31">December 31, 2025</date>, executes a written agreement in accordance with subsection (c) to accept an appointment as a nurse officer may, upon the acceptance of the agreement by the Secretary concerned, be paid an accession bonus of not more than $40,000. The bonus shall be paid in periodic installments, as determined by the Secretary concerned at the time the agreement is accepted, except that the first installment may not exceed $20,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In addition to the accession bonus payable under paragraph (1), a person selected under such paragraph shall be entitled to a monthly stipend in an amount not to exceed the stipend rate in effect under <ref>section 2121(d) of this title</ref> for each month the individual is enrolled as a full-time student in an accredited baccalaureate degree program in nursing at a civilian educational institution by the Secretary selecting the person. The continuation bonus may be paid for not more than 24 months.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Eligible Students</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A person eligible to enter into an agreement under subsection (a) is a person who—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> is enrolled as a full-time student in an accredited baccalaureate degree program in nursing at a civilian educational institution that does not have a Senior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps program established under <ref>section 2102 of this title</ref> by the Secretary selecting the person or that has a Senior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps program for which the student is ineligible;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> has completed the second year of an accredited baccalaureate degree program in nursing and has more than 6 months of academic work remaining before graduation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> meets the qualifications for appointment as an officer of a reserve component of the Army, Navy, or Air Force as set forth in <ref>section 12201 of this title</ref> or, in the case of the Public Health Service, section 207 of the Public Health Service Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 209</ref>) and the regulations of the Secretary concerned.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Required Agreement</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The agreement referred to in subsection (a) shall provide that the person executing the agreement agrees to the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> That the person will complete the nursing degree program described in subsection (b)(1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> That, upon acceptance of the agreement by the Secretary concerned, the person will enlist in a reserve component of an armed force.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> That the person will accept an appointment as an officer in the Nurse Corps of the Army or the Navy or as an officer designated as a nurse officer in the Air Force or commissioned corps of the Public Health Service, as the case may be, upon graduation from the nursing degree program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> That the person will serve on active duty as such an officer—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> for a period of 4 years in the case of a person whose agreement was accepted by the Secretary concerned during that person’s fourth year of the nursing degree program; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for a period of 5 years in the case of a person whose agreement was accepted by the Secretary concerned during that person’s third year of the nursing degree program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Repayment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A person who does not complete a nursing degree program in which the person is enrolled in accordance with the agreement entered into under subsection (a), or having completed the nursing degree program, does not become an officer in the Nurse Corps of the Army or the Navy or an officer designated as a nurse officer of the Air Force or commissioned corps of the Public Health Service or does not complete the period of obligated active service required under the agreement, shall be subject to the repayment provisions of section 303a(e) or 373 of title 37.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretaries concerned shall prescribe regulations to carry out this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title VII, § 707(a)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1474</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title VI, § 613(c)</ref>, title XIV, § 1484(d)(1), <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1577</ref>, 1716; <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title VI, § 612(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1376</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title VI, § 612(h)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2421</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title VI, § 611(a)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1679</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title VI, § 612(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2783</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title VI, § 612(a)</ref>, title XV, § 1501(c)(23), <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 359</ref>, 499; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title VI, § 612(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2543</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title VI, § 612(a)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1786</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title VI, § 612(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2039</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title VI, § 612(a)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 650</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title VI, § 622(a)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–151; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title V, § 538</ref>, title VI, § 612(a), <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1107</ref>, 1135; <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title VI</ref>, §§ 612(a), 615(h), <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2567</ref>, 2569; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title VI, § 612(a)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1501</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title VI, § 612(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1947</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title VI</ref>, §§ 622(a), 687(c)(6), <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3294</ref>, 3334; <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title VI, § 612(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2248</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title VI, § 612(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 148</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title VI, §§ 612(a), 616(a), (b), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4484</ref>, 4486; <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title VI, § 612(a)(1)</ref>, title X, § 1073(c)(3), <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2353</ref>, 2474; <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title VI, § 612(a)(1)</ref>, title X, § 1075(b)(28), <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4236</ref>, 4370; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title VI, § 612(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1449</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title VI, § 612(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1776</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title VI, § 612(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 780</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title VI, § 612(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3400</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title VI, § 612(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 838</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title VI, § 612(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2157</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title VI</ref>, §§ 612(a)(1), 618(a)(1)(G), <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1421</ref>, 1426; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VI, § 611(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1797</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title VI, § 611(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1426</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title VI, § 611(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3673</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title VI, § 611(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1769</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title VI, § 601(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2619</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title V, § 544</ref>, title VI, § 613(b)(1), <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 265</ref>, 291; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title VI, § 611(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1932</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>