<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 104—</num>
<heading>UNIFORMED SERVICES UNIVERSITY OF THE HEALTH SCIENCES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2112.</num>
<heading> Establishment</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> There is established a Uniformed Services University of the Health Sciences (in this chapter referred to as the “University”) with authority to grant appropriate certificates, certifications, undergraduate degrees, and advanced degrees.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The University shall be so organized as to graduate not fewer than 100 medical students annually.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The headquarters of the University shall be at a site or sites selected by the Secretary of Defense within 25 miles of the District of Columbia.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Except as provided in subsection (a), the numbers of persons to be graduated from the University shall be prescribed by the Secretary of Defense. In so prescribing the number of persons to be graduated from the University, the Secretary of Defense shall institute actions necessary to ensure the maximum number of first-year enrollments in the University consistent with the academic capacity of the University and the needs of the uniformed services for medical personnel.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The development of the University may be by such phases as the Secretary of Defense may prescribe subject to the requirements of subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 92–426, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1972-09-21">Sept. 21, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 713</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 96–107, title VIII, § 803(a)</ref>, <date date="1979-11-09">Nov. 9, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 811</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 511(63)</ref>, (64), <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2925</ref>, 2926; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title X, § 1072(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 446</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title X, § 1048(e)(8)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1228</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title VII, § 724(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2230</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2112a.</num>
<heading> Continued operation of University</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The University may not be closed.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title IX, § 907(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2620</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title VII, § 724(c)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2230</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2113.</num>
<heading> Administration of University</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The business of the University shall be conducted by the Secretary of Defense with funds appropriated for and provided by the Department of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall appoint a President of the University (hereinafter in this chapter referred to as the “President”).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary, after considering the recommendations of the President, shall obtain the services of such military and civilian professors, instructors, and administrative and other employees as may be necessary to operate the University. Civilian members of the faculty and staff shall be employed under salary schedules and granted retirement and other related benefits prescribed by the Secretary (after due consideration by the Secretary) so as to place the employees of the University on a comparable basis with the employees of fully accredited schools of the health professions identified by the Secretary for purposes of this paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary may confer academic titles, as appropriate, upon military and civilian members of the faculty.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The military members of the faculty shall include a professor of military, naval, or air science as the Secretary may determine.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The limitations in sections 5307 and 5373 of title 5 do not apply to the authority of the Secretary under paragraph (1) to prescribe salary schedules and other related benefits. In no event may the total amount of compensation paid to an employee under paragraph (1) in any year (including salary, allowances, differentials, bonuses, awards, and other similar cash payments) exceed the total amount of annual compensation (excluding expenses) specified in <ref>section 102 of title 3</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The Secretary may negotiate agreements with agencies of the Federal Government to utilize on a reimbursable basis appropriate existing Federal medical resources. Under such agreements the facilities concerned will retain their identities and basic missions. The Secretary may negotiate affiliation agreements with an accredited university or universities. Such agreements may include provisions for payments for educational services provided students participating in Department of Defense educational programs.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Defense may establish the following educational programs at the University:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Postdoctoral, postgraduate, and technological institutes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A graduate school of nursing.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Other schools or programs, including certificate, certification, and undergraduate degree programs, that the Secretary determines necessary in order to operate the University in a cost-effective manner.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall also establish programs in continuing medical education for military members of the health professions to the end that high standards of health care may be maintained within the military medical services.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary also is authorized—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to enter into contracts with, accept grants from, and make grants to the Henry M. Jackson Foundation for the Advancement of Military Medicine established under <ref>section 178 of this title</ref>, or any other nonprofit entity, for the purpose of carrying out cooperative enterprises in medical research, medical consultation, and medical education;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to make available to the Henry M. Jackson Foundation for the Advancement of Military Medicine, or any other nonprofit entity, on such terms and conditions as the Secretary determines appropriate, such space, facilities, equipment, and support services within the University as the Secretary considers necessary to accomplish cooperative enterprises undertaken by such Foundation, or nonprofit entity, and the University;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to enter into contracts with the Henry M. Jackson Foundation for the Advancement of Military Medicine, or any other nonprofit entity, under which the Secretary may furnish the services of such professional, technical, or clerical personnel as may be necessary to fulfill cooperative enterprises undertaken by such foundation, or nonprofit entity, and the University;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> to accept, hold, administer, invest, and spend any gift, devise, or bequest of personal property made to the University, including any gift, devise, or bequest for the support of an academic chair, teaching, research, or demonstration project;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> to enter into agreements with the Henry M. Jackson Foundation for the Advancement of Military Medicine, or with any other nonprofit entity, under which scientists or other personnel of the Foundation or other entity may be utilized by the University for the purpose of enhancing the activities of the University in education, research, and technological applications of knowledge;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> to accept the voluntary services of guest scholars and other persons; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> notwithstanding sections 2304,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002082">1</ref> 4141, and 4024 of this title, to enter into contracts and cooperative agreements with, accept grants from, and make grants to, nonprofit entities (on a sole-source basis) for the purpose specified in subparagraph (A) or for any other purpose the Secretary determines to be consistent with the mission of the University.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary may not enter into any contract with the Henry M. Jackson Foundation for the Advancement of Military Medicine, or with any other entity, if the contract would obligate the University to make outlays in advance of the enactment of budget authority for such outlays.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Scientists or other medical personnel utilized by the University under an agreement described in clause (E) of paragraph (1) may be appointed to any position within the University and may be permitted to perform such duties within the University as the Secretary may approve.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> A person who provides voluntary services under the authority of clause (F) of paragraph (1) shall be considered to be an employee of the Federal Government for the purposes of chapter 81 of title 5, relating to compensation for work-related injuries, and to be an employee of the Federal Government for the purposes of chapter 171 of title 28, relating to tort claims. Such a person who is not otherwise employed by the Federal Government shall not be considered to be a Federal employee for any other purpose by reason of the provision of such services.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 92–426, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1972-09-21">Sept. 21, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 714</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 95–589</ref>, <date date="1978-11-04">Nov. 4, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2512</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 511(64)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2926</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–36, § 3</ref>, <date date="1983-05-27">May 27, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 201</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–132, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="1983-10-17">Oct. 17, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 849</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title V, § 505</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3864</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title VII, § 726(a)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1480</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XIII, § 1322(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1671</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title X, § 1072(a)</ref>, (b)(2), (c)(1), <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 446</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title XI, § 1108</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 778</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title X, § 1087(a)(12)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–291; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title IX, § 954(a)(3)(A)</ref>, (b)(1), title XI, § 1116, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 294</ref>, 361; <ref>Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title VII, § 711</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 793</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title VII, § 724(b)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2230</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title VII, § 714(a)</ref>, title XVIII, § 1883(b)(2), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3694</ref>, 4294.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2113a.</num>
<heading> Board of Regents</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>To assist the Secretary of Defense in an advisory capacity, there is a Board of Regents of the University.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Membership</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Board shall consist of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> nine persons outstanding in the fields of health care, higher education administration, or public policy who shall be appointed from civilian life by the Secretary of Defense;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Defense, or his designee, who shall be an ex officio member;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the Director of the Defense Health Agency, who shall be an ex officio member;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the surgeons general of the uniformed services, who shall be ex officio members; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the President of the University, who shall be a nonvoting ex officio member.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Term of Office</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term of office of each member of the Board (other than ex officio members) shall be six years except that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any member appointed to fill a vacancy occurring before the expiration of the term for which his predecessor was appointed shall be appointed for the remainder of such term; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any member whose term of office has expired shall continue to serve until his successor is appointed.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Chairman</inline>.—</heading>
<content>One of the members of the Board (other than an ex officio member) shall be designated by the Secretary as Chairman. He shall be the presiding officer of the Board.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Compensation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Members of the Board (other than ex officio members) while attending conferences or meetings or while otherwise performing their duties as members shall be entitled to receive compensation at a rate to be fixed by the Secretary and shall also be entitled to receive an allowance for necessary travel expenses while so serving away from their place of residence.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Meetings</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Board shall meet at least once a quarter.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title IX, § 954(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 293</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title V, § 523</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2285</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title VII, § 715(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3694</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2113b.</num>
<heading> Academic Health System</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may establish an Academic Health System to integrate the health care, health professions education, and health research activities of the military health system, including under this chapter, in the National Capital Region.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Leadership</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary may appoint employees of the Department of Defense to leadership positions in the Academic Health System established under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Such positions may include responsibilities for management of the health care, health professions education, and health research activities described in subsection (a) and are in addition to similar leadership positions for members of the armed forces.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">National Capital Region Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “National Capital Region” means the area, or portion thereof, as determined by the Secretary, in the vicinity of the District of Columbia.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title VII, § 734(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1461</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2114.</num>
<heading> Students: selection; status; obligation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Medical students at the University shall be selected under procedures prescribed by the Secretary of Defense. In so prescribing, the Secretary shall consider the recommendations of the Board. However, selection procedures prescribed by the Secretary of Defense shall emphasize the basic requirement that students demonstrate sincere motivation and dedication to a career in the uniformed services (as defined in <ref>section 1072(1) of this title</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Medical students shall be commissioned officers of a uniformed service as determined under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense after consulting with the Secretary of Health and Human Services. They shall be appointed as regular officers in the grade of second lieutenant or ensign and shall serve on active duty in that grade.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If a member of the uniformed services selected to be a student has prior active service in a pay grade and with years of service credited for pay that would entitle the member, if the member remained in the former grade, to a rate of basic pay in excess of the rate of basic pay for regular officers in the grade of second lieutenant or ensign, the member shall be paid basic pay based on the former grade and years of service credited for pay. The amount of such basic pay for the member shall be increased on January 1 of each year by the percentage by which basic pay is increased on average on that date for that year, and the member shall continue to receive basic pay based on the former grade and years of service until the date, whether occurring before or after graduation, on which the basic pay for the member in the member’s actual grade and years of service credited for pay exceeds the amount of basic pay to which the member is entitled based on the member’s former grade and years of service.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Medical students who graduate shall be required to serve on active duty unless they are covered by <ref>section 2115 of this title</ref>. Medical students who graduate shall be required, except as provided in <ref>section 2115 of this title</ref>, to serve thereafter on active duty under such regulations as the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of Health and Human Services, as appropriate, may prescribe for not less than seven years, unless sooner released. Upon completion of, or release from, the active-duty service obligation, a member of the program who served on active-duty for less than 10 years shall serve in the Ready Reserve for the period specified in the following table:<table width="50%" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><colgroup><col/><col/></colgroup><thead><tr class="header"><th><p><b/>Period of Service on Active Duty</p></th><th><p><b>Ready Reserve Obligation</b></p></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span> Less than 8 years</span></p></td><td><p>6 years</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span> 8 years or more, but less than 9</span></p></td><td><p>4 years</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span> 9 years or more, but less than 10</span></p></td><td><p>2 years</p></td></tr></tbody></table>
<p class="indent0 firstIndent0">The service credit exclusions specified in <ref>section 2126 of this title</ref> shall apply to students covered by this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> A period of time spent in military intern or residency training shall not be creditable in satisfying a commissioned service obligation imposed by this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> A medical student who, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, is dropped from the program for deficiency in conduct or studies, or for other reasons, may be required to perform active duty in an appropriate military capacity in accordance with the active duty obligation imposed by this section. In no case shall any such student be required to serve on active duty for any period in excess of a period equal to the period he participated in the program, except that in no case may any such student be required to serve on active duty less than one year.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may enter into agreements with foreign military medical schools for reciprocal education programs under which students at the University receive specialized military medical instruction at the foreign military medical school and military medical personnel of the country of such medical school receive specialized military medical instruction at the University. Any such agreement may be made on a reimbursable basis or a nonreimbursable basis.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Not more than 40 persons at any one time may receive instruction at the University under this subsection. Attendance of such persons at the University may not result in a decrease in the number of students enrolled in the University. Subsection (b) does not apply to students receiving instruction under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The President of the University, with the approval of the Secretary of Defense, shall determine the countries from which persons may be selected to receive instruction under this subsection and the number of persons that may be selected from each country. The President may establish qualifications and methods of selection and shall select those persons who will be permitted to receive instruction at the University. The qualifications established shall be comparable to those required of United States citizens.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Each foreign country from which a student is permitted to receive instruction at the University under this subsection shall reimburse the United States for the cost of providing such instruction, unless such reimbursement is waived by the Secretary of Defense. The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe the rates for reimbursement under this paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Except as the President determines, a person receiving instruction at the University under this subsection is subject to the same regulations governing attendance, discipline, discharge, and dismissal as a student enrolled in the University. The Secretary may prescribe regulations with respect to access to classified information by a person receiving instruction under this subsection that differ from the regulations that apply to a student enrolled in the University.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> In this section, the term “commissioned service obligation” means, with respect to an officer who is a graduate of the University, the period beginning on the date of the appointment of the officer in a regular component after graduation and ending on the tenth anniversary of that appointment.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the Secretary of Health and Human Services and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, shall establish such selection procedures, service obligations, and other requirements as the Secretary considers appropriate for graduate students (other than medical students) in a postdoctoral, postgraduate, or technological institute established pursuant to <ref>section 2113(e) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A covered employee whose employment or service with the Department of Veterans Affairs, Public Health Service, or Coast Guard (as applicable) is in a position relevant to national security or health sciences may receive instruction at the University within the scope of such employment or service.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> If a covered employee receives instruction at the University pursuant to subparagraph (A), the head of the Federal agency concerned shall reimburse the University for the cost of providing such instruction to the covered employee. Amounts received by the University under this subparagraph shall be retained by the University to defray the costs of such instruction.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding subsections (b) through (e) and subsection (i), the head of the Federal agency concerned shall determine the service obligations of the covered employee receiving instruction at the University pursuant to subparagraph (A) in accordance with applicable law.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> In this paragraph—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the term “covered employee” means an employee of the Department of Veterans Affairs, a civilian employee of the Public Health Service, a member of the commissioned corps of the Public Health Service, a member of the Coast Guard, or a civilian employee of the Coast Guard; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the term “head of the Federal agency concerned” means the head of the Federal agency that employs, or has jurisdiction over the uniformed service of, a covered employee permitted to receive instruction at the University under subparagraph (A) in the relevant position described in such subparagraph.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> A graduate of the University who is relieved of the graduate’s active-duty service obligation under subsection (c) before the completion of that active-duty service obligation may be given, with or without the consent of the graduate, an alternative obligation in the same manner as provided in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (1) of <ref>section 2123(e) of this title</ref> or paragraph (2) of such section for members of the Armed Forces Health Professions Scholarship and Financial Assistance program.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 92–426, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1972-09-21">Sept. 21, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 715</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 96–107, title VIII, § 803(b)</ref>, <date date="1979-11-09">Nov. 9, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 812</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title I, § 114</ref>, title V, § 511(65), <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2877</ref>, 2926; <ref>Pub. L. 98–525, title XV, § 1535</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2633</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title V, § 511(a)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1439</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title V, § 533(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1564</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title VII, § 732(a)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1696</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title X, § 1072(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 446</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title VII, § 741(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2599</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title X, § 1073(a)(38)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1902</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title V, § 501(e)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1874</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title V, § 524(a)</ref>, title IX, § 954(a)(3)(B), (b)(2), <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 103</ref>, 294; <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title X, § 1061(b)(8), (9), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4613</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title VII, § 718</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1790</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2114a.</num>
<heading> Eligibility of members of foreign militaries to enroll in the University</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Defense may permit an individual who is a member of the military of a foreign country—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> to enroll (including as a full-time student) and receive instruction—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> as a medical student of the University; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in a postdoctoral, postgraduate, or certificate program of the University; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to participate in training exercises of the University.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Enrollment of an individual under this section—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> shall be subject to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the academic capacity of the University described in <ref>section 2112(b) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> an international agreement or qualifying non-binding instrument (as such terms are defined in <ref>section 112b of title 1</ref>); and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> may not decrease the number of members of the uniformed services enrolled in the University; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> may not be given priority over the enrollment of a member of the uniformed services.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The number of individuals simultaneously enrolled under this section may not exceed—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> 10, in the case of medical students of the University; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> 40, with regards to all postdoctoral, postgraduate, and certificate programs of the University.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Qualifications; Selection</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary may select an individual to enroll under this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> who was nominated for such enrollment by the medical command of the military of a foreign country; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> pursuant to regulations prescribed by the Secretary regarding—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> qualifications for such enrollment that are comparable to the qualifications required of a United States citizen; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> procedures for such selection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reimbursement</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall require the foreign country of an individual enrolled under this section to reimburse the United States for the cost of providing instruction to such individual.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall prescribe rates for such reimbursement that equal or exceed the cost to the United States of providing such instruction to a member of the uniformed services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary may waive, in whole or in part, reimbursement with regards to an individual enrolled under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> Amounts received by the Secretary under this subsection shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> be used to defray the costs of providing instruction to an individual enrolled under this section;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> be credited to appropriations available for the maintenance and operation of the University; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> remain available for until expended.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The source and the disposition of such amounts shall be specifically identified in records of the University.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Applicability of Regulations and Policies</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Subject to paragraphs (2) through (4), and to the determination of the Secretary, an individual enrolled under this section shall be subject to the same regulations and policies that apply to a member of the uniformed services enrolled in the University.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary may prescribe regulations regarding access to classified information by an individual enrolled under this section that differ from the regulations that apply to a member of the uniformed services enrolled in the University.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> An individual enrolled under this section shall not be entitled to an appointment in a uniformed service by reason of completing of a program of the University.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content><ref>Section 2114 of this title</ref> shall not apply to an individual enrolled under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title V, § 553</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1894</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2115.</num>
<heading> Graduates: limitation on number permitted to perform civilian Federal service</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Defense may allow not more than 20 percent of the graduates of each class at the University to perform civilian Federal service for not less than seven years following the completion of their professional education in lieu of active duty in a uniformed service if the needs of the uniformed services do not require that such graduates perform active duty in a uniformed service and as long as the Secretary of Defense does not recall such persons to active duty in the uniformed services. Such persons who execute an agreement in writing to perform such civilian Federal service may be released from active duty following the completion of their professional education. The location and type of their duty shall be determined by the Secretary of Defense after consultation with the heads of Federal agencies concerned.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 92–426, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1972-09-21">Sept. 21, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 716</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 96–107, title VIII, § 803(c)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="1979-11-09">Nov. 9, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 812</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2116.</num>
<heading> Military nursing research</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “military nursing research” means research on the furnishing of care and services by nurses in the armed forces.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “TriService Nursing Research Program” means the program of military nursing research authorized under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Program Authorized</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may establish at the University a program of military nursing research.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">TriService Research Group</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The TriService Nursing Research Program shall be administered by a TriService Nursing Research Group composed of Army, Navy, and Air Force nurses who are involved in military nursing research and are designated by the Secretary concerned to serve as members of the group.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duties of Group</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The TriService Nursing Research Group shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> develop for the Department of Defense recommended guidelines for requesting, reviewing, and funding proposed military nursing research projects; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> make available to Army, Navy, and Air Force nurses and Department of Defense officials concerned with military nursing research—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> information about nursing research projects that are being developed or carried out in the Army, Navy, and Air Force; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> expertise and information beneficial to the encouragement of meaningful nursing research.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Research Topics</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For purposes of this section, military nursing research includes research on the following issues:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Issues regarding how to improve the results of nursing care and services provided in the armed forces in time of peace.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Issues regarding how to improve the results of nursing care and services provided in the armed forces in time of war.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Issues regarding how to prevent complications associated with battle injuries.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Issues regarding how to prevent complications associated with the transporting of patients in the military medical evacuation system.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Issues regarding how to improve methods of training nursing personnel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Clinical nursing issues, including such issues as prevention and treatment of child abuse and spouse abuse.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Women’s health issues.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Wellness issues.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> Preventive medicine issues.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> Home care management issues.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> Case management issues.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title VII, § 741(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 384</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2117.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title V, § 525(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2286</ref>]</heading>
</section>
</chapter>