<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 324—</num>
<heading>SELECTED ACQUISITION REPORTS</heading>
<section>
<num>[§ 4350.</num>
<heading> Omitted]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4351.</num>
<heading> Selected Acquisition Reports</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “program acquisition unit cost”, with respect to a major defense acquisition program, means the amount equal to (A) the total cost for development and procurement of, and system-specific military construction for, the acquisition program, divided by (B) the number of fully-configured end items to be produced for the acquisition program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “procurement unit cost”, with respect to a major defense acquisition program, means the amount equal to (A) the total of all funds programmed to be available for obligation for procurement for the program, divided by (B) the number of fully-configured end items to be procured.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “major contract”, with respect to a major defense acquisition program, means each of the six largest prime, associate, or Government-furnished equipment contracts under the program that is in excess of $40,000,000 and that is not a firm, fixed price contract.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “full life-cycle cost”, with respect to a major defense acquisition program, means all costs of development, procurement, military construction, and operations and support, without regard to funding source or management control.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall submit to Congress at the end of each fiscal-year quarter a report on current major defense acquisition programs and any program that is estimated by the Secretary of Defense to require an eventual total expenditure for research, development, test, and evaluation of more than $300,000,000 (based on fiscal year 1990 constant dollars) or an eventual total expenditure for procurement, including all planned increments or spirals, of more than $1,800,000,000 (based on fiscal year 1990 constant dollars). Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3), each such report shall include a status report on each defense acquisition program that at the end of such quarter is a major defense acquisition program. Reports under this section shall be known as Selected Acquisition Reports.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> A status report on a major defense acquisition program need not be included in the Selected Acquisition Report for the second, third, or fourth quarter of a fiscal year if such a report was included in a previous Selected Acquisition Report for that fiscal year and during the period since that report there has been—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> less than a 15 percent increase in program acquisition unit cost and current procurement unit cost for the program (or for each designated subprogram under the program); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> less than a six-month delay in any program schedule milestone shown in the Selected Acquisition Report.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Defense may waive the requirement for submission of Selected Acquisition Reports for a program for a fiscal year if—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the program has not entered system development and demonstration;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a reasonable cost estimate has not been established for such program; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the system configuration for such program is not well defined.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives a written notification of each waiver under subparagraph (A) for a program for a fiscal year not later than 60 days before the President submits the budget to Congress pursuant to <ref>section 1105 of title 31</ref> in that fiscal year.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Each Selected Acquisition Report for the first quarter for a fiscal year shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the same information, in detailed and summarized form, as is provided in reports submitted under <ref>section 4205 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> for each major defense acquisition program or designated major subprogram included in the report—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Baseline Estimate (as that term is defined in <ref>section 4371(a)(4) of this title</ref>), along with the associated risk and sensitivity analysis of that estimate;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the original Baseline Estimate (as that term is defined in <ref>section 4214(d)(1) of this title</ref>), along with the associated risk and sensitivity analysis of that estimate;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> if the original Baseline Estimate was adjusted or revised pursuant to <ref>section 4214(d)(2) of this title</ref>, such adjusted or revised estimate, along with the associated risk and sensitivity analysis of that estimate; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the primary risk parameters associated with the current procurement cost for the program (as that term is used in subsection (e)(4));</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a summary of the history of significant developments from the date each major defense acquisition program or designated major subprogram included in the report was first included in a Selected Acquisition Report and program highlights since the last Selected Acquisition Report;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the significant schedule and technical risks for each such program or subprogram, identified at each major milestone and as of the quarter for which the current report is submitted;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the current program acquisition cost and program acquisition unit cost for each such program or subprogram included in the report and the history of those costs from the December 2001 reporting period to the end of the quarter for which the current report is submitted;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the current procurement unit cost for each such program or subprogram included in the report and the history of that cost from the December 2001 reporting period to the end of the quarter for which the current report is submitted;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> for each major defense acquisition program that receives Milestone B approval after <date date="2019-01-01">January 1, 2019</date>, a brief summary description of the key elements of the modular open system approach as defined in <ref>section 4401 of this title</ref> or, if a modular open system approach was not used, the rationale for not using such an approach; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> such other information as the Secretary of Defense considers appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Each Selected Acquisition Report for the first quarter of a fiscal year shall be designed to provide to the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives the information such Committees need to perform their oversight functions. Whenever the Secretary of Defense proposes to make changes in the content of a Selected Acquisition Report, the Secretary shall submit a notice of the proposed changes to such committees. The changes shall be considered approved by the Secretary, and may be incorporated into the report, only after the end of the 60-day period beginning on the date on which the notice is received by those committees.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> In addition to the material required by paragraphs (1) and (2), each Selected Acquisition Report for the first quarter of a fiscal year shall include the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A full life-cycle cost analysis for each major defense acquisition program and each designated major subprogram included in the report that is in the system development and demonstration stage or has completed that stage. The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that this subparagraph is implemented in a uniform manner, to the extent practicable, throughout the Department of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> If the system that is included in that major defense acquisition program has an antecedent system, a full life-cycle cost analysis for that system.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Selected Acquisition Reports for the first quarter of a fiscal year shall be known as comprehensive annual Selected Acquisition Reports.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Each Selected Acquisition Report for the second, third, and fourth quarters of a fiscal year shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> with respect to each major defense acquisition program that was included in the most recent comprehensive annual Selected Acquisition Report, the information described in subsection (e); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> with respect to each major defense acquisition program that was not included in the most recent comprehensive annual Selected Acquisition Report, the information described in subsection (c).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Selected Acquisition Reports for the second, third, and fourth quarters of a fiscal year shall be known as Quarterly Selected Acquisition Reports.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<chapeau> Information to be included under this subsection in a Quarterly Selected Acquisition Report with respect to a major defense acquisition program is as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The quantity of items to be purchased under the program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The program acquisition cost.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The program acquisition unit cost for the program (or for each designated major subprogram under the program).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The current procurement cost for the program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The current procurement unit cost for the program (or for each designated major subprogram under the program).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The reasons for any change in program acquisition cost, program acquisition unit cost, procurement cost, or procurement unit cost or in program schedule from the previous Selected Acquisition Report.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The reasons for any significant changes (from the previous Selected Acquisition Report) in the total program cost for development and procurement of the software component of the program or subprogram, schedule milestones for the software component of the program or subprogram, or expected performance for the software component of the program or subprogram that are known, expected, or anticipated by the program manager.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> The major contracts under the program and designated major subprograms under the program and the reasons for any cost or schedule variances under those contracts since the last Selected Acquisition Report.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> Program highlights since the last Selected Acquisition Report.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> Each comprehensive annual Selected Acquisition Report shall be submitted within 30 days after the date on which the President transmits the Budget to Congress for the following fiscal year, and each Quarterly Selected Acquisition Report shall be submitted within 45 days after the end of the fiscal-year quarter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> The requirements of this section with respect to a major defense acquisition program or designated major subprogram shall cease to apply after 90 percent of the items to be delivered to the United States under the program or subprogram (shown as the total quantity of items to be purchased under the program or subprogram in the most recent Selected Acquisition Report) have been delivered or 90 percent of planned expenditures under the program or subprogram have been made.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Total program reporting under this section shall apply to a major defense acquisition program when funds have been appropriated for such program and the Secretary of Defense has decided to proceed to system development and demonstration of such program. Reporting may be limited to the development program as provided in paragraph (2) before a decision is made by the Secretary of Defense to proceed to system development and demonstration if the Secretary notifies the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives of the intention to submit a limited report under this subsection not less than 15 days before a report is due under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> A limited report under this subsection shall include the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The same information, in detail and summarized form, as is provided in reports submitted under subsections (b)(1) and (b)(3) of <ref>section 4205 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Reasons for any change in the development cost and schedule.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The major contracts under the development program and designated major subprograms under the program and the reasons for any cost or schedule variances under those contracts since the last Selected Acquisition Report.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Program highlights since the last Selected Acquisition Report.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Other information as the Secretary of Defense considers appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The submission requirements for a limited report under this subsection shall be the same as for quarterly Selected Acquisition Reports for total program reporting.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Form of Report</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A Selected Acquisition Report required under this section shall be submitted in unclassified form without any designation relating to dissemination control, but may contain a classified annex.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Termination</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The requirements under this section shall terminate after the final submission covering fiscal year 2023.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 97–252, title XI, § 1107(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-08">Sept. 8, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 739</ref>, § 139a; amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–525, title XII, § 1242(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2606</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title XII, § 1201</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 715</ref>; renumbered § 2432 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 99–433, title I</ref>, §§ 101(a)(5), 110(d)(13), (g)(7), <date date="1986-10-01">Oct. 1, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 995</ref>, 1003, 1004; <ref>Pub. L. 99–500, § 101(c) [title X, § 961(a)]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-18">Oct. 18, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1783–82</ref>, 1783–175, and <ref>Pub. L. 99–591, § 101(c) [title X, § 961(a)]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-30">Oct. 30, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3341–82</ref>, 3341–175; <ref>Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title IX</ref>, formerly title IV, § 961(a), <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3955</ref>, renumbered title IX, <ref>Pub. L. 100–26, § 3(5)</ref>, <date date="1987-04-21">Apr. 21, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 273</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–26, § 7(b)(3)</ref>, (k)(2), <date date="1987-04-21">Apr. 21, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 279</ref>, 284; <ref>Pub. L. 100–180, div. A, title XII, § 1233(a)(1)</ref>, title XIII, § 1314(a)(1), <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1161</ref>, 1175; <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title VIII, § 811(c)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1493</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XIV</ref>, §§ 1407(a)–(c), 1484(f)(4), <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1681</ref>, 1717; <ref>Pub. L. 102–25, title VII, § 701(f)(3)</ref>, <date date="1991-04-06">Apr. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 115</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title VIII, § 801(b)(2)</ref>, title X, § 1061(a)(14), <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1412</ref>, 1473; <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title VIII, § 817(c)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2455</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–355, title III, § 3002(a)(1)</ref>, (b)–(h), <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3328</ref>, 3329; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1502(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 502</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title VIII, § 806</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2606</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title VIII, § 841(c)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1843</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1067(1)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 774</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title VIII, § 821(a)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1181</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title X, § 1045(a)(6)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1612</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title VIII, § 801(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2004</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title X, § 1071(g)(10)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2402</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title VIII, § 811(b), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4521</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title VIII, § 812</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1491</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title VIII, § 812(a)</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 807</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title X, § 1071(g)(2)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3511</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title VIII</ref>, §§ 805(b), 841, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2255</ref>, 2288; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title VIII, § 830(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1492</ref>; renumbered § 4351 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1849(a)</ref>–(d), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4259</ref>, 4260; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title VIII, § 805(a)</ref>, title XVII, § 1701(<i>o</i>)(1), (3), (4), <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1816</ref>, 2146, 2147; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XVIII, § 1801(a)(35)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 685</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§§ 4352 to 4358.</num>
<heading> Omitted]</heading>
</section>
</chapter>