<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 871—</num>
<heading>CIVILIAN EMPLOYEES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 8742.</num>
<heading> Physical examination: employees engaged in hazardous occupations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Navy may provide for physical examination by civilians of employees engaged in hazardous occupations, where the professional services of the Medical Department are not available. The Secretary may compensate these civilians for their services, on a contract or fee basis, at the rates customary in the locality.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Secretary, to the extent he considers proper, may delegate the authority conferred by this section to any person in the Department of the Navy, with or without the authority to make successive redelegations.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 462</ref>, § 7472; renumbered § 8742, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(d)(6)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8743.</num>
<heading> Employment of aliens</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Laws prohibiting payment of compensation to a person who is not a citizen of the United States do not apply to a person whose employment by the Department of the Navy is determined by the Secretary of the Navy to be necessary to obtain for the armed forces the benefits of the special technical or scientific knowledge or experience possessed by that person and not readily obtainable from a citizen.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 462</ref>, § 7473; renumbered § 8743, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(d)(6)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8746.</num>
<heading> Administration of oaths by clerks and employees</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Chief clerks and inspectors attached to any office of inspector of naval material, chief clerks attached to the field service of the Department of the Navy, to naval shipyards and stations, and to Marine Corps posts and stations, and such other clerks and employees attached to those activities as the Secretary of the Navy designates, may administer—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> oaths required by law or regulation relating to claims against, or applications to, the United States of officers and of employees of the Department; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> oaths of office to officers and employees of the Department.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> There may be no compensation for the administration of oaths under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 463</ref>, § 7476; renumbered § 8746, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(d)(6)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8747.</num>
<heading> Transportation of dependents and household effects of civilian personnel stationed outside the United States: payment in lieu of transportation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> When civilian employees of the Department of the Navy are located at duty stations outside the United States, the dependents and household effects of such personnel may be transported—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> from the locations outside the United States to locations designated by such personnel or their dependents; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> from those designated locations to the duty stations to which the personnel are ordered.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">The Secretary of the Navy may determine the civilian employees whose dependents and household effects may be transported under this section.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Authority to transport household effects under this section includes authority to pack and unpack those effects.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Transportation of dependents and household effects is authorized under this section either before or after orders are issued relieving the civilian concerned from the duty station outside the United States. The transportation may be by Government or commercial facilities.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> In place of the transportation in kind authorized for dependents, the Secretary may authorize the payment, after the travel has been completed, of an amount equal to the commercial transportation costs, including taxes if paid, of all parts of the travel for which transportation in kind was not furnished.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> Current appropriations available for travel and transportation may be used for expenditures under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 463</ref>, § 7477; renumbered § 8747, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(d)(6)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8748.</num>
<heading> Naval War College and Marine Corps University: civilian faculty members</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority of Secretary</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the Navy may employ as many civilians as professors, instructors, and lecturers at a school of the Naval War College or of the Marine Corps University as the Secretary considers necessary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Compensation of Faculty Members</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The compensation of persons employed under this section shall be as prescribed by the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Application to Certain Faculty Members</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section shall not apply with respect to professors, instructors, and lecturers employed at a school of the Naval War College or of the Marine Corps University if the duration of the principal course of instruction offered at the school or college involved is less than 10 months.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 464</ref>, § 7478; <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title XI, § 1124(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1559</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title XI, § 1109(a)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1927</ref>; renumbered § 8748, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(d)(6)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8749.</num>
<heading> Civil service mariners of Military Sealift Command: release of drug and alcohol test results to Coast Guard</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Release of Drug or Alcohol Test Results to Coast Guard</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the Navy may release to the Commandant of the Coast Guard the results of a drug or alcohol test of any employee of the Department of the Navy who is employed in any capacity on board a vessel of the Military Sealift Command. Any such release shall be in accordance with the standards and procedures applicable to the disclosure and reporting to the Coast Guard of drug or alcohol test results and drug or alcohol test records of individuals employed on vessels documented under the laws of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Waiver</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The results of a drug or alcohol test of an employee may be released under subsection (a) without the prior written consent of the employee that is otherwise required under section 503(e) of the Supplemental Appropriations Act, 1987 (<ref>5 U.S.C. 7301</ref> note).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title XI, § 1103(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2141</ref>, § 7479; renumbered § 8749 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(d)(6)</ref>, title XI, § 1114(b), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>, 2013; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title XVII, § 1731(a)(60)(A)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1815</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title X, § 1081(a)(46)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3873</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8749a.</num>
<heading> Civil service mariners of Military Sealift Command: alcohol testing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Navy may prescribe regulations establishing a program to conduct on-duty reasonable suspicion alcohol testing and post-accident alcohol testing of civil service mariners of the Military Sealift Command who are assigned to vessels.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added § 7479a and renumbered § 8749a, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(d)(6)</ref>, title XI, § 1114(a), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>, 2013; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title XVII, § 1731(a)(60)(B)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1815</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8750.</num>
<heading> Special agents of the Naval Criminal Investigative Service: authority to execute warrants and make arrests</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the Navy may authorize any Department of the Navy civilian employee described in subsection (b) to have the same authority to execute and serve warrants and other processes issued under the authority of the United States and to make arrests without a warrant as may be authorized under <ref>section 1585a of this title</ref> for special agents of the Defense Criminal Investigative Service.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Agents To Have Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subsection (a) applies to any employee of the Department of the Navy who is a special agent of the Naval Criminal Investigative Service (or any successor to that service) whose duties include conducting, supervising, or coordinating investigations of criminal activity in programs and operations of the Department of the Navy.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Guidelines for Exercise of Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The authority provided under subsection (a) shall be exercised in accordance with guidelines prescribed by the Secretary of the Navy and approved by the Secretary of Defense and the Attorney General and any other applicable guidelines prescribed by the Secretary of the Navy, the Secretary of Defense, or the Attorney General.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title V, § 554(b)(1)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–126, § 7480; renumbered § 8750, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(d)(6)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>