<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 1403—</num>
<heading>SELECTION BOARDS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 14101.</num>
<heading> Convening of selection boards</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Promotion Boards</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Whenever the needs of the Army, Navy, Air Force, or Marine Corps require, the Secretary concerned shall convene a selection board to recommend for promotion to the next higher grade, under chapter 1405 of this title, officers on the reserve active-status list of that armed force in a permanent grade from first lieutenant through brigadier general or, in the case of the Navy Reserve, lieutenant (junior grade) through rear admiral (lower half). A selection board convened under this subsection shall be known as a “promotion board”.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A promotion board convened to recommend reserve officers of the Army or reserve officers of the Air Force for promotion (A) to fill a position vacancy under <ref>section 14315 of this title</ref>, or (B) to the grade of brigadier general or major general, shall be known as a “vacancy promotion board”. Any other promotion board convened under this subsection shall be known as a “mandatory promotion board”.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Paragraph (1) does not require the convening of a selection board in the case of officers in the permanent grade of first lieutenant or, in the case of the Navy, lieutenant (junior grade) when the Secretary concerned recommends for promotion to the next higher grade under <ref>section 14308(b)(4) of this title</ref> all such officers whom the Secretary finds to be fully qualified for promotion.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Selective Early Separation Boards</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Whenever the needs of the Army, Navy, Air Force, or Marine Corps require, the Secretary concerned may convene a selection board to recommend officers of that armed force—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> for selective early removal from the reserve active-status list under <ref>section 14704 of this title</ref>; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> for selective early retirement under <ref>section 14705 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1611</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2924</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title V, § 514(a)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1732</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title V, § 505(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1087</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title V, § 511(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1459</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title V, § 515(b)(1)(PP)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3234</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 14102.</num>
<heading> Selection boards: appointment and composition</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appointment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Members of selection boards convened under <ref>section 14101 of this title</ref> shall be appointed by the Secretary of the military department concerned in accordance with this section. Promotion boards and special selection boards shall consist of five or more officers. Selection boards convened under <ref>section 14101(b) of this title</ref> shall consist of three or more officers. All of the officers of any such selection board shall be of the same armed force as the officers under consideration by the board.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Composition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>At least one-half of the members of such a selection board shall be reserve officers, to include at least one reserve officer from each reserve component from which officers are to be considered by the board. Each member of a selection board must hold a permanent grade higher than the grade of the officers under consideration by the board, and no member of a board may hold a grade below major or lieutenant commander. The members of a selection board shall represent the diverse population of the armed force concerned to the extent practicable.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Representation of Competitive Categories</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraph (2), a selection board shall include at least one officer from each competitive category of officers to be considered by the board.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A selection board need not include an officer from a competitive category to be considered by the board if there is no officer of that competitive category on the reserve active-status list or the active-duty list in a permanent grade higher than the grade of the officers to be considered by the board and otherwise eligible to serve on the board. However, in such a case, the Secretary of the military department concerned, in his discretion, may appoint as a member of the board a retired officer of that competitive category who is in the same armed force as the officers under consideration by the board who holds a higher grade than the grade of the officers under consideration.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition of Service on Consecutive Promotion Boards</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No officer may be a member of two successive promotion boards convened under <ref>section 14101(a) of this title</ref> for the consideration of officers of the same competitive category and grade if the second of the two boards is to consider any officer who was considered and not recommended for promotion to the next higher grade by the first of the two boards.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1611</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2924</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title V, § 511(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1459</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title V, § 503(b)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3565</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 14103.</num>
<heading> Oath of members</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each member of a selection board convened under <ref>section 14101 of this title</ref> shall take an oath to perform the duties of a member of the board without prejudice or partiality, having in view both the special fitness of officers and the efficiency of the member’s armed force.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1611</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2925</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 14104.</num>
<heading> Nondisclosure of board proceedings</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition on Disclosure</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The proceedings of a selection board convened under section 14101 or 14502 of this title may not be disclosed to any person not a member of the board, except as authorized or required to process the report of the board. This prohibition is a statutory exemption from disclosure, as described in <ref>section 552(b)(3) of title 5</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibited Uses of Board Discussions, Deliberations, Notes, and Records</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The discussions and deliberations of a selection board described in subsection (a) and any written or documentary record of such discussions and deliberations—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> are immune from legal process;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> may not be admitted as evidence; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> may not be used for any purpose in any action, suit, or judicial or administrative proceeding without the consent of the Secretary of the military department concerned.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Applicability</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section applies to all selection boards convened under section 14101 or 14502 of this title, regardless of the date on which the board was convened.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1611</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2925</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title V, § 547(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2216</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title V, § 503(c)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4208</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 14105.</num>
<heading> Notice of convening of promotion board</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Required Notice</inline>.—</heading>
<content>At least 30 days before a promotion board is convened under <ref>section 14101(a) of this title</ref> to consider officers in a grade and competitive category for promotion to the next higher grade, the Secretary concerned shall either (1) notify in writing the officers eligible for consideration by the board for promotion regarding the convening of the board, or (2) issue a general written notice to the armed force concerned regarding the convening of the board.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Content of Notice</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A notice under subsection (a) shall include the date on which the board is to convene and (except in the case of a vacancy promotion board) the name and date of rank of the junior officer, and of the senior officer, in the promotion zone as of the date of the notice.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1611</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2925</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 14106.</num>
<heading> Communication with board by officers under consideration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to regulations prescribed by the Secretary of the military department concerned, an officer eligible for consideration by a promotion board convened under <ref>section 14101(a) of this title</ref> who is in the promotion zone or above the promotion zone, or who is to be considered by a vacancy promotion board, may send a written communication to the board calling attention to any matter concerning the officer which the officer considers important to the officer’s case. Any such communication shall be sent so as to arrive not later than 10 calendar days before the date on which the board convenes. The board shall give consideration to any timely communication under this section.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1611</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2925</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title V, § 505(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3227</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title V, § 501(b)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1373</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 14107.</num>
<heading> Information furnished by the Secretary concerned to promotion boards</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Integrity of the Promotion Selection Board Process</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations governing information furnished to selection boards convened under <ref>section 14101(a) of this title</ref>. Those regulations shall apply uniformly among the military departments. Any regulations prescribed by the Secretary of a military department to supplement those regulations may not take effect without the approval of the Secretary of Defense in writing.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> No information concerning a particular eligible officer may be furnished to a selection board except for the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Information that is in the officer’s official military personnel file and that is provided to the selection board in accordance with the regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense pursuant to paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Other information that is determined by the Secretary of the military department concerned, after review by that Secretary in accordance with standards and procedures set out in the regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense pursuant to paragraph (1), to be substantiated, relevant information that could reasonably and materially affect the deliberations of the promotion board.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Subject to such limitations as may be prescribed in those regulations, information communicated to the board by the officer in accordance with this section, <ref>section 14106 of this title</ref> (including any comment on information referred to in subparagraph (A) regarding that officer), or other applicable law.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> A factual summary of the information described in subparagraphs (A), (B), and (C) that, in accordance with the regulations prescribed pursuant to paragraph (1) is prepared by administrative personnel for the purpose of facilitating the work of the selection board.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> In the case of an eligible officer considered for promotion to a grade above lieutenant colonel, or, in the case of the Navy, commander, any credible information of an adverse nature, including any substantiated adverse finding or conclusion from an officially documented investigation or inquiry, shall be furnished to the selection board in accordance with standards and procedures set out in the regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense pursuant to paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The standards and procedures referred to in subparagraph (A) shall require the furnishing to the selection board, and to each individual member of the board, the information described in that subparagraph with regard to an officer in a grade specified in that subparagraph at each stage or phase of the selection board, concurrent with the screening, rating, assessment, evaluation, discussion, or other consideration by the board or member of the official military personnel file of the officer, or of the officer.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> With respect to the consideration of an officer for promotion to a grade at or below major general or, in the Navy, rear admiral, the requirements in subparagraphs (A) and (B) may be met through the convening and actions of a special selection board with respect to the officer under <ref>section 14502a of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Information provided to a promotion board in accordance with paragraphs (2) and (3) shall be made available to all members of the board and shall be made a part of the record of the board. Communication of such information shall be in a written form or in the form of an audio or video recording. If a communication is in the form of an audio or video recording, a written transcription of the recording shall also be made a part of the record of the promotion board.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Paragraphs (2), (3), and (4) do not apply to the furnishing of appropriate administrative processing information to the promotion board by an administrative staff designated to assist the board, but only to the extent that oral communications are necessary to facilitate the work of the board.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> Information furnished to a promotion board that is described in subparagraph (B), (C), or (D) of paragraph (2), or in paragraph (3), may not be furnished to a later promotion board unless—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the information has been properly placed in the official military personnel file of the officer concerned; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the information is provided to the later selection board in accordance with paragraph (2) or (3), as applicable.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(7)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> Before information described in paragraph (2)(B) or (3) regarding an eligible officer is furnished to a selection board, the Secretary of the military department concerned shall ensure—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> that such information is made available to such officer; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> that the officer is afforded a reasonable opportunity to submit comments on that information to the promotion board.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> If an officer cannot be given access to the information referred to in subparagraph (A) because of its classification status, the officer shall, to the maximum extent practicable, be furnished an appropriate summary of the information.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Information To Be Furnished</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of the military department concerned shall furnish to a promotion board convened under <ref>section 14101(a) of this title</ref> the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In the case of a mandatory promotion board, the maximum number (as determined in accordance with <ref>section 14307 of this title</ref>) of officers in each competitive category under consideration that the board is authorized to recommend for promotion to the next higher grade.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The name of each officer in each competitive category under consideration who is to be considered by the board for promotion.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The pertinent records (as determined by the Secretary) of each officer whose name is furnished to the board.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Information or guidelines relating to the needs of the armed force concerned for officers having particular skills, including (except in the case of a vacancy promotion board) guidelines or information relating to either a minimum number or a maximum number of officers with particular skills within a competitive category.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Such other information or guidelines as the Secretary concerned may determine to be necessary to enable the board to perform its functions.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Modifying Furnished Information</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Information or guidelines furnished to a selection board under subsection (a) may not be modified, withdrawn, or supplemented after the board submits its report to the Secretary of the military department concerned pursuant to <ref>section 14109(a) of this title</ref>. However, in the case of a report returned to a board pursuant to <ref>section 14110(a) of this title</ref> for further proceedings because of a determination by the Secretary of the military department concerned that the board acted contrary to law, regulation, or guidelines, the Secretary may modify, withdraw, or supplement such information or guidelines as part of a written explanation to the board as provided in that section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Officers in Health-Professions Competitive Categories</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of each military department, under uniform regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, shall include in guidelines furnished to a promotion board convened under <ref>section 14101(a) of this title</ref> that is considering officers in a health-professions competitive category for promotion to a grade below colonel or, in the case of officers of the Navy Reserve, captain, a direction that the board give consideration to an officer’s clinical proficiency and skill as a health professional to at least as great an extent as the board gives to the officer’s administrative and management skills.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1611</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2926</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title V</ref>, §§ 506(b), 515(b)(1)(QQ), <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3227</ref>, 3234; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title V, § 505(d)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3573</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 14108.</num>
<heading> Recommendations by promotion boards</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Recommendation of Best Qualified Officers</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A promotion board convened under <ref>section 14101(a) of this title</ref> shall recommend for promotion to the next higher grade those officers considered by the board whom the board considers best qualified for promotion within each competitive category considered by the board or, in the case of a vacancy promotion board, among those officers considered to fill a vacancy. In determining those officers who are best qualified for promotion, the board shall give due consideration to the needs of the armed force concerned for officers with particular skills (as noted in the guidelines or information furnished the board under <ref>section 14107 of this title</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Actions Required</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A promotion board convened under <ref>section 14101(a) of this title</ref> may not recommend an officer for promotion unless—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the officer receives the recommendation of a majority of the members of the board;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a majority of the members of the board finds that the officer is fully qualified for promotion; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a majority of the members of the board, after consideration by all members of the board of any adverse information about the officer that is provided to the board under <ref>section 14107 of this title</ref>, finds that the officer is among the officers best qualified for promotion to meet the needs of the armed force concerned consistent with the requirement of exemplary conduct set forth in section 7233, 8167, or 9233 of this title, as applicable.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Board Recommendation Required for Promotion</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as otherwise provided by law, an officer on the reserve active-status list may not be promoted to a higher grade under chapter 1405 of this title unless the officer is considered and recommended for promotion to that grade by a promotion board convened under <ref>section 14101(a) of this title</ref> (or by a special selection board convened under <ref>section 14502 of this title</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Disclosure of Board Recommendations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The recommendations of a promotion board may be disclosed only in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense. Those recommendations may not be disclosed to a person not a member of the board (or a member of the administrative staff designated by the Secretary concerned to assist the board) until the written report of the recommendations of the board, required by <ref>section 14109 of this title</ref>, is signed by each member of the board.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition of Coercion and Unauthorized Influence of Actions of Board Members</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary convening a promotion board under <ref>section 14101(a) of this title</ref>, and an officer or other official exercising authority over any member of a selection board, may not—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> censure, reprimand, or admonish the selection board or any member of the board with respect to the recommendations of the board or the exercise of any lawful function within the authorized discretion of the board; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> attempt to coerce or, by any unauthorized means, influence any action of a promotion board or any member of a promotion board in the formulation of the board’s recommendations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Higher Placement of Officers of Particular Merit on Promotion List</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In selecting officers to be recommended for promotion, a promotion board may, when authorized by the Secretary concerned, recommend that officers of particular merit, from among those officers selected for promotion, be placed higher on the promotion list established by the Secretary under <ref>section 14308(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> A promotion board may make a recommendation under paragraph (1) only if an officer receives the recommendation of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a majority of the members of the promotion board; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an alternative requirement established by the Secretary concerned and furnished to the promotion board as part of the guidelines under <ref>section 14107 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> For officers who receive recommendations under paragraph (1), the board shall recommend the order in which those officers should be placed on the promotion list.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1611</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2928</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title V, § 512(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2184</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 809(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1840</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title V, § 510(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1347</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 14109.</num>
<heading> Reports of promotion boards: in general</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report of Officers Recommended for Promotion</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each promotion board convened under <ref>section 14101(a) of this title</ref> shall submit to the Secretary of the military department concerned a report in writing containing a list of the names of the officers recommended by the board for promotion. The report shall be signed by each member of the board.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Certification</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each report under subsection (a) shall include a certification—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> that the board has carefully considered the record of each officer whose name was furnished to the board; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> that, in the case of a promotion board convened under <ref>section 14101(a) of this title</ref>, in the opinion of a majority of the members of the board, the officers recommended for promotion by the board are best qualified for promotion to meet the needs of the armed force concerned (as noted in the guidelines or information furnished the board under <ref>section 14107 of this title</ref>) among those officers whose names were furnished to the selection board.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Show-Cause Recommendations</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A promotion board convened under <ref>section 14101(a) of this title</ref> shall include in its report to the Secretary concerned the name of any reserve officer before it for consideration for promotion whose record, in the opinion of a majority of the members of the board, indicates that the officer should be required to show cause for retention in an active status.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If such a report names an officer as having a record which indicates that the officer should be required to show cause for retention, the Secretary concerned may provide for the review of the record of that officer as provided under regulations prescribed under <ref>section 14902 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report of Officers Recommended for Higher Placement on Promotion List</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A promotion board convened under <ref>section 14101(a) of this title</ref> shall, when authorized under <ref>section 14108(f) of this title</ref>, include in its report to the Secretary concerned—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the names of those officers the promotion board recommends be placed higher on the promotion list; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the order in which the promotion board recommends those officers should be placed on the promotion list.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1611</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2928</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title V, § 510(b)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1347</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 14110.</num>
<heading> Reports of promotion boards: review by Secretary</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Review of Report</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Upon receipt of the report of a promotion board submitted under <ref>section 14109(a) of this title</ref>, the Secretary of the military department concerned shall review the report to determine whether the board has acted contrary to law or regulation or to guidelines furnished the board under <ref>section 14107(a) of this title</ref>. Following that review, unless the Secretary concerned makes a determination as described in subsection (b), the Secretary shall submit the report as required by <ref>section 14111 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Return of Report for Further Proceedings</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If, on the basis of a review of the report under subsection (a), the Secretary of the military department concerned determines that the board acted contrary to law or regulation or to guidelines furnished the board under <ref>section 14107(a) of this title</ref>, the Secretary shall return the report, together with a written explanation of the basis for such determination, to the board for further proceedings. Upon receipt of a report returned by the Secretary concerned under this subsection, the selection board (or a subsequent selection board convened under <ref>section 14101(a) of this title</ref> for the same grade and competitive category) shall conduct such proceedings as may be necessary in order to revise the report to be consistent with law, regulation, and such guidelines and shall resubmit the report, as revised, to the Secretary in accordance with <ref>section 14109 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1611</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2929</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 14111.</num>
<heading> Reports of selection boards: transmittal to President</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transmittal to President</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary concerned, after final review of the report of a selection board under <ref>section 14110 of this title</ref>, shall submit the report with the Secretary’s recommendations, to the Secretary of Defense for transmittal by the Secretary to the President for approval or disapproval. If the authority of the President to approve or disapprove the report of a promotion board is delegated to the Secretary of Defense, that authority may not be redelegated except to an official in the Office of the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Removal of Name From Board Report</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraph (2), the name of an officer recommended for promotion by a selection board may be removed from the report of the selection board only by the President.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In the case of an officer recommended by a selection board for promotion to a grade below brigadier general or rear admiral (lower half), the name of the officer may also be removed from the report of the selection board by the Secretary of Defense or the Deputy Secretary of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Recommendations for Removal of Selected Officers From Report</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the Secretary of a military department or the Secretary of Defense makes a recommendation under this section that the name of an officer be removed from the report of a promotion board and the recommendation is accompanied by information that was not presented to that promotion board, that information shall be made available to that officer. The officer shall then be afforded a reasonable opportunity to submit comments on that information to the officials making the recommendation and the officials reviewing the recommendation. If an eligible officer cannot be given access to such information because of its classification status, the officer shall, to the maximum extent practicable, be provided with an appropriate summary of the information.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1611</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2929</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title V, § 513(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2185</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 14112.</num>
<heading> Dissemination of names of officers selected</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Time for Dissemination</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The names of the officers recommended for promotion in the report of a selection board shall be disseminated to the armed force concerned as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In the case of officers recommended for promotion to a grade below brigadier general or rear admiral (lower half), such names may be disseminated upon, or at any time after, the transmittal of the report to the President.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In the case of officers recommended for promotion to a grade above colonel or, in the case of the Navy, captain, such names may be disseminated upon, or at any time after, the approval of the report by the President.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> In the case of officers whose names have not been sooner disseminated, such names shall be promptly disseminated—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> upon confirmation of the promotion of the officers by the Senate (in the case of promotions required to be submitted to the Senate for confirmation); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> upon the approval of the report by the President (in the case of promotions not required to be submitted to the Senate for confirmation).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Names Not Disseminated</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A list of names of officers disseminated under subsection (a) may not include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any name removed by the President from the report of the selection board containing that name, if dissemination is under the authority of paragraph (2) or (3)(B) of that subsection; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the name of any officer whose promotion the Senate failed to confirm, if dissemination is under the authority of paragraph (3)(A) of that subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1611</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2930</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title V, § 503(b)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–101.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>