<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 1217—</num>
<heading>MISCELLANEOUS RIGHTS AND BENEFITS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 12601.</num>
<heading> Compensation: Reserve on active duty accepting from any person</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any Reserve who, before being ordered to active duty, was receiving compensation from any person may, while he is on that duty, receive compensation from that person.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1662(g)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2995</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12602.</num>
<heading> Members of Army National Guard of United States and Air National Guard of United States: credit for service as members of National Guard</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> For the purposes of laws providing benefits for members of the Army National Guard of the United States and their dependents and beneficiaries—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> military training, duty, or other service performed by a member of the Army National Guard of the United States in his status as a member of the Army National Guard for which he is entitled to pay from the United States shall be considered military training, duty, or other service, as the case may be, in Federal service as a Reserve of the Army;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> full-time National Guard duty performed by a member of the Army National Guard of the United States shall be considered active duty in Federal service as a Reserve of the Army; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> inactive-duty training performed by a member of the Army National Guard of the United States in his status as a member of the Army National Guard, in accordance with regulations prescribed under <ref>section 502 of title 32</ref> or other express provision of law, shall be considered inactive-duty training in Federal service as a Reserve of the Army.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> For the purposes of laws providing benefits for members of the Air National Guard of the United States and their dependents and beneficiaries—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> military training, duty, or other service performed by a member of the Air National Guard of the United States in his status as a member of the Air National Guard for which he is entitled to pay from the United States shall be considered military training, duty, or other service, as the case may be, in Federal service as a Reserve of the Air Force;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> full-time National Guard duty performed by a member of the Air National Guard of the United States shall be considered active duty in Federal service as a Reserve of the Air Force; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> inactive-duty training performed by a member of the Air National Guard of the United States in his status as a member of the Air National Guard, in accordance with regulations prescribed under <ref>section 502 of title 32</ref> or other express provision of law, shall be considered inactive-duty training in Federal service as a Reserve of the Air Force.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1662(g)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2995</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12603.</num>
<heading> Attendance at inactive-duty training assemblies: commercial travel at Federal supply schedule rates</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Federal Supply Schedule Travel</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Commercial travel under Federal supply schedules is authorized for the travel of a Reserve to the location of inactive duty training to be performed by the Reserve and from that location upon completion of the training.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe in regulations such requirements, conditions, and restrictions for travel under the authority of subsection (a) as the Secretary considers appropriate. The regulations shall include policies and procedures for preventing abuses of that travel authority.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reimbursement Not Authorized</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A Reserve is not entitled to Government reimbursement for the cost of travel authorized under subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Treatment of Transportation as Use by Military Departments</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For the purposes of <ref>section 501 of title 40</ref>, travel authorized under subsection (a) shall be treated as transportation for the use of a military department.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title VI, § 635(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2044</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–217, § 3(b)(41)</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1298</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12604.</num>
<heading> Billeting in Department of Defense facilities: Reserves attending inactive-duty training</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority for Billeting on Same Basis as Active Duty Members Traveling Under Orders</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations authorizing a Reserve traveling to inactive-duty training at a location more than 50 miles from that Reserve’s residence to be eligible for billeting in Department of Defense facilities on the same basis and to the same extent as a member of the armed forces on active duty who is traveling under orders away from the member’s permanent duty station.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Proof of Reason for Travel</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall include in the regulations the means for confirming a Reserve’s eligibility for billeting under subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Lodging in Kind</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In the case of a member of a reserve component performing active duty for training or inactive-duty training who is not otherwise entitled to travel and transportation allowances in connection with such duty, the Secretary concerned may reimburse the member for housing service charge expenses incurred by the member in occupying transient government housing during the performance of such duty. If transient government housing is unavailable or inadequate, the Secretary concerned may provide the member with lodging in kind.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any payment or other benefit under this subsection shall be provided in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary concerned.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary may pay service charge expenses under paragraph (1) and expenses of providing lodging in kind under such paragraph out of funds appropriated for operation and maintenance for the reserve component concerned. Use of a Government charge card is authorized for payment of these expenses.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Decisions regarding the availability or adequacy of government housing at a military installation under paragraph (1) shall be made by the installation commander.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title VI, § 663(a)(1)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–168; amended <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title VI, § 603(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1765</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12605.</num>
<heading> Presentation of United States flag: members transferred from an active status or discharged after completion of eligibility for retired pay</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Presentation of Flag</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Upon the transfer from an active status or discharge of a Reserve who has completed the years of service required for eligibility for retired pay under chapter 1223 of this title, the Secretary concerned shall present a United States flag to the member.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Multiple Presentations Not Authorized</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A member is not eligible for presentation of a flag under subsection (a) if the member has previously been presented a flag under this section or any provision of law providing for the presentation of a United States flag incident to release from active service for retirement.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">No Cost to Recipient</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The presentation of a flag under this section shall be at no cost to the recipient.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title VI, § 652(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 664</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>