<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 80—</num>
<heading>MISCELLANEOUS INVESTIGATION REQUIREMENTS AND OTHER DUTIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1561.</num>
<heading> Complaints of sexual harassment: independent investigation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Action on Complaints Alleging Sexual Harassment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A commanding officer or officer in charge of a unit, vessel, facility, or area of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, or Space Force who receives from a member of the command or a civilian employee under the supervision of the officer a formal complaint alleging a claim of sexual harassment by a member of the armed forces or a civilian employee of the Department of Defense shall, to the extent practicable, direct that an independent investigation of the matter be carried out in accordance with this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Commencement of Investigation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>To the extent practicable, a commanding officer or officer in charge receiving such a formal complaint shall forward such complaint to an independent investigator within 72 hours after receipt of the complaint, and shall further—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> forward the formal complaint or a detailed description of the allegation to the next superior officer in the chain of command who is authorized to convene a general court-martial; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> advise the complainant of the commencement of the investigation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duration of Investigation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>To the extent practicable, a commanding officer or officer in charge shall ensure that an independent investigator receiving a formal complaint of sexual harassment under this section completes the investigation of the complaint not later than 14 days after the date on which the investigation is commenced, and that the findings of the investigation are forwarded to the commanding officer or officer in charge specified in subsection (a) for action as appropriate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report on Investigation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>To the extent practicable, a commanding officer or officer in charge shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> submit a final report on the results of the independent investigation, including any action taken as a result of the investigation, to the next superior officer referred to in subsection (b)(1) within 20 days after the date on which the investigation is commenced; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> submit a report on the progress made in completing the investigation to the next superior officer referred to in subsection (b)(1) within 20 days after the date on which the investigation is commenced and every 14 days thereafter until the investigation is completed and, upon completion of the investigation, then submit a final report on the results of the investigation, including any action taken as a result of the investigation, to that next superior officer.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The term “independent investigator” means a civilian employee of the Department of Defense or a member of the Army, Navy, Marine Corps, Air Force, or Space Force who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is outside the immediate chain of command of the complainant and the subject of the investigation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> is trained in the investigation of sexual harassment, as determined by—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Defense, in the case of a civilian employee of the Department of Defense;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the Secretary of the Army, in the case of a member of the Army;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the Secretary of the Navy, in the case of a member of the Navy or Marine Corps; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the Secretary of the Air Force, in the case of a member of the Air Force or Space Force.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “sexual harassment” means conduct that constitutes the offense of sexual harassment as punishable under <ref>section 934 of this title</ref> (article 134) pursuant to the regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense for purposes of such section (article).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title V, § 591(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1760</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title V, § 548(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2129</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 924(b)(3)(Z)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3821</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title V, § 543(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1709</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title V, § 546(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2584</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1561a.</num>
<heading> Civilian orders of protection: force and effect on military installations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Force and Effect</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A civilian order of protection shall have the same force and effect on a military installation as such order has within the jurisdiction of the court that issued such order.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Civilian Order of Protection Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “civilian order of protection” has the meaning given the term “protection order” in <ref>section 2266(5) of title 18</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations to carry out this section. The regulations shall be designed to further good order and discipline by members of the armed forces and civilians present on military installations.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 107–311, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2455</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1561b.</num>
<heading> Confidential reporting of sexual harassment</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reporting Process</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding <ref>section 1561 of this title</ref>, the Secretary of Defense shall prescribe in regulations a process by which a member of an armed force under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of a military department may confidentially allege a complaint of sexual harassment to an individual outside the immediate chain of command of the member.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Receipt of Complaints</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An individual designated and trained to receive complaints under the process under subsection (a) shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> maintain the confidentiality of the member alleging the complaint;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> explain to the member alleging the complaint the different avenues of redress available to resolve the complaint and the different consequences of each avenue on the manner in which the complaint will be investigated (if at all), including an explanation of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The manner in which to file a complaint concerning alleged sexual harassment with the official or office designated for receipt of such complaint through such avenue of redress.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> That confidentiality in connection with the complaint cannot be maintained when there is a clear and present risk to health or safety.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> If the alleged sexual harassment also involves an allegation of sexual assault, including sexual contact—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the manner in which to file a confidential report with a Sexual Assault Response Coordinator or a Sexual Assault Prevention and Response Victim Advocate; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> options available pursuant to such reporting, including a Restricted Report or Unrestricted Report, and participation in the Catch a Serial Offender Program.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The services and assistance available to the member in connection with the complaint and the alleged sexual harassment.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Education and Tracking</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> educate members under the jurisdiction of the Secretaries of the military departments regarding the process established under this section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> track complaints alleged pursuant to the process.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reports</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than <date date="2023-04-30">April 30, 2023</date>, and April 30 every two years thereafter, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives a report containing data on the complaints of sexual harassment alleged pursuant to the process under subsection (a) during the previous two calendar years. Any data on such complaints shall not contain any personally identifiable information.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title V, § 532(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3601</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1562.</num>
<heading> Database on domestic violence incidents</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Database on Domestic Violence Incident</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall establish a central database of information on the incidents of domestic violence involving members of the armed forces.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reporting of Information for the Database</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall require that the Secretaries of the military departments maintain and report annually to the administrator of the database established under subsection (a) any information received on the following matters:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Each domestic violence incident reported to a commander, a law enforcement authority of the armed forces, or a family advocacy program of the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The number of those incidents that involve evidence determined sufficient for supporting disciplinary action and, for each such incident, a description of the substantiated allegation and the action taken by command authorities in the incident.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The number of those incidents that involve evidence determined insufficient for supporting disciplinary action and for each such case, a description of the allegation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title V, § 594(a)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 643</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1562a.</num>
<heading> Complaints of retaliation by victims of sexual assault or sexual harassment and related persons: tracking by Department of Defense</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designation of Responsible Component</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall designate a component of the Office of the Secretary of Defense to be responsible for documenting and tracking all covered allegations of retaliation and shall ensure that the Secretaries concerned and the Inspector General of the Department of Defense provide to such component the information required to be documented and tracked as described in subsection (b).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Tracking of Allegations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The head of the component designated by the Secretary under subsection (a) shall document and track each covered allegation of retaliation, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> that such an allegation has been reported and by whom;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the date of the report;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the nature of the allegation and the name of the person or persons alleged to have engaged in such retaliation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the Department of Defense component or other entity responsible for the investigation of or inquiry into the allegation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the entry of findings;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> referral of such findings to a decisionmaker for review and action, as appropriate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the outcome of final action; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> any other element of information pertaining to the allegation determined appropriate by the Secretary or the head of the component designated by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered Allegation of Retaliation Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the term “covered allegation of retaliation” means an allegation of retaliation—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> made by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an alleged victim of sexual assault or sexual harassment;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an individual charged with providing services or support to an alleged victim of sexual assault or sexual harassment;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a witness or bystander to an alleged sexual assault or sexual harassment; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> any other person associated with an alleged victim of a sexual assault or sexual harassment; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> without regard to whether the allegation is reported to or investigated or inquired into by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Department of Defense Inspector General or any other inspector general;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a military criminal investigative organization;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a commander or other person at the direction of the commander;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> another military or civilian law enforcement organization; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> any other organization, officer, or employee of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title V, § 544(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1710</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1563.</num>
<heading> Consideration of proposals from Members of Congress for honorary promotions: procedures for review and promotion</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Review by Secretary Concerned</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Upon request of a Member of Congress, the Secretary concerned shall review a proposal for the honorary promotion (whether or not posthumous) of a former member or retired member of the armed forces that is not otherwise authorized by law. Based upon such review, the Secretary shall make a determination as to the merits of approving the promotion.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice of Results of Review</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Upon making a determination under subsection (a) as to the merits of approving the honorary promotion, the Secretary concerned shall submit to the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives and to the requesting Member of Congress a detailed discussion of the rationale supporting the determination.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority To Make</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Defense may make an honorary promotion (whether or not posthumous) of a former member or retired member of the armed forces to any grade not exceeding the grade of major general or rear admiral (upper half) following the submittal of the determination of the Secretary concerned under subsection (b) in connection with the proposal for the promotion if the determination is to approve the making of the promotion.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may not make an honorary promotion under this subsection until 60 days after the date on which the Secretary concerned submits the determination in connection with the proposal for the promotion under subsection (b), and the detailed rationale supporting the determination as described in that subsection, to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives and the requesting Member in accordance with that subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The authority to make an honorary promotion under this subsection shall apply notwithstanding that the promotion is not otherwise authorized by law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Any promotion pursuant to this subsection is honorary, and shall not affect the pay, retired pay, or other benefits from the United States to which the former member or retired member concerned is or would have been entitled based upon the military service of such former member or retired member, nor affect any benefits to which any other person may become entitled based on the military service of such former member or retired member.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the term “Member of Congress” means—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a Senator; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a Representative in, or a Delegate or Resident Commissioner to, Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title V, § 542(a)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–114; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title X, § 1031(a)(11)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1597</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title V, § 523(b)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3598</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XVII, § 1741(a)(6)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 680</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1563a.</num>
<heading> Honorary promotions on the initiative of the Department of Defense</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary may make an honorary promotion (whether or not posthumous) of a former member or retired member of the armed forces to any grade not exceeding the grade of major general or rear admiral (upper half) if the Secretary determines that the promotion is merited.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The authority to make an honorary promotion under this subsection shall apply notwithstanding that the promotion is not otherwise authorized by law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice to Congress</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may not make an honorary promotion pursuant to subsection (a) until 60 days after the date on which the Secretary submits to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives a notice of the determination to make the promotion, including a detailed discussion of the rationale supporting the determination.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice of Promotion</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Upon making an honorary promotion pursuant to subsection (a), the Secretary shall expeditiously notify the former member or retired member concerned, or the next of kin of such former member or retired member if such former member or retired member is deceased, of the promotion.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Nature of Promotion</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any promotion pursuant to this section is honorary, and shall not affect the pay, retired pay, or other benefits from the United States to which the former member or retired member concerned is entitled or would have been entitled based on the military service of such former member or retired member, nor affect any benefits to which any other person is or may become entitled based on the military service of such former member or retired member.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title V, § 523(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3597</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XVII, § 1741(a)(6)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 680</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1564.</num>
<heading> Security clearance investigations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Expedited Process</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense may prescribe a process for expediting the completion of the background investigations necessary for granting security clearances for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Department of Defense personnel and Department of Defense contractor personnel who are engaged in sensitive duties that are critical to the national security; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> any individual who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> submits an application for a position as an employee of the Department of Defense for which—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the individual is qualified; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a security clearance is required; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> is—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a member of the armed forces who was retired or separated, or is expected to be retired or separated, for physical disability pursuant to chapter 61 of this title;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the spouse of a member of the armed forces who retires or is separated, after <date date="2011-01-07">January 7, 2011</date>, for a physical disability as a result of a wound, injuries or illness incurred or aggravated in the line of duty (as determined by the Secretary concerned); or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the spouse of a member of the armed forces who dies, after <date date="2011-01-07">January 7, 2011</date>, as a result of a wound, injury, or illness incurred or aggravated in the line of duty (as determined by the Secretary concerned).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Required Features</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The process developed under subsection (a) shall provide for the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Quantification of the requirements for background investigations necessary for grants of security clearances for Department of Defense personnel and Department of Defense contractor personnel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Categorization of personnel on the basis of the degree of sensitivity of their duties and the extent to which those duties are critical to the national security.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Prioritization of the processing of background investigations on the basis of the categories of personnel determined under paragraph (2).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reinvestigation or Readjudication of Certain Individuals</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Defense shall conduct an investigation or adjudication under subsection (a) of any individual described in paragraph (2) upon—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> conviction of that individual by a court of competent jurisdiction for—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> sexual assault;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> sexual harassment;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> fraud against the United States; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> any other violation that the Secretary determines renders that individual susceptible to blackmail or raises serious concern regarding the ability of that individual to hold a security clearance; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> determination by a commanding officer that that individual has committed an offense described in subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> An individual described in this paragraph is an individual who has a security clearance and is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a flag officer;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a general officer; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> an employee of the Department of Defense in the Senior Executive Service.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall ensure that relevant information on the conviction or determination described in paragraph (1) of an individual described in paragraph (2) during the preceding year, regardless of whether the individual has retired or resigned or has been discharged, released, or otherwise separated from the armed forces, is reported into Federal law enforcement records and security clearance databases, and that such information is transmitted, as appropriate, to other Federal agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> In this subsection:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The term “sexual assault” includes rape, sexual assault, forcible sodomy, aggravated sexual contact, abusive sexual contact, and attempts to commit such offenses, as those terms are defined in chapter 47 of this title (the Uniform Code of Military Justice).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The term “sexual harassment” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 1561 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The term “fraud against the United States” means a violation of <ref>section 932 of this title</ref> (article 132 of the Uniform Code of Military Justice).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Review</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall conduct an annual review of the process prescribed under subsection (a) and shall revise that process as determined necessary in relation to ongoing Department of Defense missions.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consultation Requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall consult with the Secretaries of the military departments and the heads of Defense Agencies in carrying out this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Sensitive Duties</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For the purposes of this section, it is not necessary for the performance of duties to involve classified activities or classified matters in order for the duties to be considered sensitive and critical to the national security.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of Appropriated Funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may use funds authorized to be appropriated to the Department of Defense for operation and maintenance to conduct background investigations under this section for individuals described in subsection (a)(2).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title X, § 1072(a)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–276; amended <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title III, § 351(a)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4192</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title X, § 1076(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1951</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title V, § 542</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1762</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title X, § 1081(a)(29)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3872</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1564a.</num>
<heading> Counterintelligence polygraph program</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority for Program</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may carry out a program for the administration of counterintelligence polygraph examinations to persons described in subsection (b). The program shall be conducted in accordance with the standards specified in subsection (e).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Persons Covered</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Except as provided in subsection (d), the following persons are subject to this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> With respect to persons whose duties are described in subsection (c)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> military and civilian personnel of the Department of Defense;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> personnel of defense contractors;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> persons assigned or detailed to the Department of Defense; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> applicants for a position in the Department of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> A person who is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a national of the United States (as such term is defined in section 101 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<ref>8 U.S.C. 1101</ref>)) and also a national of a foreign state; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> either—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a civilian employee or contractor who requires access to classified information; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a member of the armed forces who requires access to classified information.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered Types of Duties</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense may provide, under standards established by the Secretary, that a person described in subsection (b)(1) is subject to this section if that person’s duties involve—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> access to information that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> has been classified at the level of top secret; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is designated as being within a special access program under section 4.4(a) of Executive Order No. 12958 (or a successor Executive order); or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> assistance in an intelligence or military mission in a case in which the unauthorized disclosure or manipulation of information, as determined under standards established by the Secretary of Defense, could reasonably be expected to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> jeopardize human life or safety;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> result in the loss of unique or uniquely productive intelligence sources or methods vital to United States security; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> compromise technologies, operational plans, or security procedures vital to the strategic advantage of the United States and its allies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exceptions From Coverage for Certain Intelligence Agencies and Functions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>This section does not apply to the following persons:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A person assigned or detailed to the Central Intelligence Agency or to an expert or consultant under a contract with the Central Intelligence Agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> A person who is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> employed by or assigned or detailed to the National Security Agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an expert or consultant under contract to the National Security Agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> an employee of a contractor of the National Security Agency; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a person applying for a position in the National Security Agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A person assigned to a space where sensitive cryptographic information is produced, processed, or stored.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> A person employed by, or assigned or detailed to, an office within the Department of Defense for the collection of specialized national foreign intelligence through reconnaissance programs or a contractor of such an office.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Standards</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Polygraph examinations conducted under this section shall comply with all applicable laws and regulations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Such examinations may be authorized for any of the following purposes:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> To assist in determining the initial eligibility for duties described in subsection (c) of, and aperiodically thereafter, on a random basis, to assist in determining the continued eligibility of, persons described in subsections (b)(1) and (c).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> With the consent of, or upon the request of, the examinee, to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> resolve serious credible derogatory information developed in connection with a personnel security investigation; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> exculpate him- or herself of allegations or evidence arising in the course of a counterintelligence or personnel security investigation.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> To assist, in a limited number of cases when operational exigencies require the immediate use of a person’s services before the completion of a personnel security investigation, in determining the interim eligibility for duties described in subsection (c) of the person.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> With respect to persons described in subsection (b)(2), to assist in assessing any counterintelligence threats identified in an authorized investigation of foreign preference or foreign influence risks, as described in part 147 of title 32, Code of Federal Regulations, or such successor regulations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> Polygraph examinations conducted under this section shall provide adequate safeguards, prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, for the protection of the rights and privacy of persons subject to this section under subsection (b) who are considered for or administered polygraph examinations under this section. Such safeguards shall include the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The examinee shall receive timely notification of the examination and its intended purpose and may only be given the examination with the consent of the examinee.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The examinee shall be advised of the examinee’s right to consult with legal counsel.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> All questions asked concerning the matter at issue, other than technical questions necessary to the polygraph technique, must have a relevance to the subject of the inquiry.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Oversight</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall establish a process to monitor responsible and effective application of polygraph examinations within the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall make information on the use of polygraphs within the Department of Defense available to the congressional defense committees.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Polygraph Research Program</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall carry out a continuing research program to support the polygraph examination activities of the Department of Defense. The program shall include the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> An on-going evaluation of the validity of polygraph techniques used by the Department.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Research on polygraph countermeasures and anti-countermeasures.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Developmental research on polygraph techniques, instrumentation, and analytic methods.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title X, § 1041(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1607</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title X, § 1054(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3436</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title XVI, § 1623(a)</ref>–(c), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2119</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1564b.</num>
<heading> Security vetting for foreign nationals</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Standards and Process</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the Security Executive Agent established pursuant to Executive Order 13467 (73 Fed. Reg. 38103; <ref>50 U.S.C. 3161</ref> note), shall develop uniform and consistent standards and a centralized process for the screening and vetting of covered foreign individuals requiring access to systems, facilities, personnel, information, or operations, of the Department of Defense, including with respect to the background investigations of covered foreign individuals requiring access to classified information.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall ensure that the standards developed under paragraph (1) are consistent with relevant directives of the Security Executive Agent.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall designate an official of the Department of Defense to be responsible for executing the centralized process developed under paragraph (1) and adjudicating any information discovered pursuant to such process.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Other Uses</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In addition to using the centralized process developed under subsection (a)(1) for covered foreign individuals, the Secretary may use the centralized process in determining whether to grant a security clearance to any individual with significant foreign influence or foreign preference issues, in accordance with the adjudicative guidelines under part 147 of title 32, Code of Federal Regulations, or such successor regulation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered Foreign Individual Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the term “covered foreign individual” means an individual who meets the following criteria:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The individual is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a national of a foreign state;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a national of the United States (as such term is defined in section 101 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<ref>8 U.S.C. 1101</ref>)) and also a national of a foreign state; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> an alien who is lawfully admitted for permanent residence (as such term is defined in section 101 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<ref>8 U.S.C. 1101</ref>)).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The individual is either—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a civilian employee of the Department of Defense or a contractor of the Department; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a member of the armed forces.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title XVI, § 1622(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2117</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1565.</num>
<heading> DNA identification information: collection from certain offenders; use</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Collection of DNA Samples</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned shall collect a DNA sample from each member of the armed forces under the Secretary’s jurisdiction who is, or has been, convicted of a qualifying military offense (as determined under subsection (d)).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> For each member described in paragraph (1), if the Combined DNA Index System (in this section referred to as “CODIS”) of the Federal Bureau of Investigation contains a DNA analysis with respect to that member, or if a DNA sample has been or is to be collected from that member under section 3(a) of the DNA Analysis Backlog Elimination Act of 2000, the Secretary concerned may (but need not) collect a DNA sample from that member.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned may enter into agreements with other Federal agencies, units of State or local government, or private entities to provide for the collection of samples described in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Analysis and Use of Samples</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary concerned shall furnish each DNA sample collected under subsection (a) to the Secretary of Defense. The Secretary of Defense shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> carry out a DNA analysis on each such DNA sample in a manner that complies with the requirements for inclusion of that analysis in CODIS; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> furnish the results of each such analysis to the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation for inclusion in CODIS.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “DNA sample” means a tissue, fluid, or other bodily sample of an individual on which a DNA analysis can be carried out.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “DNA analysis” means analysis of the deoxyribonucleic acid (DNA) identification information in a bodily sample.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Qualifying Military Offenses</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The offenses that shall be treated for purposes of this section as qualifying military offenses are the following offenses, as determined by the Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Attorney General:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Any offense under the Uniform Code of Military Justice for which a sentence of confinement for more than one year may be imposed.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any other offense under the Uniform Code of Military Justice that is comparable to a qualifying Federal offense (as determined under section 3(d) of the DNA Analysis Backlog Elimination Act of 2000 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 14135a(d)</ref>)).<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002074">1</ref></content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Expungement</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall promptly expunge, from the index described in subsection (a) of section 210304 of the Violent Crime Control and Law Enforcement Act of 1994, the DNA analysis of a person included in the index on the basis of a qualifying military offense if the Secretary receives, for each conviction of the person of a qualifying offense, a certified copy of a final court order establishing that such conviction has been overturned.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of paragraph (1), the term “qualifying offense” means any of the following offenses:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A qualifying Federal offense, as determined under section 3 of the DNA Analysis Backlog Elimination Act of 2000.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A qualifying District of Columbia offense, as determined under section 4 of the DNA Analysis Backlog Elimination Act of 2000.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> A qualifying military offense.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> For purposes of paragraph (1), a court order is not “final” if time remains for an appeal or application for discretionary review with respect to the order.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section shall be carried out under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Secretary of Homeland Security and the Attorney General. Those regulations shall apply, to the extent practicable, uniformly throughout the armed forces.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–546, § 5(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2000-12-19">Dec. 19, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2731</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–296, title XVII, § 1704(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2314</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–405, title II, § 203(c)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-30">Oct. 30, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2270</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1565a.</num>
<heading> DNA samples maintained for identification of human remains: use for law enforcement purposes</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Compliance with Court Order</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Subject to paragraph (2), if a valid order of a Federal court (or military judge) so requires, an element of the Department of Defense that maintains a repository of DNA samples for the purpose of identification of human remains shall make available, for the purpose specified in subsection (b), such DNA samples on such terms and conditions as such court (or military judge) directs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A DNA sample with respect to an individual shall be provided under paragraph (1) in a manner that does not compromise the ability of the Department of Defense to maintain a sample with respect to that individual for the purpose of identification of human remains.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered Purpose</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The purpose referred to in subsection (a) is the purpose of an investigation or prosecution of a felony, or any sexual offense, for which no other source of DNA information is reasonably available.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “DNA sample” has the meaning given such term in <ref>section 1565(c) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title X, § 1063(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2653</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1565b.</num>
<heading> Victims of sexual assault: access to legal assistance and services of Sexual Assault Response Coordinators and Sexual Assault Victim Advocates</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Availability of Legal Assistance and Victim Advocate Services</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> A member of the armed forces, or a dependent of a member, who is the victim of a sexual assault may be provided the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Legal assistance provided by military or civilian legal assistance counsel pursuant to sections 1044 and 1044e of this title.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Assistance provided by a Sexual Assault Response Coordinator.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Assistance provided by a Sexual Assault Victim Advocate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A member of the armed forces or dependent who is the victim of sexual assault shall be informed of the availability of assistance under paragraph (1) as soon as the member or dependent seeks assistance from a Sexual Assault Response Coordinator, a Sexual Assault Victim Advocate, a military criminal investigator, a victim/witness liaison, or a trial counsel. The member or dependent shall also be informed that the legal assistance and the services of a Sexual Assault Response Coordinator or a Sexual Assault Victim Advocate under paragraph (1) are optional and may be declined, in whole or in part, at any time.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Subject to such exceptions for exigent circumstances as the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of the Department in which the Coast Guard is operating may prescribe, notice of the availability of a Special Victims’ Counsel under <ref>section 1044e of this title</ref> shall be provided to a member of the armed forces or dependent who is the victim of sexual assault before any military criminal investigator or trial counsel interviews, or requests any statement from, the member or dependent regarding the alleged sexual assault.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Legal assistance and the services of Sexual Assault Response Coordinators and Sexual Assault Victim Advocates under paragraph (1) shall be available to a member or dependent regardless of whether the member or dependent elects unrestricted or restricted (confidential) reporting of the sexual assault.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Restricted Reporting</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, a member of the armed forces, or an adult dependent of a member, who is the victim of a sexual assault may elect to confidentially disclose the details of the assault to an individual specified in paragraph (2) and receive medical treatment, legal assistance under <ref>section 1044 of this title</ref>, or counseling, without initiating an official investigation of the allegations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The individuals specified in this paragraph are the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A Sexual Assault Response Coordinator.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A Sexual Assault Victim Advocate.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Healthcare personnel specifically identified in the regulations required by paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> In the case of information disclosed pursuant to paragraph (1), any State law or regulation that would require an individual specified in paragraph (2) to disclose the personally identifiable information of the adult victim or alleged perpetrator of the sexual assault to a State or local law enforcement agency shall not apply, except when reporting is necessary to prevent or mitigate a serious and imminent threat to the health or safety of an individual.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Sexual assault</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “sexual assault” includes the offenses of rape, sexual assault, forcible sodomy, aggravated sexual contact, abusive sexual contact, and attempts to commit such offenses, as punishable under applicable Federal or State law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">State</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “State” includes the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, and any territory or possession of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title V, § 581(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1431</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title XVII, § 1716(a)(3)(C)</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 969</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title V</ref>, §§ 534(b), 536, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 816</ref>, 817.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1566.</num>
<heading> Voting assistance: compliance assessments; assistance</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations to require that the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, and Space Force ensure their compliance with any directives issued by the Secretary of Defense in implementing any voting assistance program.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Voting Assistance Programs Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the term “voting assistance programs” means—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Federal Voting Assistance Program carried out under the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 1973ff</ref> et seq.); <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002075">1</ref> and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any similar program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Effectiveness and Compliance Reviews</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Inspector General of each of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, and Space Force shall conduct—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an annual review of the effectiveness of voting assistance programs; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an annual review of the compliance with voting assistance programs of that armed force.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Upon the completion of each annual review under paragraph (1), each Inspector General specified in that paragraph shall submit to the Inspector General of the Department of Defense a report on the results of each such review. Such report shall be submitted in time each year to be reflected in the report of the Inspector General of the Department of Defense under paragraph (3).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> Not later than March 31 each year, the Inspector General of the Department of Defense shall submit to Congress a report on—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the effectiveness during the preceding calendar year of voting assistance programs; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the level of compliance during the preceding calendar year with voting assistance programs of each of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, and Space Force.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>[(d)</num>
<content> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title V, § 596(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2235</ref>.]</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regular Military Department Assessments</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of each military department shall include in the set of issues and programs to be reviewed during any management effectiveness review or inspection at the installation level an assessment of compliance with the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 1973ff</ref> et seq.) <sup>1</sup> and with Department of Defense regulations regarding the Federal Voting Assistance Program.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Voting Assistance Officers</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Voting assistance officers shall be appointed or assigned under Department of Defense regulations. Commanders at all levels are responsible for ensuring that unit voting officers are trained and equipped to provide information and assistance to members of the armed forces on voting matters. Performance evaluation reports pertaining to a member who has been assigned to serve as a voting assistance officer shall comment on the performance of the member as a voting assistance officer.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Under regulations and procedures (including directives) prescribed by the Secretary, a member of the armed forces appointed or assigned to duty as a voting assistance officer shall, to the maximum extent practicable, be given the time and resources needed to perform the member’s duties as a voting assistance officer during the period in advance of a general election when members and their dependents are preparing and submitting absentee ballots.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Delivery of Mail From Overseas Preceding Federal Elections</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> During the four months preceding a general Federal election month, the Secretary of Defense shall periodically conduct surveys of all overseas locations and vessels at sea with military units responsible for collecting mail for return shipment to the United States and all port facilities in the United States and overseas where military-related mail is collected for shipment to overseas locations or to the United States. The purpose of each survey shall be to determine if voting materials are awaiting shipment at any such location and, if so, the length of time that such materials have been held at that location. During the fourth and third months before a general Federal election month, such surveys shall be conducted biweekly. During the second and first months before a general Federal election month, such surveys shall be conducted weekly.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall ensure that voting materials are transmitted expeditiously by military postal authorities at all times. The Secretary shall, to the maximum extent practicable, implement measures to ensure that a postmark or other official proof of mailing date is provided on each absentee ballot collected at any overseas location or vessel at sea whenever the Department of Defense is responsible for collecting mail for return shipment to the United States. The Secretary shall ensure that the measures implemented under the preceding sentence do not result in the delivery of absentee ballots to the final destination of such ballots after the date on which the election for Federal office is held.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> In this section, the term “general Federal election month” means November in an even-numbered year.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice of Deadlines and Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of each military department, utilizing the voting assistance officer network established for each military installation, shall, to the maximum extent practicable, provide notice to members of the armed forces stationed at that installation of the last date before a general Federal election for which absentee ballots mailed from a postal facility located at that installation can reasonably be expected to be timely delivered to the appropriate State and local election officials.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Registration and Voting Information for Members and Dependents</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of each military department, using a variety of means including both print and electronic media, shall, to the maximum extent practicable, ensure that members of the armed forces and their dependents who are qualified to vote have ready access to information regarding voter registration requirements and deadlines (including voter registration), absentee ballot application requirements and deadlines, and the availability of voting assistance officers to assist members and dependents to understand and comply with these requirements.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of each military department shall make the national voter registration form prepared for purposes of the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act by the Federal Election Commission available so that each person who enlists shall receive such form at the time of the enlistment, or as soon thereafter as practicable.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Where practicable, a special day or days shall be designated at each military installation for the purpose of informing members of the armed forces and their dependents of election timing, registration requirements, and voting procedures.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title XVI, § 1602(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1274</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title VII, § 701</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1722</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title X, § 1084(d)(13)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2062</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title V, § 596(a)</ref>, (d), <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2235</ref>, 2236; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 924(b)(1)(M)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3820</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1566a.</num>
<heading> Voting assistance: voter assistance offices</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designation of Offices on Military Installations as Voter Assistance Offices</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense under subsection (f), the Secretaries of the military departments shall designate offices on installations under their jurisdiction, or at such installations as the Secretary of the military department concerned shall determine are best located to provide access to voter assistance services for all covered individuals in a particular location, to provide absent uniformed services voters, particularly those individuals described in subsection (b), and their family members with the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Information on voter registration procedures and absentee ballot procedures (including the official post card form prescribed under section 101 of the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 1973ff</ref>)).<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002076">1</ref></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Information and assistance, if requested, including access to the Internet where practicable, to register to vote in an election for Federal office.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Information and assistance, if requested, including access to the Internet where practicable, to update the individual’s voter registration information, including instructions for absent uniformed services voters to change their address by submitting the official post card form prescribed under section 101 of the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act to the appropriate State election official.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Information and assistance, if requested, to request an absentee ballot under the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 1973ff</ref> et seq.).<sup>1</sup></content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered Individuals</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The individuals described in this subsection are absent uniformed services voters who—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> are undergoing a permanent change of duty station;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> are deploying overseas for at least six months;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> are returning from an overseas deployment of at least six months; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> otherwise request assistance related to voter registration.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Timing of Provision of Assistance</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense under subsection (f) shall ensure, to the maximum extent practicable and consistent with military necessity, that the assistance provided under subsection (a) is provided to a covered individual described in subsection (b)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> if described in subsection (b)(1), as part of the administrative in-processing of the covered individual upon arrival at the new duty station of the covered individual;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> if described in subsection (b)(2), as part of the administrative out-processing of the covered individual in preparation for deployment from the home duty station of the covered individual;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> if described in subsection (b)(3), as part of the administrative in-processing of the covered individual upon return to the home duty station of the covered individual; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> if described in subsection (b)(4), at the time the covered individual requests such assistance.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Outreach</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of each military department, or the Presidential designee, shall take appropriate actions to inform absent uniformed services voters of the assistance available under subsection (a), including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the availability of information and voter registration assistance at offices designated under subsection (a); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the time, location, and manner in which an absent uniformed services voter may utilize such assistance.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority To Designate Voting Assistance Offices as Voter Registration Agency on Military Installations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may authorize the Secretaries of the military departments to designate offices on military installations as voter registration agencies under section 7(a)(2) of the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 1973gg–5(a)(2)</ref>) <sup>1</sup> for all purposes of such Act. Any office so designated shall discharge the requirements of this section, under the regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense under subsection (f).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations relating to the administration of the requirements of this section. The regulations shall be prescribed before the regularly scheduled general election for Federal office held in November 2010, and shall be implemented for such general election for Federal office and for each succeeding election for Federal office.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of a military department shall provide the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives with notice of any decision by the Secretary to close a voter assistance office that was designated on an installation before the date of the enactment of this paragraph. The notice shall include the rational for the closure, the timing of the closure, the number of covered individuals supported by the office, and the plan for providing the assistance available under subsection (a) to covered individuals after the closure of the office.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “absent uniformed services voter” has the meaning given that term in section 107(1) of the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 1973ff–6(1)</ref>).<sup>1</sup></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “Federal office” has the meaning given that term in section 107(3) of the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 1973ff–6(3)</ref>).<sup>1</sup></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “Presidential designee” means the official designated by the President under section 101(a) of the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 1973ff(a)</ref>).<sup>1</sup></content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title V, § 583(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2328</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title X, § 1075(b)(21)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4370</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title V, § 592</ref>, title X, § 1071(e)(2), <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3395</ref>, 3509.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1567.</num>
<heading> Duration of military protective orders</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A military protective order issued by a military commander shall remain in effect until such time as the military commander terminates the order or issues a replacement order.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title V, § 561(a), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4470</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title X, § 1073(a)(16)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2473</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1567a.</num>
<heading> Mandatory notification of issuance of military protective order to civilian law enforcement</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Initial Notification</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In the event a military protective order is issued against a member of the armed forces, the commander of the unit to which the member is assigned shall, not later than seven days after the date of the issuance of the order, notify the appropriate civilian authorities of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the issuance of the protective order; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the individuals involved in the order.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notification in Event of Transfer</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In the event that a member of the armed forces against whom a military protective order is issued is transferred to another unit—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> not later than the date of the transfer, the commander of the unit from which the member is transferred shall notify the commander of the unit to which the member is transferred of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the issuance of the protective order; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the individuals involved in the order; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> not later than seven days after receiving the notice under paragraph (1), the commander of the unit to which the member is transferred shall provide notice of the order to the appropriate civilian authorities in accordance with subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notification of Changes or Termination</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The commander of the unit to which the member is assigned also shall notify the appropriate civilian authorities of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any change made in a protective order covered by subsection (a); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the termination of the protective order.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title V, § 562(a), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4470</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title X, § 1073(a)(17)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2473</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title V, § 543(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1376</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>