<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 1011—</num>
<heading>NATIONAL GUARD BUREAU</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 10501.</num>
<heading> National Guard Bureau</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">National Guard Bureau</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is in the Department of Defense the National Guard Bureau, which is a joint activity of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Purposes</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The National Guard Bureau is the channel of communications on all matters pertaining to the National Guard, the Army National Guard of the United States, and the Air National Guard of the United States between (1) the Department of the Army and Department of the Air Force, and (2) the several States.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title IX, § 904(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2824</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title XVIII, § 1812(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 497</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10502.</num>
<heading> Chief of the National Guard Bureau: appointment; adviser on National Guard matters; grade; succession</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appointment</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>There is a Chief of the National Guard Bureau, who is responsible for the organization and operations of the National Guard Bureau. The Chief of the National Guard Bureau is appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. Such appointment shall be made from officers of the Army National Guard of the United States or the Air National Guard of the United States who—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> are recommended for such appointment by their respective Governors or, in the case of the District of Columbia, the commanding general of the District of Columbia National Guard;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> are recommended for such appointment by the Secretary of the Army or the Secretary of the Air Force;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> have had at least 10 years of federally recognized commissioned service in an active status in the National Guard;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> are in a grade above the grade of brigadier general;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> are determined by the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, in accordance with criteria and as a result of a process established by the Chairman, to have significant joint duty experience;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> are determined by the Secretary of Defense to have successfully completed such other assignments and experiences so as to possess a detailed understanding of the status and capabilities of National Guard forces and the missions of the National Guard Bureau as set forth in <ref>section 10503 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> have a level of operational experience in a position of significant responsibility, professional military education, and demonstrated expertise in national defense and homeland defense matters that are commensurate with the advisory role of the Chief of the National Guard Bureau; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> possess such other qualifications as the Secretary of Defense shall prescribe for purposes of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Term of Office</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> An officer appointed as Chief of the National Guard Bureau serves at the pleasure of the President for a term of four years. An officer may be reappointed as Chief of the National Guard Bureau.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Except as provided in <ref>section 14508(d) of this title</ref>, while holding the office of Chief of the National Guard Bureau, the Chief of the National Guard Bureau may not be removed from the reserve active-status list, or from an active status, under any provision of law that otherwise would require such removal due to completion of a specified number of years of service or a specified number of years of service in grade.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading> Advisor on National Guard Matters.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Chief of the National Guard Bureau is—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a principal advisor to the Secretary of Defense, through the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, on matters involving non-federalized National Guard forces and on other matters as determined by the Secretary of Defense; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the principal adviser to the Secretary of the Army and the Chief of Staff of the Army, and to the Secretary of the Air Force and the Chief of Staff of the Air Force, on matters relating to the National Guard, the Army National Guard of the United States, and the Air National Guard of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Member of Joint Chiefs of Staff</inline>.—</heading>
<content>As a member of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, the Chief of the National Guard Bureau has the specific responsibility of addressing matters involving non-Federalized National Guard forces in support of homeland defense and civil support missions.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Grade and Exclusion From General and Flag Officer Authorized Strength</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Chief of the National Guard Bureau shall be appointed to serve in the grade of general.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall designate, pursuant to subsection (b) of <ref>section 526 of this title</ref>, the position of Chief of the National Guard Bureau as one of the general officer and flag officer positions to be excluded from the limitations in subsection (a) of such section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Succession</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> When there is a vacancy in the office of the Chief of the National Guard Bureau or in the absence or disability of the Chief, the Vice Chief of the National Guard Bureau acts as Chief and performs the duties of the Chief until a successor is appointed or the absence or disability ceases.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> When there is a vacancy in the offices of both the Chief and the Vice Chief of the National Guard Bureau or in the absence or disability of both the Chief and the Vice Chief of the National Guard Bureau, or when there is a vacancy in one such office and in the absence or disability of the officer holding the other, the senior officer of the Army National Guard of the United States or the Air National Guard of the United States on duty with the National Guard Bureau shall perform the duties of the Chief until a successor to the Chief or Vice Chief is appointed or the absence or disability of the Chief or Vice Chief ceases, as the case may be.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title IX, § 904(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2824</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title V, § 507(a)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1876</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title XVIII</ref>, §§ 1811, 1825(c)(2), <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 496</ref>, 502; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title V</ref>, §§ 511(a)(1),(2), 512(b), <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1391</ref>, 1393.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10503.</num>
<heading> Functions of National Guard Bureau: charter</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, the Secretary of the Army, and the Secretary of the Air Force, shall develop and prescribe a charter for the National Guard Bureau. The charter shall reflect the full scope of the duties and activities of the Bureau, including the following matters:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Allocating unit structure, strength authorizations, and other resources to the Army National Guard of the United States and the Air National Guard of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The role of the National Guard Bureau in support of the Secretary of the Army and the Secretary of the Air Force.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Prescribing the training discipline and training requirements for the Army National Guard and the Air National Guard and the allocation of Federal funds for the training of the Army National Guard and the Air National Guard.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Ensuring that units and members of the Army National Guard and the Air National Guard are trained by the States in accordance with approved programs and policies of, and guidance from, the Chief, the Secretary of the Army, and the Secretary of the Air Force.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Monitoring and assisting the States in the organization, maintenance, and operation of National Guard units so as to provide well-trained and well-equipped units capable of augmenting the active forces in time of war or national emergency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Planning and administering the budget for the Army National Guard of the United States and the Air National Guard of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Supervising the acquisition and supply of, and accountability of the States for, Federal property issued to the National Guard through the property and fiscal officers designated, detailed, or appointed under <ref>section 708 of title 32</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Granting and withdrawing, in accordance with applicable laws and regulations, Federal recognition of (A) National Guard units, and (B) officers of the National Guard.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> Establishing policies and programs for the employment and use of National Guard technicians under <ref>section 709 of title 32</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> Supervising and administering the Active Guard and Reserve program as it pertains to the National Guard.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> Issuing directives, regulations, and publications consistent with approved policies of the Army and Air Force, as appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> Facilitating and supporting the training of members and units of the National Guard to meet State requirements.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Assisting the Secretary of Defense in facilitating and coordinating with the entities listed in subparagraph (B) the use of National Guard personnel and resources for operations conducted under title 32, or in support of State missions.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> The entities listed in this subparagraph for purposes of subparagraph (A) are the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Other Federal agencies.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The Adjutants General of the States.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> The combatant command the geographic area of responsibility of which includes the United States.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> Such other functions as the Secretary of Defense may prescribe.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title IX, § 904(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2825</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title XVIII, § 1813(a)</ref>–(c)(1), <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 497</ref>, 498; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title X, § 1081(3)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1960</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10504.</num>
<heading> Chief of National Guard Bureau: annual reports</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Report on State of the National Guard</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Chief of the National Guard Bureau shall submit to the Secretary of Defense, through the Secretaries of the Army and the Air Force, an annual report on the state of the National Guard and the ability of the National Guard to meet its missions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The annual report required by paragraph (1) shall be prepared in conjunction with the Secretary of the Army and the Secretary of the Air Force and may be submitted in classified and unclassified versions.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Submission of Report to Congress</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall transmit the annual report of the Chief of the National Guard Bureau to Congress, together with such comments on the report as the Secretary considers appropriate. The report shall be transmitted at the same time each year that the annual report of the Secretary under <ref>section 113(c) of this title</ref> is submitted to Congress.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Report on Non-federalized Service National Guard Personnel, Training, and Equipment Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Not later than January 31 of each of calendar years 2018 through 2020, the Chief of the National Guard Bureau, in coordination with the Secretary of Defense, shall submit to the recipients described in paragraph (3) a report that identifies the personnel, training, and equipment required by the non-Federalized National Guard—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to support civilian authorities in connection with natural and man-made disasters during the covered period; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to carry out prevention, protection, mitigation, response, and recovery activities relating to such disasters during the covered period.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> In preparing each report under paragraph (1), the Chief of the National Guard Bureau shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> consult with the chief executive of each State, the Council of Governors, and other appropriate civilian authorities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> collect and validate information from each State relating to the personnel, training, and equipment requirements described in paragraph (1);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> set forth separately the personnel, training, and equipment requirements for—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> each of the emergency support functions of the National Response Framework; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> each of the Federal Emergency Management Agency regions;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> assess core civilian capability gaps relating to natural and man-made disasters, as identified by States in submissions to the Department of Homeland Security;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> take into account threat and hazard identifications and risk assessments of the Department of Defense, the Department of Homeland Security, and the States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> assess the budgets of each State to support the personnel, training, and equipment requirements of the non-Federalized National Guard.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The annual report required by paragraph (1) shall be submitted to the following officials:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The congressional defense committees, the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Homeland Security.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The Council of Governors.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Army.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Air Force.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> The Commander of the United States Northern Command.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> The Commander of the United States Indo-Pacific Command.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> The Commander of the United States Cyber Command.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> In this subsection, the term “covered period” means the fiscal year beginning after the date on which a report is submitted under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title IX, § 904(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2825</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title III, § 333(a)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1354–1356</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title X, § 1081(a)(30)</ref>, title XII, § 1251(b)(1), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1985</ref>, 2053.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10505.</num>
<heading> Vice Chief of the National Guard Bureau</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appointment</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> There is a Vice Chief of the National Guard Bureau, appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. The appointment shall be made from officers of the Army National Guard of the United States or the Air National Guard of the United States who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> are recommended for such appointment by their respective Governors or, in the case of the District of Columbia, the commanding general of the District of Columbia National Guard;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> are recommended by the Secretary of the Army, in the case of officers of the Army National Guard of the United States, or by the Secretary of the Air Force, in the case of officers of the Air National Guard of the United States, and by the Secretary of Defense;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> are determined by the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, in accordance with criteria and as a result of a process established by the Chairman, to have significant joint duty experience; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> have had at least 10 years of federally recognized commissioned service in an active status in the National Guard.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Chief of the National Guard Bureau and the Vice Chief of the National Guard Bureau may not both be members of the Army or of the Air Force.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Except as provided in subparagraph (B), an officer appointed as Vice Chief of the National Guard Bureau serves for a term of four years, but may be removed from office at any time for cause.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The term of the Vice Chief of the National Guard Bureau shall end upon the appointment of a Chief of the National Guard Bureau who is a member of the same armed force as the Vice Chief.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may waive the restrictions in paragraph (2) and the provisions of paragraph (3) for not more than 90 days to provide for the orderly transition of officers appointed to serve in the positions of Chief of the National Guard Bureau and the Vice Chief of the National Guard Bureau.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duties</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Vice Chief of the National Guard Bureau performs such duties as may be prescribed by the Chief of the National Guard Bureau.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Grade</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Vice Chief of the National Guard Bureau shall be appointed to serve in the grade of general.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall designate, pursuant to subsection (b) of <ref>section 526 of this title</ref>, the position of Vice Chief of the National Guard Bureau as one of the general officer and flag officer positions to be excluded from the limitations in subsection (a) of such section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title IX, § 904(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2826</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title V</ref>, §§ 507(c), 508(a)–(b)(3), (c)(1), <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1876</ref>, 1877; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title V, § 511(b)</ref>, (c)(1), (d)(1), <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1392</ref>, 1393; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title V</ref>, §§ 502(rr), 511, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2106</ref>, 2112; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title V, § 512</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 244</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10506.</num>
<heading> Other senior National Guard Bureau officers</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Additional General Officers</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> In addition to the Chief and Vice Chief of the National Guard Bureau, there shall be assigned to the National Guard Bureau—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> two officers selected by the Secretary of the Army (after consultation with the Chief of the National Guard Bureau) from officers of the Army National Guard of the United States who have been nominated by their respective Governors or, in the case of the District of Columbia, the commanding general of the District of Columbia National Guard, the senior of whom shall be appointed in accordance with paragraph (3) and shall serve as Director, Army National Guard, with the other serving as Deputy Director, Army National Guard; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> two officers selected by the Secretary of the Air Force (after consultation with the Chief of the National Guard Bureau) from officers of the Air National Guard of the United States who have been nominated by their respective Governors or, in the case of the District of Columbia, the commanding general of the District of Columbia National Guard, the senior of whom shall be appointed in accordance with paragraph (3) and shall serve as Director, Air National Guard, with the other serving as Deputy Director, Air National Guard.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Director and Deputy Director, Army National Guard, and the Director and Deputy Director, Air National Guard, shall assist the Chief of the National Guard Bureau in carrying out the functions of the National Guard Bureau as they relate to their respective branches.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, shall appoint the Director, Army National Guard, from general officers of the Army National Guard of the United States and shall appoint the Director, Air National Guard, from general officers of the Air National Guard of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Defense may not recommend an officer to the President for appointment as Director, Army National Guard, or as Director, Air National Guard, unless the officer—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is recommended by the Secretary of the military department concerned; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> is determined by the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, in accordance with criteria and as a result of a process established by the Chairman, to have significant joint duty experience.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> An officer on active duty for service as the Director, Army National Guard, or the Director, Air National Guard, shall be counted for purposes of the grade limitations under sections 525 and 526 of this title.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The Director, Army National Guard, and the Director, Air National Guard, are appointed for a period of four years, but may be removed for cause at any time. An officer serving as either Director may be reappointed for one additional four-year period.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Other Officers</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There are in the National Guard Bureau a legal counsel, a comptroller, and an inspector general, each of whom shall be appointed by the Chief of the National Guard Bureau. They shall perform such duties as the Chief may prescribe.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title IX, § 904(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2827</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title V, § 554(f)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 617</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title V, § 507(e)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–105; <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title V, § 501(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2529</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title V</ref>, §§ 508(b)(4), 536(a), <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1877</ref>, 1901; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title V, § 511(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1393</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title V, § 512(a)</ref>–(c), <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3358</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title V, § 502(ss)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2107</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10507.</num>
<heading> National Guard Bureau: assignment of officers of regular or reserve components</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as provided in <ref>section 12402(b) of this title</ref>, the President may assign to duty in the National Guard Bureau as many regular or reserve officers of the Army or Air Force as he considers necessary.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1661(c)(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2982</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1501(b)(6)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 496</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10508.</num>
<heading> National Guard Bureau: general provisions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Manpower Requirements of National Guard Bureau</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The manpower requirements of the National Guard Bureau as a joint activity of the Department of Defense shall be determined in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Personnel for Functions of National Guard Bureau.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Chief of the National Guard Bureau may program for, appoint, employ, administer, detail, and assign persons under sections 2102, 2103, 2105, and 3101 of title 5, subchapter IV of chapter 53 of title 5, or <ref>section 328 of title 32</ref>, within the National Guard Bureau and the National Guard of each State, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the District of Columbia, Guam, and the Virgin Islands to execute the functions of the National Guard Bureau and the missions of the National Guard, and missions as assigned by the Chief of the National Guard Bureau.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Administration through adjutants general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Chief of the National Guard Bureau may designate the adjutants general referred to in <ref>section 314 of title 32</ref> to appoint, employ, and administer the National Guard employees authorized by this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Administrative actions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Notwithstanding the Intergovernmental Personnel Act of 1970 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 4701</ref> et seq.) and under regulations prescribed by the Chief of the National Guard Bureau, all personnel actions or conditions of employment, including adverse actions under title 5, pertaining to a person appointed, employed, or administered by an adjutant general under this subsection shall be accomplished by the adjutant general of the jurisdiction concerned. For purposes of any administrative complaint, grievance, claim, or action arising from, or relating to, such a personnel action or condition of employment:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The adjutant general of the jurisdiction concerned shall be considered the head of the agency and the National Guard of the jurisdiction concerned shall be considered the employing agency of the individual and the sole defendant or respondent in any administrative action.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The National Guard of the jurisdiction concerned shall defend any administrative complaint, grievance, claim, or action, and shall promptly implement all aspects of any final administrative order, judgment, or decision.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> In any civil action or proceeding brought in any court arising from an action under this section, the United States shall be the sole defendant or respondent.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The Attorney General of the United States shall defend the United States in actions arising under this section described in subparagraph (C).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Any settlement, judgment, or costs arising from an action described in subparagraph (A) or (C) shall be paid from appropriated funds allocated to the National Guard of the jurisdiction concerned.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title XVIII, § 1812(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 497</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title IX, § 932</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2363</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title V, § 517</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1754</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>