<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 1805—</num>
<heading>MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 18501.</num>
<heading> Reserve components: personnel and logistic support by military departments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary concerned is responsible for providing the personnel, equipment, facilities, and other general logistic support necessary to enable units and Reserves in the Ready Reserve of the reserve components under his jurisdiction to satisfy the training requirements and mobilization readiness requirements for those units and Reserves as recommended by the Secretary concerned and by the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff and approved by the Secretary of Defense, and as recommended by the Commandant of the Coast Guard and approved by the Secretary of Homeland Security when the Coast Guard is not operated as a service of the Navy.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1664(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3011</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–296, title XVII, § 1704(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2314</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 18502.</num>
<heading> Reserve components: supplies, services, and facilities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned shall make available to the reserve components under his jurisdiction the supplies, services, and facilities of the armed forces under his jurisdiction that he considers necessary to support and develop those components.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Whenever he finds it to be in the best interest of the United States, the Secretary concerned may issue supplies of the armed forces under his jurisdiction to the reserve components under his jurisdiction, without charge to the appropriations for those components for the cost or value of the supplies or for any related expense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Whenever he finds it to be in the best interest of the United States, the Secretary of the Army or the Secretary of the Air Force may issue to the Army National Guard or the Air National Guard, as the case may be, supplies of the armed forces under his jurisdiction that are in addition to supplies issued to that National Guard under <ref>section 702 of title 32</ref> or charged against its appropriations under section 106 or 107 of title 32, without charge to the appropriations for those components for the cost or value of the supplies or for any related expense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Supplies issued under subsection (b) or (c) may be repossessed or redistributed as prescribed by the Secretary concerned.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1664(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3012</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 18505.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002195">1</ref></num>
<heading> Reserves traveling for inactive-duty training: space-required travel on military aircraft</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> A member of a reserve component traveling for inactive-duty training (including a place other than the place of the member’s unit training assembly if the member is performing inactive-duty training in another location) may travel in a space-required status on aircraft of the armed forces between the member’s home and the place of the inactive-duty training.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> A member traveling in a space-required status on any such aircraft under subsection (a) is not authorized to receive travel, transportation, or per diem allowances in connection with that travel.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title V, § 517(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 594</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title III, § 384(a), (b)(1)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–87; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title V, § 518</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1096</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 18506.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title V, § 589(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3279</ref>]</heading>
</section>
</chapter>