<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 963—</num>
<heading>PROCUREMENT</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 9531.</num>
<heading> Commercial Augmentation Space Reserve.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002182">1</ref></heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Program</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may carry out a program to be known as the “Commercial Augmentation Space Reserve” program. Under the program, the Secretary may include in a contract for the procurement of space products or services one or more provisions under which a qualified contractor agrees to provide additional space products or services to the Department of Defense on an as-needed basis under circumstances determined by the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Security Measures</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In carrying out the program under subsection (a), the Secretary—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall ensure that each contract under, and qualified contractor participating in, the program complies with applicable security measures, including any security measures required under the National Industrial Security program (or any successor to such program); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> may establish and implement such additional security measures as the Secretary determines appropriate to protect the national security interests of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Commitment of Space Products or Services as a Business Factor</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In determining the quantity of business to be received under a space product or services contract pursuant to subsection (a), the Secretary may use as a factor the relative amount of space product or service committed to the program under subsection (a) by the qualified contractor involved.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The term “citizen of the United States” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an individual who is a citizen of the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a partnership each of whose partners is an individual who is a citizen of the United States; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a corporation or association organized under the laws of the United States or a State, the District of Columbia, or a territory or possession of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “qualified contractor” means a contractor that is a citizen of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “space products or services” means commercial products and commercial services (as those terms are defined in section 2.101 of the Federal Acquisition Regulation) and noncommercial products and noncommercial services offered by commercial companies that operate to, through, or from space, including any required terrestrial ground, support, and network systems and associated services that can be used to support military functions and missions.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XVI, § 1602(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2158</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9532.</num>
<heading> Factories, arsenals, and depots: manufacture at</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Air Force may have supplies needed for the Department of the Air Force made in factories, arsenals, or depots owned by the United States, so far as those factories, arsenals, or depots can make those supplies on an economical basis.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 576</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§§ 9534, 9535.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title VIII, § 823(4)</ref>, (5), <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1707</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9536.</num>
<heading> Equipment: bakeries, schools, kitchens, and mess halls</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Money necessary for the following items for the use of enlisted members of the Air Force or the Space Force may be spent from appropriations for regular supplies:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Equipment for air base bakeries.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Furniture, textbooks, paper, and equipment for air base schools.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Tableware and mess furniture for kitchens and mess halls.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 576</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 923(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3816</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§§ 9537, 9538.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title VIII, § 823(6)</ref>, (7), <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1707</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9540.</num>
<heading> Architectural and engineering services</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Whenever he considers that it is advantageous to the national defense and that existing facilities of the Department of the Air Force are inadequate, the Secretary of the Air Force may, by contract or otherwise, employ the architectural or engineering services of any person outside that Department for producing and delivering designs, plans, drawings, and specifications needed for any public works or utilities project of the Department.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The fee for any service under this section may not be more than 10 percent of the estimated cost, as determined by the Secretary, of the project to which it applies.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Sections 305, 3324, and 7204, chapter 51, and subchapters III, IV, and VI of chapter 53 of title 5 do not apply to employment under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 577</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–718, § 28</ref>, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1119</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title VII, § 703(c)(3)</ref>, title VIII, § 801(a)(3)(I), <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1217</ref>, 1222; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 514(15)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2936</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2881(c)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 780</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 9541.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title VIII, § 822(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1707</ref>]</heading>
</section>
</chapter>