<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 152—</num>
<heading>ISSUE OF SUPPLIES, SERVICES, AND FACILITIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2551.</num>
<heading> Equipment and barracks: national veterans’ organizations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary of a military department, under conditions prescribed by him, may lend cots, blankets, pillows, mattresses, bed sacks, and other supplies under the jurisdiction of that department to any recognized national veterans’ organization for use at its national or state convention or national youth athletic or recreation tournament. He may, under conditions prescribed by him, also permit the organization to use unoccupied barracks under the jurisdiction of that department for such an occasion.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Property lent under subsection (a) may be delivered on terms and at times agreed upon by the Secretary of the military department concerned and representatives of the veterans’ organization. However, the veterans’ organization must defray any expense incurred by the United States in the delivery, return, rehabilitation, or replacement of that property, as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the military department concerned shall require a good and sufficient bond for the return in good condition of property lent or used under subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 142</ref>, § 2541; renumbered § 2551, <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title X, § 1033(b)(1)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–260.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2552.</num>
<heading> Equipment for instruction and practice: American National Red Cross</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of a military department, under regulations to be prescribed by him, may lend equipment under the jurisdiction of that department that is on hand, and that can be temporarily spared, to any organization formed by the American National Red Cross that needs it for instruction and practice for the purpose of aiding the Army, Navy, or Air Force in time of war. The Secretary shall by regulation require the immediate return, upon request, of equipment lent under this section. The Secretary shall require a bond, in double the value of the property issued under this section, for the care and safekeeping of that property and for its return when required.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 142</ref>, § 2542; renumbered § 2552, <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title X, § 1033(b)(1)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–260.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2553.</num>
<heading> Equipment and services: Presidential inaugural ceremonies</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Assistance Authorized</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense may, with respect to the ceremonies relating to the inauguration of a President, provide the assistance referred to in subsection (b) to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Presidential Inaugural Committee; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the congressional Joint Inaugural Committee.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Assistance</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Assistance that may be provided under subsection (a) is the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Planning and carrying out activities relating to security and safety.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Planning and carrying out ceremonial activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Loan of property.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Any other assistance that the Secretary considers appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reimbursement</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Presidential Inaugural Committee shall reimburse the Secretary for any costs incurred in connection with the provision to the committee of assistance referred to in subsection (b)(4).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Costs reimbursed under paragraph (1) shall be credited to the appropriations from which the costs were paid. The amount credited to an appropriation shall be proportionate to the amount of the costs charged to that appropriation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Loaned Property</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>With respect to property loaned for a presidential inauguration under subsection (b)(3), the Presidential Inaugural Committee shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> return that property within nine days after the date of the ceremony inaugurating the President;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> give good and sufficient bond for the return in good order and condition of that property;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> indemnify the United States for any loss of, or damage to, that property; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> defray any expense incurred for the delivery, return, rehabilitation, replacement, or operation of that property.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “Presidential Inaugural Committee” means the committee referred to in <ref>section 501 of title 36</ref> that is appointed with respect to the inauguration of a President-elect and Vice President-elect.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “congressional Joint Inaugural Committee” means the joint committee of the Senate and House of Representatives referred to in <ref>section 507 of title 36</ref> that is appointed with respect to the inauguration of a President-elect and Vice President-elect.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 85–861, § 1(48)(A)</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1458</ref>, § 2543; amended <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 511(81)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2927</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title III, § 366(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2495</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–225, § 4(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1498</ref>; renumbered § 2553, <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title X, § 1033(b)(1)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–260.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2554.</num>
<heading> Equipment and other services: Boy Scout Jamborees</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense is hereby authorized, under such regulations as he may prescribe, to lend to the Boy Scouts of America, for the use and accommodation of Scouts, Scouters, and officials who attend any national or world Boy Scout Jamboree, such cots, blankets, commissary equipment, flags, refrigerators, and other equipment and without reimbursement, furnish services and expendable medical supplies, as may be necessary or useful to the extent that items are in stock and items or services are available.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Such equipment is authorized to be delivered at such time prior to the holding of any national or world Boy Scout Jamboree, and to be returned at such time after the close of any such jamboree, as may be agreed upon by the Secretary of Defense and the Boy Scouts of America. No expense shall be incurred by the United States Government for the delivery, return, rehabilitation, or replacement of such equipment.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense, before delivering such property, shall take from the Boy Scouts of America, good and sufficient bond for the safe return of such property in good order and condition, and the whole without expense to the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense is hereby authorized under such regulations as he may prescribe, to provide, without expense to the United States Government, transportation from the United States or military commands overseas, and return, on vessels of the Military Sealift Command or aircraft of the Air Mobility Command for (1) those Boy Scouts, Scouters, and officials certified by the Boy Scouts of America, as representing the Boy Scouts of America at any national or world Boy Scout Jamboree, and (2) the equipment and property of such Boy Scouts, Scouters, and officials and the property loaned to the Boy Scouts of America, by the Secretary of Defense pursuant to this section to the extent that such transportation will not interfere with the requirements of military operations.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> Before furnishing any transportation under subsection (d), the Secretary of Defense shall take from the Boy Scouts of America, a good and sufficient bond for the reimbursement to the United States by the Boy Scouts of America, of the actual costs of transportation furnished under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> Amounts paid to the United States to reimburse it for expenses incurred under subsection (b) and for the actual costs of transportation furnished under subsection (d) shall be credited to the current applicable appropriations or funds to which such expenses and costs were charged and shall be available for the same purposes as such appropriations or funds.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> In the case of a Boy Scout Jamboree held on a military installation, the Secretary of Defense may provide personnel services and logistical support at the military installation in addition to the support authorized under subsections (a) and (d).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<content> Other departments of the Federal Government are authorized, under such regulations as may be prescribed by the Secretary thereof, to provide to the Boy Scouts of America, equipment and other services, under the same conditions and restrictions prescribed in the preceding subsections for the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall provide at least the same level of support under this section for a national or world Boy Scout Jamboree as was provided under this section for the preceding national or world Boy Scout Jamboree.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Defense may waive paragraph (1), if the Secretary—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> determines that providing the support subject to paragraph (1) would be detrimental to the national security of the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> submits to Congress a report containing such determination in a timely manner, and before the waiver takes effect.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 92–249</ref>, <date date="1972-03-10">Mar. 10, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 62</ref>, § 2544; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title III, § 376</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 283</ref>; renumbered § 2554, <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title X, § 1033(b)(1)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–260l; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title IX, § 931(a)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1200</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–148, div. A, title VIII, § 8126(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2005-12-30">Dec. 30, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 2729</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title X, § 1058(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3443</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2555.</num>
<heading> Transportation services: international Girl Scout events</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense is authorized, under such regulations as he may prescribe, to provide, without expense to the United States Government, transportation from the United States or military commands overseas, and return, on vessels of the Military Sealift Command or aircraft of the Air Mobility Command for (1) those Girl Scouts and officials certified by the Girl Scouts of the United States of America as representing the Girl Scouts of the United States of America at any International World Friendship Event or Troops on Foreign Soil meeting which is endorsed and approved by the National Board of Directors of the Girl Scouts of the United States of America and is conducted outside of the United States, (2) United States citizen delegates coming from outside of the United States to triennial meetings of the National Council of the Girl Scouts of the United States of America, and (3) the equipment and property of such Girl Scouts and officials, to the extent that such transportation will not interfere with the requirements of military operations.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Before furnishing any transportation under subsection (a), the Secretary of Defense shall take from the Girl Scouts of the United States of America a good and sufficient bond for the reimbursement to the United States by the Girl Scouts of the United States of America, of the actual costs of transportation furnished under subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Amounts paid to the United States to reimburse it for the actual costs of transportation furnished under subsection (a) shall be credited to the current applicable appropriations or funds to which such costs were charged and shall be available for the same purposes as such appropriations or funds.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–492, § 1</ref>, <date date="1978-10-20">Oct. 20, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1642</ref>, § 2545; renumbered § 2555, <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title X, § 1033(b)(1)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–260; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title IX, § 931(a)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1200</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2556.</num>
<heading> Shelter for homeless; incidental services</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of a military department may make military installations under his jurisdiction available for the furnishing of shelter to persons without adequate shelter. The Secretary may, incidental to the furnishing of such shelter, provide services as described in subsection (b). Shelter and incidental services provided under this section may be provided without reimbursement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned shall carry out this section in cooperation with appropriate State and local governmental entities and charitable organizations. The Secretary shall, to the maximum extent practicable, use the services and personnel of such entities and organizations in determining to whom and the circumstances under which shelter is furnished under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Services that may be provided incident to the furnishing of shelter under this section are the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Utilities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Bedding.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Security.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Transportation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Renovation of facilities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Minor repairs undertaken specifically to make suitable space available for shelter to be provided under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Property liability insurance.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Shelter and incidental services may only be provided under this section to the extent that the Secretary concerned determines will not interfere with military preparedness or ongoing military functions.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned may provide bedding for support of shelters for the homeless that are operated by entities other than the Department of Defense. Bedding may be provided under this subsection without reimbursement, but may only be provided to the extent that the Secretary determines that the provision of such bedding will not interfere with military requirements.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations for the administration of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 98–94, title III, § 305(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1983-09-24">Sept. 24, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 628</ref>, § 2546; amended <ref>Pub. L. 99–167, title VIII, § 825</ref>, <date date="1985-12-03">Dec. 3, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 992</ref>; renumbered § 2556, <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title X, § 1033(b)(1)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–260.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2557.</num>
<heading> Excess nonlethal supplies: availability for humanitarian relief, domestic emergency assistance, and homeless veterans assistance</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may make available for humanitarian relief purposes any nonlethal excess supplies of the Department of Defense. In addition, the Secretary may make nonlethal excess supplies of the Department available to support domestic emergency assistance activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may make excess clothing, shoes, sleeping bags, and related nonlethal excess supplies available to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs for distribution to homeless veterans and programs assisting homeless veterans. The transfer of nonlethal excess supplies to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs under this paragraph shall be without reimbursement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Excess supplies made available for humanitarian relief purposes under this section shall be transferred to the Secretary of State, who shall be responsible for the distribution of such supplies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Excess supplies made available under this section to support domestic emergency assistance activities shall be transferred to the Secretary of Homeland Security. The Secretary of Defense may provide assistance in the distribution of such supplies at the request of the Secretary of Homeland Security.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> This section does not constitute authority to conduct any activity which, if carried out as an intelligence activity by the Department of Defense, would require a notice to the intelligence committees under title V of the National Security Act of 1947 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3091</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The term “nonlethal excess supplies” means property, other than real property, of the Department of Defense—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> that is excess property, as defined in regulations of the Department of Defense; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> that is not a weapon, ammunition, or other equipment or material that is designed to inflict serious bodily harm or death.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “intelligence committees” means the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title XIV, § 1454(a)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 761</ref>, § 2547; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–26, § 7(k)(2)</ref>, <date date="1987-04-21">Apr. 21, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 284</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XIII, § 1322(a)(10)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1671</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–88, title VI, § 602(c)(3)</ref>, <date date="1991-08-14">Aug. 14, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 444</ref>; renumbered § 2557, <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title X, § 1033(b)(1)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–260; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title III, § 361(a)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1064</ref>, 1065; <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title X, § 1074(a)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4368</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title X, § 1071(c)(3)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3508</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2558.</num>
<heading> National military associations: assistance at national conventions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority To Provide Services</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of a military department may provide services described in subsection (c) in connection with an annual conference or convention of a national military association.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Conditions for Providing Services</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Services may be provided under this section only if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the provision of the services in any case is approved in advance by the Secretary concerned;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the services can be provided in conjunction with training in appropriate military skills; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the services can be provided within existing funds otherwise available to the Secretary concerned.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered Services</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Services that may be provided under this section are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> limited air and ground transportation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> communications;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> medical assistance;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> administrative support; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> security support.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">National Military Associations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall designate those organizations which are national military associations for purposes of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations to carry out this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title III, § 329(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1417</ref>, § 2548; renumbered § 2558, <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title X, § 1033(b)(1)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–260.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2559.</num>
<heading> Provision of medical care to foreign military and diplomatic personnel: reimbursement required; waiver for provision of reciprocal services</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reimbursement Required</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in subsection (b), whenever the Secretary of Defense provides medical care in the United States on an inpatient basis to foreign military and diplomatic personnel or their dependents, the Secretary shall require that the United States be reimbursed for the costs of providing such care. Payments received as reimbursement for the provision of such care shall be credited to the appropriations against which charges were made for the provision of such care.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Waiver When Reciprocal Services Provided United States Military Personnel</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding subsection (a), the Secretary of Defense may provide inpatient medical care in the United States without cost to military personnel and their dependents from a foreign country if comparable care is made available to a comparable number of United States military personnel and their dependents in that foreign country.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XIV, § 1481(f)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1707</ref>, § 2549; renumbered § 2559, <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title X, § 1033(b)(1)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–260.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2560.</num>
<heading> Aircraft and vehicles: limitation on leasing to non-Federal agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Defense (or Secretary of a military department) may not lease to a non-Federal agency in the United States any aircraft or vehicle owned or operated by the Department of Defense if suitable aircraft or vehicles are commercially available in the private sector. However, nothing in the preceding sentence shall affect authorized and established procedures for the sale of surplus aircraft or vehicles.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XIV, § 1481(g)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1707</ref>, § 2550; renumbered § 2560, <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title X, § 1033(b)(1)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–260.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2561.</num>
<heading> Humanitarian assistance</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authorized Assistance</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> To the extent provided in defense authorization Acts, funds authorized to be appropriated to the Department of Defense for a fiscal year for humanitarian assistance shall be used for the purpose of providing transportation of humanitarian relief and for other humanitarian purposes worldwide.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may use the authority provided by paragraph (1) to transport supplies intended for use to respond to, or mitigate the effects of, an event or condition, such as an oil spill, that threatens serious harm to the environment, but only if other sources to provide such transportation are not readily available. The Secretary may require reimbursement for costs incurred by the Department of Defense to transport supplies under this paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Availability of Funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>To the extent provided in appropriation Acts, funds appropriated for humanitarian assistance for the purposes of this section shall remain available until expended.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Notice Before Provision of Assistance.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> If the Secretary of Defense uses the authority under subsection (a) to provide assistance for any program or activity in an amount in excess of $5,000,000, the Secretary shall provide to the congressional committees specified in subsection (g) notice in writing of the use of such authority in accordance with paragraph (2). Notice under this subsection shall include an identification of each of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The amount, type, and purpose of assistance to be provided and the recipient of the assistance.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The goals and objectives of the assistance.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The number and role of any members of the Armed Forces involved in the provision of the assistance.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Any other information the Secretary determines is relevant.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Notice required under paragraph (1) shall be provided—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> before the provision of assistance under subsection (a) using funds authorized to be appropriated to the Department of Defense for a fiscal year for humanitarian assistance; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> not later than 48 hours after the provision of such assistance, if the Secretary determines that extraordinary circumstances that affect the national security interests of the United States exist.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Status Reports</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional committees specified in subsection (g) an annual report on the provision of humanitarian assistance pursuant to this section for the prior fiscal year. The report shall be submitted each year at the time of the budget submission by the President for the next fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Each report required by paragraph (1) shall cover all provisions of law that authorize appropriations for humanitarian assistance to be available from the Department of Defense for the purposes of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> Each report under this subsection shall set forth the following information regarding activities during the previous fiscal year:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The total amount of funds obligated for humanitarian assistance under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A comprehensive list of humanitarian assistance efforts for which support was provided under this section, disaggregated by foreign partner country, amount obligated, and purpose specified in subsection (b).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> A description of the manner in which such efforts address—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the humanitarian needs of the foreign partner country; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Department of Defense objectives and broader United States national security objectives.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> A description of any transfer of nonlethal excess supplies of the Department of Defense made available for humanitarian relief purposes under <ref>section 2557 of this title</ref>, including, for each such transfer—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the date of the transfer;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the entity to which the transfer is made; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the quantity of items transferred.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report Regarding Relief for Unauthorized Countries</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In any case in which the Secretary of Defense provides for the transportation of humanitarian relief to a country to which the transportation of humanitarian relief has not been specifically authorized by law, the Secretary shall notify the congressional committees specified in subsection (g) and the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and House of Representatives of the Secretary’s intention to provide such transportation. The notification shall be submitted not less than 15 days before the commencement of such transportation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “defense authorization Act” means an Act that authorizes appropriations for one or more fiscal years for military activities of the Department of Defense, including authorizations of appropriations for the activities described in paragraph (7) of <ref>section 114(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Congressional Committees</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The congressional committees referred to in subsections (c)(1), (d)(1), and (e) are the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title III, § 304(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2361</ref>, § 2551; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XIII, § 1312</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 474</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1067(1)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 774</ref>; renumbered § 2561 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title X, § 1033(b)(1), (c)(1)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–260; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title III, § 312(d)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1430</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title X, § 1076(f)(31)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1953</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title X, § 1053(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2777</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XVII, § 1702</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2207</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2562.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1253(a)(1)(C)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2532</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2563.</num>
<heading> Articles and services of industrial facilities: sale to persons outside the Department of Defense</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority To Sell Outside DOD</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may sell in accordance with this section to a person outside the Department of Defense articles and services referred to in paragraph (2) that are not available from any United States commercial source.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Except as provided in subparagraph (B), articles and services referred to in paragraph (1) are articles and services that are manufactured or performed by any working-capital funded industrial facility of the armed forces.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The authority in this section does not apply to sales of articles and services by a working-capital funded Army industrial facility (including a Department of the Army arsenal) that manufactures large caliber cannons, gun mounts, recoil mechanisms, ammunition, munitions, or components thereof, which are governed by regulations required by <ref>section 7543 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designation of Participating Industrial Facilities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may designate facilities referred to in subsection (a) as the facilities from which articles and services manufactured or performed by such facilities may be sold under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Conditions for Sales</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> A sale of articles or services may be made under this section only if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Defense determines that the articles or services are not available from a commercial source in the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the purchaser agrees to hold harmless and indemnify the United States, except as provided in paragraph (3), from any claim for damages or injury to any person or property arising out of the articles or services;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the articles or services can be substantially manufactured or performed by the industrial facility concerned with only incidental subcontracting;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> it is in the public interest to manufacture the articles or perform the services;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the Secretary determines that the sale of the articles or services will not interfere with the military mission of the industrial facility concerned; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the sale of the goods and services is made on the basis that it will not interfere with performance of work by the industrial facility concerned for the Department of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may waive the condition in paragraph (1)(A) and subsection (a)(1) that an article or service must be not available from a United States commercial source in the case of a particular sale if the Secretary determines that the waiver is necessary for reasons of national security and notifies Congress regarding the reasons for the waiver.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Paragraph (1)(B) does not apply in any case of willful misconduct or gross negligence or in the case of a claim by a purchaser of articles or services under this section that damages or injury arose from the failure of the Government to comply with quality, schedule, or cost performance requirements in the contract to provide the articles or services.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Methods of Sale</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall permit a purchaser of articles or services under this section to use advance incremental funding to pay for the articles or services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> In the sale of articles and services under this section, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> charge the purchaser, at a minimum, the variable costs, capital improvement costs, and equipment depreciation costs that are associated with the articles or services sold;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> enter into a firm, fixed-price contract or, if agreed by the purchaser, a cost reimbursement contract for the sale; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> develop and maintain (from sources other than appropriated funds) working capital to be available for paying design costs, planning costs, procurement costs, and other costs associated with the articles or services sold.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Deposit of Proceeds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Proceeds from sales of articles and services under this section shall be credited to the funds, including working capital funds and operation and maintenance funds, incurring the costs of manufacture or performance.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Relationship to Arms Export Control Act</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section shall be construed to affect the application of the export controls provided for in section 38 of the Arms Export Control Act (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2778</ref>) to items which incorporate or are produced through the use of an article sold under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The term “advance incremental funding”, with respect to a sale of articles or services, means a series of partial payments for the articles or services that includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> one or more partial payments before the commencement of work or the incurring of costs in connection with the manufacture of the articles or the performance of the services, as the case may be; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> subsequent progress payments that result in full payment being completed as the required work is being completed.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “not available”, with respect to an article or service proposed to be sold under this section, means that the article or service is unavailable from a commercial source in the required quantity and quality or within the time required.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The term “variable costs”, with respect to sales of articles or services, means the costs that are expected to fluctuate directly with the volume of sales and—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the case of articles, the volume of production necessary to satisfy the sales orders; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of services, the extent of the services sold.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title III, § 339(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2718</ref>, § 2553; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title III, § 331(a)(2)</ref>, (b), <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 566</ref>, 567; renumbered § 2563, <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title X, § 1033(b)(1)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–260; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title III, § 343(a)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1061</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 809(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1840</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2564.</num>
<heading> Provision of support for certain sporting events</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Security and Safety Assistance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>At the request of a Federal, State, or local government agency responsible for providing law enforcement services, security services, or safety services, the Secretary of Defense may authorize the commander of a military installation or other facility of the Department of Defense or the commander of a specified or unified combatant command to provide assistance for the World Cup Soccer Games, the Goodwill Games, the Olympics, and any other civilian sporting event in support of essential security and safety at such event, but only if the Attorney General certifies that such assistance is necessary to meet essential security and safety needs.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Other Assistance</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense may authorize a commander referred to in subsection (a) to provide assistance for a sporting event referred to in that subsection in support of other needs relating to such event, but only—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to the extent that such needs cannot reasonably be met by a source other than the Department;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to the extent that the provision of such assistance does not adversely affect the military preparedness of the armed forces; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> if the organization requesting such assistance agrees to reimburse the Department for amounts expended by the Department in providing the assistance in accordance with the provisions of <ref>section 277 of this title</ref> and other applicable provisions of law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inapplicability to Certain Events</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subsections (a) and (b) do not apply to the following sporting events:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Sporting events for which funds have been appropriated before <date date="1996-09-23">September 23, 1996</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Special Olympics.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Paralympics.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> A sporting event sanctioned by the United States Olympic Committee through the Paralympic Military Program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> Any national or international paralympic sporting event (other than a sporting event described in paragraphs (1) through (4))—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is held in the United States or any of its territories or commonwealths;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> is governed by the International Paralympic Committee; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> is sanctioned by the United States Olympic Committee;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for which participation exceeds 100 amateur athletes; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> in which at least 10 percent of the athletes participating in the sporting event are members or former members of the armed forces who are participating in the sporting event based upon an injury or wound incurred in the line of duty in the armed force and veterans who are participating in the sporting event based upon a service-connected disability.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Terms and Conditions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may require such terms and conditions in connection with the provision of assistance under this section as the Secretary considers necessary and appropriate to protect the interests of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Relationship to Other Laws</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Assistance provided under this section shall be subject to the provisions of sections 275 and 276 of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Funding for Support of Certain Events</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Amounts for the provision of support for a sporting event described in paragraph (4) or (5) of subsection (c) may be derived from the Support for International Sporting Competitions, Defense account established by section 5802 of the Omnibus Consolidated Appropriations Act, 1997 (<ref>Public Law 104–208</ref>; <ref>10 U.S.C. 2564</ref> note), notwithstanding any limitation under that section relating to the availability of funds in such account for the provision of support for international sporting competitions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The total amount expended for any fiscal year to provide support for sporting events described in subsection (c)(5) may not exceed $1,000,000.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title III, § 367(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2496</ref>, § 2554; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title X, § 1073(a)(56)</ref>, (c)(2)(A), <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1903</ref>, 1904; renumbered § 2564, <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title X, § 1033(b)(1)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–260; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title III, § 372(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 81</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title X, § 1051(a)(20)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1561</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2564a.</num>
<heading> Provision of assistance for adaptive sports programs: members of the armed forces; certain veterans</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Program Authorized</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Defense may establish a military adaptive sports program to support the provision of adaptive sports programming for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any member of the armed forces who is eligible to participate in adaptive sports because of an injury, illness, or wound incurred in the line of duty in the armed forces; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> any veteran (as defined in <ref>section 101 of title 38</ref>), during the one-year period following the veteran’s date of separation, who—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is on the Temporary Disability Retirement List or Permanently Disabled Retirement List;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> is eligible to participate in adaptive sports because of an injury, illness, or wound incurred in the line of duty in the armed forces; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> was enrolled in the program authorized under this section prior to the veteran’s date of separation.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> In establishing the military adaptive sports program, the Secretary of Defense shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> consult with the Secretary of Veterans Affairs; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> avoid duplicating programs conducted by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs under <ref>section 521A of title 38</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Provision of Assistance; Purpose</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Under such criteria as the Secretary of Defense may establish under the military adaptive sports program, the Secretary may award grants to, or enter into contracts and cooperative agreements with, entities for the purpose of planning, developing, managing, and implementing adaptive sports programming for members and veterans described in subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall use competitive procedures to award any grant or to enter into any contract or cooperative agreement under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of Assistance</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Assistance provided under the military adaptive sports program shall be used—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> for the purposes specified in subsection (b); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> for such related activities and expenses as the Secretary of Defense may authorize.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title V, § 589(a)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1437</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title V, § 592(a)</ref>–(c)(1), <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1414</ref>, 1415.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2565.</num>
<heading> Nuclear test monitoring equipment: furnishing to foreign governments</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority To Transfer Title to or Otherwise Provide Nuclear Test Monitoring Equipment</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subject to subsection (b), the Secretary of Defense may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> transfer title or otherwise provide to a foreign government (A) equipment for the monitoring of nuclear test explosions, and (B) associated equipment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> as part of any such conveyance or provision of equipment, install such equipment on foreign territory or in international waters; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> inspect, test, maintain, repair, or replace any such equipment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Agreement Required</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Nuclear test explosion monitoring equipment may be provided to a foreign government under subsection (a) only pursuant to the terms of an agreement between the United States and the foreign government receiving the equipment in which the recipient foreign government agrees—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to provide the United States with timely access to the data produced, collected, or generated by the equipment; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to permit the Secretary of Defense to take such measures as the Secretary considers necessary to inspect, test, maintain, repair, or replace that equipment, including access for purposes of such measures.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Promptly after entering into any agreement under subsection (b), the Secretary of Defense shall submit to Congress a report on the agreement. The report shall identify the country with which the agreement was made, the anticipated costs to the United States to be incurred under the agreement, and the national interest of the United States that is furthered by the agreement.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Delegation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may delegate the authority of the Secretary to carry out this section only to the Secretary of the Air Force. Such a delegation may be redelegated.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title XII, § 1203(a)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–324, § 2555; renumbered § 2565 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title XII, § 1201(a)(1)</ref>, (b), <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1245</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2566.</num>
<heading> Space and services: provision to military welfare societies</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority To Provide Space and Services</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary concerned may provide, without charge, space and services under the jurisdiction of that Secretary to a military welfare society.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The term “military welfare society” means the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Army Emergency Relief Society.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Navy-Marine Corps Relief Society.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The Air Force Aid Society, Inc.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The Coast Guard Mutual Assistance.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “services” includes lighting, heating, cooling, electricity, office furniture, office machines and equipment, telephone and other information technology services (including installation of lines and equipment, connectivity, and other associated services), and security systems (including installation and other associated expenses).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title X, § 1066(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2656</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title X, § 1043</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1903</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2567.</num>
<heading> Space and services: provision to WIC offices</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Allotment of Space and Provision of Services Authorized</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Upon application by a WIC office, the Secretary of a military department may allot space on a military installation under the jurisdiction of the Secretary to the WIC office without charge for rent or services if the Secretary determines that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the WIC office provides or will provide services solely to members of the armed forces assigned to the installation, civilian employees of the Department of Defense employed at the installation, or dependents of such members or employees;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> space is available on the installation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> operation of the WIC office will not hinder military mission requirements; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the security situation at the installation permits the presence of a non-Federal entity on the installation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “services” includes the provision of lighting, heating, cooling, and electricity.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “WIC office” means a local agency (as defined in subsection (b)(6) of section 17 of the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 1786</ref>)) that participates in the special supplemental nutrition program for women, infants, and children under such section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2812(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2716</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2568.</num>
<heading> Retention of combat uniforms by members deployed in support of contingency operations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of a military department may authorize a member of the armed forces under the jurisdiction of the Secretary who has been deployed in support of a contingency operation for at least 30 days to retain, after that member is no longer so deployed, the combat uniform issued to that member as organizational clothing and individual equipment.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title III, § 376(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 84</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2568a.</num>
<heading> Damaged personal protective equipment: award to members separating from the Armed Forces and veterans</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of a military department, acting through a disposition service distribution center of the Defense Logistics Agency, may award to a covered individual the demilitarized PPE of that covered individual. The award of PPE under this section shall be without cost to the covered individual.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The term “covered individual” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> a member of the armed forces—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> under the jurisdiction of the Secretary concerned; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> who is separating from the armed forces; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a veteran who was under the jurisdiction of the Secretary concerned while a member of the armed forces.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The term “PPE” means personal protective equipment that was damaged in combat or otherwise—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> during the deployment of a covered individual; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> after <date date="2001-09-11">September 11, 2001</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VI, § 623(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1800</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>