<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 301—</num>
<heading>RESEARCH AND ENGINEERING GENERALLY</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>GENERAL</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4001.</num>
<heading> Research and development projects</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of a military department may engage in basic research, applied research, advanced research, and development projects that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> are necessary to the responsibilities of such Secretary’s department in the field of research and development; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> either—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> relate to weapon systems and other military needs; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> are of potential interest to the Department of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authorized Means</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of a military department may perform research and development projects—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> by contract, cooperative agreement, or grant, in accordance with chapter 63 of title 31;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> through one or more military departments;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> by using employees and consultants of the Department of Defense;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> by mutual agreement with the head of any other department or agency of the Federal Government;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> by transactions (other than contracts, cooperative agreements, and grants) entered into pursuant to section 4021 or 4022 of this title; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> by purchases through procurement for experimental purposes pursuant to <ref>section 4023 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirement of Potential Department of Defense Interest</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Funds appropriated to the Department of Defense or to a military department may not be used to finance any research project or study unless the project or study is, in the opinion of the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of that military department, respectively, of potential interest to the Department of Defense or to such military department, respectively.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Additional Provisions Applicable to Cooperative Agreements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Additional authorities, conditions, and requirements relating to certain cooperative agreements authorized by this section are provided in sections 4021 and 4026 of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 87–651, title II, § 208(a)</ref>, <date date="1962-09-07">Sept. 7, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 523</ref>, § 2358; amended <ref>Pub. L. 97–86, title IX, § 910</ref>, <date date="1981-12-01">Dec. 1, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1120</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–370, § 1(g)(3)</ref>, <date date="1988-07-19">July 19, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 846</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title VIII, § 827(a)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1712</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–355, title I, § 1301(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3284</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title II, § 267(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2468</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title VIII, § 862</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1494</ref>; renumbered § 4001 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1841(b)(1)</ref>, (2)(A), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4243</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(u)(2)(B)</ref>, (C), (F)(i)(I), (II), <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2151</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§§ 4002, 4003.</num>
<heading> Omitted]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4004.</num>
<heading> Contract authority for development and demonstration of initial or additional prototype units</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A contract initially awarded from the competitive selection of a proposal resulting from a general solicitation referred to in <ref>section 3012(2) of this title</ref> may contain a contract line item or contract option for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the development and demonstration or initial production of technology developed under the contract; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the delivery of initial or additional items if the item or a prototype thereof is created as the result of work performed under the contract.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Limitations.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Minimal amount</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A contract line item or contract option described in subsection (a)(2) shall require the delivery of the minimal amount of initial or additional items to allow for the timely competitive solicitation and award of a follow-on development or production contract for those items.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Term</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A contract line item or contract option described in subsection (a) shall be for a term of not more than 2 years.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Dollar value of work</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The dollar value of the work to be performed pursuant to a contract line item or contract option described in subsection (a) may not exceed $100,000,000, in fiscal year 2017 constant dollars.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Applicability</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The authority provided in subsection (a) applies only to the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of the Army, the Secretary of the Navy, and the Secretary of the Air Force.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Procedures</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall establish procedures to collect and analyze information on the use and benefits of the authority under this section and related impacts on performance, affordability, and capability delivery.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title VIII, § 861(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1493</ref>, § 2302e; renumbered § 4004 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title VIII, § 831(a)</ref>, title XVIII, §§ 1818(c), 1841(b)(1), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3753</ref>, 4243; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1841(b)(2)(D)</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(u)(2)(F)(i)(V)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2152</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(u)(2)(B)</ref>, (v)(1)(A), <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2151</ref>, 2154.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4007.</num>
<heading> Science and technology programs to be conducted so as to foster the transition of science and technology to higher levels of research, development, test, and evaluation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Policy</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each official specified in subsection (b) shall ensure that the management and conduct of the science and technology programs under the authority of that official are carried out in a manner that will foster the transition of science and technology to higher levels of research, development, test, and evaluation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered Officials</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subsection (a) applies to the following officials of the Department of Defense:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of each military department.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Director of the Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The directors and heads of other offices and agencies of the Department of Defense with assigned research, development, test, and evaluation responsibilities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title IX, § 904(a)(1)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–225, § 2359; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title IX, § 902(55)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1549</ref>; renumbered § 4007, <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1841(b)(1)</ref>, (c), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4243</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(u)(2)(B)</ref>, (D), <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2151</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§§ 4008, 4009.</num>
<heading> Omitted]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4010.</num>
<heading> Defense Established Program to Stimulate Competitive Research</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Program Required</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense, acting through the Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering, shall carry out a Defense Established Program to Stimulate Competitive Research (DEPSCoR) as part of the university research programs of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Program Objectives</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The objectives of the program are as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> To increase the number of university researchers in eligible States capable of performing science and engineering research responsive to the needs of the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> To enhance the capabilities of institutions of higher education in eligible States to develop, plan, and execute science and engineering research that is relevant to the mission of the Department of Defense and competitive under the peer-review systems used for awarding Federal research assistance.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> To increase the probability of long-term growth in the competitively awarded financial assistance that institutions of higher education in eligible States receive from the Federal Government for science and engineering research.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Program Activities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In order to achieve the program objectives, the following activities are authorized under the program:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Competitive award of grants for research and instrumentation to support such research.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Competitive award of financial assistance for graduate students.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> To provide assistance to science and engineering researchers at institutions of higher education in eligible States through collaboration between Department of Defense laboratories and such researchers.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Any other activities that are determined necessary to further the achievement of the objectives of the program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Eligible States</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering shall designate which States are eligible States for the purposes of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Under Secretary shall designate a State as an eligible State if, as determined by the Under Secretary—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the average annual amount of all Department of Defense obligations for science and engineering research and development that were in effect with institutions of higher education in the State for the three fiscal years preceding the fiscal year for which the designation is effective or for the last three fiscal years for which statistics are available is less than the amount determined by multiplying 60 percent times the amount equal to 1/50 of the total average annual amount of all Department of Defense obligations for science and engineering research and development that were in effect with institutions of higher education in the United States for such three preceding or last fiscal years, as the case may be; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the State has demonstrated a commitment to developing research bases in the State and to improving science and engineering research and education programs in areas relevant to the mission of the Department of Defense at institutions of higher education in the State.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Under Secretary shall not remove a designation of a State under paragraph (2) because the State exceeds the funding levels specified under subparagraph (A) of such paragraph unless the State has exceeded such funding levels for at least two consecutive years.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Coordination With Similar Federal Programs</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary may consult with the Director of the National Science Foundation and the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy in the planning, development, and execution of the program and may coordinate the program with the Established Program to Stimulate Competitive Research conducted by the National Science Foundation and with similar programs sponsored by other departments and agencies of the Federal Government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> All solicitations under the Defense Established Program to Stimulate Competitive Research may be made to, and all awards may be made through, the State committees established for purposes of the Established Program to Stimulate Competitive Research conducted by the National Science Foundation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A State committee referred to in paragraph (2) shall ensure that activities carried out in the State of that committee under the Defense Established Program to Stimulate Competitive Research are relevant to the mission of the Department of Defense and coordinated with the activities carried out in the State under other similar initiatives of the Federal Government to stimulate competitive research.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">State Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “State” means a State of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, the Virgin Islands, American Samoa, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title II, § 214(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1589</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4014.</num>
<heading> Coordination and communication of defense research activities and technology domain awareness</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Coordination of Department of Defense Research, Development, and Technological Data</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense shall promote, monitor, and evaluate programs for the communication and exchange of research, development, and technological data—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> among the Defense research facilities, combatant commands, and other organizations that are involved in developing for the Department of Defense the technological requirements for new items for use by combat forces;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> among Defense research facilities and other offices, agencies, and bureaus in the Department that are engaged in related technological matters;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> among other research facilities and other departments or agencies of the Federal Government that are engaged in research, development, and technological matters;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> among private commercial, research institution, and university entities engaged in research, development, and technological matters potentially relevant to defense on a voluntary basis;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to the extent practicable, to achieve full awareness of scientific and technological advancement and innovation wherever it may occur, whether funded by the Department of Defense, another element of the Federal Government, or other entities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> through development and distribution of clear technical communications to the public, military operators, acquisition organizations, and civilian and military decision-makers that convey successes of research and engineering activities supported by the Department and the contributions of such activities to support national needs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Defense Research Facility Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “Defense research facility” has the meaning given that term by <ref>section 4125(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1841(d)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4243</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(u)(2)(E)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2151</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XVIII, § 1801(a)(30)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 685</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 4015.</num>
<heading> Omitted]</heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>AGREEMENTS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4021.</num>
<heading> Research projects: transactions other than contracts and grants</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Additional Forms of Transactions Authorized</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of each military department may enter into transactions (other than contracts, cooperative agreements, and grants) under the authority of this subsection in carrying out basic, applied, and advanced research projects. The authority under this subsection is in addition to the authority provided in <ref>section 4001 of this title</ref> to use contracts, cooperative agreements, and grants in carrying out such projects.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exercise of Authority by Secretary of Defense</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In any exercise of the authority in subsection (a), the Secretary of Defense shall act through the Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency, the Defense Innovation Unit, or any other element of the Department of Defense that the Secretary may designate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Advance Payments</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The authority provided under subsection (a) may be exercised without regard to <ref>section 3324 of title 31</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Recovery of Funds</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A cooperative agreement for performance of basic, applied, or advanced research authorized by <ref>section 4001 of this title</ref> and a transaction authorized by subsection (a) may include a clause that requires a person or other entity to make payments to the Department of Defense or any other department or agency of the Federal Government as a condition for receiving support under the agreement or other transaction.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The amount of any payment received by the Federal Government pursuant to a requirement imposed under paragraph (1) may be credited, to the extent authorized by the Secretary of Defense, to the appropriate account established under subsection (f). Amounts so credited shall be merged with other funds in the account and shall be available for the same purposes and the same period for which other funds in such account are available.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Conditions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to the maximum extent practicable, no cooperative agreement containing a clause under subsection (d) and no transaction entered into under subsection (a) provides for research that duplicates research being conducted under existing programs carried out by the Department of Defense; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to the extent that the Secretary determines practicable, the funds provided by the Government under a cooperative agreement containing a clause under subsection (d) or a transaction authorized by subsection (a) do not exceed the total amount provided by other parties to the cooperative agreement or other transaction.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Support Accounts</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is hereby established on the books of the Treasury separate accounts for each of the military departments, the Defense Innovation Unit, and the Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency for support of research projects and development projects provided for in cooperative agreements containing a clause under subsection (d) and research projects provided for in transactions entered into under subsection (a). Funds in those accounts shall be available for the payment of such support.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Education and Training</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> ensure that management, technical, and contracting personnel of the Department of Defense involved in the award or administration of transactions under this section or other innovative forms of contracting are afforded opportunities for adequate education and training; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> establish minimum levels and requirements for continuous and experiential learning for such personnel, including levels and requirements for acquisition certification programs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Guidance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall issue guidance to carry out this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Protection of Certain Information From Disclosure</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Disclosure of information described in paragraph (2) is not required, and may not be compelled, under <ref>section 552 of title 5</ref> for five years after the date on which the information is received by the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Paragraph (1) applies to information described in subparagraph (B) that is in the records of the Department of Defense if the information was submitted to the Department in a competitive or noncompetitive process having the potential for resulting in an award, to the party submitting the information, of a cooperative agreement for performance of basic, applied, or advanced research authorized by <ref>section 4001 of this title</ref> or another transaction authorized by subsection (a).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> The information referred to in subparagraph (A) is the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> A proposal, proposal abstract, and supporting documents.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> A business plan submitted on a confidential basis.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Technical information submitted on a confidential basis.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title II, § 251(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1403</ref>, § 2371; amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XIV, § 1484(k)(9)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1719</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title VIII, § 826</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1442</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title II, § 217</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2352</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–35, title II, § 201(c)(4)</ref>, <date date="1993-05-31">May 31, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 98</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title VIII, § 827(b)</ref>, title XI, § 1182(a)(6), <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1712</ref>, 1771; <ref>Pub. L. 103–355, title I, § 1301(b)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3285</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1502(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 502</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title II, § 267(a)</ref>–(c)(1)(A), title X, § 1073(e)(1)(B), <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2467</ref>, 2468, 2658; <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title VIII, § 832</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1842</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title VIII, § 817</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2089</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1067(1)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 774</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title X, § 1031(a)(19)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1597</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title X, § 1071(f)(20)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3511</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title VIII, § 863</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1494</ref>; renumbered § 4021 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1841(b)(1)</ref>, (2)(B), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4243</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title VIII, § 821(a)</ref>, title XVII, § 1701(u)(2)(B), (F)(i)(III), <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1825</ref>, 2151; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title IX, § 913(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 367</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4022.</num>
<heading> Authority of the Department of Defense to carry out certain prototype projects</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Subject to paragraph (2), the Director of the Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency, the Director of the Defense Innovation Unit, the Secretary of a military department, or any other official designated by the Secretary of Defense may, under the authority of <ref>section 4021 of this title</ref>, carry out prototype projects that are directly relevant to enhancing the mission effectiveness of personnel of the Department of Defense or improving platforms, systems, components, or materials proposed to be acquired or developed by the Department of Defense, or to improvement of platforms, systems, components, or materials in use by the armed forces.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The authority of this section—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> may be exercised for a transaction for a prototype project that is expected to cost the Department of Defense in excess of $100,000,000 but not in excess of $500,000,000 (including all options) only upon a written determination by the head of the contracting activity, or, for the Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency, the Defense Innovation Unit, or the Missile Defense Agency, the director of the agency that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the requirements of subsection (d) will be met; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the use of the authority of this section is essential to promoting the success of the prototype project;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> may be exercised for a transaction for a prototype project that is expected to cost the Department of Defense in excess of $500,000,000 (including all options) only if—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> the senior procurement executive for the agency as designated for the purpose of <ref>section 1702(c) of title 41</ref>, or, for the Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency, the Defense Innovation Unit, or the Missile Defense Agency, the director of the agency, determines in writing that—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the requirements of subsection (d) will be met; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the use of the authority of this section is essential to meet critical national security objectives; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the congressional defense committees are notified in writing at least 30 days before such authority is exercised; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> may be exercised for a transaction for a follow-on production contract or transaction that is awarded pursuant to subsection (f) and expected to cost the Department of Defense in excess of $100,000,000 (including all options) only if a covered official—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> determines in writing that—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the requirements of subsection (d) were met for the prior transaction for the prototype project that provided for the award of the follow-on production contract or transaction, and the requirements of subsection (f) will be met; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the use of the authority of this section is essential to meet critical national security objectives; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> notifies the congressional defense committees in writing of the determinations required under clause (i) at the time such authority is exercised.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The authority of the head of the contracting activity, director of the Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency, director of the Defense Innovation Unit, director of the Missile Defense Agency, or the senior procurement executive, as applicable, under paragraph (2) may not be delegated.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Exercise of Authority.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Subsection (e)(2) of such section 4021 shall not apply to projects carried out under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> To the maximum extent practicable, competitive procedures shall be used when entering into agreements to carry out the prototype projects under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Comptroller General Access to Information</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Each agreement entered into by an official referred to in subsection (a) to carry out a project under that subsection that provides for payments in a total amount in excess of $5,000,000 shall include a clause that provides for the Comptroller General, in the discretion of the Comptroller General, to examine the records of any party to the agreement or any entity that participates in the performance of the agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The requirement in paragraph (1) shall not apply with respect to a party or entity, or a subordinate element of a party or entity, that has not entered into any other agreement that provides for audit access by a Government entity in the year prior to the date of the agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The right provided to the Comptroller General in a clause of an agreement under paragraph (1) is limited as provided in subparagraph (B) in the case of a party to the agreement, an entity that participates in the performance of the agreement, or a subordinate element of that party or entity if the only agreements or other transactions that the party, entity, or subordinate element entered into with Government entities in the year prior to the date of that agreement are cooperative agreements or transactions that were entered into under this section or <ref>section 4021 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The only records of a party, other entity, or subordinate element referred to in subparagraph (A) that the Comptroller General may examine in the exercise of the right referred to in that subparagraph are records of the same type as the records that the Government has had the right to examine under the audit access clauses of the previous agreements or transactions referred to in such subparagraph that were entered into by that particular party, entity, or subordinate element.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The head of the contracting activity that is carrying out the agreement may waive the applicability of the requirement in paragraph (1) to the agreement if the head of the contracting activity determines that it would not be in the public interest to apply the requirement to the agreement. The waiver shall be effective with respect to the agreement only if the head of the contracting activity transmits a notification of the waiver to Congress and the Comptroller General before entering into the agreement. The notification shall include the rationale for the determination.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The Comptroller General may not examine records pursuant to a clause included in an agreement under paragraph (1) more than three years after the final payment is made by the United States under the agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appropriate Use of Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that no official of an agency enters into a transaction (other than a contract, grant, or cooperative agreement) for a prototype project under the authority of this section unless one of the following conditions is met:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> There is at least one nontraditional defense contractor or nonprofit research institution participating to a significant extent in the prototype project.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> All significant participants in the transaction other than the Federal Government are small businesses (including small businesses participating in a program described under section 9 of the Small Business Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 638</ref>)) or nontraditional defense contractors.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> At least one third of the total cost of the prototype project is to be paid out of funds provided by sources other than the Federal Government.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The senior procurement executive for the agency determines in writing that exceptional circumstances justify the use of a transaction that provides for innovative business arrangements or structures that would not be feasible or appropriate under a contract, or would provide an opportunity to expand the defense supply base in a manner that would not be practical or feasible under a contract.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the amounts counted for the purposes of this subsection as being provided, or to be provided, by a party to a transaction with respect to a prototype project that is entered into under this section other than the Federal Government do not include costs that were incurred before the date on which the transaction becomes effective.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> Costs that were incurred for a prototype project by a party after the beginning of negotiations resulting in a transaction (other than a contract, grant, or cooperative agreement) with respect to the project before the date on which the transaction becomes effective may be counted for purposes of this subsection as being provided, or to be provided, by the party to the transaction if and to the extent that the official responsible for entering into the transaction determines in writing that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the party incurred the costs in anticipation of entering into the transaction; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> it was appropriate for the party to incur the costs before the transaction became effective in order to ensure the successful implementation of the transaction.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The requirements of this subsection do not apply to follow-on production contracts or transactions under subsection (f).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The term “covered official” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a service acquisition executive;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Director of the Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Director of the Defense Innovation Unit;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Director of the Missile Defense Agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the Undersecretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the Undersecretary of Defense for Research and Engineering.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “nontraditional defense contractor” has the meaning given the term under <ref>section 3014 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “service acquisition executive” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 101(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “small business” means a small business concern as defined under section 3 of the Small Business Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 632</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> The term “prototype project” includes a project that addresses—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a proof of concept, model, or process, including a business process;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> reverse engineering to address obsolescence;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a pilot or novel application of commercial technologies for defense purposes;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> agile development activity;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the creation, design, development, or demonstration of operational utility; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> any combination of subparagraphs (A) through (E).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The term “follow-on production contract or transaction” means a contract or transaction to produce, sustain, or otherwise implement the results of a successfully completed prototype project for continued or expanded use by the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Follow-on Production Contracts or Transactions</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A transaction entered into under this section for a prototype project may provide for the award of a follow-on production contract or transaction to the participants in the transaction. A transaction includes all individual prototype subprojects awarded under the transaction to a consortium of United States industry and academic institutions. A follow-on production award may be provided for in a transaction entered into under this section for a prototype project, awarded with respect to such a transaction as one or more separate awards, or a combination thereof.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> A follow-on production contract or transaction provided for in a transaction under paragraph (1), one or more separate awards of follow-on production contracts or transactions with respect to a transaction described in such paragraph, or a combination thereof, may be awarded to the participants in the transaction without the use of competitive procedures, notwithstanding the requirements of chapter 221 of this title and even if explicit notification was not listed within the request for proposal for the transaction if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> competitive procedures were used for the selection of parties for participation in the transaction; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the participants in the transaction successfully completed the prototype project provided for in the transaction.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A follow-on production contract or transaction may be awarded, pursuant to this subsection, when the Department determines that an individual prototype or prototype subproject as part of a consortium is successfully completed by the participants.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Award of a follow-on production contract or transaction pursuant to the terms under this subsection is not contingent upon the successful completion of all activities within a consortium as a condition for an award for follow-on production of a successfully completed prototype or prototype subproject within that consortium.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Contracts and transactions entered into pursuant to this subsection may be awarded using the authority in subsection (a), under the authority of chapter 137 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002126">1</ref> of this title, or under such procedures, terms, and conditions as the Secretary of Defense may establish by regulation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority To Provide Prototypes and Follow-on Production Items as Government-furnished Equipment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An agreement entered into pursuant to the authority of subsection (a) or a follow-on contract or transaction entered into pursuant to the authority of subsection (f) may provide for prototypes or follow-on production items to be provided to another contractor as Government-furnished equipment.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Applicability of Procurement Ethics Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An agreement entered into under the authority of this section shall be treated as a Federal agency procurement for the purposes of chapter 21 of title 41.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Pilot Authority for Use of Other Transactions for Installation or Facility Prototyping.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of a military department may establish a pilot program under which the Secretary may, under the authority of this section, carry out prototype projects that are directly relevant to enhancing the ability of the Department of Defense to prototype the design, development, or demonstration of new construction techniques or technologies to improve military installations or facilities (as such terms are defined in <ref>section 2801 of this title</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limits</inline>.—</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> In carrying out prototype projects under the pilot program established under paragraph (1)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> not more than two prototype projects may begin to be carried out per fiscal year under such pilot program; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the aggregate value of all transactions entered into under such pilot program may not exceed $300,000,000.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The requirements of this paragraph shall not apply to projects carried out for the purpose of repairing a facility.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of amounts</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of a military department may carry out prototype projects under the pilot program established under paragraph (1) using amounts available to the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of a military department (as applicable) for military construction, operation and maintenance, or research, development, test, and evaluation, notwithstanding—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> subchapters I and III of chapter 169 of this title; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> chapters 221 and 223 of this title.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Sunset.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the authority to carry out prototype projects under the pilot program established under paragraph (1) shall terminate on <date date="2030-09-30">September 30, 2030</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Ongoing project exception</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subparagraph (A) shall not apply with respect to prototype projects being carried out under the pilot program established under paragraph (1) on the date described in subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title VIII, § 815(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 893</ref>, § 2371b; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title II, § 216</ref>, title VIII, § 864, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1328</ref>, 1494; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title II, § 211</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1674</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title XVII, § 1731(a)(46)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1814</ref>; renumbered § 4022 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII</ref>, §§ 1841(b)(1), (2)(C), 1883(b)(2), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4243</ref>, 4294; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title VIII, § 821(b)</ref>, title XVII, § 1701(u)(2)(B), (F)(i)(IV), <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1825</ref>, 2151; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title VIII</ref>, §§ 842, 843, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2717</ref>, 2718; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title VIII</ref>, §§ 821, 822(a), title IX, § 913(a), <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 326</ref>, 327, 367; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title VIII</ref>, §§ 816–818(a), <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1981</ref>, 1982.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4023.</num>
<heading> Procurement for experimental purposes</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense and the Secretaries of the military departments may each buy ordnance, signal, chemical activity, transportation, energy, medical, space-flight, telecommunications, and aeronautical supplies, including parts and accessories, and designs thereof, that the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary concerned considers necessary for experimental or test purposes in the development of the best supplies that are needed for the national defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Procedures</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Purchases under this section may be made inside or outside the United States and by contract or otherwise. Chapter 137 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002127">1</ref> of this title applies only when such purchases are made in quantities greater than necessary for experimentation, technical evaluation, assessment of operational utility, or safety or to provide a residual operational capability.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title VIII, § 822(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1706</ref>, § 2373; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title X, § 1070(g)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2859</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title VIII, § 812</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 395</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title VIII, § 814</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 893</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 886</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1916</ref>; renumbered § 4023, <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1841(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4243</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(u)(2)(B)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2151</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4024.</num>
<heading> Merit-based award of grants for research and development</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> It is the policy of Congress that an agency named in <ref>section 3063 of this title</ref> should not be required by legislation to award a new grant for research, development, test, or evaluation to a non-Federal Government entity. It is further the policy of Congress that any program, project, or technology identified in legislation be awarded through merit-based selection procedures.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> A provision of law may not be construed as requiring a new grant to be awarded to a specified non-Federal Government entity unless that provision of law—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> specifically refers to this subsection;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> specifically identifies the particular non-Federal Government entity involved; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> specifically states that the award to that entity is required by such provision of law in contravention of the policy set forth in subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> For purposes of this section, a grant is a new grant unless the work provided for in the grant is a continuation of the work performed by the specified entity under a preceding grant.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> This section shall not apply with respect to any grant that calls upon the National Academy of Sciences to investigate, examine, or experiment upon any subject of science or art of significance to an agency named in <ref>section 3063 of this title</ref> and to report on such matters to the Congress or any agency of the Federal Government.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–355, title VII, § 7203(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3380</ref>, § 2374; renumbered § 4024 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII</ref>, §§ 1841(b)(1), (c), 1883(b)(2), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4243</ref>, 4294; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(u)(2)(B)</ref>, (D), <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2151</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XVIII, § 1801(a)(31)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 685</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4025.</num>
<heading> Prizes for advanced technology achievements</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense, acting through the Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering, the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment, and the service acquisition executive for each military department, may carry out programs to award cash prizes and other types of prizes, including procurement contracts and other agreements, that the Secretary determines are appropriate to recognize outstanding achievements in basic, advanced, and applied research, technology development, and prototype development that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> have the potential for application to the performance of the military missions of the Department of Defense; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> demonstrate management practices that improve the schedule or performance, reduce the costs, or otherwise support the transition of technology into acquisition programs or operational use.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Competition Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each program under subsection (a) shall use a competitive process for the selection of recipients of cash prizes and for the selection of recipients of procurement contracts and other agreements. The process shall include the widely-advertised solicitation of submissions.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitations</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> No prize competition may result in the award of a prize with a fair market value of more than $10,000,000 without the approval of the Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> No prize competition may result in the award of more than $1,000,000 in cash prizes without the approval of the Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> No prize competition may result in the award of a solely nonmonetary prize with a fair market value of more than $10,000 without the approval of the Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Relationship to Other Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A program under subsection (a) may be carried out in conjunction with or in addition to the exercise of any other authority of an official referred to in that subsection.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Acceptance of Funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In addition to such sums as may be appropriated or otherwise made available to the Secretary to award prizes under this section, the Secretary may accept funds or nonmonetary items from other departments and agencies of the Federal Government, from State and local governments, and from the private sector, to award prizes under this section. The Secretary may not give any special consideration to any private sector entity in return for a donation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of Prize Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Use of prize authority under this section shall be considered the use of competitive procedures for the purposes of chapter 221 of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Congressional Notice.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 15 days after a procurement contract or other agreement that exceeds a fair market value of $10,000,000 is awarded under the authority under a program under subsection (a), the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees written notice of such award.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contents</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each notice submitted under paragraph (1) shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the value of the relevant procurement contract or other agreement, as applicable, including all options;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> if applicable, a summary of the management practice that contributed to an improvement to schedule or performance or a reduction in cost relating to the transition of technology;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> an identification of any program executive officer (as defined in <ref>section 1737 of this title</ref>) responsible for implementation or oversight of research results, technology development, prototype development, or management practices (as applicable) for which an award was made under this section, and a brief summary of lessons learned by such program executive officer in carrying out such implementation or oversight;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a brief description of the research result, technology development, or prototype for which such procurement contract or other agreement, as applicable, was awarded; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> an explanation of the benefit to the performance of the military mission of the Department of Defense resulting from the award.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title II, § 244(a)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 552</ref>, § 2374a; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title II, § 248(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2502</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title X, § 1031(a)(20)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1598</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title II, § 257</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3184</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title II, § 212</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2119</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title II, § 253</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2243</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title IX, § 901(j)(4)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4324</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title II, § 263</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 726</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title II, § 211</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3324</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title X, § 1079(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 999</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title X, § 1081(c)(6)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2420</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title II, § 213</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1324</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title X, § 1081(a)(21)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1984</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title II, § 215</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1257</ref>; renumbered § 4025 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII</ref>, §§ 1841(b)(1), 1842(b), 1883(b)(2), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4244</ref>, 4294; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title VIII, § 822</ref>, title XVII, § 1701(q)(1), (u)(2)(B), (3)(B), <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1825</ref>, 2148, 2151, 2152; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title VIII, § 844</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2719</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4026.</num>
<heading> Cooperative research and development agreements under Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Defense, in carrying out research projects through the Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency, and the Secretary of each military department, in carrying out research projects, may permit the director of any federally funded research and development center to enter into cooperative research and development agreements with any person, any agency or instrumentality of the United States, any unit of State or local government, and any other entity under the authority granted by section 12 of the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 (<ref>15 U.S.C. 3710a</ref>). Technology may be transferred to a non-Federal party to such an agreement consistent with the provisions of sections 11 and 12 of such Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 3710</ref>, 3710a).</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added and amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title II, § 267(c)(1)(A)</ref>, (B), <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2468</ref>, § 2371a; <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title X, § 1073(a)(50)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1903</ref>; renumbered § 4026 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII</ref>, §§ 1841(b)(1), 1844(b)(1), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4243</ref>, 4245; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(u)(2)(B)</ref>, (5)(B), <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2151</ref>, 2154.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4027.</num>
<heading> Disclosure requirements for recipients of research and development funds</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in subsections (b) and (c), an individual or entity (including a State or local government) that uses funds received from the Department of Defense to carry out research or development activities shall include, in any public document pertaining to such activities, a clear statement indicating the dollar amount of the funds received from the Department for such activities.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The disclosure requirement under subsection (a) shall not apply to a public document consisting of fewer than 280 characters.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Waiver</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may waive the disclosure requirement under subsection (a) on a case-by-case basis.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Public Document Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “public document” means any document or other written statement made available for public reference or use, regardless of whether such document or statement is made available in hard copy or electronic format.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title II, § 212(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3456</ref>, § 2374b; renumbered § 4027, <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(e)(4)(A)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2139</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>