<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 859—</num>
<heading>PROFESSIONAL MILITARY EDUCATION SCHOOLS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 8591.</num>
<heading> Degree granting authority for Naval War College</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of the Navy, the President of the Naval War College may, upon the recommendation of the faculty of the Naval War College components, confer appropriate degrees upon graduates who meet the degree requirements.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A degree may not be conferred under this section unless—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Education has recommended approval of the degree in accordance with the Federal Policy Governing Granting of Academic Degrees by Federal Agencies; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Naval War College is accredited by the appropriate civilian academic accrediting agency or organization to award the degree, as determined by the Secretary of Education.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Congressional Notification Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> When seeking to establish degree granting authority under this section, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and House of Representatives—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a copy of the self assessment questionnaire required by the Federal Policy Governing Granting of Academic Degrees by Federal Agencies, at the time the assessment is submitted to the Department of Education’s National Advisory Committee on Institutional Quality and Integrity; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the subsequent recommendations and rationale of the Secretary of Education regarding the establishment of the degree granting authority.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Upon any modification or redesignation of existing degree granting authority, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and House of Representatives a report containing the rationale for the proposed modification or redesignation and any subsequent recommendation of the Secretary of Education on the proposed modification or redesignation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and House of Representatives a report containing an explanation of any action by the appropriate academic accrediting agency or organization not to accredit the Naval War College to award any new or existing degree.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title IX, § 912(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1626</ref>, § 7101; amended <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title V, § 543(f)(1), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4461</ref>; renumbered § 8591, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8592.</num>
<heading> Degree granting authority for Marine Corps University</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of the Navy, the President of the Marine Corps University may, upon the recommendation of the directors and faculty of the Marine Corps University, confer appropriate degrees upon graduates who meet the degree requirements.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A degree may not be conferred under this section unless—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Education has recommended approval of the degree in accordance with the Federal Policy Governing Granting of Academic Degrees by Federal Agencies; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Marine Corps University is accredited by the appropriate civilian academic accrediting agency or organization to award the degree, as determined by the Secretary of Education.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Congressional Notification Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> When seeking to establish degree granting authority under this section, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and House of Representatives—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a copy of the self assessment questionnaire required by the Federal Policy Governing Granting of Academic Degrees by Federal Agencies, at the time the assessment is submitted to the Department of Education’s National Advisory Committee on Institutional Quality and Integrity; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the subsequent recommendations and rationale of the Secretary of Education regarding the establishment of the degree granting authority.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Upon any modification or redesignation of existing degree granting authority, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and House of Representatives a report containing the rationale for the proposed modification or redesignation and any subsequent recommendation of the Secretary of Education on the proposed modification or redesignation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and House of Representatives a report containing an explanation of any action by the appropriate academic accrediting agency or organization not to accredit the Marine Corps University to award any new or existing degree.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Board of Advisors</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the Navy shall establish a board of advisors for the Marine Corps University. The Secretary shall ensure that the board is established so as to meet all requirements of the appropriate regional accrediting association.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title IX, § 911(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2828</ref>, § 7102; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title V, § 532(a)</ref>–(b)(3)(A), (c)(1), <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1104</ref>, 1105; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title V, § 531(a)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1472</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title X, § 1084(d)(31)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2063</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title V, § 543(g)(1), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4462</ref>; renumbered § 8592, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8593.</num>
<heading> Naval War College: acceptance of grants for faculty research for scientific, literary, and educational purposes</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Acceptance of Research Grants</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the Navy may authorize the President of the Naval War College to accept qualifying research grants. Any such grant may only be accepted if the work under the grant is to be carried out by a professor or instructor of the College for a scientific, literary, or educational purpose.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Qualifying Grants</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A qualifying research grant under this section is a grant that is awarded on a competitive basis by an entity referred to in subsection (c) for a research project with a scientific, literary, or educational purpose.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Entities From Which Grants May Be Accepted</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A grant may be accepted under this section only from a corporation, fund, foundation, educational institution, or similar entity that is organized and operated primarily for scientific, literary, or educational purposes.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Administration of Grant Funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall establish an account for administering funds received as research grants under this section. The President of the Naval War College shall use the funds in the account in accordance with applicable provisions of the regulations and the terms and condition of the grants received.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Related Expenses</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to such limitations as may be provided in appropriations Acts, appropriations available for the Naval War College may be used to pay expenses incurred by the College in applying for, and otherwise pursuing, the award of qualifying research grants.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall prescribe regulations for the administration of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title V, § 522(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3242</ref>, § 7103; renumbered § 8593, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8594.</num>
<heading> Marine Corps University: acceptance of grants for faculty research for scientific, literary, and educational purposes</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Acceptance of Research Grants</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the Navy may authorize the President of the Marine Corps University to accept qualifying research grants. Any such grant may only be accepted if the work under the grant is to be carried out by a professor or instructor of one of the institutions comprising the University for a scientific, literary, or educational purpose.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Qualifying Grants</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A qualifying research grant under this section is a grant that is awarded on a competitive basis by an entity referred to in subsection (c) for a research project with a scientific, literary, or educational purpose.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Entities From Which Grants May Be Accepted</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A grant may be accepted under this section only from a corporation, fund, foundation, educational institution, or similar entity that is organized and operated primarily for scientific, literary, or educational purposes.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Administration of Grant Funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall establish an account for administering funds received as research grants under this section. The President of the Marine Corps University shall use the funds in the account in accordance with applicable provisions of the regulations and the terms and condition of the grants received.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Related Expenses</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to such limitations as may be provided in appropriations Acts, appropriations available for the Marine Corps University may be used to pay expenses incurred by the University in applying for, and otherwise pursuing, the award of qualifying research grants.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall prescribe regulations for the administration of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title V, § 522(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3242</ref>, § 7104; renumbered § 8594, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8595.</num>
<heading> United States Naval Community College: establishment and degree granting authority</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment and Function</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>There is a United States Naval Community College. The primary function of such College shall be to provide—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> programs of academic instruction and professional and technical education for individuals described in subsection (b) in—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> academic and technical fields of the liberal arts and sciences which are relevant to the current and future needs of the Navy and Marine Corps, including in designated fields of national and economic importance such as cybersecurity, artificial intelligence, machine learning, data science, and software engineering; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> their practical duties;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> remedial, developmental, or continuing education programs, as prescribed by the Secretary of the Navy, which are necessary to support, maintain, or extend programs under paragraph (1);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> support and advisement services for individuals pursuing such programs; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> continuous monitoring of the progress of such individuals.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Individuals Eligible for Programs</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subject to such other eligibility requirements as the Secretary of the Navy may prescribe, the following individuals are eligible to participate in programs and services under subsection (a):</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Enlisted members of the Navy and Marine Corps.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Officers of the Navy and Marine Corps who hold a commission but have not completed a postsecondary degree.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Civilian employees of the Department of the Navy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> Other individuals, as determined by the Secretary of the Navy, so long as access to programs and services under subsection (a) by such individuals is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in alignment with the mission of the United States Naval Community College; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> determined to support the mission or needs of the Department of the Navy.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Degree and Credential Granting Authority.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of the Navy, the head of the United States Naval Community College may, upon the recommendation of the directors and faculty of the College, confer appropriate degrees or academic credentials upon graduates who meet the degree or credential requirements.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A degree or credential may not be conferred under this subsection unless—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Education has recommended approval of the degree or credential in accordance with the Federal Policy Governing Granting of Academic Degrees by Federal Agencies; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the United States Naval Community College is accredited by the appropriate civilian academic accrediting agency or organization to award the degree or credential, as determined by the Secretary of Education.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Congressional notification requirements.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> When seeking to establish degree or credential granting authority under this subsection, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and House of Representatives—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a copy of the self assessment questionnaire required by the Federal Policy Governing Granting of Academic Degrees by Federal Agencies, at the time the assessment is submitted to the Department of Education’s National Advisory Committee on Institutional Quality and Integrity; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the subsequent recommendations and rationale of the Secretary of Education regarding the establishment of the degree or credential granting authority.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Upon any modification or redesignation of existing degree or credential granting authority, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and House of Representatives a report containing the rationale for the proposed modification or redesignation and any subsequent recommendation of the Secretary of Education on the proposed modification or redesignation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and House of Representatives a report containing an explanation of any action by the appropriate academic accrediting agency or organization not to accredit the United States Naval Community College to award any new or existing degree or credential.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Civilian Faculty Members.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority of secretary</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the Navy may employ as many civilians as professors, instructors, and lecturers at the United States Naval Community College as the Secretary considers necessary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Compensation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The compensation of persons employed under this subsection shall be prescribed by the Secretary of the Navy.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title V, § 557(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1739</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>