<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 771—</num>
<heading>ISSUE OF SERVICEABLE MATERIAL OTHER THAN TO ARMED FORCES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7652.</num>
<heading> Rifles and ammunition for target practice: educational institutions having corps of cadets</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Army may lend, without expense to the United States, magazine rifles and appendages that are not of the existing service models in use at the time and that are not necessary for a proper reserve supply, to any educational institution having a uniformed corps of cadets of sufficient number for target practice. He may also issue 40 rounds of ball cartridges for each cadet for each range at which target practice is held, but not more than 120 rounds each year for each cadet participating in target practice.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The institutions to which property is lent under subsection (a) shall use it for target practice, take proper care of it and return it when required.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall prescribe regulations to carry out this section, containing such other requirements as he considers necessary to safeguard the interests of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 260</ref>, § 4652; renumbered § 7652, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 808(d)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1839</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7653.</num>
<heading> Ordnance and ordnance stores: District of Columbia high schools</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Army, under regulations to be prescribed by him, may issue to the high schools of the District of Columbia ordnance and ordnance stores required for military instruction and practice. The Secretary shall require a bond in double the value of the property issued under this section, for the care and safekeeping of that property and, except for property properly expended, for its return when required.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 261</ref>, § 4653; renumbered § 7653, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 808(d)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1839</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7654.</num>
<heading> Quartermaster supplies: military instruction camps</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Under such conditions as he may prescribe, the Secretary of the Army may issue, to any educational institution at which an Army officer is detailed as professor of military science and tactics, such quartermaster supplies as are necessary to establish and maintain a camp for the military instruction of its students. The Secretary shall require a bond in the value of the property issued under this section, for the care and safekeeping of that property and, except for property properly expended, for its return when required.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 261</ref>, § 4654; renumbered § 7654, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 808(d)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1839</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7655.</num>
<heading> Arms and ammunition: agencies and departments of the United States</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Whenever required for the protection of public money and property, the Secretary of the Army may lend arms and their accouterments, and issue ammunition, to a department or independent agency of the United States, upon request of its head. Property lent or issued under this subsection may be delivered to an officer of the department or agency designated by the head thereof, and that officer shall account for the property to the Secretary of the Army. Property lent or issued under this subsection and not properly expended shall be returned when it is no longer needed.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> The department or agency to which property is lent or issued under subsection (a) shall transfer funds to the credit of the Department of the Army to cover the costs of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> ammunition issued;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> replacing arms and accouterments that have been lost or destroyed, or cannot be repaired;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> repairing arms and accouterments returned to the Department of the Army; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> making and receiving shipments by the Department of the Army.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 261</ref>, § 4655; renumbered § 7655, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 808(d)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1839</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7656.</num>
<heading> Aircraft and equipment: civilian aviation schools</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Army, under regulations to be prescribed by him, may lend aircraft, aircraft parts, and aeronautical equipment and accessories that are required for instruction, training, and maintenance, to accredited civilian aviation schools at which personnel of the Department of the Army or the Department of the Air Force are pursuing a course of instruction and training under detail by competent orders.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 261</ref>, § 4656; <ref>Pub. L. 97–295, § 1(42)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-12">Oct. 12, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1298</ref>; renumbered § 7656, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 808(d)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1839</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7657.</num>
<heading> Sale of ammunition for avalanche-control purposes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to the needs of the Army, the Secretary of the Army may sell ammunition for military weapons which are used for avalanche-control purposes to any State (or entity of a State) or to any other non-Federal entity that has been authorized by a State to use those weapons in that State for avalanche-control purposes. Sales of ammunition under this section shall be on a reimbursable basis and shall be subject to the condition that the ammunition be used only for avalanche-control purposes.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 98–525, title XV, § 1538(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2636</ref>, § 4657; renumbered § 7657, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 808(d)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1839</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>