<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 3—</num>
<heading>GENERAL POWERS AND FUNCTIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 121.</num>
<heading> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President may prescribe regulations to carry out his functions, powers, and duties under this title.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 6</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 122.</num>
<heading> Official registers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of a military department may have published, annually or at such other times as he may designate, official registers containing the names of, and other pertinent information about, such regular and reserve officers of the armed forces under his jurisdiction as he considers appropriate. The register may also contain any other list that the Secretary considers appropriate.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 85–861, § 1(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1437</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 122a.</num>
<heading> Public availability of Department of Defense reports required by law</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>To the maximum extent practicable, on or after the date on which each report described in subsection (b) is submitted to Congress, the Secretary of Defense, acting through the Assistant to the Secretary of Defense for Public Affairs, shall ensure that the report is made available to the public by—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> posting the report on a publicly accessible Internet website of the Department of Defense; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> upon request, transmitting the report by other means, as long as such transmission is at no cost to the Department.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered Reports</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraph (2), a report described in this subsection is any report that is required by law to be submitted to Congress by the Secretary of Defense, or by any element of the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> A report otherwise described in paragraph (1) is not a report described in this subsection if the report contains—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> classified information;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> proprietary information;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> information that is exempt from disclosure under <ref>section 552 of title 5</ref> (commonly referred to as the “Freedom of Information Act”); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> any other type of information that the Secretary of Defense determines should not be made available to the public in the interest of national security.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Semi-annual Summaries</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than January 1 and July 1 of each year, the Secretary of Defense shall make publicly available on an appropriate internet website a summary of all reports submitted to Congress by the Department of Defense for the preceding six-month period that are required to be submitted by statute. Each such summary shall include, for each report covered by the summary, the title of report, the date of delivery, and the section of law under which such report is required.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title X, § 1061(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4362</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title X, § 1068</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1589</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title X, § 1081(a)</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 871</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title X, § 1081(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1594</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title X, § 1062(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1909</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 123.</num>
<heading> Authority to suspend officer personnel laws during war or national emergency</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> In time of war, or of national emergency declared by Congress or the President after <date date="1980-11-30">November 30, 1980</date>, the President may suspend the operation of any provision of law relating to the promotion, involuntary retirement, or separation of commissioned officers of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, Space Force, or Coast Guard Reserve. So long as such war or national emergency continues, any such suspension may be extended by the President.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Any such suspension shall, if not sooner ended, end on the last day of the two-year period beginning on the date on which the suspension (or the last extension thereof) takes effect or on the last day of the one-year period beginning on the date of the termination of the war or national emergency, whichever occurs first. With respect to the end of any such suspension, the preceding sentence supersedes the provisions of title II of the National Emergencies Act (<ref>50 U.S.C. 1621–162</ref>2) which provide that powers or authorities exercised by reason of a national emergency shall cease to be exercised after the date of the termination of the emergency.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> If a provision of law pertaining to the promotion of reserve officers is suspended under this section and if the Secretary of Defense submits to Congress proposed legislation to adjust the grades and dates of rank of reserve commissioned officers other than commissioned warrant officers, such proposed legislation shall, so far as practicable, be the same as that recommended for adjusting the grades and dates of rank of officers of the regular component of the armed force concerned.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Upon the termination of a suspension made under the authority of subsection (a) of a provision of law otherwise requiring the separation or retirement of officers on active duty because of age, length of service or length of service in grade, or failure of selection for promotion, the Secretary concerned shall extend by up to 90 days the otherwise required separation or retirement date of any officer covered by the suspended provision whose separation or retirement date, but for the suspension, would have been before the date of the termination of the suspension or within 90 days after the date of such termination.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 85–861, § 1(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1437</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 86–559, § 1(1)</ref>, <date date="1960-06-30">June 30, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 264</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–718, § 1</ref>, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1115</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–130, § 1(1)</ref>, <date date="1967-11-08">Nov. 8, 1967</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 374</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V</ref>, §§ 501(3), 511(1), <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2907</ref>, 2920; <ref>Pub. L. 97–22, § 10(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1981-07-10">July 10, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 137</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1622(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2961</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1501(c)(4)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 498</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title V, § 508(b)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1090</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 924(b)(2)(A)(i)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3821</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 123a.</num>
<heading> Suspension of end-strength and other strength limitations in time of war or national emergency</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">During War or National Emergency</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> If at the end of any fiscal year there is in effect a war or national emergency, the President may waive any statutory end strength with respect to that fiscal year. Any such waiver may be issued only for a statutory end strength that is prescribed by law before the waiver is issued.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> When a designation of a major disaster or emergency (as those terms are defined in section 102 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 5122</ref>)) is in effect, the President may waive any statutory limit that would otherwise apply during the period of the designation on the number of members of a reserve component or the Space Force who are authorized to be on active duty under subparagraph (A) or (B) of <ref>section 115(b)(1) of this title</ref>, if the President determines the waiver is necessary to provide assistance in responding to the major disaster or emergency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Termination of Waiver</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Upon the termination of a war or national emergency with respect to which the President has exercised the authority provided by subsection (a)(1), the President may defer the effectiveness of any statutory end strength with respect to the fiscal year during which the termination occurs. Any such deferral may not extend beyond the last day of the sixth month beginning after the date of such termination.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A waiver granted under subsection (a)(2) shall terminate not later than 90 days after the date on which the designation of the major disaster or emergency that was the basis for the waiver expires.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Statutory End Strength</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “statutory end strength” means any end-strength limitation with respect to a fiscal year that is prescribed by law for any military or civilian component of the armed forces or of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XIV, § 1483(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1715</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title IV, § 421(b)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1076</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title IV, § 416(a)–(c)(1), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4430</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XVII, § 1722(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 667</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 123b.</num>
<heading> Forces stationed abroad: limitation on number</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">End-Strength Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No funds appropriated to the Department of Defense may be used to support a strength level of members of the armed forces assigned to permanent duty ashore in nations outside the United States at the end of any fiscal year at a level in excess of 203,000.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception for Wartime</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subsection (a) does not apply in the event of a declaration of war or an armed attack on any member nation of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization, Japan, the Republic of Korea, or any other ally of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Presidential Waiver</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The President may waive the operation of subsection (a) if the President declares an emergency. The President shall immediately notify Congress of any such waiver.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XIII, § 1312(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2894</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 124.</num>
<heading> Detection and monitoring of aerial and maritime transit of illegal drugs: Department of Defense to be lead agency</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Lead Agency</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Department of Defense shall serve as the single lead agency of the Federal Government for the detection and monitoring of aerial and maritime transit of illegal drugs into the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The responsibility conferred by paragraph (1) shall be carried out in support of the counter-drug activities of Federal, State, local, and foreign law enforcement agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Performance of Detection and Monitoring Function</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> To carry out subsection (a), Department of Defense personnel may operate equipment of the Department to intercept a vessel or an aircraft detected outside the land area of the United States for the purposes of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> identifying and communicating with that vessel or aircraft; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> directing that vessel or aircraft to go to a location designated by appropriate civilian officials.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In cases in which a vessel or an aircraft is detected outside the land area of the United States, Department of Defense personnel may begin or continue pursuit of that vessel or aircraft over the land area of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">United States Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “United States” means the land area of the several States and any territory, commonwealth, or possession of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title XII, § 1202(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1563</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title X, § 1088(b)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1485</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 125.</num>
<heading> Functions, powers, and duties: transfer, reassignment, consolidation, or abolition</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Subject to section 2 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3002</ref>), the Secretary of Defense shall take appropriate action (including the transfer, reassignment, consolidation, or abolition of any function, power, or duty) to provide more effective, efficient, and economical administration and operation, and to eliminate duplication, in the Department of Defense. However, except as provided by subsections (b) and (c), a function, power, or duty vested in the Department of Defense, or an officer, official, or agency thereof, by law may not be substantially transferred, reassigned, consolidated, or abolished.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding subsection (a), if the President determines it to be necessary because of hostilities or an imminent threat of hostilities, any function, power, or duty vested by law in the Department of Defense, or an officer, official, or agency thereof, including one assigned to the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, or Space Force by section 7062(b), 8062, 8063, 9062(c), or 9081 of this title, may be transferred, reassigned, or consolidated. The transfer, reassignment, or consolidation remains in effect until the President determines that hostilities have terminated or that there is no longer an imminent threat of hostilities, as the case may be.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding subsection (a), the Secretary of Defense may assign or reassign the development and operational use of new weapons or weapons systems to one or more of the military departments or one or more of the armed forces.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 87–651, title II, § 201(a)</ref>, <date date="1962-09-07">Sept. 7, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 515</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 89–501, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="1966-07-13">July 13, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 278</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–525, title XIV, § 1405(1)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2621</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–433, title I, § 103</ref>, title III, § 301(b)(1), title V, § 514(c)(1), <date date="1986-10-01">Oct. 1, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 996</ref>, 1022, 1055; <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XIII, § 1301(3)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1668</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title X, § 1071(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3508</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 809(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1840</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 924(b)(3)(A)</ref>, (b)(6), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3821</ref>, 3822.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 125a.</num>
<heading> Reform: improvement of efficacy and efficiency</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall take such action as is necessary to reform the Department of Defense to improve the efficacy and efficiency of the Department, and to improve the ability of the Department to prioritize among and assess the costs and benefits of covered elements of reform.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Policy</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall develop a policy and issue guidance to implement reform within the Department and to improve the ability of the Department to prioritize among and assess the costs and benefits of covered elements of reform.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Framework for Reform.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than <date date="2023-02-01">February 1, 2023</date>, the Secretary shall establish policies, guidance, and a consistent reporting framework to measure the progress of the Department toward covered elements of reform, including by establishing categories of reform, consistent metrics, and a process for prioritization of reform activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Scope</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The framework required by paragraph (1) may address duties under the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content><ref>Section 125 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content><ref>Section 192 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content><ref>Section 2222 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content><ref>Section 1124 of title 31</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content><ref>Section 11319 of title 40</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consultation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall consult with the Deputy Secretary of Defense, the Performance Improvement Officer of the Department of Defense, the Chief Data Officer of the Department of Defense, the Chief Information Officer of the Department of Defense, the Director for Administration and Management of the Department of Defense, and the financial managers of the military departments in carrying out activities under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered Elements of Reform</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For purposes of this section and the policies, guidance, and reporting framework required by subsection (c), covered elements of reform may include the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Business systems modernization.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Enterprise business operations process re-engineering.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Expanded and modernized collection, management, dissemination, and visualization of data to support decision-making at all levels of the enterprise.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Improvements in workforce training and education and increasing capabilities of the Department workforce to support and execute reform activities and business processes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Improvements to decision-making processes to enable cost savings, cost avoidance, or investments to develop process improvements.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Development and implementation of a uniform methodology for tracking and assessing cost savings and cost avoidance from reform initiatives.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Implementation of reform-focused research to improve management and administrative science.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Tracking and implementation of technological approaches to improve management decision-making, such as artificial intelligence tools.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> Such other elements as the Secretary considers appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Report</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>At the same time the budget of the President for a fiscal year is submitted to Congress pursuant to <ref>section 1105 of title 31</ref>, the Secretary shall, using the policies, guidance, and reporting framework required by subsection (c), submit to the congressional defense committees a report, including detailed narrative justifications and tradeoff analyses between options, on the actions of the Department as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The activities, expenditures, and accomplishments carried out or made to effect reform under this section during the fiscal year in which such budget is submitted.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The proposed activities, expenditures, and accomplishments to effect reform under this section, and consistent with priorities established by the Secretary, during the fiscal year covered by such budget and each of the four succeeding fiscal years.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 911(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3800</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title IX, § 911</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2750</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 126.</num>
<heading> Transfer of funds and employees</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> When a function, power, or duty or an activity of a department or agency of the Department of Defense is transferred or assigned to another department or agency of that department, balances of appropriations that the Secretary of Defense determines are available and needed to finance or discharge that function, power, duty, or activity, as the case may be, may, with the approval of the President, be transferred to the department or agency to which that function, power, duty or activity, as the case may be, is transferred, and used for any purpose for which those appropriations were originally available. Balances of appropriations so transferred shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> be credited to any applicable appropriation account of the receiving department or agency; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> be credited to a new account that may be established on the books of the Department of the Treasury;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">and be merged with the funds already credited to that account and accounted for as one fund. Balances of appropriations credited to an account under clause (1) are subject only to such limitations as are specifically applicable to that account. Balances of appropriations credited to an account under clause (2) are subject only to such limitations as are applicable to the appropriations from which they are transferred.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> When a function, power, or duty or an activity of a department or agency of the Department of Defense is transferred to another department or agency of that department, those civilian employees of the department or agency from which the transfer is made that the Secretary of Defense determines are needed to perform that function, power, or duty, or for that activity, as the case may be, may, with the approval of the President, be transferred to the department or agency to which that function, power, duty, or activity, as the case may be, is transferred. The authorized strength in civilian employees of a department or agency from which employees are transferred under this section is reduced by the number of employees so transferred. The authorized strength in civilian employees of a department or agency to which employees are transferred under this section is increased by the number of employees so transferred.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 87–651, title II, § 201(a)</ref>, <date date="1962-09-07">Sept. 7, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 516</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 511(2)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2920</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 127.</num>
<heading> Emergency and extraordinary expenses</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Subject to the limitations of subsection (c), and within the limitation of appropriations made for the purpose, the Secretary of Defense, the Inspector General of the Department of Defense, and the Secretary of a military department within his department, may provide for any emergency or extraordinary expense which cannot be anticipated or classified. When it is so provided in such an appropriation, the funds may be spent on approval or authority of the Secretary concerned or the Inspector General for any purpose he determines to be proper, and such a determination is final and conclusive upon the accounting officers of the United States. The Secretary concerned or the Inspector General may certify the amount of any such expenditure authorized by him that he considers advisable not to specify, and his certificate is sufficient voucher for the expenditure of that amount. The authority to expend amounts made available for the Military Intelligence Program for intelligence and counterintelligence objects of a confidential, extraordinary, or emergency nature is provided by <ref>section 429a of this title</ref> instead of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The authority conferred by this section may be delegated by the Secretary of Defense to any person in the Department of Defense, by the Inspector General to any person in the Office of the Inspector General, or by the Secretary of a military department to any person within his department, with or without the authority to make successive re­delegations.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Funds may not be obligated or expended in an amount in excess of $500,000 under the authority of subsection (a) or (b) until the Secretary of Defense has notified the congressional defense committees of the intent to obligate or expend the funds, and—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the case of an obligation or expenditure in excess of $1,000,000, 15 days have elapsed since the date of the notification; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of an obligation or expenditure in excess of $500,000, but not in excess of $1,000,000, 5 days have elapsed since the date of the notification.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Subparagraph (A) or (B) of paragraph (1) shall not apply to an obligation or expenditure of funds otherwise covered by such subparagraph if the Secretary of Defense determines that the national security objectives of the United States will be compromised by the application of the subparagraph to the obligation or expenditure. If the Secretary makes a determination with respect to an obligation or expenditure under the preceding sentence, the Secretary shall immediately notify the committees referred to in paragraph (1) that such obligation or expenditure is necessary and provide any relevant information (in classified form, if necessary) jointly to the chairman and ranking minority member (or their designees) of such committees.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A notification under paragraph (1) and information referred to in paragraph (2) shall include the amount to be obligated or expended, as the case may be, and the purpose of the obligation or expenditure.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding paragraph (1), funds may not be obligated or expended in an amount in excess of $100,000 under the authority of subsection (a) or (b) for intelligence or counter-intelligence activities until the Secretary of Defense has notified the congressional defense committees and the congressional intelligence committees of the intent to obligate or expend the funds and 15 days have elapsed since the date of the notification.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may waive subparagraph (A) if the Secretary determines that such a waiver is necessary due to extraordinary circumstances that affect the national security of the United States. If the Secretary issues a waiver under this subparagraph, the Secretary shall submit to the congressional defense and congressional intelligence committees, by not later than 48 hours after issuing the waiver, written notice of and justification for the waiver.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Report</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Not later than December 1 each year, the Secretary of Defense shall submit—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to the congressional defense committees a report on all expenditures during the preceding fiscal year under subsections (a) and (b); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to the congressional intelligence committees a report on expenditures relating to intelligence and counter-intelligence during the preceding fiscal year under subsections (a) and (b).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Each report submitted under paragraph (1) shall include, for each individual expenditure covered by such report in an amount in excess of $100,000, the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A detailed description of the purpose of such expenditure.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The amount of such expenditure.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> An identification of the approving authority for such expenditure.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> A justification why other authorities available to the Department could not be used for such expenditure.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Any other matters the Secretary considers appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition of Congressional Intelligence Committees</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “congressional intelligence committees” means the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 94–106, title VIII, § 804(a)</ref>, <date date="1975-10-07">Oct. 7, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 538</ref>, § 140; amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–94, title XII, § 1268(2)</ref>, <date date="1983-09-24">Sept. 24, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 705</ref>; renumbered § 127 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 99–433, title I</ref>, §§ 101(a)(3), 110(d)(4), <date date="1986-10-01">Oct. 1, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 994</ref>, 1002; <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title III, § 361</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1627</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title III, § 378</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2737</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title IX, § 915</ref>, title XV, § 1502(a)(5), <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 413</ref>, 502; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1067(1)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 774</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title X, § 1031(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1596</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title X</ref>, §§ 1041(a)–(c), 1081(a)(4), <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1552</ref>, 1553, 1594; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title X, § 1012</ref>, title XVII, § 1731(a)(5), <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1577</ref>, 1812; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XVI, § 1614(e)(2)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2169</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 127a.</num>
<heading> Operations for which funds are not provided in advance: funding mechanisms</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Defense shall use the procedures prescribed by this section with respect to any operation specified in paragraph (2) that involves—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the deployment (other than for a training exercise) of elements of the armed forces for a purpose other than a purpose for which funds have been specifically provided in advance; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the provision of humanitarian assistance, disaster relief, or support for law enforcement (including immigration control) for which funds have not been specifically provided in advance.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> This section applies to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any operation the incremental cost of which is expected to exceed $50,000,000; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any other operation the expected incremental cost of which, when added to the expected incremental costs of other operations that are currently ongoing, is expected to result in a cumulative incremental cost of ongoing operations of the Department of Defense in excess of $100,000,000.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Any operation the incremental cost of which is expected not to exceed $10,000,000 shall be disregarded for the purposes of subparagraph (B).</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> This section does not provide authority for the President or the Secretary of Defense to carry out any operation, but establishes mechanisms for the Department of Defense by which funds are provided for operations that the armed forces are required to carry out under some other authority.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Waiver of Requirement To Reimburse Support Units</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall direct that, when a unit of the armed forces participating in an operation described in subsection (a) receives services from an element of the Department of Defense that operates through the Defense Business Operations Fund (or a successor fund), such unit of the armed forces may not be required to reimburse that element for the incremental costs incurred by that element in providing such services, notwithstanding any other provision of law or any Government accounting practice.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The amounts which but for paragraph (1) would be required to be reimbursed to an element of the Department of Defense (or a fund) shall be recorded as an expense attributable to the operation and shall be accounted for separately.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transfer Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Whenever there is an operation of the Department of Defense described in subsection (a), the Secretary of Defense may transfer amounts described in paragraph (3) to accounts from which incremental expenses for that operation were incurred in order to reimburse those accounts for those incremental expenses. Amounts so transferred shall be merged with and be available for the same purposes as the accounts to which transferred.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The total amount that the Secretary of Defense may transfer under the authority of this section in any fiscal year is $200,000,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Transfers under this subsection may only be made from amounts appropriated to the Department of Defense for any fiscal year that remain available for obligation, other than amounts within any operation and maintenance appropriation that are available for (A) an account (known as a budget activity 1 account) that is specified as being for operating forces, or (B) an account (known as a budget activity 2 account) that is specified as being for mobilization.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The authority provided by this subsection is in addition to any other authority provided by law authorizing the transfer of amounts available to the Department of Defense. However, the Secretary may not use any such authority under another provision of law for a purpose described in paragraph (1) if there is authority available under this subsection for that purpose.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The authority provided by this subsection to transfer amounts may not be used to provide authority for an activity that has been denied authorization by Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> A transfer made from one account to another under the authority of this subsection shall be deemed to increase the amount authorized for the account to which the amount is transferred by an amount equal to the amount transferred.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>[(d)</num>
<content> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title X, § 1031(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1596</ref>.]</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitations</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary may not restore balances in the Defense Business Operations Fund through increases in rates charged by that fund in order to compensate for costs incurred and not reimbursed due to subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary may not restore balances in the Defense Business Operations Fund or any other fund or account through the use of unobligated amounts in an operation and maintenance appropriation that are available within that appropriation for (A) an account (known as a budget activity 1 account) that is specified as being for operating forces, or (B) an account (known as a budget activity 2 account) that is specified as being for mobilization.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Submission of Requests for Supplemental Appropriations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>It is the sense of Congress that whenever there is an operation described in subsection (a), the President should, not later than 90 days after the date on which notification is provided pursuant to subsection (a)(3), submit to Congress a request for the enactment of supplemental appropriations for the then-current fiscal year in order to provide funds to replenish the Defense Business Operations Fund or any other fund or account of the Department of Defense from which funds for the incremental expenses of that operation were derived under this section and should, as necessary, submit subsequent requests for the enactment of such appropriations.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Incremental Costs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of this section, incremental costs of the Department of Defense with respect to an operation are the costs of the Department that are directly attributable to the operation (and would not have been incurred but for the operation). Incremental costs do not include the cost of property or services acquired by the Department that are paid for by a source outside the Department or out of funds contributed by such a source.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Relationship to War Powers Resolution</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section may not be construed as altering or superseding the War Powers Resolution. This section does not provide authority to conduct any military operation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">GAO Compliance Reviews</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Comptroller General of the United States shall from time to time, and when requested by a committee of Congress, conduct a review of the defense funding structure under this section to determine whether the Department of Defense is complying with the requirements and limitations of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title XI, § 1108(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1751</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title X, § 1003(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 415</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title X, § 1031(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1596</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title X, § 1075(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4369</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title X, § 1061(1)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1583</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 127b.</num>
<heading> Department of Defense rewards program</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense may pay a monetary amount, or provide a payment-in-kind, to a person as a reward for providing United States Government personnel, or government personnel of allied forces participating in a combined operation with the armed forces, with information or nonlethal assistance that is beneficial to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an operation or activity of the armed forces, or of allied forces participating in a combined operation with the armed forces, conducted outside the United States against international terrorism; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> force protection of the armed forces, or of allied forces participating in a combined operation with the armed forces.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The amount or value of a reward provided under this section may not exceed $5,000,000.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Delegation of Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The authority of the Secretary of Defense under subsection (a) may be delegated only—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to the Deputy Secretary of Defense and an Under Secretary of Defense, without further redelegation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to the commander of a combatant command, but only for a reward in an amount or with a value not in excess of $1,000,000.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A commander of a combatant command to whom authority to provide rewards under this section is delegated under paragraph (1) may further delegate that authority, but only for a reward in an amount or with a value not in excess of $10,000, except that such a delegation may be made to the commander’s deputy commander, or to the commander of a command directly subordinate to that commander, without regard to such limitation. Such a delegation may be made to the commander of a command directly subordinate to the commander of a combatant command only with the approval of the Secretary of Defense, the Deputy Secretary of Defense, or an Under Secretary of Defense to whom authority has been delegated under subparagraph (1)(A).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Subject to subparagraph (B), an official who has authority delegated under paragraph (1) or (2) may use that authority, acting through government personnel of allied forces, to offer and make rewards.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe policies and procedures for making rewards in the manner described in subparagraph (A), which shall include guidance for the accountability of funds used for making rewards in that manner. The policies and procedures shall not take effect until 30 days after the date on which the Secretary submits the policies and procedures to the congressional defense committees. Rewards may not be made in the manner described in subparagraph (A) except under policies and procedures that have taken effect.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Coordination</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe policies and procedures for the offering and making of rewards under this section and otherwise for administering the authority under this section. Such policies and procedures shall be prescribed in consultation with the Secretary of State and the Attorney General and shall ensure that the making of a reward under this section does not duplicate or interfere with the payment of a reward authorized by the Secretary of State or the Attorney General.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall consult with the Secretary of State regarding the making of any reward under this section in an amount or with a value in excess of $2,000,000.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Persons Not Eligible</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The following persons are not eligible to receive a reward under this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A citizen of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> An officer or employee of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> An employee of a contractor of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Report</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Not later than February 1 of each year, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives a report on the administration of the rewards program under this section during the preceding fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Each report for a fiscal year under this subsection shall include the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Information on the total amount expended during that fiscal year to carry out the rewards program under this section during that fiscal year.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Specification of the amount, if any, expended during that fiscal year to publicize the availability of rewards under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> With respect to each reward provided during that fiscal year—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the amount or value of the reward and whether the reward was provided as a monetary payment or in some other form;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the recipient of the reward and the recipient’s geographic location; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a description of the information or assistance for which the reward was paid, together with an assessment of the significance and benefit of the information or assistance.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> A description of the status of program implementation in each geographic combatant command, including in which countries the program is being operated.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> A description of efforts to coordinate and de-conflict the authority under subsection (a) with similar rewards programs administered by the United States Government.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> An assessment of the effectiveness of the program in meeting its objectives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary may submit the report in classified form if the Secretary determines that it is necessary to do so.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Determinations by the Secretary</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A determination by the Secretary under this section is final and conclusive and is not subject to judicial review.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report on Designation of Countries for Which Rewards May Be Paid</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not later than 15 days after the date on which the Secretary designates a country as a country in which an operation or activity of the armed forces is occurring in connection with which rewards may be paid under this section, the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives a report on the designation. Each report shall include the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The country so designated.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The reason and justification for the designation of the country.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> An estimate of the amount or value of the rewards to be paid as monetary payment or payment-in-kind under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title X, § 1065(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2655</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title X, § 1056(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3439</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title XIV, § 1401</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2433</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title X, § 1033</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 307</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title X, § 1071</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2470</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title X, § 1031</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4351</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title X</ref>, §§ 1033, 1064(3), <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1572</ref>, 1587; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title X, § 1021(a)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1911</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title X, § 1031</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3491</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title X, § 1042(a)</ref>–(d)(1), <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 976</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title X, § 1063</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2408</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 127c.</num>
<heading> Purchase of weapons overseas: force protection</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>When elements of the armed forces are engaged in ongoing military operations in a country, the Secretary of Defense may, for the purpose of protecting United States forces in that country, purchase weapons from any foreign person, foreign government, international organization, or other entity located in that country.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The total amount expended during any fiscal year for purchases under this section may not exceed $15,000,000.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Semiannual Congressional Report</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In any case in which the authority provided in subsection (a) is used during the period of the first six months of a fiscal year, or during the period of the second six months of a fiscal year, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives a report on the use of that authority during that six-month period. Each such report shall be submitted not later than 30 days after the end of the six-month period during which the authority is used. Each such report shall include the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The number and type of weapons purchased under subsection (a) during that six-month period covered by the report, together with the amount spent for those weapons and the Secretary’s estimate of the fair market value of those weapons.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A description of the dispositions (if any) during that six-month period of weapons purchased under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title XII, § 1231(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3467</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 127d.</num>
<heading> Support of special operations for irregular warfare</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may, with the concurrence of the relevant Chief of Mission, expend up to $20,000,000 during any fiscal year to provide support to foreign forces, irregular forces, groups, or individuals engaged in supporting or facilitating ongoing and authorized irregular warfare operations by United States Special Operations Forces.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Funds for support under this section in a fiscal year shall be derived from amounts authorized to be appropriated for that fiscal year for the Department of Defense for operation and maintenance.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Procedures.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The authority in this section shall be exercised in accordance with such procedures as the Secretary shall establish for purposes of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The procedures required under paragraph (1) shall establish, at a minimum, the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Policy guidance for the execution of, and constraints within, activities under the authority in this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The processes through which activities under the authority in this section are to be developed, validated, and coordinated, as appropriate, with relevant entities of the United States Government.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The processes through which legal reviews and determinations are made to comply with the authority in this section and ensure that the exercise of such authority is consistent with the national security of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The processes to ensure, to the extent practicable, that before a decision to provide support is made, the recipients of support do not pose a counterintelligence or force protection threat and have not engaged in gross violations of human rights.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<chapeau> The processes by which the Department shall keep the congressional defense committees fully and currently informed of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the requirements for the use of the authority in this section; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> activities conducted under such authority.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice to congress on procedures and material modifications</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall notify the congressional defense committees of the procedures established pursuant to this section before any exercise of the authority in this section, and shall notify such committee of any material modification of the procedures.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Construction of Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Nothing in this section shall be construed to constitute a specific statutory authorization for any of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The conduct of a covert action, as such term is defined in section 503(e) of the National Security Act of 1947 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3093(e)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The introduction of United States Armed Forces (including as such term is defined in section 8(c) of the War Powers Resolution (<ref>50 U.S.C. 1547(c)</ref>)) into hostilities or into situations wherein hostilities are clearly indicated by the circumstances.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The provision of support to regular forces, irregular forces, groups, or individuals for the conduct of operations that United States Special Operations Forces are not otherwise legally authorized to conduct themselves.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The conduct or support of activities, directly or indirectly, that are inconsistent with the laws of armed conflict.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Delegation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The authority of the Secretary to make funds available under this section for support of a military operation may not be delegated.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Programmatic and Policy Oversight</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Assistant Secretary of Defense for Special Operations and Low-Intensity Conflict shall have primary programmatic and policy oversight within the Office of the Secretary of Defense of support to irregular warfare activities authorized by this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Notification.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 15 days before exercising the authority in this section to make funds available to initiate support of an ongoing and authorized operation or changing the scope or funding level of any support under this section for such an operation by $500,000 or an amount equal to 10 percent of such funding level (whichever is less), the Secretary shall notify the congressional defense committees of the use of such authority with respect to such operation. Any such notification shall be in writing.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A notification required by this subsection shall include the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The type of support to be provided to United States Special Operations Forces, and a description of the ongoing and authorized operation to be supported.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A description of the foreign forces, irregular forces, groups, or individuals engaged in supporting or facilitating the ongoing and authorized operation that is to be the recipient of funds.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The type of support to be provided to the recipient of the funds, and a description of the end-use monitoring to be used in connection with the use of the funds.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The amount obligated under the authority to provide support.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The duration for which the support is expected to be provided, and an identification of the timeframe in which the provision of support will be reviewed by the commander of the applicable combatant command for a determination with respect to the necessity of continuing such support.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<chapeau> The determination of the Secretary that the provision of support does not constitute any of the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> An introduction of United States Armed Forces (including as such term is defined in section 8(c) of the War Powers Resolution (<ref>50 U.S.C. 1547(c)</ref>)) into hostilities, or into situations where hostilities are clearly indicated by the circumstances, without specific statutory authorization within the meaning of section 5(b) of such Resolution (<ref>50 U.S.C. 1544(b)</ref>).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> A covert action, as such term is defined in section 503(e) of the National Security Act of 1947 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3093(e)</ref>).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> An authorization for the provision of support to regular forces, irregular forces, groups, or individuals for the conduct of operations that United States Special Operations Forces are not otherwise legally authorized to conduct themselves.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> The conduct or support of activities, directly or indirectly, that are inconsistent with the laws of armed conflict.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Notification of Suspension or Termination of Support.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 48 hours after suspending or terminating support to any foreign force, irregular force, group, or individual provided pursuant to the authority in this section, the Secretary shall submit to the congressional defense committees a written notice of such suspension or termination.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The written notice required by paragraph (1) shall include each of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A description of the reasons for the suspension or termination of such support.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A description of any effect on regional, theater, or global campaign plan objectives anticipated to result from such suspension or termination.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> A plan for such suspension or termination, and, in the case of support that is planned to be transitioned to any other program of the Department of Defense or to a program of any other Federal department or agency, a detailed description of the transition plan, including the resources, equipment, capabilities, and personnel associated with such plan.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Biannual Reports.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report on preceding fiscal year</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 120 days after the close of each fiscal year in which subsection (a) is in effect, the Secretary shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report on the support provided under this section during the preceding fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report on current calendar year</inline>.—</heading>
<content> Not later than 180 days after the submittal of each report required by paragraph (1), the Secretary shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report on the support provided under this section during the first half of the fiscal year in which the report under this paragraph is submitted.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each report required by this subsection shall include the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A summary of the ongoing irregular warfare operations, and associated authorized campaign plans, being conducted by United States Special Operations Forces that were supported or facilitated by foreign forces, irregular forces, groups, or individuals for which support was provided under this section during the period covered by such report.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A description of the support or facilitation provided by such foreign forces, irregular forces, groups, or individuals to United States Special Operations Forces during such period.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The type of recipients that were provided support under this section during such period, identified by authorized category (foreign forces, irregular forces, groups, or individuals).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> A detailed description of the support provided to the recipients under this section during such period.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The total amount obligated for support under this section during such period, including budget details.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> The intended duration of support provided under this section during such period.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> An assessment of value of the support provided under this section during such period, including a summary of significant activities undertaken by foreign forces, irregular forces, groups, or individuals to support irregular warfare operations by United States Special Operations Forces.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> The total amount obligated for support under this section in prior fiscal years.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Quarterly Briefings.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not less frequently than quarterly, the Secretary shall provide to the congressional defense committees a briefing on the use of the authority provided by this section, and other matters relating to irregular warfare, with the primary purposes of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> keeping the congressional defense committees fully and currently informed of irregular warfare requirements and activities, including emerging combatant commands requirements; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> consulting with the congressional defense committees regarding such matters.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each briefing required by paragraph (1) shall include the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> An update on irregular warfare activities within each geographic combatant command and a description of the manner in which such activities support the respective theater campaign plan and the National Defense Strategy.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> An overview of relevant authorities and legal issues, including limitations.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> An overview of irregular warfare-related interagency activities and initiatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> A description of emerging combatant command requirements for the use of the authority provided by this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(k)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Irregular Warfare Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to subsection (d), in this section, the term “irregular warfare” means Department of Defense activities not involving armed conflict that support predetermined United States policy and military objectives conducted by, with, and through regular forces, irregular forces, groups, and individuals.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XII, § 1201(a)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 437</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 127e.</num>
<heading> Support of special operations to combat terrorism</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may, with the concurrence of the relevant Chief of Mission, expend up to $100,000,000 during any fiscal year to provide support to foreign forces, irregular forces, groups, or individuals engaged in supporting or facilitating authorized ongoing military operations by United States special operations forces to combat terrorism.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Funds for support under this section in a fiscal year shall be derived from amounts authorized to be appropriated for that fiscal year for the Department of Defense for operation and maintenance.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Procedures.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The authority in this section shall be exercised in accordance with such procedures as the Secretary shall establish for purposes of this section. The Secretary shall notify the congressional defense committees of any material change to such procedures.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The procedures required under paragraph (1) shall establish, at a minimum, each of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Policy, strategy, or other guidance for the execution of, and constraints within, activities conducted under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The processes through which activities conducted under this section are to be developed, validated, and coordinated, as appropriate, with relevant Federal entities.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The processes through which legal reviews and determinations are made to comply with this section and ensure that the exercise of the authority in this section is consistent with the national security of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Notification.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 15 days before exercising the authority in this section to make funds available to initiate support of an approved military operation or changing the scope or funding level of any support for such an operation by $1,000,000 or an amount equal to 20 percent of such funding level (whichever is less), or not later than 48 hours after exercising such authority if the Secretary determines that extraordinary circumstances that impact the national security of the United States exist, the Secretary shall notify the congressional defense committees of the use of such authority with respect to that operation. Any such notification shall be in writing.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A notification required by this subsection shall include the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The type of support provided or to be provided to United States special operations forces and a description of the authorized ongoing operation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A description of the foreign forces, irregular forces, groups, or individuals engaged in supporting or facilitating the authorized ongoing operation who will receive support provided under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> A detailed description of the support provided or to be provided to the recipient.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The amount obligated under the authority to provide support.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> A detailed description of the legal and operational authorities related to the authorized ongoing operation, including relevant execute orders issued by the Secretary of Defense and combatant commanders related to the authorized ongoing operation, including an identification of operational activities United States Special Operations Forces are authorized to conduct under such execute orders.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> The duration for which the support is expected to be provided and an identification of the timeframe in which the provision of support will be reviewed by the combatant commander for a determination regarding the necessity of continuation of support.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> A description of the entities with which the recipients of support are engaged in hostilities and whether each such entity is covered under an authorization for use of military force.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> A description of the steps taken to ensure the support is consistent with United States national security objectives.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> A description of the steps taken to ensure that the recipients of support have not engaged in human rights violations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Notification of Suspension or Termination of Support.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 48 hours after suspending or terminating support to any foreign force, irregular force, group, or individual under the authority in this section, the Secretary shall submit to the congressional defense committees a written notice of such suspension or termination.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Notice provided under paragraph (1) with respect to the suspension or termination of support shall include each of the following elements:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A description of the reasons for the suspension or termination of such support.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A description of any effects on regional, theatre, or global campaign plan objectives anticipated to result from the suspension or termination of such support.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> A plan for the suspension or termination of the support, and, in the case of support that is planned to be transitioned to another program of the Department of Defense or another Federal department or agency, a detailed description of the transition plan, including the resources, equipment, capabilities, and personnel associated with such plan.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Delegation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The authority of the Secretary to make funds available under this section for support of a military operation may not be delegated.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Construction of Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Nothing in this section may be construed to constitute authority to conduct or provide statutory authorization for any of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A covert action, as such term is defined in section 503(e) of the National Security Act of 1947 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3093(e)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> An introduction of the armed forces, (including as such term is defined in section 8(c) of the War Powers Resolution (<ref>50 U.S.C. 1547(c)</ref>), into hostilities, or into situations where hostilities are clearly indicated by the circumstances, without specific statutory authorization within the meaning of section 5(b) of such Resolution (<ref>50 U.S.C. 1544(b)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Activities or support of activities, directly or indirectly, that are inconsistent with the laws of armed conflict.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Oversight by ASD for SOLIC</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Assistant Secretary of Defense for Special Operations and Low Intensity Conflict shall have primary responsibility within the Office of the Secretary of Defense for oversight of policies and programs for support authorized by this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Biannual Reports.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report on preceding calendar year</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 120 days after the last day of each fiscal year, the Secretary shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report on the support provided under this section during the preceding calendar year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report on current calendar year</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than six months after the date of the submittal of the report most recently submitted under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report on the support provided under this section during the first half of the calendar year in which the report under this paragraph is submitted.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each report required by this subsection shall include, for the period covered by such report, the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A summary of the ongoing military operations by United States special operations forces to combat terrorism that were supported or facilitated by foreign forces, irregular forces, groups, or individuals for which support was provided under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A description of the support or facilitation provided by such foreign forces, irregular forces, groups, or individuals to United States special operations forces.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The type of recipients that were provided support under this section, identified by authorized category (foreign forces, irregular forces, groups, or individuals).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The total amount obligated for support under this section, including budget details.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The total amount obligated in prior fiscal years under this section and applicable preceding authority.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> The intended duration of support provided under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> A description of the support or training provided to the recipients of support under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> A value assessment of the support provided under this section, including a summary of significant activities undertaken by foreign forces, irregular forces, groups, or individuals to support operations by United States special operations forces to combat terrorism.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1203(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2474</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title X, § 1031</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1550</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title X, § 1041</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1585</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title X</ref>, §§ 1051, 1081(a)(7), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3847</ref>, 3871.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 127f.</num>
<heading> Expenditure of funds for clandestine activities that support operational preparation of the environment and non-conventional assisted recovery capabilities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Amounts appropriated or otherwise made available for the Department of Defense for operation and maintenance, Defense-wide, may be used for any purpose the Secretary of Defense determines to be proper—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> for operational preparation of the environment for operations of a confidential nature; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to establish, develop, and maintain non-conventional assisted recovery capabilities to facilitate the recovery of United States military and civilian personnel, or other individuals, who become isolated or separated.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Such a determination is final and conclusive upon the accounting officers of the United States. The Secretary may certify the amount of any such expenditure authorized by the Secretary that the Secretary considers advisable not to specify, and the Secretary’s certificate is sufficient voucher for the expenditure of that amount.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authorized Activities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Activities authorized by subsection (a) may, in limited and special circumstances as determined by the Secretary of Defense, include the provision of support to foreign forces, irregular forces, groups, or individuals to conduct operational preparation of the environment and to conduct or support operations to establish, develop, and maintain non-conventional assisted recovery capabilities to facilitate the recovery of United States military and civilian personnel, or other individuals, who become isolated or separated. Such support may include limited amounts of equipment, supplies, training, transportation, or other logistical support or funding.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Procedures.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The authority in this section shall be exercised in accordance with such procedures as the Secretary of Defense shall establish for purposes of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The procedures required under paragraph (1) shall establish, at a minimum, each of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Policy, strategy, or other guidance for the execution of, and constraints within, activities conducted under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The processes through which activities conducted under this section are to be developed, validated, and coordinated, as appropriate, with relevant Federal entities.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The processes through which legal reviews and determinations are made to comply with the authority in this section and ensure that the exercise of such authority is consistent with the national security interests of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> The processes by which the Department of Defense shall keep the congressional defense committees fully and currently informed of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the requirements for the use of the authority in this section; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> activities conducted under such authority.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice to congress</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall notify the congressional defense committees of any material change to the procedures established under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> may expend up to $40,000,000 in any fiscal year for the purposes described in subsection (a); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> may not delegate the authority under this section with respect to any expenditure in excess of $250,000.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exclusion of Intelligence Activities</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> This section does not constitute authority to conduct, or expend funds for, intelligence, counterintelligence, or intelligence-related activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In this subsection, the terms “intelligence” and “counterintelligence” have the meaning given those terms in section 3 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3003</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Quarterly Briefing</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>On a quarterly basis, the Assistant Secretary of Defense for Special Operations and Low Intensity Conflict, in coordination with elements of the Department of Defense that the Assistant Secretary determines appropriate, shall provide to the congressional defense committees a briefing outlining the clandestine activities carried out pursuant to subsection (a) during the period covered by the briefing, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an update on such activities carried out in each geographic combatant command and a description of how such activities support the respective theater campaign plan;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an overview of the authorities and legal issues, including limitations, relating to such activities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> any other matters the Assistant Secretary considers appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Report</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not later than December 31 each year, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report on expenditures made under this section during the fiscal year preceding the year in which the report is submitted. Each report shall include, for each expenditure under this section during the fiscal year covered by such report—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a description of activities carried out for the purposes described in subsection (a);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the amount of such expenditures;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> an identification of the type of recipients to receive support, including foreign forces, irregular forces, groups or individuals, as appropriate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the total amount of funds obligated for such expenditures in prior fiscal years; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> any other matters the Secretary considers appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Non-Conventional Assisted Recovery Capabilities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Funding used to establish, develop, and maintain non-conventional assisted recovery capabilities under this section may only be obligated and expended with the concurrence of the relevant Chief of Mission or Chiefs of Mission.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Oversight by Assistant Secretary of Defense for Special Operations and Low Intensity Conflict</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Assistant Secretary of Defense for Special Operations and Low Intensity Conflict shall have primary responsibility within the Office of the Secretary of Defense for oversight of policies and programs authorized by this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Operational Preparation of the Environment Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “operational preparation of the environment” means the conduct of activities in likely or potential operational areas to set conditions for mission execution.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title X, § 1052(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3849</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title X, § 1093(b)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1935</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title XVI, § 1621</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2933</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XII, § 1221(a)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 451</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 128.</num>
<heading> Control and physical protection of special nuclear material: limitation on dissemination of unclassified information</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In addition to any other authority or requirement regarding protection from dissemination of information, and subject to <ref>section 552(b)(3) of title 5</ref>, the Secretary of Defense, with respect to special nuclear materials, shall prescribe such regulations, after notice and opportunity for public comment thereon, or issue such orders as may be necessary to prohibit the unauthorized dissemination of unclassified information pertaining to security measures, including security plans, procedures, and equipment for the physical protection of special nuclear material.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary may prescribe regulations or issue orders under paragraph (1) to prohibit the dissemination of any information described in such paragraph only if and to the extent that the Secretary determines that the unauthorized dissemination of such information could reasonably be expected to have a significant adverse effect on the health and safety of the public or the common defense and security by significantly increasing the likelihood of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> illegal production of nuclear weapons, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> theft, diversion, or sabotage of special nuclear materials, equipment, or facilities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> In making a determination under paragraph (2), the Secretary may consider what the likelihood of an illegal production, theft, diversion, or sabotage referred to in such paragraph would be if the information proposed to be prohibited from dissemination under this section were at no time available for dissemination.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary shall exercise his authority under this subsection to prohibit the dissemination of any information described in paragraph (1)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> so as to apply the minimum restrictions needed to protect the health and safety of the public or the common defense and security; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> upon a determination that the unauthorized dissemination of such information could reasonably be expected to result in a significant adverse effect on the health and safety of the public or the common defense and security by significantly increasing the likelihood of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> illegal production of nuclear weapons, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> theft, diversion, or sabotage of nuclear materials, equipment, or facilities.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Nothing in this section shall be construed to authorize the Secretary to withhold, or to authorize the withholding of, information from the appropriate committees of the Congress.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Any determination by the Secretary concerning the applicability of this section shall be subject to judicial review pursuant to <ref>section 552(a)(4)(B) of title 5</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Information that the Secretary prohibits to be disseminated pursuant to subsection (a) that is provided to a State or local government shall remain under the control of the Department of Defense, and a State or local law authorizing or requiring a State or local government to disclose such information shall not apply to such information.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–180, div. A, title XI, § 1123(a)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1149</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XIII, § 1311(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1669</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title X, § 1031(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1596</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XVI, § 1662(a)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2614</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 129.</num>
<heading> Civilian personnel management</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The civilian personnel of the Department of Defense shall be managed each fiscal year solely on the basis of and consistent with (1) the total force management policies and procedures established under <ref>section 129a of this title</ref>, (2) the workload required to carry out the functions and activities of the department, and (3) the funds made available to the department for such fiscal year. The management of such personnel in any fiscal year shall not be subject to any constraint or limitation in terms of man years, end strength, full-time equivalent positions, or maximum number of employees. The Secretary of Defense and the Secretaries of the military departments may not be required to make a reduction in the number of full-time equivalent positions in the Department of Defense except in accordance with the requirements of this section and <ref>section 129a of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> With respect to each budget activity within an appropriation for a fiscal year for operations and maintenance, the Secretary of Defense shall ensure that there are employed during that fiscal year employees in the number and with the combination of skills and qualifications that are necessary to carry out the functions within that budget activity as determined under the total force management policies and procedures established under <ref>section 129a of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Not later than February 1 of each year—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report on the management of the civilian workforce of the Office of the Secretary of Defense and the Defense Agencies and Field Activities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Secretary of each military department shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report on the management of the civilian workforces under the jurisdiction of such Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Each report under paragraph (1) shall contain, with respect to the civilian workforce under the jurisdiction of the official submitting the report, the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> An assessment of the projected size and associated cost of such civilian workforce in the current year and for each year in the future-years defense program.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> If the projected size and associated cost of such civilian workforce has changed from the previous year’s projected size and associated cost, an explanation of the reasons for the increase or decrease from the previous projection, including an explanation of any efforts to reduce the overall costs of the total force of military, civilian, and contract workforces.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> In the case of a transfer of functions between military, civilian, and contractor workforces, an explanation of the reasons for the transfer and the steps that have been taken to control the overall cost of the function to the Department.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 97–86, title IX, § 904(a)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-01">Dec. 1, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1114</ref>, § 140b; renumbered § 129, <ref>Pub. L. 99–433, title I, § 101(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-01">Oct. 1, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 994</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title V, § 533</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3873</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title III, § 312(b)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1335</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title X, § 1031</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 428</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title X, § 1074(a)(1)</ref>, title XVI, § 1603, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2658</ref>, 2735; <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title XI, § 1101</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1922</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1067(1)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 774</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title IX, § 932</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1543</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XI, § 1101(a)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2443</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title XI, § 1103</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1596</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XI, § 1102</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1949</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 129a.</num>
<heading> General policy for total force management</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Policies and Procedures</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall establish policies and procedures for determining the most appropriate and cost efficient mix of military, civilian, and contractor personnel to perform the mission of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Risk Mitigation Over Cost</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In establishing the policies and procedures under subsection (a), the Secretary shall clearly provide that attainment of a Department of Defense workforce sufficiently sized and comprised of the appropriate mix of personnel necessary to carry out the mission of the Department and the core mission areas of the armed forces takes precedence over cost. The Secretary may not reduce the civilian workforce programmed full-time equivalent levels unless the Secretary conducts an appropriate analysis of the impacts of such reductions on workload, military force structure, lethality, readiness, operational effectiveness, stress on the military force, and fully burdened costs.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Delegation of Responsibilities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall delegate responsibility for implementation of the policies and procedures established under subsection (a) as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Under Secretary of Defense for Personnel and Readiness shall have overall responsibility for guidance to implement such policies and procedures.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretaries of the military departments and the heads of the Defense Agencies shall have overall responsibility for the requirements determination, planning, programming, and budgeting for such policies and procedures. The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that the requirements determination, planning, programming, and budgeting conducted under this paragraph considers all components of the total force (including active and reserve military, the civilian workforce, and contract support) in a holistic manner—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to avoid duplication of efforts and waste of resources attributable to a component working outside the scope of its responsibilities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to ensure that risk, cost, and mission validation and prioritization considerations are consistent with the national defense strategy.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment shall be responsible for ensuring that the defense acquisition system, as defined in <ref>section 3001 of this title</ref>, is consistent with such policies and procedures and with implementation pursuant to paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Under Secretary of Defense (Comptroller) shall be responsible for ensuring that the budget for the Department of Defense is consistent with such policies and procedures. The Under Secretary shall notify the congressional defense committees of any deviations from such policies and procedures that are recommended in the budget.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of Plan, Inventory, and List</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The policies and procedures established by the Secretary under subsection (a) shall specifically require the Department of Defense to use the following when making determinations regarding the appropriate workforce mix necessary to perform its mission:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The inventory of contracts for services required by <ref>section 4505(c) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The list of activities required by the Federal Activities Inventory Reform Act of 1998 (<ref>Public Law 105–270</ref>; <ref>31 U.S.C. 501</ref> note).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Considerations in Converting Performance of Functions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau> If conversion of functions to performance by either Department of Defense civilian personnel or contractor personnel is considered, the Under Secretary of Defense for Personnel and Readiness shall ensure compliance with—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content><ref>section 2463 of this title</ref> (relating to guidelines and procedures for use of civilian employees to perform Department of Defense functions); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content><ref>section 2461 of this title</ref> (relating to public-private competition required before conversion to contractor performance).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Construction With Other Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Nothing in this title may be construed as authorizing—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a military department or Defense Agency to directly convert a function to contractor performance without complying with <ref>section 2461 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the use of contractor personnel for functions that are inherently governmental even if there is a military or civilian personnel shortfall in the Department of Defense;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> restrictions on the use by a military department or Defense Agency of contractor personnel to perform functions closely associated with inherently governmental functions, provided that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> there are adequate resources to maintain sufficient capabilities within the Department in the functional area being considered for performance by contractor personnel; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> there is adequate Government oversight of contractor personnel performing such functions;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the establishment of numerical goals or budgetary savings targets for the conversion of functions to performance by either Department of Defense civilian personnel or for conversion to performance by contractor personnel; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the imposition of a civilian hiring freeze that may inhibit the implementation of the policies and procedures established under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Performance of Civilian Functions by Military Personnel</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Functions performed by civilian personnel should not be performed by military personnel except—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> if the Secretary of the military department concerned determines in writing based on mission requirements that the performance of such functions by military personnel is cost-effective, taking into account the fully-burdened costs of the civilian, military, and contractor workforces, including the impact of the performance of such functions on military career progression or when required by military necessity; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> such functions may be performed by military personnel for a period that does not exceed one year if the Secretary of the military department concerned determines that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the performance of such functions by military personnel is required to address critical staffing needs resulting from a reduction in personnel or budgetary resources by reason of an Act of Congress; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the military department concerned is in compliance with the policies, procedures, and analysis required by this section and <ref>section 129 of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In determining the workforce mix between civilian and military personnel, the Secretary of a military department shall reserve military personnel for the performance of the functions that, in the estimation of the Secretary, are required to be performed by military personnel in order to achieve national defense goals or in order to enable the proper functioning of the military department. In making workforce decisions, the Secretary shall account for the relative budgetary impact of military versus civilian personnel in determining the functions required to be performed by military personnel.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XIV, § 1483(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1715</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title IX, § 931(a)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1541</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title IX, § 914</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2350</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title X</ref>, §§ 1051(a)(6)(B), 1081(a)(5), <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1560</ref>, 1594; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title IX, § 933</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1938</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title IX, § 902(1)</ref>, title XI, § 1106, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1542</ref>, 1597; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 912</ref>, title XVIII, §§ 1808(d)(1), 1883(b)(2), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3802</ref>, 4160, 4294; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title IX, § 911</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 364</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 129b.</num>
<heading> Authority to procure personal services</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subject to subsection (b), the Secretary of Defense and the Secretaries of the military departments may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> procure the services of experts or consultants (or of organizations of experts or consultants) in accordance with <ref>section 3109 of title 5</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> pay in connection with such services travel expenses of individuals, including transportation and per diem in lieu of subsistence while such individuals are traveling from their homes or places of business to official duty stations and return as may be authorized by law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Conditions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The services of experts or consultants (or organizations thereof) may be procured under subsection (a) only if the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of the military department concerned, as the case may be, determines that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the procurement of such services is advantageous to the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> such services cannot adequately be provided by the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Procurement of the services of experts and consultants (or organizations thereof) under subsection (a) shall be carried out under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Additional Authority for Personal Services Contracts</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> In addition to the authority provided under subsection (a), the Secretary of Defense may enter into personal services contracts if the personal services—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> are to be provided by individuals outside the United States, regardless of their nationality, and are determined by the Secretary to be necessary and appropriate for supporting the activities and programs of the Department of Defense outside the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> directly support the mission of a defense intelligence component or counter-intelligence organization of the Department of Defense; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> directly support the mission of the special operations command of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The contracting officer for a personal services contract under this subsection shall be responsible for ensuring that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the services to be procured are urgent or unique; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> it would not be practicable for the Department to obtain such services by other means.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The requirements of <ref>section 3109 of title 5</ref> shall not apply to a contract entered into under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XIV, § 1481(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1704</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title X, § 1061(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1472</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title VIII, § 841(a)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1552</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 129c.</num>
<heading> Medical personnel: limitations on reductions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Reduction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For any fiscal year, the Secretary of Defense may not make a reduction in the number of medical personnel of the Department of Defense described in subsection (b) unless the Secretary makes a certification for that fiscal year described in subsection (c).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered Reductions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subsection (a) applies to a reduction in the number of medical personnel of the Department of Defense as of the end of a fiscal year to a number that is less than—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> 95 percent of the number of such personnel at the end of the immediately preceding fiscal year; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> 90 percent of the number of such personnel at the end of the third fiscal year preceding the fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Certification</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A certification referred to in subsection (a) with respect to reductions in medical personnel of the Department of Defense for any fiscal year is a certification by the Secretary of Defense to Congress that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the number of medical personnel being reduced is excess to the current and projected needs of the Department of Defense; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> such reduction will not result in an increase in the cost of health care services provided under the Civilian Health and Medical Program of the Uniformed Services under chapter 55 of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Policy for Implementing Reductions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Whenever the Secretary of Defense directs that there be a reduction in the total number of military medical personnel of the Department of Defense, the Secretary shall require that the reduction be carried out so as to ensure that the reduction is not exclusively or disproportionately borne by any one of the armed forces and is not exclusively or disproportionately borne by either the active or the reserve components.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the term “medical personnel” means—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the members of the armed forces covered by the term “medical personnel” as defined in <ref>section 115a(e)(2) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the civilian personnel of the Department of Defense assigned to military medical facilities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title V, § 564(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 325</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title X, § 1073(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1900</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 129d.</num>
<heading> Disclosure to litigation support contractors</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Disclosure Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An officer or employee of the Department of Defense may disclose sensitive information to a litigation support contractor if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the disclosure is for the sole purpose of providing litigation support to the Government in the form of administrative, technical, or professional services during or in anticipation of litigation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> under a contract with the Government, the litigation support contractor agrees to and acknowledges—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> that sensitive information furnished will be accessed and used only for the purposes stated in the relevant contract;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> that the contractor will take all precautions necessary to prevent disclosure of the sensitive information provided to the contractor;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> that such sensitive information provided to the contractor under the authority of this section shall not be used by the contractor to compete against a third party for Government or non-Government contracts; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> that the violation of subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) is a basis for the Government to terminate the litigation support contract of the contractor.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “litigation support contractor” means a contractor (including an expert or technical consultant) under contract with the Department of Defense to provide litigation support.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “sensitive information” means confidential commercial, financial, or proprietary information, technical data, or other privileged information.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title VIII, § 802(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1484</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 130.</num>
<heading> Authority to withhold from public disclosure certain technical data</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of Defense may withhold from public disclosure any technical data with military or space application in the possession of, or under the control of, the Department of Defense, if such data may not be exported lawfully outside the United States without an approval, authorization, or license under the Export Administration Act of 1979 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 4601</ref> et seq.) or the Arms Export Control Act (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2751</ref> et seq.). However, technical data may not be withheld under this section if regulations promulgated under either such Act authorize the export of such data pursuant to a general, unrestricted license or exemption in such regulations.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Regulations under this section shall be published in the Federal Register for a period of no less than 30 days for public comment before promulgation. Such regulations shall address, where appropriate, releases of technical data to allies of the United States and to qualified United States contractors, including United States contractors that are small business concerns, for use in performing United States Government contracts.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> In this section, the term “technical data with military or space application” means any blueprints, drawings, plans, instructions, computer software and documentation, or other technical information that can be used, or be adapted for use, to design, engineer, produce, manufacture, operate, repair, overhaul, or reproduce any military or space equipment or technology concerning such equipment.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 98–94, title XII, § 1217(a)</ref>, <date date="1983-09-24">Sept. 24, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 690</ref>, § 140c; amended <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title XIII, § 1303(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 738</ref>; renumbered § 130 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 99–433, title I</ref>, §§ 101(a)(3), 110(d)(6), <date date="1986-10-01">Oct. 1, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 994</ref>, 1003; <ref>Pub. L. 100–26, § 7(k)(3)</ref>, <date date="1987-04-21">Apr. 21, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 284</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XIV, § 1484(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1715</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title X, § 1081(b)(3)(A)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2418</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 130a.</num>
<heading> Department of Defense support for funerals and memorial events for Members and former Members of Congress</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Support for Funerals</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to subsection (b), the Secretary of Defense may provide such support as the Secretary considers appropriate for a funeral or memorial event for a Member or former Member of Congress, including support with respect to transportation to and from such a funeral or memorial event, in accordance with this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requests for Support; Secretary Determination</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary may provide support under this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> upon request from the Speaker of the House of Representatives, the Minority Leader of the House of Representatives, the Majority Leader of the Senate, or the Minority Leader of the Senate; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> if the Secretary determines such support is necessary to carry out duties or responsibilities of the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of Funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may use funds authorized to be appropriated for operation and maintenance to provide support under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title X, § 1042(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2770</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 130b.</num>
<heading> Personnel in overseas, sensitive, or routinely deployable units: nondisclosure of personally identifying information</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exemption From Disclosure</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense and, with respect to the Coast Guard when it is not operating as a service in the Navy, the Secretary of Homeland Security may, notwithstanding <ref>section 552 of title 5</ref>, authorize to be withheld from disclosure to the public personally identifying information regarding—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any member of the armed forces assigned to an overseas unit, a sensitive unit, or a routinely deployable unit; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any employee of the Department of Defense or of the Coast Guard whose duty station is with any such unit.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exceptions</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The authority in subsection (a) is subject to such exceptions as the President may direct.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Subsection (a) does not authorize any official to withhold, or to authorize the withholding of, information from Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “personally identifying information”, with respect to any person, means the person’s name, rank, duty address, and official title and information regarding the person’s pay.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “unit” means a military organization of the armed forces designated as a unit by competent authority.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “overseas unit” means a unit that is located outside the United States and its territories.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> The term “sensitive unit” means a unit that is primarily involved in training for the conduct of, or conducting, special activities or classified missions, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a unit involved in collecting, handling, disposing, or storing of classified information and materials;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> a unit engaged in training—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> special operations units;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> security group commands weapons stations; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> communications stations; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any other unit that is designated as a sensitive unit by the Secretary of Defense or, in the case of the Coast Guard when it is not operating as a service in the Navy, by the Secretary of Homeland Security.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The term “routinely deployable unit” means a unit that normally deploys from its permanent home station on a periodic or rotating basis to meet peacetime operational requirements that, or to participate in scheduled training exercises that, routinely require deployments outside the United States and its territories. Such term includes a unit that is alerted for deployment outside the United States and its territories during an actual execution of a contingency plan or in support of a crisis operation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1044(a)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 761</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–296, title XVII, § 1704(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2314</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 130c.</num>
<heading> Nondisclosure of information: certain sensitive information of foreign governments and international organizations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exemption From Disclosure</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The national security official concerned (as defined in subsection (h)) may withhold from public disclosure otherwise required by law sensitive information of foreign governments in accordance with this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Information Eligible for Exemption</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For the purposes of this section, information is sensitive information of a foreign government only if the national security official concerned makes each of the following determinations with respect to the information:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> That the information was provided by, otherwise made available by, or produced in cooperation with, a foreign government or international organization.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> That the foreign government or international organization is withholding the information from public disclosure (relying for that determination on the written representation of the foreign government or international organization to that effect).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> That any of the following conditions are met:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The foreign government or international organization requests, in writing, that the information be withheld.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The information was provided or made available to the United States Government on the condition that it not be released to the public.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The information is an item of information, or is in a category of information, that the national security official concerned has specified in regulations prescribed under subsection (g) as being information the release of which would have an adverse effect on the ability of the United States Government to obtain the same or similar information in the future.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Information of Other Agencies</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the national security official concerned provides to the head of another agency sensitive information of a foreign government, as determined by that national security official under subsection (b), and informs the head of the other agency of that determination, then the head of the other agency shall withhold the information from any public disclosure unless that national security official specifically authorizes the disclosure.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitations</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> If a request for disclosure covers any sensitive information of a foreign government (as described in subsection (b)) that came into the possession or under the control of the United States Government before <date date="2000-10-30">October 30, 2000</date>, and more than 25 years before the request is received by an agency, the information may be withheld only as set forth in paragraph (3).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> If a request for disclosure covers any sensitive information of a foreign government (as described in subsection (b)) that came into the possession or under the control of the United States Government on or after the date referred to in paragraph (1), the authority to withhold the information under this section is subject to the provisions of subparagraphs (B) and (C).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> Information referred to in subparagraph (A) may not be withheld under this section after—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the date that is specified by a foreign government or international organization in a request or expression of a condition described in paragraph (1) or (2) of subsection (b) that is made by the foreign government or international organization concerning the information; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> if there are more than one such foreign governments or international organizations, the latest date so specified by any of them.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> If no date is applicable under subparagraph (B) to a request referred to in subparagraph (A) and the information referred to in that subparagraph came into possession or under the control of the United States more than 10 years before the date on which the request is received by an agency, the information may be withheld under this section only as set forth in paragraph (3).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Information referred to in paragraph (1) or (2)(C) may be withheld under this section in the case of a request for disclosure only if, upon the notification of each foreign government and international organization concerned in accordance with the regulations prescribed under subsection (g)(2), any such government or organization requests in writing that the information not be disclosed for an additional period stated in the request of that government or organization. After the national security official concerned considers the request of the foreign government or international organization, the official shall designate a later date as the date after which the information is not to be withheld under this section. The later date may be extended in accordance with a later request of any such foreign government or international organization under this paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Information Protected Under Other Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section does not apply to information or matters that are specifically required in the interest of national defense or foreign policy to be protected against unauthorized disclosure under criteria established by an Executive order and are classified, properly, at the confidential, secret, or top secret level pursuant to such Executive order.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Disclosures Not Affected</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Nothing in this section shall be construed to authorize any official to withhold, or to authorize the withholding of, information from the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Comptroller General, unless the information relates to activities that the President designates as foreign intelligence or counterintelligence activities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The national security officials referred to in subsection (h)(1) shall each prescribe regulations to carry out this section. The regulations shall include criteria for making the determinations required under subsection (b). The regulations may provide for controls on access to and use of, and special markings and specific safeguards for, a category or categories of information subject to this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The regulations shall include procedures for notifying and consulting with each foreign government or international organization concerned about requests for disclosure of information to which this section applies.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The term “national security official concerned” means the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense, with respect to information of concern to the Department of Defense, as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Homeland Security, with respect to information of concern to the Coast Guard, as determined by the Secretary, but only while the Coast Guard is not operating as a service in the Navy.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Energy, with respect to information concerning the national security programs of the Department of Energy, as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “agency” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 552(f) of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The term “international organization” means the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A public international organization designated pursuant to section 1 of the International Organizations Immunities Act (<ref>59 Stat. 669</ref>; <ref>22 U.S.C. 288</ref>) as being entitled to enjoy the privileges, exemptions, and immunities provided in such Act.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A public international organization created pursuant to a treaty or other international agreement as an instrument through or by which two or more foreign governments engage in some aspect of their conduct of international affairs.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> An official mission, except a United States mission, to a public international organization referred to in subparagraph (A) or (B).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title X, § 1073(a)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–277; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title X, § 1048(a)(3)</ref>, (c)(1), <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1222</ref>, 1226; <ref>Pub. L. 107–296, title XVII, § 1704(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2314</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 130d.</num>
<heading> Treatment under Freedom of Information Act of certain confidential information shared with State and local personnel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Confidential business information and other sensitive but unclassified homeland security information in the possession of the Department of Defense that is shared, pursuant to section 892 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<ref>6 U.S.C. 482</ref>), with State and local personnel (as defined in such section) shall not be subject to disclosure under <ref>section 552 of title 5</ref> by virtue of the sharing of such information with such personnel.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title XIV, § 1405(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2436</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 130e.</num>
<heading> Treatment under Freedom of Information Act of certain critical infrastructure security information</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exemption</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense may exempt Department of Defense critical infrastructure security information from disclosure pursuant to <ref>section 552(b)(3) of title 5</ref>, upon a written determination that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the information is Department of Defense critical infrastructure security information; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the public interest consideration in the disclosure of such information does not outweigh preventing the disclosure of such information.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designation of Department of Defense Critical Infrastructure Security Information</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In addition to any other authority or requirement regarding protection from dissemination of information, the Secretary may designate information as being Department of Defense critical infrastructure security information, including during the course of creating such information, to ensure that such information is not disseminated without authorization. Information so designated is subject to the determination process under subsection (a) to determine whether to exempt such information from disclosure described in such subsection.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Information Provided to State and Local Governments</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Department of Defense critical infrastructure security information covered by a written determination under subsection (a) or designated under subsection (b) that is provided to a State or local government shall remain under the control of the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A State or local law authorizing or requiring a State or local government to disclose Department of Defense critical infrastructure security information that is covered by a written determination under subsection (a) shall not apply to such information.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> If a person requests pursuant to a State or local law that a State or local government disclose information that is designated as Department of Defense critical infrastructure security information under subsection (b), the State or local government shall provide the Secretary an opportunity to carry out the determination process under subsection (a) to determine whether to exempt such information from disclosure pursuant to subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transparency</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each determination of the Secretary under subsection (a) shall be made in writing and accompanied by a statement of the basis for the determination. All such determinations and statements of basis shall be available to the public, upon request.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “Department of Defense critical infrastructure security information” means sensitive but unclassified information that, if disclosed, would reveal vulnerabilities in Department of Defense critical infrastructure that, if exploited, would likely result in the significant disruption, destruction, or damage of or to Department of Defense operations, property, or facilities, including information regarding the securing and safeguarding of explosives, hazardous chemicals, or pipelines, related to critical infrastructure or protected systems owned or operated by or on behalf of the Department of Defense, including vulnerability assessments prepared by or on behalf of the Department of Defense, explosives safety information (including storage and handling), and other site-specific information on or relating to installation security.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title X, § 1091(a)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1604</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title X, § 1081(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 1000</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XVI, § 1662(b)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2614</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title IX, § 901(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 355</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 130f.</num>
<heading> Notification requirements for sensitive military operations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall promptly submit to the congressional defense committees notice in writing of any sensitive military operation conducted under this title no later than 48 hours following such operation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Procedures</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall establish and submit to the congressional defense committees procedures for complying with the requirements of subsection (a) consistent with the national security of the United States and the protection of operational integrity. The Secretary shall promptly notify the congressional defense committees in writing of any changes to such procedures at least 14 days prior to the adoption of any such changes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The congressional defense committees shall ensure that committee procedures designed to protect from unauthorized disclosure classified information relating to national security of the United States are sufficient to protect the information that is submitted to the committees pursuant to this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> In the event of an unauthorized disclosure of a sensitive military operation covered by this section, the Secretary shall ensure, to the maximum extent practicable, that the congressional defense committees are notified immediately of the sensitive military operation concerned. The notification under this paragraph may be verbal or written, but in the event of a verbal notification a written notification shall be provided by not later than 48 hours after the provision of the verbal notification.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Briefing Requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall periodically brief the congressional defense committees on Department of Defense personnel and equipment assigned to sensitive military operations, including Department of Defense support to such operations conducted under the National Security Act of 1947 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3001</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Sensitive Military Operation Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the term “sensitive military operation” means—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a lethal operation or capture operation conducted by the armed forces or conducted by a foreign partner in coordination with the armed forces that targets a specific individual or individuals;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an operation conducted by the armed forces in self-defense or in defense of foreign partners, including during a cooperative operation; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> an operation conducted by the armed forces to free an individual from the control of hostile foreign forces.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rule of Construction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section shall be construed to provide any new authority or to alter or otherwise affect the War Powers Resolution (<ref>50 U.S.C. 1541</ref> et seq.), the Authorization for Use of Military Force (<ref>Public Law 107–40</ref>; <ref>50 U.S.C. 1541</ref> note), or any requirement under the National Security Act of 1947 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3001</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Collective Self-defense Notification Requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 48 hours after the date on which a foreign partner force has been designated as eligible for the provision of collective self-defense by the armed forces for the purposes of subsection (d)(1)(B), the Secretary of Defense shall provide to the congressional defense committees notice in writing of such designation.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title X, § 1041(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 856</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title X, § 1043</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 977</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title X, § 1036(a)</ref>–(f)(1), <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2391</ref>, 2392; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title X, § 1081(a)(6)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1594</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title X, § 1031(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1953</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title X, § 1042</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1903</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 130g.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 394]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 130h.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XVI, § 1649(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2199</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 130i.</num>
<heading> Protection of certain facilities and assets from unmanned aircraft</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding <ref>section 46502 of title 49</ref>, or any provision of title 18, the Secretary of Defense may take, and may authorize members of the armed forces and officers and civilian employees of the Department of Defense with assigned duties that include safety, security, or protection of personnel, facilities, or assets, to take, such actions described in subsection (b)(1) that are necessary to mitigate the threat (as defined by the Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Secretary of Transportation) that an unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft poses to the safety or security of a covered facility or asset.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Actions Described</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The actions described in this paragraph are the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Detect, identify, monitor, and track the unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft, without prior consent, including by means of intercept or other access of a wire communication, an oral communication, or an electronic communication used to control the unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Warn the operator of the unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft, including by passive or active, and direct or indirect physical, electronic, radio, and electromagnetic means.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Disrupt control of the unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft, without prior consent, including by disabling the unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft by intercepting, interfering, or causing interference with wire, oral, electronic, or radio communications used to control the unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Seize or exercise control of the unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Seize or otherwise confiscate the unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Use reasonable force to disable, damage, or destroy the unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall develop the actions described in paragraph (1) in coordination with the Secretary of Transportation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Forfeiture</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft described in subsection (a) that is seized by the Secretary of Defense is subject to forfeiture to the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations and Guidance</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Transportation may prescribe regulations and shall issue guidance in the respective areas of each Secretary to carry out this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Transportation shall coordinate in the development of guidance under paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall coordinate with the Secretary of Transportation and the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration before issuing any guidance or otherwise implementing this section if such guidance or implementation might affect aviation safety, civilian aviation and aerospace operations, aircraft airworthiness, or the use of airspace.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Privacy Protection</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The regulations prescribed or guidance issued under subsection (d) shall ensure that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the interception or acquisition of, or access to, communications to or from an unmanned aircraft system under this section is conducted in a manner consistent with the fourth amendment to the Constitution and applicable provisions of Federal law;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> communications to or from an unmanned aircraft system are intercepted, acquired, or accessed only to the extent necessary to support a function of the Department of Defense;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> records of such communications are not maintained for more than 180 days unless the Secretary of Defense determines that maintenance of such records—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is necessary to support one or more functions of the Department of Defense; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is required for a longer period to support a civilian law enforcement agency or by any other applicable law or regulation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> such communications are not disclosed outside the Department of Defense unless the disclosure—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> would fulfill a function of the Department of Defense;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> would support a civilian law enforcement agency or the enforcement activities of a regulatory agency of the Federal Government in connection with a criminal or civil investigation of, or any regulatory action with regard to, an action described in subsection (b)(1); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> is otherwise required by law or regulation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Budget</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall submit to Congress, as a part of the defense budget materials for each fiscal year after fiscal year 2018, a consolidated funding display that identifies the funding source for the actions described in subsection (b)(1) within the Department of Defense. The funding display shall be in unclassified form, but may contain a classified annex.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Semiannual Briefings</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> On a semiannual basis during the five-year period beginning <date date="2018-03-01">March 1, 2018</date>, the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Transportation, shall jointly provide a briefing to the appropriate congressional committees on the activities carried out pursuant to this section. Such briefings shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> policies, programs, and procedures to mitigate or eliminate impacts of such activities to the National Airspace System;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a description of instances where actions described in subsection (b)(1) have been taken;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> how the Secretaries have informed the public as to the possible use of authorities under this section; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> how the Secretaries have engaged with Federal, State, and local law enforcement agencies to implement and use such authorities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Each briefing under paragraph (1) shall be in unclassified form, but may be accompanied by an additional classified briefing.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rule of Construction</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Nothing in this section may be construed to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> vest in the Secretary of Defense any authority of the Secretary of Transportation or the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration under title 49; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> vest in the Secretary of Transportation or the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration any authority of the Secretary of Defense under this title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Partial Termination</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided by paragraph (2), the authority to carry out this section with respect to the covered facilities or assets specified in clauses (iv) through (viii) of subsection (j)(3)(C) shall terminate on <date date="2026-12-31">December 31, 2026</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The President may extend by 180 days the termination date specified in paragraph (1) if before <date date="2026-11-15">November 15, 2026</date>, the President certifies to Congress that such extension is in the national security interests of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The term “appropriate congressional committees” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the congressional defense committees;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Select Committee on Intelligence, the Committee on the Judiciary, and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence, the Committee on the Judiciary, and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “budget”, with respect to a fiscal year, means the budget for that fiscal year that is submitted to Congress by the President under <ref>section 1105(a) of title 31</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The term “covered facility or asset” means any facility or asset that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is identified by the Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Secretary of Transportation with respect to potentially impacted airspace, through a risk-based assessment for purposes of this section;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is located in the United States (including the territories and possessions of the United States); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> directly relates to the missions of the Department of Defense pertaining to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> nuclear deterrence, including with respect to nuclear command and control, integrated tactical warning and attack assessment, and continuity of government;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> missile defense;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> national security space;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> assistance in protecting the President or the Vice President (or other officer immediately next in order of succession to the office of the President) pursuant to the Presidential Protection Assistance Act of 1976 (<ref>18 U.S.C. 3056</ref> note);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> air defense of the United States, including air sovereignty, ground-based air defense, and the National Capital Region integrated air defense system;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> combat support agencies (as defined in paragraphs (1) through (4) of <ref>section 193(f) of this title</ref>);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> special operations activities specified in paragraphs (1) through (9) of <ref>section 167(k) of this title</ref>;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> production, storage, transportation, or decommissioning of high-yield explosive munitions, by the Department; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ix)</num>
<content> a Major Range and Test Facility Base (as defined in <ref>section 4173 of this title</ref>).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “defense budget materials”, with respect to a fiscal year, means the materials submitted to Congress by the Secretary of Defense in support of the budget for that fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The terms “electronic communication”, “intercept”, “oral communication”, and “wire communication” have the meanings given those terms in <ref>section 2510 of title 18</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The terms “unmanned aircraft” and “unmanned aircraft system” have the meanings given those terms in <ref>section 44801 of title 49</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XVI, § 1697(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2639</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title XVI, § 1692</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1788</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title XVI, § 1694</ref>, title XVII, § 1731(a)(6), <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1791</ref>, 1812; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title X, § 1081(a)(8)</ref>, title XVIII, § 1845(c)(4), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3871</ref>, 4247; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XVI, § 1681</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 611</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(a)(2)</ref>, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2871(c)(1), <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2203</ref>, 2281.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§§ 130j, 130k.</num>
<heading> Renumbered §§ 395, 396]</heading>
</section>
</chapter>