<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 22—</num>
<heading>NATIONAL GEOSPATIAL-INTELLIGENCE AGENCY</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>MISSIONS AND AUTHORITY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 441.</num>
<heading> Establishment</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency is a combat support agency of the Department of Defense and has significant national missions.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Director</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Director of the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency is the head of the agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Upon a vacancy in the position of Director, the Secretary of Defense shall recommend to the President an individual for appointment to the position.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> If an officer of the armed forces on active duty is appointed to the position of Director, the position shall be treated as having been designated by the President as a position of importance and responsibility for purposes of <ref>section 601 of this title</ref> and shall carry the grade of lieutenant general, or, in the case of an officer of the Navy, vice admiral.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Director of National Intelligence Collection Tasking Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Unless otherwise directed by the President, the Director of National Intelligence shall have authority (except as otherwise agreed by the Director and the Secretary of Defense) to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> approve collection requirements levied on national imagery collection assets;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> determine priorities for such requirements; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> resolve conflicts in such priorities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Availability and Continued Improvement of Imagery Intelligence Support to All-Source Analysis and Production Function</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Director of National Intelligence, shall take all necessary steps to ensure the full availability and continued improvement of imagery intelligence support for all-source analysis and production.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XI, § 1112(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2678</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title IX, § 921(d)(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1568</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title IX, § 931(a)(9)</ref>, (10), (c)(1)(A), <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 285</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title IX, § 932(a)(8), (9), (b)(1), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4576</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title X, § 1073(c)(10)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2475</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 442.</num>
<heading> Missions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">National Security Missions</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency shall, in support of the national security objectives of the United States, provide geospatial intelligence consisting of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Imagery.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Imagery intelligence.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Geospatial information.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> As directed by the Director of National Intelligence, the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency shall develop a system to facilitate the analysis, dissemination, and incorporation of likenesses, videos, and presentations produced by ground-based platforms, including handheld or clandestine photography taken by or on behalf of human intelligence collection organizations or available as open-source information, into the National System for Geospatial Intelligence.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The authority provided by this paragraph does not include authority for the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency to manage tasking of handheld or clandestine photography taken by or on behalf of human intelligence collection organizations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Geospatial intelligence provided in carrying out paragraphs (1) and (2) shall be timely, relevant, and accurate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Navigation Information</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency shall improve the means for safe navigation by providing, under the authority of the Secretary of Defense, accurate geospatial information for use by the departments and agencies of the United States, the merchant marine, and navigators generally.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Maps, Charts, Etc</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency shall acquire, prepare, and distribute maps, safe-for-navigation charts and datasets, books, and geomatics products as authorized under subchapter II of this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">National Missions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency also has national missions as specified in section 110(a) of the National Security Act of 1947 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3045(a)</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Systems</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency may, in furtherance of a mission of the Agency, design, develop, deploy, operate, and maintain systems related to the processing and dissemination of imagery intelligence and geospatial information that may be transferred to, accepted or used by, or used on behalf of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the armed forces, including any combatant command, component of a combatant command, joint task force, or tactical unit; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any other department or agency of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Validation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency shall assist the Joint Chiefs of Staff, combatant commands, and the military departments in establishing, coordinating, consolidating, and validating mapping, charting, geomatics data, and safety of navigation capability requirements through a formal process governed by the Joint Staff. Consistent with validated requirements, the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency shall provide aeronautical and nautical charts that are safe for navigation, maps, books, datasets, models, and geomatics products.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XI, § 1112(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2678</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title IX, § 921(c)(1)</ref>, (d)(2)(A), (f), <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1568</ref>, 1570; <ref>Pub. L. 111–259, title IV, § 432</ref>, <date date="2010-10-07">Oct. 7, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2732</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title X, § 1071(c)(6)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3509</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVI, § 1621(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4052</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 443.</num>
<heading> Imagery intelligence and geospatial information: support for foreign countries, regional organizations, and security alliances</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of Appropriated Funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Director of the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency may use appropriated funds available to the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency to provide foreign countries, regional organizations with defense or security components, and security alliances of which the United States is a member with imagery intelligence and geospatial information support.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of Funds Other Than Appropriated Funds</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Director may use funds other than appropriated funds to provide foreign countries with imagery intelligence and geospatial information support, notwithstanding provisions of law relating to the expenditure of funds of the United States, except that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> no such funds may be expended, in whole or in part, by or for the benefit of the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency for a purpose for which Congress had previously denied funds;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> proceeds from the sale of imagery intelligence or geospatial information items may be used only to purchase replacement items similar to the items that are sold; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the authority provided by this subsection may not be used to acquire items or services for the principal benefit of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Accommodation Procurements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The authority under this section may be exercised to conduct accommodation procurements on behalf of foreign countries.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Coordination With Director of National Intelligence</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Director of the Agency shall coordinate with the Director of National Intelligence any action under this section that involves imagery intelligence or intelligence products or involves providing support to an intelligence or security service of a foreign country.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XI, § 1112(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2679</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title X, § 1073(a)(7)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1900</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title IX, § 921(d)(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1568</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title IX, § 931(a)(11)</ref>, (c)(1)(B), <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 285</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title IX, § 932(a)(10), (b)(2), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4576</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title X, § 1073(c)(10)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2475</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title IX, § 921(a)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1878</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 444.</num>
<heading> Support from Central Intelligence Agency</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Support Authorized</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Director of the Central Intelligence Agency may provide support in accordance with this section to the Director of the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency. The Director of the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency may accept support provided under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Administrative and Contract Services</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In furtherance of the national intelligence effort, the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency may provide administrative and contract services to the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency as if that agency were an organizational element of the Central Intelligence Agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Services provided under paragraph (1) may include the services of security police. For purposes of section 15 of the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3515</ref>), an installation of the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency that is provided security police services under this section shall be considered an installation of the Central Intelligence Agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Support provided under this subsection shall be provided under terms and conditions agreed upon by the Secretary of Defense and the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Detail of Personnel</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Director of the Central Intelligence Agency may detail personnel of the Central Intelligence Agency indefinitely to the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency without regard to any limitation on the duration of interagency details of Federal Government personnel.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reimbursable or Nonreimbursable Support</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Support under this section may be provided and accepted on either a reimbursable basis or a nonreimbursable basis.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority To Transfer Funds</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Director of the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency may transfer funds available for that agency to the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency for the Central Intelligence Agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Director of the Central Intelligence Agency—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> may accept funds transferred under paragraph (1); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> shall expend such funds, in accordance with the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3501</ref> et seq.), to provide administrative and contract services or detail personnel to the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XI, § 1112(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2680</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title IX, § 921(d)(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1568</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title IX, § 931(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 285</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title IX, § 932(c), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4576</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title X, § 1073(c)(10)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2475</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title X, § 1071(c)(7)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3509</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 445.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 105–107, title V, § 503(c)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-20">Nov. 20, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 2262</ref>]</heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>MAPS, CHARTS, AND GEOMATICS PRODUCTS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 451.</num>
<heading> Maps, charts, books, and datasets</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of Defense may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> have the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency prepare nautical and aeronautical charts, topographic and geomatics maps, books, models, and datasets required in navigation and have those materials published and furnished to navigators; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> acquire (by purchase, lease, license, or barter) all necessary rights, including copyrights and other intellectual property rights, required to prepare, publish, and furnish to navigators the products described in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 97–295, § 1(50)(C)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-12">Oct. 12, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1299</ref>, § 2792; renumbered § 451 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XI, § 1112(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2682</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title IX, § 921(d)(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1568</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVI, § 1621(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4053</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 452.</num>
<heading> Pilot charts</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> There shall be conspicuously printed on pilot charts prepared in the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency the following: “Prepared from data furnished by the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency of the Department of Defense and by the Department of Commerce, and published at the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency under the authority of the Secretary of Defense”.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Commerce shall furnish to the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, as quickly as possible, all meteorological information received by the Secretary that is necessary for, and of the character used in, preparing pilot charts.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 97–295, § 1(50)(C)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-12">Oct. 12, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1299</ref>, § 2793; renumbered § 452 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XI, § 1112(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2682</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title IX, § 921(d)(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1568</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 453.</num>
<heading> Sale of maps, charts, and navigational publications: prices; use of proceeds</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prices</inline>.—</heading>
<content>All maps, charts, and other publications offered for sale by the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency shall be sold at prices and under regulations that may be prescribed by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of Proceeds To Pay Foreign Licensing Fees</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may pay any NGA foreign data acquisition fee out of the proceeds of the sale of maps, charts, and other publications of the Agency, and those proceeds are hereby made available for that purpose.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In this subsection, the term “NGA foreign data acquisition fee” means any licensing or other fee imposed by a foreign country or international organization for the acquisition or use of data or products by the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 97–295, § 1(50)(C)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-12">Oct. 12, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1299</ref>, § 2794; renumbered § 453 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XI, § 1112(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2682</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1010(a)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 739</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title IX, § 921(d)(2)(A)</ref>, (B), <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1568</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 454.</num>
<heading> Exchange of mapping, charting, and geomatics data with foreign countries, international organizations, nongovernmental organizations, and academic institutions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Foreign Countries and International Organizations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may authorize the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency to exchange or furnish mapping, charting, and geomatics data, supplies and services to a foreign country or international organization pursuant to an agreement for the production or exchange of such data.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Nongovernmental Organizations and Academic Institutions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may authorize the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency to exchange or furnish mapping, charting, and geomatics data, supplies, and services relating to areas outside of the United States to a nongovernmental organization or an academic institution engaged in geospatial information research or production of such areas pursuant to an agreement for the production or exchange of such data.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–569, title VI, § 601(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3202</ref>, § 2795; renumbered § 454 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XI, § 1112(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2682</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title IX, § 921(d)(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1568</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title IX, § 923(a)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1539</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVI, § 1621(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4053</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 455.</num>
<heading> Maps, charts, and geomatics data: public availability; exceptions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency shall offer for sale maps and charts at scales of 1:500,000 and smaller, except those withheld in accordance with subsection (b) or those specifically authorized under criteria established by Executive order to be kept secret in the interest of national defense or foreign policy and in fact properly classified pursuant to such Executive order.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of Defense may withhold from public disclosure any geomatics product in the possession of, or under the control of, the Department of Defense—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> that was obtained or produced, or that contains information that was provided, pursuant to an international agreement that restricts disclosure of such product or information to government officials of the agreeing parties or that restricts use of such product or information to government purposes only;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> that contains information that the Secretary of Defense has determined in writing would, if disclosed, reveal sources and methods, or capabilities, used to obtain source material for production of the geomatics product; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> that contains information that the Director of the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency has determined in writing would, if disclosed, jeopardize or interfere with ongoing military or intelligence operations, reveal military operational or contingency plans, or reveal, jeopardize, or compromise military or intelligence capabilities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In this subsection, the term “geomatics product” means imagery, imagery intelligence, or geospatial information.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Regulations to implement this section (including any amendments to such regulations) shall be published in the Federal Register for public comment for a period of not less than 30 days before they take effect.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Regulations under this section shall address the conditions under which release of geomatics products authorized under subsection (b) to be withheld from public disclosure would be appropriate—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the case of allies of the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of qualified United States contractors (including contractors that are small business concerns) who need such products for use in the performance of contracts with the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–88, title V, § 502(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-08-14">Aug. 14, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 435</ref>, § 2796; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–359, title V, § 502</ref>, <date date="1994-10-14">Oct. 14, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3430</ref>; renumbered § 455 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XI, § 1112(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2682</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title IX, § 933(a)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1866</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title X, § 1074], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–280; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title IX, § 921(d)(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1568</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVI, § 1621(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4053</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 456.</num>
<heading> Civil actions barred</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No civil action may be brought against the United States on the basis of the content of geospatial information prepared or disseminated by the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title X, § 1074(b)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2861</ref>, § 2798; renumbered § 456 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XI, § 1112(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2682</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title IX, § 921(d)(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1568</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVI, § 1621(e)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4053</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 457.</num>
<heading> Operational files previously maintained by or concerning activities of National Photographic Interpretation Center: authority to withhold from public disclosure</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may withhold from public disclosure operational files described in subsection (b) to the same extent that operational files may be withheld under section 701 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3141</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered Operational Files</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The authority under subsection (a) applies to operational files in the possession of the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> as of <date date="1996-09-22">September 22, 1996</date>, were maintained by the National Photographic Interpretation Center; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> concern the activities of the Agency that, as of such date, were performed by the National Photographic Interpretation Center.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Operational Files Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “operational files” has the meaning given that term in section 701(b) of the National Security Act of 1947 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3141(b)</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1045(a)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 762</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title IX, § 921(d)(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1568</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title X, § 1071(c)(8)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3509</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>PERSONNEL MANAGEMENT</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 461.</num>
<heading> Management rights</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Scope</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If there is no obligation under the provisions of chapter 71 of title 5 for the head of an agency of the United States to consult or negotiate with a labor organization on a particular matter by reason of that matter being covered by a provision of law or a Governmentwide regulation, the Director of the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency is not obligated to consult or negotiate with a labor organization on that matter even if that provision of law or regulation is inapplicable to the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Bargaining Units</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Director of the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency shall accord exclusive recognition to a labor organization under <ref>section 7111 of title 5</ref> only for a bargaining unit that was recognized as appropriate for the Defense Mapping Agency on <date date="1996-09-30">September 30, 1996</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Termination of Bargaining Unit Coverage of Position Modified To Affect National Security Directly</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> If the Director of the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency determines that the responsibilities of a position within a collective bargaining unit should be modified to include intelligence, counterintelligence, investigative, or security duties not previously assigned to that position and that the performance of the newly assigned duties directly affects the national security of the United States, then, upon such a modification of the responsibilities of that position, the position shall cease to be covered by the collective bargaining unit and the employee in that position shall cease to be entitled to representation by a labor organization accorded exclusive recognition for that collective bargaining unit.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A determination described in paragraph (1) that is made by the Director of the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency may not be reviewed by the Federal Labor Relations Authority or any court of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XI, § 1112(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2681</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title IX, § 921(d)(2)(A)</ref>, (C), <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1568</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 462.</num>
<heading> Financial assistance to certain employees in acquisition of critical skills</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Defense may establish an undergraduate training program with respect to civilian employees of the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency that is similar in purpose, conditions, content, and administration to the program established by the Secretary of Defense under section 16 of the National Security Agency Act of 1959 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3614</ref>) for civilian employees of the National Security Agency.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 107–108, title V, § 504(a)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1405</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title IX, § 921(d)(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1568</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title X, § 1071(c)(9)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3509</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>DEFINITIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 467.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “function” means any duty, obligation, responsibility, privilege, activity, or program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> The term “imagery” means, except as provided in subparagraph (B), a likeness or presentation of any natural or manmade feature or related object or activity and the positional data acquired at the same time the likeness or representation was acquired, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> products produced by space-based national intelligence reconnaissance systems; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> likenesses or presentations produced by satellites, airborne platforms, unmanned aerial vehicles, or other similar means.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Such term does not include handheld or clandestine photography taken by or on behalf of human intelligence collection organizations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “imagery intelligence” means the technical, geographic, and intelligence information derived through the interpretation or analysis of imagery and collateral materials.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> The term “geospatial information” means information that identifies the geographic location and characteristics of natural or constructed features and boundaries on or about the earth and includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> data and information derived from, among other things, remote sensing, mapping, and surveying technologies; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> mapping, charting, geomatics data, and related products and services.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The term “geospatial intelligence” means the exploitation and analysis of imagery and geospatial information to describe, assess, and visually depict physical features and geographically referenced activities on or about the earth. Geospatial intelligence consists of imagery, imagery intelligence, and geospatial information.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XI, § 1112(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2682</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title IX, § 933(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1866</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title IX, § 921(b)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1568</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVI, § 1621(f)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4054</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>