<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 49—</num>
<heading>MISCELLANEOUS PROHIBITIONS AND PENALTIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 971.</num>
<heading> Service credit: officers may not count service performed while serving as cadet or midshipman</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition on Counting Enlisted Service Performed While at Service Academy or in Navy Reserve</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The period of service under an enlistment or period of obligated service while also performing service as a cadet or midshipman or serving as a midshipman in the Navy Reserve may not be counted in computing, for any purpose, the length of service of an officer of an armed force or an officer in the Commissioned Corps of the Public Health Service.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition on Counting Service as a Cadet or Midshipman</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In computing length of service for any purpose, service as a cadet or midshipman may not be credited to any of the following officers:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> An officer of the Navy or Marine Corps.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A commissioned officer of the Army, Air Force, or Space Force.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> An officer of the Coast Guard.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> An officer in the Commissioned Corps of the Public Health Service.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Service as a Cadet or Midshipman Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the term “service as a cadet or midshipman” means—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> service as a cadet at the United States Military Academy, United States Air Force Academy, or United States Coast Guard Academy; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> service as a midshipman at the United States Naval Academy.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 85–861, § 1(20)</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1442</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 90–235, § 6(a)</ref> (1), <date date="1968-01-02">Jan. 2, 1968</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 761</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–557, § 17(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2867</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title VI, § 652(a)(1)(A)</ref>, (2), <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1461</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title V, § 581</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2537</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title X, § 1073(a)(13)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1900</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title V, § 515(b)(1)(D)</ref>, (2), <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3233</ref>, 3234; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 924(b)(22)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3824</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 972.</num>
<heading> Members: effect of time lost</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Enlisted Members Required To Make Up Time Lost</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An enlisted member of an armed force who—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> deserts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> is absent from his organization, station, or duty for more than one day without proper authority, as determined by competent authority;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> is confined by military or civilian authorities for more than one day in connection with a trial, whether before, during, or after the trial; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> is unable for more than one day, as determined by competent authority, to perform his duties because of intemperate use of drugs or alcoholic liquor, or because of disease or injury resulting from his misconduct;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">is liable, after his return to full duty, to serve for a period that, when added to the period that he served before his absence from duty, amounts to the term for which he was enlisted or inducted.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Officers Not Allowed Service Credit for Time Lost</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In the case of an officer of an armed force who after <date date="1996-02-10">February 10, 1996</date>—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> deserts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> is absent from his organization, station, or duty for more than one day without proper authority, as determined by competent authority;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> is confined by military or civilian authorities for more than one day in connection with a trial, whether before, during, or after the trial; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> is unable for more than one day, as determined by competent authority, to perform his duties because of intemperate use of drugs or alcoholic liquor, or because of disease or injury resulting from his misconduct;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">the period of such desertion, absence, confinement, or inability to perform duties may not be counted in computing, for any purpose other than basic pay under <ref>section 205 of title 37</ref>, the officer’s length of service.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Waiver of Recoupment of Time Lost for Confinement</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary concerned shall waive liability for a period of confinement in connection with a trial under subsection (a)(3), or exclusion of a period of confinement in connection with a trial under subsection (b)(3), in a case upon the occurrence of any of the following events:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> For each charge—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the charge is dismissed before or during trial in a final disposition of the charge; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the trial results in an acquittal of the charge.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> For each charge resulting in a conviction in such trial—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the conviction is set aside in a final disposition of such charge, other than in a grant of clemency; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a judgment of acquittal or a dismissal is entered upon a reversal of the conviction on appeal.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 85–861, § 1(20)</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1443</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title V, § 561(a)</ref>–(c)(1), <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 321</ref>, 322; <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title X, § 1073(a)(14)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1900</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title V, § 572</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1921</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 973.</num>
<heading> Duties: officers on active duty; performance of civil functions restricted</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> No officer of an armed force on active duty may accept employment if that employment requires him to be separated from his organization, branch, or unit, or interferes with the performance of his military duties.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> This subsection applies—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to a regular officer of an armed force on the active-duty list (and a regular officer of the Coast Guard on the active duty promotion list);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to a retired regular officer of an armed force serving on active duty under a call or order to active duty for a period in excess of 270 days;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to a reserve officer of an armed force serving on active duty under a call or order to active duty for a period in excess of 270 days; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> to an officer on the Space Force officer list serving on active duty under <ref>section 20105(b) of this title</ref> or under a call or order to active duty for a period in excess of 270 days.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> Except as otherwise authorized by law, an officer to whom this subsection applies may not hold, or exercise the functions of, a civil office in the Government of the United States—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> that is an elective office;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> that requires an appointment by the President by and with the advice and consent of the Senate; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> that is a position in the Executive Schedule under sections 5312 through 5317 of title 5.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> An officer to whom this subsection applies may hold or exercise the functions of a civil office in the Government of the United States that is not described in subparagraph (A) when assigned or detailed to that office or to perform those functions.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Except as otherwise authorized by law, an officer to whom this subsection applies by reason of subparagraph (A) of paragraph (1) may not hold or exercise, by election or appointment, the functions of a civil office in the government of a State (or of any political subdivision of a State).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> An officer to whom this subsection applies by reason of subparagraph (B) or (C) of paragraph (1) may not hold, by election or appointment, a civil office in the government of a State (or of any political subdivision of a State) if the holding of such office while this subsection so applies to the officer—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is prohibited under the laws of that State; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> as determined by the Secretary of Defense or by the Secretary of Homeland Security with respect to the Coast Guard when it is not operating as a service in the Navy, interferes with the performance of the officer’s duties as an officer of the armed forces.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Except as otherwise authorized by law, while an officer referred to in subparagraph (A) is serving on active duty, the officer may not exercise the functions of a civil office held by the officer as described in that subparagraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to invalidate any action undertaken by an officer in furtherance of assigned official duties.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> In this subsection, the term “State” includes the District of Columbia and a territory, possession, or commonwealth of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> An officer to whom subsection (b) applies may seek and hold nonpartisan civil office on an independent school board that is located exclusively on a military reservation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense, and the Secretary of Homeland Security with respect to the Coast Guard when it is not operating in the Navy, shall prescribe regulations to implement this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 90–235, § 4(a)(5)(A)</ref>, <date date="1968-01-02">Jan. 2, 1968</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 759</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title I, § 116</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2878</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–94, title X, § 1002(a)</ref>, <date date="1983-09-24">Sept. 24, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 655</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title V, § 556</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1570</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title V, § 506</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 591</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–296, title XVII, § 1704(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2314</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title V, § 545</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1479</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XVII, § 1722(f)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 672</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 974.</num>
<heading> Military musical units and musicians: performance policies; restriction on performance in competition with local civilian musicians</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Military Musicians Performing in an Official Capacity</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A military musical unit, and a member of the armed forces who is a member of such a unit performing in an official capacity, may not engage in the performance of music in competition with local civilian musicians.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of paragraph (1), the following shall, except as provided in paragraph (3), be included among the performances that are considered to be a performance of music in competition with local civilian musicians:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> A performance that is more than incidental to an event that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is not supported, in whole or in part, by United States Government funds; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> is not free to the public.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> A performance of background, dinner, dance, or other social music at an event that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is not supported, in whole or in part, by United States Government funds; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> is held at a location not on a military installation.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of paragraph (1), the following shall not be considered to be a performance of music in competition with local civilian musicians:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A performance (including background, dinner, dance, or other social music) at an official United States Government event that is supported, in whole or in part, by United States Government funds.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> A performance at a concert, parade, or other event, that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is a patriotic event or a celebration of a national holiday; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> is free to the public.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> A performance that is incidental to an event that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is not supported, in whole or in part, by United States Government funds; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> is not free to the public.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> A performance (including background, dinner, dance, or other social music) at—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an event that is sponsored by a military welfare society, as defined in <ref>section 2566 of this title</ref>;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> an event that is a traditional military event intended to foster the morale and welfare of members of the armed forces and their families; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> an event that is specifically for the benefit or recognition of members of the armed forces, their family members, veterans, civilian employees of the Department of Defense, or former civilian employees of the Department of Defense, to the extent provided in regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<chapeau> A performance (including background, dinner, dance, or other social music)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> to uphold the standing and prestige of the United States with dignitaries and distinguished or prominent persons or groups of the United States or another nation; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in support of fostering and sustaining a cooperative relationship with another nation.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition of Military Musicians Accepting Additional Remuneration for Official Performances</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A military musical unit, and a member of the armed forces who is a member of such a unit performing in an official capacity, may not receive remuneration for an official performance, other than applicable military pay and allowances.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Recordings</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> When authorized under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense for purposes of this section, a military musical unit may produce recordings for distribution to the public, at a cost not to exceed expenses of production and distribution.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Amounts received in payment for a recording distributed to the public under this subsection shall be credited to the appropriation or account providing the funds for the production of the recording. Any amount so credited shall be merged with amounts in the appropriation or account to which credited, and shall be available for the same purposes, and subject to the same conditions and limitations, as amounts in such appropriation or account.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Private Donations</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned may accept contributions of money, personal property, or services on the condition that such money, property, or services be used for the benefit of a military musical unit under the jurisdiction of the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any contribution of money under paragraph (1) shall be credited to the appropriation or account providing the funds for such military musical unit. Any amount so credited shall be merged with amounts in the appropriation or account to which credited, and shall be available for the same purposes, and subject to the same conditions and limitations, as amounts in such appropriation or account.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Performances at Foreign Locations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subsection (a) does not apply to a performance outside the United States, its commonwealths, or its possessions.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Military Musical Unit Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “military musical unit” means a band, ensemble, chorus, or similar musical unit of the armed forces.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title V, § 590(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 136</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title V, § 591(a)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2335</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title III, § 351</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 741</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title X, § 1051(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1560</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 975.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 2390]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 976.</num>
<heading> Membership in military unions, organizing of military unions, and recognition of military unions prohibited</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “member of the armed forces” means (A) a member of the armed forces who is serving on active duty, (B) a member of the National Guard who is serving on full-time National Guard duty, or (C) a member of a Reserve component or the Space Force while performing inactive-duty training.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The term “military labor organization” means any organization that engages in or attempts to engage in—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> negotiating or bargaining with any civilian officer or employee, or with any member of the armed forces, on behalf of members of the armed forces, concerning the terms or conditions of military service of such members in the armed forces;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> representing individual members of the armed forces before any civilian officer or employee, or any member of the armed forces, in connection with any grievance or complaint of any such member arising out of the terms or conditions of military service of such member in the armed forces; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> striking, picketing, marching, demonstrating, or any other similar form of concerted action which is directed against the Government of the United States and which is intended to induce any civilian officer or employee, or any member of the armed forces, to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> negotiate or bargain with any person concerning the terms or conditions of military service of any member of the armed forces,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> recognize any organization as a representative of individual members of the armed forces in connection with complaints and grievances of such members arising out of the terms or conditions of military service of such members in the armed forces, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> make any change with respect to the terms or conditions of military service of individual members of the armed forces.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “civilian officer or employee” means an employee, as such term is defined in <ref>section 2105 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> It shall be unlawful for a member of the armed forces, knowing of the activities or objectives of a particular military labor organization—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to join or maintain membership in such organization; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to attempt to enroll any other member of the armed forces as a member of such organization.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> It shall be unlawful for any person—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to enroll in a military labor organization any member of the armed forces or to solicit or accept dues or fees for such an organization from any member of the armed forces; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to negotiate or bargain, or attempt through any coercive act to negotiate or bargain, with any civilian officer or employee, or any member of the armed forces, on behalf of members of the armed forces, concerning the terms or conditions of service of such members;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> to organize or attempt to organize, or participate in, any strike, picketing, march, demonstration, or other similar form of concerted action involving members of the armed forces that is directed against the Government of the United States and that is intended to induce any civilian officer or employee, or any member of the armed forces, to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> negotiate or bargain with any person concerning the terms or conditions of service of any member of the armed forces,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> recognize any military labor organization as a representative of individual members of the armed forces in connection with any complaint or grievance of any such member arising out of the terms or conditions of service of such member in the armed forces, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> make any change with respect to the terms or conditions of service in the armed forces of individual members of the armed forces; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to use any military installation, facility, reservation, vessel, or other property of the United States for any meeting, march, picketing, demonstration, or other similar activity for the purpose of engaging in any activity prohibited by this subsection or by subsection (b) or (d).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> It shall be unlawful for any military labor organization to represent, or attempt to represent, any member of the armed forces before any civilian officer or employee, or any member of the armed forces, in connection with any grievance or complaint of any such member arising out of the terms or conditions of service of such member in the armed forces.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<chapeau> No member of the armed forces, and no civilian officer or employee, may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> negotiate or bargain on behalf of the United States concerning the terms or conditions of military service of members of the armed forces with any person who represents or purports to represent members of the armed forces, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> permit or authorize the use of any military installation, facility, reservation, vessel, or other property of the United States for any meeting, march, picketing, demonstration, or other similar activity which is for the purpose of engaging in any activity prohibited by subsection (b), (c), or (d).</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Nothing in this subsection shall prevent commanders or supervisors from giving consideration to the views of any member of the armed forces presented individually or as a result of participation on command-sponsored or authorized advisory councils, committees, or organizations.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> Whoever violates subsection (b), (c), or (d) shall be fined under title 18 or imprisoned not more than 5 years, or both, except that, in the case of an organization (as defined in section 18 of such title), the fine shall not be less than $25,000.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<chapeau> Nothing in this section shall limit the right of any member of the armed forces—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to join or maintain membership in any organization or association not constituting a “military labor organization” as defined in subsection (a)(2) of this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to present complaints or grievances concerning the terms or conditions of the service of such member in the armed forces in accordance with established military procedures;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to seek or receive information or counseling from any source;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to be represented by counsel in any legal or quasi-legal proceeding, in accordance with applicable laws and regulations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to petition the Congress for redress of grievances; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> to take such other administrative action to seek such administrative or judicial relief, as is authorized by applicable laws and regulations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–610, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-08">Nov. 8, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 3085</ref>, § 975; renumbered § 976, <ref>Pub. L. 96–107, title VIII, § 821(a)</ref>, <date date="1979-11-09">Nov. 9, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 820</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–525, title IV, § 414(a)(6)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2519</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title XIII, § 1343(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3992</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–26, § 7(k)(2)</ref>, <date date="1987-04-21">Apr. 21, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 284</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title X, § 1073(a)(15)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1900</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XVII, § 1741(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 680</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 977.</num>
<heading> Conversion of military medical and dental positions to civilian medical and dental positions: limitation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Process</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense, in collaboration with the Secretaries of the military departments, shall establish a process to define the military medical and dental personnel requirements necessary to meet operational medical force readiness requirements.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirements Relating to Conversion</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A military medical or dental position within the Department of Defense may be converted to a civilian medical or dental position if the Secretary determines that the position is not necessary to meet operational medical force readiness requirements, as determined pursuant to subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Grade or Level Converted</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In carrying out a conversion under subsection (b), the Secretary of Defense—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall convert the applicable military position to a civilian position with a level of compensation commensurate with the skills and experience necessary to carry out the duties of such civilian position; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> may not place any limitation on the grade or level to which the military position is so converted.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “military medical or dental position” means a position for the performance of health care functions within the armed forces held by a member of the armed forces.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “civilian medical or dental position” means a position for the performance of health care functions within the Department of Defense held by an employee of the Department or of a contractor of the Department.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “conversion”, with respect to a military medical or dental position, means a change of the position to a civilian medical or dental position, effective as of the date of the manning authorization document of the military department making the change (through a change in designation from military to civilian in the document, the elimination of the listing of the position as a military position in the document, or through any other means indicating the change in the document or otherwise).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title VII, § 721(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2227</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 978.</num>
<heading> Drug and alcohol abuse and dependency: testing of new entrants</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary concerned shall require that, except as provided under paragraph (2), each person applying for an original enlistment or appointment in the armed forces shall be required, before becoming a member of the armed forces, to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> undergo testing (by practicable, scientifically supported means) for drug and alcohol use; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> be evaluated for drug and alcohol dependency.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned may provide that, in lieu of undergoing the testing and evaluation described in paragraph (1) before becoming a member of the armed forces, a member of the armed forces under the Secretary’s jurisdiction may be administered that testing and evaluation after the member’s initial entry on active duty. In any such case, the testing and evaluation shall be carried out within 72 hours of the member’s initial entry on active duty.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned shall require an applicant for appointment as a cadet or midshipman to undergo the testing and evaluation described in paragraph (1) within 72 hours of such appointment. The Secretary concerned shall require a person to whom a commission is offered under <ref>section 2106 of this title</ref> following completion of the program of advanced training under the Reserve Officers’ Training Corps program to undergo such testing and evaluation before such an appointment is executed.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> A person who refuses to consent to testing and evaluation required by subsection (a) may not (unless that person subsequently consents to such testing and evaluation)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> be accepted for an original enlistment in the armed forces or given an original appointment as an officer in the armed forces; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> if such person is already a member of the armed forces, be retained in the armed forces.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">An original appointment of any such person as an officer shall be terminated.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A person determined, as the result of testing conducted under subsection (a)(1), to be dependent on drugs or alcohol shall be denied entrance into the armed forces.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The enlistment or appointment of a person who is determined, as a result of an evaluation conducted under subsection (a)(2), to be dependent on drugs or alcohol at the time of such enlistment or appointment shall be void.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A person who is denied entrance into the armed forces under paragraph (1), or whose enlistment or appointment is voided under paragraph (2), shall be referred to a civilian treatment facility.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned may place on excess leave any member of the armed forces whose test results under subsection (a)(2) are positive for drug or alcohol use. The Secretary may continue such member’s status on excess leave pending disposition of the member’s case and processing for administrative separation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The testing and evaluation required by subsection (a) shall be carried out under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense in consultation with the Secretary of Homeland Security. Those regulations shall apply uniformly throughout the armed forces.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> In time of war, or time of emergency declared by Congress or the President, the President may suspend the provisions of subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 97–295, § 1(14)(A)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-12">Oct. 12, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1289</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–180, div. A, title V, § 513(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1091</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–456, div. A, title V, § 521(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1972</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title V, § 513(a)</ref>–(c), <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1440</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XIV, § 1484(k)(4)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1719</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title V, § 572</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1673</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–296, title XVII, § 1704(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2314</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 979.</num>
<heading> Prohibition on loan and grant assistance to persons convicted of certain crimes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Funds appropriated to the Department of Defense may not be used to provide a loan, a guarantee of a loan, or a grant to any person who has been convicted by a court of general jurisdiction of any crime which involves the use of (or assisting others in the use of) force, trespass, or the seizure of property under the control of an institution of higher education to prevent officials or students of the institution from engaging in their duties or pursuing their studies.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 98–525, title XIV, § 1401(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2615</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 980.</num>
<heading> Limitation on use of humans as experimental subjects</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Funds appropriated to the Department of Defense may not be used for research involving a human being as an experimental subject unless—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the informed consent of the subject is obtained in advance; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in the case of research intended to be beneficial to the subject, the informed consent of the subject or a legal representative of the subject is obtained in advance.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may waive the prohibition in this section with respect to a specific research project to advance the development of a medical product necessary to the armed forces if the research project may directly benefit the subject and is carried out in accordance with all other applicable laws.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary may delegate the authority provided by paragraph (1) to the Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 98–525, title XIV, § 1401(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2615</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title VII, § 733</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1170</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title II, § 212</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 183</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 981.</num>
<heading> Limitation on number of enlisted aides</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Subject to subsection (b), the total number of enlisted members that may be assigned or otherwise detailed to duty as enlisted aides on the personal staffs of officers of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, Space Force, and Coast Guard (when operating as a service of the Navy) during a fiscal year is the number equal to the sum of (1) four times the number of officers serving on active duty at the end of the preceding fiscal year in the grade of general or admiral, and (2) two times the number of officers serving on active duty at the end of the preceding fiscal year in the grade of lieutenant general or vice admiral.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Not more than 300 enlisted members may be assigned to duty at any time as enlisted aides for officers of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, and Space Force.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> Not later than March 1 of each year, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives a report—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> specifying the number of enlisted aides authorized and allocated for general officers and flag officers of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, Space Force, and joint pool as of September 30 of the previous year; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> justifying, on a billet-by-billet basis, the authorization and assignment of each enlisted aide to each general officer and flag officer position.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 98–525, title XIV, § 1401(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2615</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title V, § 504(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3355</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XVII, § 1741(b)(4)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 680</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 982.</num>
<heading> Members: service on State and local juries</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> A member of the armed forces on active duty may not be required to serve on a State or local jury if the Secretary concerned determines that such service—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> would unreasonably interfere with the performance of the member’s military duties; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> would adversely affect the readiness of the unit, command, or activity to which the member is assigned.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> A determination by the Secretary concerned under this section is conclusive.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned shall prescribe regulations for the administration of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> In this section, the term “State” includes the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and each territory of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title V, § 502(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3863</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 983.</num>
<heading> Institutions of higher education that prevent ROTC access or military recruiting on campus: denial of grants and contracts from Department of Defense, Department of Education, and certain other departments and agencies</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Denial of Funds for Preventing ROTC Access to Campus</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>No funds described in subsection (d)(1) may be provided by contract or by grant to an institution of higher education (including any subelement of such institution) if the Secretary of Defense determines that that institution (or any subelement of that institution) has a policy or practice (regardless of when implemented) that either prohibits, or in effect prevents—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Secretary of a military department from maintaining, establishing, or operating a unit of the Senior Reserve Officer Training Corps (in accordance with section 654 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002052">1</ref> of this title and other applicable Federal laws) at that institution (or any subelement of that institution); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a student at that institution (or any subelement of that institution) from enrolling in a unit of the Senior Reserve Officer Training Corps at another institution of higher education.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Denial of Funds for Preventing Military Recruiting on Campus</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>No funds described in subsection (d)(1) may be provided by contract or by grant to an institution of higher education (including any subelement of such institution) if the Secretary of Defense determines that that institution (or any subelement of that institution) has a policy or practice (regardless of when implemented) that either prohibits, or in effect prevents—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Secretary of a military department or the Secretary of Homeland Security from gaining access to campuses, or access to students (who are 17 years of age or older) on campuses, for purposes of military recruiting in a manner that is at least equal in quality and scope to the access to campuses and to students that is provided to any other employer;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> access by military recruiters for purposes of military recruiting, with respect to students (who are 17 years of age or older) enrolled at that institution (or any subelement of that institution)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> names, addresses, electronic mail addresses (which shall be the electronic mail addresses provided by the institution, if available), and telephone listings, which information shall be made available not later than the 60th day following the date of a request; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> date and place of birth, levels of education, academic majors, degrees received, and the most recent educational institution enrolled in by the student.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exceptions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The limitation established in subsection (a) or (b) shall not apply to an institution of higher education (or any subelement of that institution) if the Secretary of Defense determines that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the institution (and each subelement of that institution) has ceased the policy or practice described in that subsection; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the institution of higher education involved has a longstanding policy of pacifism based on historical religious affiliation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered Funds</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Except as provided in paragraph (2), the limitations established in subsections (a) and (b) apply to the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Any funds made available for the Department of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Any funds made available for any department or agency for which regular appropriations are made in a Departments of Labor, Health and Human Services, and Education, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Any funds made available for the Department of Homeland Security.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Any funds made available for the National Nuclear Security Administration of the Department of Energy.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Any funds made available for the Department of Transportation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Any funds made available for the Central Intelligence Agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any Federal funding specified in paragraph (1) that is provided to an institution of higher education, or to an individual, to be available solely for student financial assistance, related administrative costs, or costs associated with attendance, may be used for the purpose for which the funding is provided.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice of Determinations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Whenever the Secretary of Defense makes a determination under subsection (a), (b), or (c), the Secretary—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall transmit a notice of the determination to the Secretary of Education and to the head of each other department and agency the funds of which are subject to the determination; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall publish in the Federal Register a notice of the determination and the effect of the determination on the eligibility of the institution of higher education (and any subelement of that institution) for contracts and grants.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title V, § 541(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 315</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title V, § 549(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 609</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–296, title XVII, § 1704(b)(1)</ref>, (3), <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2314</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title V, § 552(a)</ref>–(d), <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1911</ref>, 1912; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title X, § 1061(11)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1583</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title V, § 586</ref>, title X, § 1076(f)(10), <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1768</ref>, 1952; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title V, § 521(b)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3597</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title V, § 543</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 265</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 985.</num>
<heading> Persons convicted of capital crimes; certain other persons: denial of specified burial-related benefits</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition of Performance of Military Honors</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of a military department and the Secretary of Homeland Security, with respect to the Coast Guard when it is not operating as a service in the Navy, may not provide military honors (under <ref>section 1491 of this title</ref> or any other authority) at the funeral or burial of any of the following persons:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A person described in <ref>section 2411(b) of title 38</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A person who is a veteran (as defined in <ref>section 1491(h) of this title</ref>) or who died while on active duty or a member of a reserve component, when the circumstances surrounding the person’s death or other circumstances as specified by the Secretary of Defense are such that to provide military honors at the funeral or burial of the person would bring discredit upon the person’s service (or former service).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Disqualification From Burial in Military Cemeteries</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Except as provided in subsection (c), a person who is ineligible for interment in a national cemetery under the control of the National Cemetery Administration by reason of <ref>section 2411(b) of title 38</ref> is not entitled to or eligible for, and may not be provided, burial in—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Arlington National Cemetery;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Soldiers’ and Airmen’s National Cemetery; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> any other cemetery administered by the Secretary of a military department or the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Unclaimed Remains of Military Prisoners</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subsection (b) shall not preclude the burial at the United States Disciplinary Barracks Cemetery at Fort Leavenworth, Kansas, of a military prisoner, including a military prisoner who is a person described in <ref>section 2411(b) of title 38</ref>, who dies while in custody of a military department and whose remains are not claimed by the person authorized to direct disposition of the remains or by other persons legally authorized to dispose of the remains.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “burial” includes inurnment.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title X, § 1077(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1914</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–296, title XVII, § 1704(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2314</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title VI, § 662(b)(1)</ref>–(3), (c)(1), <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3315</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title V, § 592</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1788</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 986.</num>
<heading> Policy regarding identification of gender or personal pronouns in official correspondence</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Defense may not require or prohibit a member of the armed forces or a civilian employee of the Department of Defense to identify the gender or personal pronouns of such member or employee in any official correspondence of the Department.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title V, § 522(b)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 249</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 987.</num>
<heading> Terms of consumer credit extended to members and dependents: limitations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Interest</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A creditor who extends consumer credit to a covered member of the armed forces or a dependent of such a member shall not require the member or dependent to pay interest with respect to the extension of such credit, except as—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> agreed to under the terms of the credit agreement or promissory note;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> authorized by applicable State or Federal law; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> not specifically prohibited by this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Percentage Rate</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A creditor described in subsection (a) may not impose an annual percentage rate of interest greater than 36 percent with respect to the consumer credit extended to a covered member or a dependent of a covered member.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Mandatory Loan Disclosures.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Information required</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>With respect to any extension of consumer credit (including any consumer credit originated or extended through the internet) to a covered member or a dependent of a covered member, a creditor shall provide to the member or dependent the following information orally and in writing before the issuance of the credit:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A statement of the annual percentage rate of interest applicable to the extension of credit.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Any disclosures required under the Truth in Lending Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 1601</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> A clear description of the payment obligations of the member or dependent, as applicable.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Terms</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Such disclosures shall be presented in accordance with terms prescribed by the regulations issued by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System to implement the Truth in Lending Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 1601</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Preemption.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inconsistent laws</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in subsection (f)(2), this section preempts any State or Federal law, rule, or regulation, including any State usury law, to the extent that such law, rule, or regulation is inconsistent with this section, except that this section shall not preempt any such law, rule, or regulation that provides protection to a covered member or a dependent of such a member in addition to the protection provided by this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Different treatment under state law of members and dependents prohibited</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>States shall not—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> authorize creditors to charge covered members and their dependents annual percentage rates of interest for any consumer credit or loans higher than the legal limit for residents of the State; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> permit violation or waiver of any State consumer lending protections covering consumer credit for the benefit of residents of the State on the basis of nonresident or military status of a covered member or dependent of such a member, regardless of the member’s or dependent’s domicile or permanent home of record.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>It shall be unlawful for any creditor to extend consumer credit to a covered member or a dependent of such a member with respect to which—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the creditor rolls over, renews, repays, refinances, or consolidates any consumer credit extended to the borrower by the same creditor with the proceeds of other credit extended to the same covered member or a dependent;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the borrower is required to waive the borrower’s right to legal recourse under any otherwise applicable provision of State or Federal law, including any provision of the Servicemembers Civil Relief Act (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3901</ref> et seq.);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the creditor requires the borrower to submit to arbitration or imposes onerous legal notice provisions in the case of a dispute;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the creditor demands unreasonable notice from the borrower as a condition for legal action;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the creditor uses a check or other method of access to a deposit, savings, or other financial account maintained by the borrower, or the title of a vehicle as security for the obligation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the creditor requires as a condition for the extension of credit that the borrower establish an allotment to repay an obligation; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the borrower is prohibited from prepaying the loan or is charged a penalty or fee for prepaying all or part of the loan.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Penalties and Remedies.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Misdemeanor</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A creditor who knowingly violates this section shall be fined as provided in title 18, or imprisoned for not more than one year, or both.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Preservation of other remedies</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The remedies and rights provided under this section are in addition to and do not preclude any remedy otherwise available under law to the person claiming relief under this section, including any award for consequential and punitive damages.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contract void</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any credit agreement, promissory note, or other contract prohibited under this section is void from the inception of such contract.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Arbitration</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding <ref>section 2 of title 9</ref>, or any other Federal or State law, rule, or regulation, no agreement to arbitrate any dispute involving the extension of consumer credit shall be enforceable against any covered member or dependent of such a member, or any person who was a covered member or dependent of that member when the agreement was made.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Civil liability.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A person who violates this section with respect to any person is civilly liable to such person for—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any actual damage sustained as a result, but not less than $500 for each violation;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> appropriate punitive damages;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> appropriate equitable or declaratory relief; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> any other relief provided by law.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Costs of the action</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In any successful action to enforce the civil liability described in subparagraph (A), the person who violated this section is also liable for the costs of the action, together with reasonable attorney fees as determined by the court.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Effect of finding of bad faith and harassment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In any successful action by a defendant under this section, if the court finds the action was brought in bad faith and for the purpose of harassment, the plaintiff is liable for the attorney fees of the defendant as determined by the court to be reasonable in relation to the work expended and costs incurred.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Defenses</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A person may not be held liable for civil liability under this paragraph if the person shows by a preponderance of evidence that the violation was not intentional and resulted from a bona fide error notwithstanding the maintenance of procedures reasonably adapted to avoid any such error. Examples of a bona fide error include clerical, calculation, computer malfunction and programming, and printing errors, except that an error of legal judgment with respect to a person’s obligations under this section is not a bona fide error.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Jurisdiction, venue, and statute of limitations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An action for civil liability under this paragraph may be brought in any appropriate United States district court, without regard to the amount in controversy, or in any other court of competent jurisdiction, not later than the earlier of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> two years after the date of discovery by the plaintiff of the violation that is the basis for such liability; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> five years after the date on which the violation that is the basis for such liability occurs.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Administrative enforcement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The provisions of this section (other than paragraph (1) of this subsection) shall be enforced by the agencies specified in section 108 of the Truth in Lending Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 1607</ref>) in the manner set forth in that section or under any other applicable authorities available to such agencies by law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Servicemembers Civil Relief Act Protections Unaffected</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section may be construed to limit or otherwise affect the applicability of section 207 of the Servicemembers Civil Relief Act (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3937</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations to carry out this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Such regulations shall establish the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Disclosures required of any creditor that extends consumer credit to a covered member or dependent of such a member.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The method for calculating the applicable annual percentage rate of interest on such obligations, in accordance with the limit established under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> A maximum allowable amount of all fees, and the types of fees, associated with any such extension of credit, to be expressed and disclosed to the borrower as a total amount and as a percentage of the principal amount of the obligation, at the time at which the transaction is entered into.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Definitions of “creditor” under paragraph (5) and “consumer credit” under paragraph (6) of subsection (i), consistent with the provisions of this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Such other criteria or limitations as the Secretary of Defense determines appropriate, consistent with the provisions of this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> In prescribing regulations under this subsection, and not less often than once every two years thereafter, the Secretary of Defense shall consult with the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Federal Trade Commission.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The Office of the Comptroller of the Currency.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> The National Credit Union Administration.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> The Treasury Department.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered member</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “covered member” means a member of the armed forces who is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> on active duty under a call or order that does not specify a period of 30 days or less; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> on active Guard and Reserve Duty.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Dependent</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “dependent”, with respect to a covered member, means a person described in subparagraph (A), (D), (E), or (I) of <ref>section 1072(2) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Interest</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “interest” includes all cost elements associated with the extension of credit, including fees, service charges, renewal charges, credit insurance premiums, any ancillary product sold with any extension of credit to a servicemember or the servicemember’s dependent, as applicable, and any other charge or premium with respect to the extension of consumer credit.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual percentage rate</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “annual percentage rate” has the same meaning as in section 107 of the Truth and Lending Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 1606</ref>), as implemented by regulations of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System. For purposes of this section, such term includes all fees and charges, including charges and fees for single premium credit insurance and other ancillary products sold in connection with the credit transaction, and such fees and charges shall be included in the calculation of the annual percentage rate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Creditor</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “creditor” means a person—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> who—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is engaged in the business of extending consumer credit; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> meets such additional criteria as are specified for such purpose in regulations prescribed under this section; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> who is an assignee of a person described in subparagraph (A) with respect to any consumer credit extended.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consumer credit</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “consumer credit” has the meaning provided for such term in regulations prescribed under this section, except that such term does not include (A) a residential mortgage, or (B) a loan procured in the course of purchasing a car or other personal property, when that loan is offered for the express purpose of financing the purchase and is secured by the car or personal property procured.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title VI, § 670(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2266</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title VI</ref>, §§ 661(a), (b), 662(a), (b), 663, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1785</ref>, 1786; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title X, § 1081(b)(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2418</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 988.</num>
<heading> Prohibition on ownership or trading of stocks in certain companies by certain officials of the Department of Defense</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in subsection (b), a covered official of the Department of Defense may not own or purchase publicly traded stock of a company if that company is one of the 10 entities awarded the most amount of contract funds by the Department of Defense in a fiscal year during the five preceding fiscal years.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exceptions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>This section shall not apply to the purchase or ownership of a publicly traded stock of a company otherwise described in subsection (a) as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> If the aggregate market value of the holdings of the covered official, and the spouse and minor children of the covered official, in the stock of that company, both before and after purchase (in the case of a purchase), does not exceed the de minimis threshold established in section 2640.202(a)(2) of title 5, Code of Federal Regulations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If the stock is purchased and owned as part of an Excepted Investment Fund or mutual fund.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The term “covered official of the Department of Defense” means any of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A civilian appointed to a position in the Department of Defense by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> If serving in a key acquisition position (as designated by the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary concerned for purposes of this section), the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> A member of the armed forces in a grade above O–6.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> A civilian officer or employee in a Senior Executive Service, Senior-Level, or Scientific or Professional position.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “Excepted Investment Fund” means a widely-held investment fund described in section 102(f)(8) of the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.).<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002053">1</ref></content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title IX, § 921(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1560</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 989.</num>
<heading> Prohibition on former members of the armed forces accepting post-service employment with certain foreign governments</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided by subsection (b), a covered individual may not occupy a covered post-service position.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Temporary Waiver.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense shall establish a process under which a covered individual may be granted a temporary waiver of the prohibition under subsection (a) if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the individual, or a Federal agency on behalf of, and with the consent of, the individual, submits to the Secretary a written application for a waiver in such form and manner as the Secretary determines appropriate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Secretary determines that the waiver is necessary to advance the national security interests of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Period of waiver</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A waiver issued under paragraph (1) shall apply for a period not exceeding 5 years. The Secretary may renew such a waiver.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Revocation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may revoke a waiver issued under paragraph (1) to a covered individual with respect to a covered-post service position if the Secretary determines that the employment of the individual in the covered-post service position poses a threat to national security.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Notification.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 30 days after the date on which the Secretary issues a waiver under paragraph (1) or revokes a waiver under paragraph (3), the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives written notification of the waiver or revocation, as the case may be.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A notification required by subparagraph (A) shall include the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> With respect to a waiver issued to a covered individual—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the details of the application, including the position held by the individual in the armed forces;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the nature of the post-service position of the individual;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> a description of the national security interests that will be advanced by reason of issuing such a waiver; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> the specific reasons why the Secretary determines that issuing the waiver will advance such interests.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> With respect to a revocation of a waiver issued to a covered individual—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the details of the waiver, including any renewals of the waiver, and the dates of such waiver and renewals; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the specific reasons why the Secretary determined that the revocation is warranted.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Certification of Prohibition</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In implementing the prohibition under subsection (a), the Secretary shall establish a process under which each member of the armed forces is, before the member retires or is otherwise separated from the armed forces—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> informed in writing of the prohibition, and the penalties for violations of the prohibition; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> required to certify that the member understands the prohibition and those penalties.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Penalties</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In the case of a covered individual who knowingly and willfully fails to comply with the prohibition under subsection (a), the Secretary may, as applicable—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> withhold any pay, allowances, or benefits that would otherwise be provided to the individual by the Department of Defense; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> revoke any security clearance of the individual.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Annual Reports.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than <date date="2024-03-31">March 31, 2024</date>, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report on covered post-service employment occurring during the year covered by the report.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each report required by paragraph (1) shall include the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> The number of former covered individuals who occupy a covered post-service position, broken down by—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the name of the employer;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the foreign government, including by the specific foreign individual, agency, or entity, for whom the covered post-service employment is being performed; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the nature of the services provided as part of the covered post-service employment.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> An assessment by the Secretary of whether—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Department of Defense maintains adequate systems and processes for ensuring that former members of the armed forces are submitting required reports relating to their employment by foreign governments;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> all covered individuals who occupy a covered post-service position are in compliance with this section;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the services provided by the covered individuals who occupy a covered post-service position pose a current or future threat to the national security of the United States; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> there is any credible information or reporting that any covered individual who occupies a covered post-service position has engaged in activities that violate Federal law.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Form of report</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each report required by paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Notifications of Determinations of Certain Threats.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In addition to the annual reports under subsection (d), if the Secretary determines that the services provided by a covered individual who occupies a covered post-service position pose a threat described in clause (iii) of paragraph (2)(B) of that subsection, or include activities described in clause (iv) of such paragraph, the Secretary shall notify the congressional defense committees of that determination by not later than 30 days after making the determination.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A notification required by paragraph (1) shall include the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The name of the covered individual.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The name of the employer.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The foreign government, including the specific foreign individual, agency, or entity, for whom the covered post-service employment is being performed.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> As applicable, a description of the risk to national security and the activities that may violate Federal law.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rule of Construction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section may be construed to indemnify or shield covered individuals from prosecution under any relevant provision of title 18.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered individual</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “covered individual” means an individual who has retired or otherwise separated from an active or reserve component of the Armed Forces.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered post-service employment</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “covered post-service employment” means direct or indirect employment by, representation of, or any provision of advice or services relating to national security, intelligence, the military, or internal security to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> the government of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a country of concern (as defined in section 1(m) of the State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2651a(m)</ref>)); or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a country the Secretary of Defense determines acts as a proxy or passthrough for services for a country of concern; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any company, entity, or other person the activities of which are directly or indirectly supervised, directed, controlled, financed, or subsidized, in whole or in major part, by a government described in subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered post-service position</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “covered post-service position” means a position of employment described in paragraph (2).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title V, § 523(a)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 250</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>