<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 833—</num>
<heading>HOSPITALIZATION AND MEDICAL CARE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 8281.</num>
<heading> Members of the naval service in other United States hospitals</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> When appropriate naval hospital facilities are unavailable, the Secretary of the Navy may provide for the care and treatment of members of the naval service, entitled to treatment in naval hospitals, in other United States hospitals, if the agencies controlling the other hospitals consent. Expenses incident to such care and treatment are chargeable to the same appropriation as would be chargeable for care and treatment in a naval hospital.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The deduction authorized by section 4812 of the Revised Statutes (<ref>24 U.S.C. 16</ref>) shall be made from accounts of members hospitalized under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 387</ref>, § 6201; <ref>Pub. L. 85–861, § 36B(19)</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1571</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 513(14)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2932</ref>; renumbered § 8281, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(b)(11)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1832</ref>, 1835.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8282.</num>
<heading> Insane members of the naval service</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A member of the naval service who becomes insane may be placed in the hospital for the insane that, in the opinion of the Secretary of the Navy, is most convenient and will provide the most beneficial treatment.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 387</ref>, § 6202; renumbered § 8282, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(b)(11)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1835</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8283.</num>
<heading> Emergency medical treatment: reimbursement for expense</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Navy shall prescribe regulations for reimbursing members of the naval service for expenses of emergency or necessary medical service, including hospitalization and medicines, when the member was in a duty status at the time he received the service and the service was not available from a Federal source. For the purpose of this section, a member on leave or liberty is in a duty status.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 387</ref>, § 6203; renumbered § 8283, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(b)(11)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1835</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>