<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 877—</num>
<heading>QUARTERS, UTILITIES, AND SERVICES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 8771.</num>
<heading> Quarters or other accommodations: to whom furnished</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Under such regulations as the Secretary of the Navy prescribes, public quarters including heat, light, water, and refrigeration may be furnished for personnel in the following categories who are on active duty:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Members of the naval service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Members of the Coast Guard when it is operating as a service in the Navy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Members of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration serving with the Navy.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">If public quarters are not available for any such member, the Secretary may provide lodging accommodations for him. Lodging accommodations so provided may not be occupied by the member’s dependents.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Secretary may determine in any case whether public quarters are available within the meaning of any provision of law relating to the assignment of or commutation for public quarters.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Secretary, to the extent he considers proper, may delegate the authority conferred by subsection (a), except the authority to prescribe regulations, to any person in the Department of the Navy, with or without authority to make successive redelegations.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 467</ref>, § 7571; <ref>Pub. L. 89–718, § 8(a)</ref>, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1117</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 513(41)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2935</ref>; renumbered § 8771, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(d)(9)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1837</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8772.</num>
<heading> Quarters: accommodations in place for members on sea duty or assigned to duty in connection with commissioning or fitting out of a ship</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> If public quarters are not available, the Secretary of the Navy may provide lodging accommodations for any—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> member of the naval service;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> member of the Coast Guard when it is operating as a service in the Navy; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> member of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration serving with the Navy;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">on sea duty or assigned to duty in connection with commissioning or fitting out of a ship who is deprived of his quarters on board ship because of repairs, because the ship is under construction and is not yet habitable, or because of other conditions that make his quarters uninhabitable. Lodging accommodations so provided may not be occupied by the member’s dependents.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>[(b)</num>
<content> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title X, § 1069(a)(7)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2136</ref>.]</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Secretary, to the extent he considers proper, may delegate the authority conferred by subsection (a) to any person in the Department of the Navy, with or without the authority to make successive redelegations.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A member of the naval service on sea duty who is deprived of quarters on board ship because of repairs or because of other conditions that make the member’s quarters uninhabitable may be reimbursed for expenses incurred in obtaining housing if it is impracticable to furnish the member with accommodations under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The total amount that a member may be reimbursed under this subsection may not exceed an amount equal to the basic allowance for housing of a member of that member’s grade.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> This subsection shall not apply to a member who is entitled to basic allowance for housing.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Secretary may prescribe regulations to carry out this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary may reimburse a member of the naval service assigned to duty in connection with commissioning or fitting out of a ship in Pascagoula, Mississippi, or Bath, Maine, who is deprived of quarters on board a ship because the ship is under construction and is not yet habitable, or because of other conditions that make the member’s quarters uninhabitable, for expenses incurred in obtaining housing, but only when the Navy is unable to furnish the member with lodging accommodations under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The total amount that a member may be reimbursed under this subsection may not exceed an amount equal to the basic allowance for housing of a member without dependents of that member’s grade.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A member without dependents, or a member who resides with dependents while assigned to duty in connection with commissioning or fitting out of a ship at one of the locations specified in paragraph (1), may not be reimbursed under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Secretary may prescribe regulations to carry out this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 468</ref>, § 7572; <ref>Pub. L. 89–718, § 8(a)</ref>, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1117</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–357, § 3</ref>, <date date="1980-09-24">Sept. 24, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1182</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 513(41)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2935</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–60, title II, § 207(b)</ref>, <date date="1981-10-14">Oct. 14, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1007</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–94, title IX, § 912(a)</ref>, <date date="1983-09-24">Sept. 24, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 640</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–525, title VI</ref>, §§ 602(d)(3), 603(a), title XIV, § 1405(54), <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2536</ref>, 2537, 2625; <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title VI, § 606(a)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 638</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title VI, § 603(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3874</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title VI, § 607(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1375</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title VI, § 603(d)(2)(D)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1783</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title X, § 1069(a)(7)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2136</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title VI, § 602(a)</ref>–(d)(1), <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1447</ref>, 1448; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title X, § 1076(a)(5)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1948</ref>; renumbered § 8772, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(d)(9)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1837</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8773.</num>
<heading> Quarters: temporary; transient members</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Temporary quarters may be furnished on a rental basis to transient members of the naval service with their dependents, for periods not exceeding 60 days, without loss of entitlement to basic allowance for housing under <ref>section 403 of title 37</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 468</ref>, § 7573; <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title VI, § 603(d)(2)(E)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1783</ref>; renumbered § 8773, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(d)(9)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1837</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8776.</num>
<heading> Quarters: extension telephones</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of the Navy appropriated funds may be used to pay the cost of installation and use, other than for personal long distance calls, of extension telephones connecting public quarters occupied by personnel in the following categories with the switchboards of their official stations:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Members of the naval service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Members of the Coast Guard when it is operating as a service in the Navy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Members of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration serving with the Navy.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Secretary, to the extent he considers proper, may delegate the authority conferred by this section, except the authority to prescribe regulations, to any person in the Department of the Navy, with or without the authority to make successive redelegations.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 469</ref>, § 7576; <ref>Pub. L. 89–718, § 8(a)</ref>, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1117</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 513(41)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2935</ref>; renumbered § 8776, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(d)(9)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1837</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8777.</num>
<heading> Quarters: Nurse Corps officers; assignment in hospitals</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Under such regulations as the Secretary of the Navy prescribes, officers in the Nurse Corps may be assigned quarters in naval hospitals.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 469</ref>, § 7577; renumbered § 8777, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(d)(9)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1837</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8779.</num>
<heading> Officers’ messes and quarters: limitations on employment of enlisted members</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Under such regulations as the Secretary of the Navy prescribes, enlisted members of the naval service and enlisted members of the Coast Guard when it is operating as a service in the Navy may be assigned to duty in a service capacity in officers’ messes and public quarters where the Secretary finds that this use of the members is desirable for military reasons.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, retired enlisted members of the naval service and members of the Fleet Reserve and the Fleet Marine Corps Reserve may, when not on active duty, be voluntarily employed in any service capacity in officers’ messes and public quarters without additional expense to the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Secretary, to the extent he considers proper, may delegate the authority conferred by this section, except the authority to prescribe regulations, to any person in the Department of the Navy, with or without the authority to make successive redelegations.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 470</ref>, § 7579; renumbered § 8779, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(d)(9)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1837</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8780.</num>
<heading> Heat and light for Young Men’s Christian Association buildings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Navy may furnish, without charge, heat and light to any building of the Young Men’s Christian Association located at a naval activity.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 470</ref>, § 7580; renumbered § 8780, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(d)(9)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1837</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8781.</num>
<heading> Marine Corps post laundries: disposition of receipts</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Money received for laundry work performed by Marine Corps post laundries shall be used to pay the cost of maintenance and operation of those laundries. Any amount remaining at the end of the fiscal year after the cost has been so paid shall be deposited in the Treasury to the credit of the appropriation from which the cost of operating the laundries is paid.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The receipts and expenditures of Marine Corps post laundries shall be accounted for as public funds.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 470</ref>, § 7581; renumbered § 8781, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(d)(9)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1837</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8782.</num>
<heading> Naval and Marine Corps Historical Centers: fee for providing historical information to the public</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in subsection (b), the Secretary of the Navy may charge a person a fee for providing the person with information from the United States Naval Historical Center or the Marine Corps Historical Center that is requested by that person.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exceptions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A fee may not be charged under this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to a person for information that the person requests to carry out a duty as a member of the armed forces or an officer or employee of the United States; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> for a release of information under <ref>section 552 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Amount</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A fee charged for providing information under this section may not exceed the cost of providing the information.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Retention of Fees</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Amounts received under subsection (a) for providing information from the United States Naval Historical Center or the Marine Corps Historical Center in any fiscal year shall be credited to the appropriation or appropriations charged the costs of providing information to the public from that historical center during that fiscal year.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “United States Naval Historical Center” means the archive for historical records and materials of the Navy that the Secretary of the Navy designates as the primary archive for such records and materials.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “Marine Corps Historical Center” means the archive for historical records and materials of the Marine Corps that the Secretary of the Navy designates as the primary archive for such records and materials.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The terms “officer of the United States” and “employee of the United States” have the meanings given the terms “officer” and “employee”, respectively, in sections 2104 and 2105, respectively, of title 5.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title X, § 1085(b)(1)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–288, § 7582; renumbered § 8782, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(d)(9)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1837</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>