<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 831—</num>
<heading>MISCELLANEOUS RIGHTS AND BENEFITS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 8261.</num>
<heading> Presentation of United States flag upon retirement</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Presentation of Flag</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Upon the release of a member of the Navy or Marine Corps from active duty for retirement or transfer to the Fleet Reserve or the Fleet Marine Corps Reserve, the Secretary of the Navy shall present a United States flag to the member.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Multiple Presentations Not Authorized</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A member is not eligible for a presentation of a flag under subsection (a) if the member has previously been presented a flag under this section or any other provision of law providing for the presentation of a United States flag incident to release from active service for retirement.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">No Cost to Recipient</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The presentation of a flag under this section shall be at no cost to the recipient.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title VI, § 644(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2048</ref>, § 6141; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title VI, § 652(e)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 666</ref>; renumbered § 8261, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(b)(10)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1835</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8262.</num>
<heading> Higher retired grade and pay for members who serve satisfactorily under temporary appointments</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Unless otherwise entitled to a higher retired grade and subject to section 689, and section 1370 or 1370a (as applicable), of this title, each member, other than a retired member, of the Navy or the Marine Corps shall, when retired, be advanced on the retired list to the highest officer grade in which he served satisfactorily under a temporary appointment as determined by the Secretary of the Navy.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Each member (other than a former member of the Fleet Reserve or the Fleet Marine Corps Reserve) who is advanced on the retired list under this section is (unless otherwise entitled to higher retired pay) entitled to retired pay determined in accordance with the following table. References in the table are to sections of this title.<table width="50%" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><colgroup><col/><col/></colgroup><thead><tr class="header"><th><p>Column 1</p><p>Take</p></th><th><p>Column 2</p><p>Multiply by</p></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><p>Retired pay base computed under section 1406(d) or 1407</p></td><td><p>Retired pay multiplier prescribed under section 1409 for the years of service that may be credited to him under section 1405.</p></td></tr></tbody></table>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Each former member of the Fleet Reserve or the Fleet Marine Corps Reserve who is advanced on the retired list under this section is entitled to retired pay determined in accordance with the following table. References in the table are to sections of this title.<table width="50%" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><colgroup><col/><col/></colgroup><thead><tr class="header"><th><p>Column 1</p><p>Take</p></th><th><p>Column 2</p><p>Multiply by</p></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><p>Retired pay base computed under section 1406(d) or 1407</p></td><td><p>Retired pay multiplier prescribed under section 1409 for the number of years of service creditable for his retainer pay at the time of retirement.</p></td></tr></tbody></table>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> A member who is advanced on the retired list under this section from the grade of warrant officer, W–1, or from an enlisted grade to a commissioned grade, and who applies to the Secretary within three months after his advancement, shall, if the Secretary approves, be restored on the retired list to his former warrant officer or enlisted grade, as the case may be. A member who is restored to his former grade under this subsection is thereafter considered for all purposes as a warrant officer, W–1, or an enlisted member, as the case may be.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> Retired pay computed under subsection (b) or (c), if not a multiple of $1, shall be rounded to the next lower multiple of $1.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 385</ref>, § 6151; <ref>Pub. L. 85–422, § 11(a)(6)(A)</ref>, <date date="1958-05-20">May 20, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 131</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–861, § 1(138)</ref>, (139)(A), <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1507</ref>, 1508; <ref>Pub. L. 88–132, § 5(h)(4)</ref>, <date date="1963-10-02">Oct. 2, 1963</date>, <ref>77 Stat. 214</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–342, title VIII, § 813(d)(13)</ref>, <date date="1980-09-08">Sept. 8, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1108</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V</ref>, §§ 503(45), 513(17), <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2914</ref>, 2932; <ref>Pub. L. 98–94, title IX</ref>, §§ 922(a)(9), 923(c)(1), <date date="1983-09-24">Sept. 24, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 641</ref>, 643; <ref>Pub. L. 99–348, title II, § 203(c)</ref>, <date date="1986-07-01">July 1, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 696</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title V, § 521(d)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2517</ref>; renumbered § 8262, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(b)(10)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 183</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title V, § 508(b)(3)(A)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3585</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8263.</num>
<heading> Emergency shore duty: advance of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Under such regulations as the President approves, the Secretary of the Navy may, to meet necessary expenses, advance funds to members of the naval service detailed on emergency shore duty. The funds advanced may not exceed the reasonable estimate of expenses to be incurred for which reimbursement is authorized.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 386</ref>, § 6152; renumbered § 8263, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(b)(10)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1835</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8264.</num>
<heading> Shore patrol duty: payment of expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An officer, midshipman, or cadet of the naval service who is assigned to shore patrol duty away from his vessel or other duty station may be paid his actual services.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 386</ref>, § 6153; renumbered § 8264, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(b)(10)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1835</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8265.</num>
<heading> Mileage books: commutation tickets</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Navy may buy such mileage books, commutation tickets, and other similar transportation tickets as he considers necessary, and he may furnish them to persons ordered to perform travel on official business. Payment for those tickets before the travel is performed is not an advance of public money within the meaning of subsections (a) and (b) of <ref>section 3324 of title 31</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 386</ref>, § 6154; <ref>Pub. L. 97–258, § 3(b)(8)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1063</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–525, title XIV, § 1405(56)(A)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2626</ref>; renumbered § 8265, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(b)(10)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1835</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8266.</num>
<heading> Uniforms, accouterments, and equipment: sale at cost</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Under such regulations as the Secretary of the Navy prescribes, uniforms, accouterments, and equipment shall be sold by the United States at cost to officers and midshipmen of the naval service and, when the Coast Guard is operating as a service in the Navy, to officers of the Coast Guard.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 386</ref>, § 6155; renumbered § 8266, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(b)(10)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1835</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8267.</num>
<heading> Uniform: sale to former members of the naval service</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Under such regulations as the Secretary of the Navy prescribes, exterior articles of uniform may be sold to a person who has been discharged from the naval service honorably or under honorable conditions. This section does not modify section 772 or 773 of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Money received from sales under this section shall be covered into the Treasury to the credit of the appropriation out of which the articles were purchased.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 386</ref>, § 6156; renumbered § 8267, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(b)(10)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1835</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8270.</num>
<heading> Pension to persons serving ten years</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Every disabled person who has served in the Navy or Marine Corps as an enlisted member or petty officer, or both, for ten or more years, and has not been discharged for misconduct, may apply to the Secretary of the Navy for aid.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Upon receipt of an application under subsection (a), the Secretary of the Navy may convene a board of not less than three naval officers (one of whom shall be a surgeon) to examine into the condition of the applicant, and to recommend a suitable amount for his relief, and for a specified time. If the Secretary of the Navy approves the recommendation, he shall so certify to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, who shall pay a pension in such amount monthly to the applicant.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> No naval pension under this section shall be paid at a rate in excess of the rate payable to a veteran of World War I for permanent and total non-service-connected disability, unless the applicant’s disability is service-connected, in which case the naval pension payable to him shall not exceed the rate of disability compensation payable for total disability to a veteran of any war, or of peacetime service, as the case may be. In the case of any initial award of naval pension granted before <date date="1943-07-14">July 14, 1943</date>, where the person granted the naval pension is also entitled to pension or compensation under laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, such naval pension shall not exceed one-fourth of such pension or compensation.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 85–56, title XXII, § 2201(31)(C)</ref>, <date date="1957-06-17">June 17, 1957</date>, <ref>71 Stat. 161</ref>, § 6160; amended <ref>Pub. L. 85–857, § 13(v)(4)</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1268</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title XIII, § 1301(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 736</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title XVI, § 1621(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1603</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XIV, § 1484(j)(4)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1719</ref>; renumbered § 8270, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(b)(10)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1835</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8271.</num>
<heading> Settlement of accounts: remission or cancellation of indebtedness of members</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the Navy may have remitted or cancelled any part of the indebtedness of a person to the United States or any instrumentality of the United States incurred while the person was serving as a member of the naval service, whether as a regular or a reserve in active status, but only if the Secretary considers such action to be in the best interest of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Retroactive Applicability to Certain Debts</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The authority in subsection (a) may be exercised with respect to any debt covered by that subsection that is incurred on or after <date date="2001-10-07">October 7, 2001</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section shall be administered under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 86–511, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1960-06-11">June 11, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 207</ref>, § 6161; amended <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title VI, § 683(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3322</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title VI, § 673(b)(1)</ref>, (2), (e)(2), <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2271</ref>, 2272; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title X, § 1063(c)(7)(B)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 323</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title VI, § 671(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2173</ref>; renumbered § 8271, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(b)(10)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1835</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>