<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 1611—</num>
<heading>OTHER EDUCATIONAL ASSISTANCE PROGRAMS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 16401.</num>
<heading> Marine Corps Platoon Leaders Class: college tuition assistance program</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of the Navy may provide financial assistance to an eligible member of the Marine Corps Reserve for expenses of the member while the member is pursuing on a full-time basis at an institution of higher education a program of education approved by the Secretary that leads to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a baccalaureate degree in less than five academic years; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a doctor of jurisprudence or bachelor of laws degree in not more than four academic years.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Eligibility</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> To be eligible for financial assistance under this section, a member of the Marine Corps Reserve must—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> be a member of the Marine Corps Platoon Leaders Class program and have successfully completed one six-week (or longer) increment of military training required under that program;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> be enrolled on a full-time basis in a program of education referred to in subsection (a) at any institution of higher education; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> enter into a written agreement with the Secretary described in paragraph (2).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> A written agreement referred to in paragraph (1)(C) is an agreement between the member and the Secretary in which the member agrees—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to accept an appointment as a commissioned officer in the Marine Corps, if tendered by the President;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to serve on active duty for at least five years; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> under such terms and conditions as shall be prescribed by the Secretary, to serve in the Marine Corps Reserve until the eighth anniversary of the date of the appointment.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered Expenses</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Expenses for which financial assistance may be provided under this section are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> tuition and fees charged by the institution of higher education involved;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the cost of books; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> in the case of a program of education leading to a baccalaureate degree, laboratory expenses.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Amount</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The amount of financial assistance provided to a member under this section shall be prescribed by the Secretary, but may not exceed $13,800 for any academic year.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitations</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Financial assistance may be provided to a member under this section only for three consecutive academic years.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Not more than 450 members may participate in the financial assistance program under this section in any academic year.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Failure To Complete Program</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> An enlisted member who receives financial assistance under this section may be ordered to active duty in the Marine Corps by the Secretary to serve in an appropriate enlisted grade for such period as the Secretary prescribes, but not for more than four years, and an officer who receives financial assistance under this section shall be subject to the repayment provisions of section 303a(e) or 373 of title 37, if the member—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> completes the military and academic requirements of the Marine Corps Platoon Leaders Class program and refuses to accept an appointment as a commissioned officer in the Marine Corps when offered or, if already a commissioned officer in the Marine Corps, refuses to accept an assignment on active duty when offered;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> fails to complete the military or academic requirements of the Marine Corps Platoon Leaders Class program; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> is disenrolled from the Marine Corps Platoon Leaders Class program for failure to maintain eligibility for an original appointment as a commissioned officer under <ref>section 532 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Any requirement to repay any portion of financial assistance received under this section shall be administered under the regulations issued under section 303a(e) or 373 of title 37. The Secretary of the Navy may waive the requirements of paragraph (1) in the case of a person who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> becomes unqualified to serve on active duty as an officer due to a circumstance not within the control of the person;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is not physically qualified for appointment under <ref>section 532 of this title</ref> and later is determined by the Secretary of the Navy under <ref>section 505 of this title</ref> to be unqualified for service as an enlisted member of the Marine Corps due to a physical or medical condition that was not the result of misconduct or grossly negligent conduct; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> fails to complete the military or academic requirements of the Marine Corps Platoon Leaders Class program due to a circumstance not within the control of the person.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Institution of Higher Education Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “institution of higher education” has the meaning given that term in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<ref>20 U.S.C. 1001</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title V, § 551(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 612</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title V, § 533(a)–(d), (f)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–110, 1654A–111; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title VI, § 687(c)(15)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3336</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title VI, § 618(a)(1)(R)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1426</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title V, § 559</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1899</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>