<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 361—</num>
<heading>CONTRACT ADMINISTRATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4601.</num>
<heading> Electronic submission and processing of claims for contract payments</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Submission of Claims</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall require that any claim for payment under a Department of Defense contract shall be submitted to the Department of Defense in electronic form.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Processing</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A contracting officer, contract administrator, certifying official, or other officer or employee of the Department of Defense who receives a claim for payment in electronic form in accordance with subsection (a) and is required to transmit the claim to any other officer or employee of the Department of Defense for processing under procedures of the department shall transmit the claim and any additional documentation necessary to support the determination and payment of the claim to such other officer or employee electronically.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Waiver Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the Secretary of Defense determines that the requirement for using electronic means for submitting claims under subsection (a), or for transmitting claims and supporting documentation under subsection (b), is unduly burdensome in any category of cases, the Secretary may exempt the cases in that category from the application of the requirement.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Implementation of Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In implementing subsections (a) and (b), the Secretary of Defense shall provide for the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Policies, requirements, and procedures for using electronic means for the submission of claims for payment to the Department of Defense and for the transmission, between Department of Defense officials, of claims for payment received in electronic form, together with supporting documentation (such as receiving reports, contracts and contract modifications, and required certifications).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The format in which information can be accepted by the corporate database of the Defense Finance and Accounting Service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The requirements to be included in contracts regarding the electronic submission of claims for payment by contractors.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Claim for Payment Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “claim for payment” means an invoice or any other demand or request for payment.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title X, § 1008(a)(1)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–249, § 2227; renumbered § 4601, <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1861(b)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4277</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4602.</num>
<heading> Contracted property and services: prompt payment of vouchers</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Of the contract vouchers that are received by the Defense Finance and Accounting Service by means of the mechanization of contract administration services system, the number of such vouchers that remain unpaid for more than 30 days as of the last day of each month may not exceed 5 percent of the total number of the contract vouchers so received that remain unpaid on that day.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contract Voucher Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “contract voucher” means a voucher or invoice for the payment to a contractor for services or deliverable items provided by the contractor under a contract funded by the Department of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title X, § 1006(a)(1)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–247, § 2226; amended <ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 5(b)(7)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3842</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 836(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1869</ref>; renumbered § 4602, <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1861(b)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4277</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4603.</num>
<heading> Advance notification of contract performance outside the United States</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notification</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A firm that is performing a Department of Defense contract for an amount exceeding $10,000,000, or is submitting a bid or proposal for such a contract, shall notify the Department of Defense in advance of any intention of the firm or any first-tier subcontractor of the firm to perform outside the United States and Canada any part of the contract that exceeds $500,000 in value and could be performed inside the United States or Canada.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If a firm submitting a bid or proposal for a Department of Defense contract is required to submit a notification under this subsection, and the firm is aware, at the time it submits its bid or proposal, that the firm intends to perform outside the United States and Canada any part of the contract that exceeds $500,000 in value and could be performed inside the United States or Canada, the firm shall include the notification in its bid or proposal.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The notification by a firm under paragraph (1) with respect to a first-tier subcontractor shall be made, to the maximum extent practicable, at least 30 days before award of the subcontract.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Recipient of Notification</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The firm shall transmit the notification—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in the case of a contract of a military department, to such officer or employee of that military department as the Secretary of the military department may direct; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in the case of any other Department of Defense contract, to such officer or employee of the Department of Defense as the Secretary of Defense may direct.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Availability of Notifications</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that the notifications (or copies) are maintained in compiled form for a period of 5 years after the date of submission and are available for use in the preparation of the national defense technology and industrial base assessment carried out under <ref>section 4816 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inapplicability to Certain Contracts</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>This section shall not apply to contracts for any of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Commercial products or commercial services (as defined in sections 103 and 103a, respectively, of title 41).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Military construction.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Ores.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Natural gas.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Utilities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Petroleum products and crudes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Timber.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Subsistence.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title VIII, § 840(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2466</ref>, § 2410g; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. D, title XLIII, § 4321(b)(16)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 673</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 5(b)(30)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3845</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 836(e)(7)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1870</ref>; renumbered § 4603 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII</ref>, §§ 1861(b), 1883(b)(2), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4277</ref>, 4294.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>