<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 160—</num>
<heading>ENVIRONMENTAL RESTORATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2700.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “CERCLA” means the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 9601</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The terms “environment”, “facility”, “hazardous substance”, “person”, “pollutant or contaminant”, “release”, “removal”, “response”, “disposal”, and “hazardous waste” have the meanings given those terms in section 101 of CERCLA (<ref>42 U.S.C. 9601</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “Administrator” means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> The term “National Guard facility” includes land used for training the National Guard pursuant to chapter 5 of title 32 with funds provided by the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of a military department, without regard to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the owner or operator of the facility; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> whether the facility is under the jurisdiction of the Department of Defense or a military department.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–499, title II, § 211(a)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-17">Oct. 17, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1725</ref>, § 2707; renumbered § 2700 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title III, § 313(a)(1)</ref>, (c)(1), <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2507</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title X, § 1075(b)(46)(A)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4371</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title III, § 316(b)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1304</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title III, § 314(b)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3514</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title III, § 313(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2502</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title III, § 312(a)</ref>, title XVIII, § 1801(a)(22), <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 215</ref>, 684.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2701.</num>
<heading> Environmental restoration program</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Environmental Restoration Program.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall carry out a program of environmental restoration at facilities under the jurisdiction of the Secretary and at National Guard facilities. The program shall be known as the “Defense Environmental Restoration Program”.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Application of section 120 of cercla</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Activities of the program described in subsection (b)(1) shall be carried out subject to, and in a manner consistent with, section 120 (relating to Federal facilities) of CERCLA (<ref>42 U.S.C. 9620</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consultation with epa</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The program shall be carried out in consultation with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Administrative office within osd</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall identify an office within the Office of the Secretary which shall have responsibility for carrying out the program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Program Goals</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Goals of the program shall include the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The identification, investigation, research and development, and cleanup of contamination from a hazardous substance or pollutant or contaminant.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Correction of other environmental damage (such as detection and disposal of unexploded ordnance) which creates an imminent and substantial endangerment to the public health or welfare or to the environment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Demolition and removal of unsafe buildings and structures, including buildings and structures of the Department of Defense at sites formerly used by or under the jurisdiction of the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Responsibility for Response Actions.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Basic responsibility</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall carry out (in accordance with the provisions of this chapter and CERCLA) all response actions with respect to releases of hazardous substances or pollutants or contaminants from each of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Each facility or site owned by, leased to, or otherwise possessed by the United States and under the jurisdiction of the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Each facility or site which was under the jurisdiction of the Secretary and owned by, leased to, or otherwise possessed by the United States at the time of actions leading to contamination by hazardous substances or pollutants or contaminants.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Each vessel owned or operated by the Department of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Each National Guard facility being used for training the National Guard pursuant to chapter 5 of title 32 with funds provided by the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of a military department at the time of actions leading to contamination by hazardous substances or pollutants or contaminants.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Other responsible parties</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Paragraph (1) shall not apply to a removal or remedial action if the Administrator has provided for response action by a potentially responsible person in accordance with section 122 (relating to settlements) of CERCLA (<ref>42 U.S.C. 9622</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">State fees and charges</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall pay fees and charges imposed by State authorities for permit services for the disposal of hazardous substances or pollutants or contaminants on lands which are under the jurisdiction of the Secretary to the same extent that nongovernmental entities are required to pay fees and charges imposed by State authorities for permit services. The preceding sentence shall not apply with respect to a payment that is the responsibility of a lessee, contractor, or other private person.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Services of Other Entities.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to paragraph (3), the Secretary may enter into agreements on a reimbursable or other basis with any other Federal agency, any State or local government agency, any Indian tribe, any owner of covenant property, or any nonprofit conservation organization to obtain the services of the agency, Indian tribe, owner, or organization to assist the Secretary in carrying out any of the Secretary’s responsibilities under this section. Services which may be obtained under this subsection include the identification, investigation, and cleanup of any off-site contamination resulting from the release of a hazardous substance or waste at a facility under the Secretary’s jurisdiction or at a National Guard facility.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Cross-fiscal year agreements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An agreement with an agency under paragraph (1) may be for a period that begins in one fiscal year and ends in another fiscal year so long as the period of the agreement does not exceed two years. This two-year limitation does not apply to an agreement funded using amounts in the Department of Defense Base Closure Account established by section 2906 of the Defense Base Closure and Realignment Act of 1990 (part A of title XXIX of <ref>Public Law 101–510</ref>; <ref>10 U.S.C. 2687</ref> note).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on reimbursable agreements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An agreement with an agency under paragraph (1) may not provide for reimbursement of the agency for regulatory enforcement activities. An agreement under such paragraph with respect to a site also may not change the cleanup standards selected for the site pursuant to law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this subsection:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The term “Indian tribe” has the meaning given such term in section 101(36) of CERCLA (<ref>42 U.S.C. 9601(36)</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The term “nonprofit conservation organization” means any non-governmental nonprofit organization whose primary purpose is conservation of open space or natural resources.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The term “owner of covenant property” means an owner of property subject to a covenant provided by the United States in accordance with the requirements of paragraphs (3) and (4) of section 120(h) of CERCLA (<ref>42 U.S.C. 9620(h)</ref>), so long as the covenant property is the site at which the services procured under paragraph (1) are to be performed.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Savings clause</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this subsection affects the applicability of section 120 of CERCLA (<ref>42 U.S.C. 9620</ref>) to the Department of Defense or the obligations and responsibilities of the Department of Defense under subsection (h) of such section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Response Action Contractors</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The provisions of section 119 of CERCLA (<ref>42 U.S.C. 9619</ref>) apply to response action contractors (as defined in that section) who carry out response actions under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of Appropriated Funds at Former DOD Sites</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Appropriations available to the Department of Defense may be used at sites formerly used by the Department of Defense for removal of unsafe buildings or debris of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Removal of Unsafe Buildings and Debris Before Release From Federal Control</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In the case of property formerly used by the Department of Defense which is to be released from Federal Government control and at which there are unsafe buildings or debris of the Department of Defense, all actions necessary to comply with regulations of the General Services Administration on the transfer of property in a safe condition shall be completed before the property is released from Federal Government control, except in the case of property to be conveyed to an entity of State or local government or to a native corporation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Surety-Contractor Relationship</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any surety which provides a bid, performance, or payment bond in connection with any direct Federal procurement for a response action contract under the Defense Environmental Restoration Program and begins activities to meet its obligations under such bond, shall, in connection with such activities or obligations, be entitled to any indemnification and the same standard of liability to which its principal was entitled under the contract or under any applicable law or regulation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Surety Bonds.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Applicability of sections 3131 and 3133 of title 40</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If under sections 3131 and 3133 of title 40 surety bonds are required for any direct Federal procurement of any response action contract under the Defense Environmental Restoration Program and are not waived pursuant to <ref>section 3134 of title 40</ref>, the surety bonds shall be issued in accordance with sections 3131 and 3133.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation of accrual of rights of action under bonds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If, under applicable Federal law, surety bonds are required for any direct Federal procurement of any response action contract under the Defense Environmental Restoration Program, no right of action shall accrue on the performance bond issued on such contract to or for the use of any person other than an obligee named in the bond.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Liability of sureties under bonds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If, under applicable Federal law, surety bonds are required for any direct Federal procurement of any response action contract under the Defense Environmental Restoration Program, unless otherwise provided for by the Secretary in the bond, in the event of a default, the surety’s liability on a performance bond shall be only for the cost of completion of the contract work in accordance with the plans and specifications of the contract less the balance of funds remaining to be paid under the contract, up to the penal sum of the bond. The surety shall in no event be liable on bonds to indemnify or compensate the obligee for loss or liability arising from personal injury or property damage whether or not caused by a breach of the bonded contract.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Nonpreemption</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section shall be construed as preempting, limiting, superseding, affecting, applying to, or modifying any State laws, regulations, requirements, rules, practices, or procedures. Nothing in this section shall be construed as affecting, applying to, modifying, limiting, superseding, or preempting any rights, authorities, liabilities, demands, actions, causes of action, losses, judgment, claims, statutes of limitation, or obligations under Federal or State law, which do not arise on or under the bond.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Applicability</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Subsections (h) and (i) shall not apply to bonds executed before <date date="1991-12-05">December 5, 1991</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Subsections (h) and (i) shall not apply to bonds to which section 119(g) of CERCLA (<ref>42 U.S.C. 9619(g)</ref>) applies.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(k)</num>
<heading> UXO <inline class="small-caps">Program Manager</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall designate a program manager who shall serve as the single point of contact in the Department of Defense for policy and budgeting issues involving the characterization, research, remediation, and management of explosive and related risks with respect to unexploded ordnance, discarded military munitions, and munitions constituents at defense sites (as such terms are defined in section 2710 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002095">1</ref> of this title) that pose a threat to human health or safety.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The position of program manager shall be filled by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an employee in a position that is equivalent to pay grade O–6 or above; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a member of the armed forces who is serving in the grade of colonel or, in the case of the Navy, captain, or in a higher grade.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The program manager shall report to the Assistant Secretary of Defense for Energy, Installations, and Environment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The program manager may establish an independent advisory and review panel that may include representatives of the National Academy of Sciences, nongovernmental organizations with expertise regarding unexploded ordnance, discarded military munitions, or munitions constituents, the Environmental Protection Agency, States (as defined in section 2710 <sup>1</sup> of this title), and tribal governments. If established, the panel shall report annually to Congress on progress made by the Department of Defense to address unexploded ordnance, discarded military munitions, or munitions constituents at defense sites and make such recommendations as the panel considers appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–499, title II, § 211(a)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-17">Oct. 17, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1719</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XIV, § 1481(i)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1708</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title III, § 336(a)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1342</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title III, § 331(b)</ref>, title X, § 1052(35), <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2373</ref>, 2501; <ref>Pub. L. 103–35, title II, § 201(d)(6)</ref>, <date date="1993-05-31">May 31, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 99</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title III</ref>, §§ 322, 323, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2711</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title III, § 321(a)(1)</ref>, title XV, § 1504(a)(1), div. D, title XLIII, § 4321(b)(22), <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 251</ref>, 513, 673; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title III, § 329</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2483</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title III, § 314</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1053</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–217, § 3(b)(17)</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1296</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title III</ref>, §§ 311, 312, 313(c)(2), div. B, title XXVIII, § 2812(c), <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2506</ref>, 2508, 2709; <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title X, § 1084(d)(24)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2062</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title III, § 312(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3190</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–284, § 2</ref>, <date date="2006-09-27">Sept. 27, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1211</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title III</ref>, §§ 311, 312, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2137</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title X, § 1073(a)(28)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2474</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title X, § 1075(b)(46)(B)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4371</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. B, title XXVII, § 2711(c)(4)(A)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 2144</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title IX, § 901(n)(2)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3469</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title III, § 316(c)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1304</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title III, § 313(b)</ref>, (c), <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2503</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title III, § 312(b)</ref>–(d), <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 215</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2702.</num>
<heading> Research, development, and demonstration program</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Program</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>As part of the Defense Environmental Restoration Program, the Secretary of Defense shall carry out a program of research, development, and demonstration with respect to hazardous wastes. The program shall be carried out in consultation and cooperation with the Administrator and the advisory council established under section 311(a)(5) of CERCLA (<ref>42 U.S.C. 9660(a)(5)</ref>). The program shall include research, development, and demonstration with respect to each of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Means of reducing the quantities of hazardous waste generated by activities and facilities under the jurisdiction of the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Methods of treatment, disposal, and management (including recycling and detoxifying) of hazardous waste of the types and quantities generated by current and former activities of the Secretary and facilities currently and formerly under the jurisdiction of the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Identifying more cost-effective technologies for cleanup of hazardous substances.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Toxicological data collection and methodology on risk of exposure to hazardous waste generated by the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The testing, evaluation, and field demonstration of any innovative technology, processes, equipment, or related training devices which may contribute to establishment of new methods to control, contain, and treat hazardous substances, to be carried out in consultation and cooperation with, and to the extent possible in the same manner and standards as, testing, evaluation, and field demonstration carried out by the Administrator, acting through the office of technology demonstration of the Environmental Protection Agency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Special Permit</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator may use the authorities of section 3005(g) of the Solid Waste Disposal Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 6925(g)</ref>) to issue a permit for testing and evaluation which receives support under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contracts and Grants</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may enter into contracts and cooperative agreements with, and make grants to, universities, public and private profit and nonprofit entities, and other persons to carry out the research, development, and demonstration authorized under this section. Such contracts may be entered into only to the extent that appropriated funds are available for that purpose.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Information Collection and Dissemination.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall develop, collect, evaluate, and disseminate information related to the use (or potential use) of the treatment, disposal, and management technologies that are researched, developed, and demonstrated under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Role of epa</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The functions of the Secretary under paragraph (1) shall be carried out in cooperation and consultation with the Administrator. To the extent appropriate and agreed upon by the Administrator and the Secretary, the Administrator shall evaluate and disseminate such information through the office of technology demonstration of the Environmental Protection Agency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–499, title II, § 211(a)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-17">Oct. 17, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1721</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title X, § 1084(d)(25)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2063</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2703.</num>
<heading> Environmental restoration accounts</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment of Accounts</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>There are hereby established in the Department of Defense the following accounts:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> An account to be known as the “Environmental Restoration Account, Defense”.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> An account to be known as the “Environmental Restoration Account, Army”.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> An account to be known as the “Environmental Restoration Account, Navy”.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> An account to be known as the “Environmental Restoration Account, Air Force”.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> An account to be known as the “Environmental Restoration Account, Formerly Used Defense Sites”.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Program Elements for Ordnance Remediation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall establish a program element for remediation of unexploded ordnance, discarded military munitions, and munitions constituents within each environmental restoration account established under subsection (a). In this subsection, the terms “discarded military munitions” and “munitions constituents” have the meanings given such terms in <ref>section 2710 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Obligation of Authorized Amounts</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Funds authorized for deposit in an account under subsection (a) may be obligated or expended from the account only to carry out the environmental restoration functions of the Secretary of Defense and the Secretaries of the military departments under this chapter and under any other provision of law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Funds authorized for deposit in an account under subsection (a) shall remain available until expended.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Budget Reports</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In proposing the budget for any fiscal year pursuant to <ref>section 1105 of title 31</ref>, the President shall set forth separately the amounts requested for environmental restoration programs of the Department of Defense and of each of the military departments under this chapter and under any other Act.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Credit of Amounts Recovered</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The following amounts shall be credited to the appropriate environmental restoration account:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Amounts recovered under CERCLA for response actions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any other amounts recovered from a contractor, insurer, surety, or other person to reimburse the Department of Defense or a military department for any expenditure for environmental response activities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Payments of Fines and Penalties</inline>.—</heading>
<content>None of the funds appropriated to the Environmental Restoration Account, Defense, or to any environmental restoration account of a military department, may be used for the payment of a fine or penalty (including any supplemental environmental project carried out as part of such penalty) imposed against the Department of Defense or a military department unless the act or omission for which the fine or penalty is imposed arises out of an activity funded by the environmental restoration account concerned and the payment of the fine or penalty has been specifically authorized by law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Sole Source of Funds for Operation and Monitoring of Environmental Remedies</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in subsection (h), the sole source of funds for all phases of an environmental remedy at a site under the jurisdiction of the Department of Defense, a National Guard facility, or a formerly used defense site shall be the applicable environmental restoration account established under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In this subsection, the term “environmental remedy” has the meaning given the term “remedy” in section 101 of CERCLA (<ref>42 U.S.C. 9601</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Sole Source of Funds for Environmental Remediation at Certain Base Realignment and Closure Sites</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In the case of property disposed of pursuant to a base closure law and subject to a covenant that was required to be provided by paragraphs (3) and (4) of section 120(h) of CERCLA (<ref>42 U.S.C. 9620(h)</ref>), the sole source of funds for services procured under <ref>section 2701(d)(1) of this title</ref> shall be the Department of Defense Base Closure Account established under section 2906 of the Defense Base Closure and Realignment Act of 1990 (part A of title XXIX of <ref>Public Law 101–510</ref>; <ref>10 U.S.C. 2687</ref> note). The limitation in this subsection shall expire upon the closure of such base closure account.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–499, title II, § 211(a)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-17">Oct. 17, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1722</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title III, § 321</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2710</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title III, § 322</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 252</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title III, § 322(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2477</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title III, § 321</ref>, title X, § 1066(a)(27), <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 560</ref>, 772; <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title III, §§ 311, 312], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–53, 1654A–54; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title III, § 312</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1051</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title III, § 313(a)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1430</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title X, § 1084(d)(26)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2063</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title III, § 312(b)</ref>, title X, § 1056(c)(7), <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3191</ref>, 3439; <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title X, § 1071(a)(23)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2399</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. B, title XXVII, § 2711(c)(4)(B)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 2144</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title III, § 311</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3336</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title III, § 312(e)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 215</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2704.</num>
<heading> Commonly found unregulated hazardous substances</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Notice to HHS.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall notify the Secretary of Health and Human Services of the hazardous substances which the Secretary of Defense determines to be the most commonly found unregulated hazardous substances at facilities under the Secretary’s jurisdiction. The notification shall be of not less than the 25 most widely used such substances.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this subsection, the term “unregulated hazardous substance” means a hazardous substance—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> for which no standard, requirement, criteria, or limitation is in effect under the Toxic Substances Control Act, the Safe Drinking Water Act, the Clean Air Act, or the Clean Water Act; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for which no water quality criteria are in effect under any provision of the Clean Water Act.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Toxicological Profiles</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall take such steps as necessary to ensure the timely preparation of toxicological profiles of each of the substances of which the Secretary is notified under subsection (a). The profiles of such substances shall include each of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The examination, summary, and interpretation of available toxicological information and epidemiologic evaluations on a hazardous substance in order to ascertain the levels of significant human exposure for the substance and the associated acute, subacute, and chronic health effects.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A determination of whether adequate information on the health effects of each substance is available or in the process of development to determine levels of exposure which present a significant risk to human health of acute, subacute, and chronic health effects.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Where appropriate, toxicological testing directed toward determining the maximum exposure level of a hazardous substance that is safe for humans.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">DOD Support</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall transfer to the Secretary of Health and Human Services such toxicological data, such sums from amounts appropriated to the Department of Defense, and such personnel of the Department of Defense as may be necessary (1) for the preparation of toxicological profiles under subsection (b) or (2) for other health related activities under section 104(i) of CERCLA (<ref>42 U.S.C. 9604(i)</ref>). The Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall enter into a memorandum of understanding regarding the manner in which this section shall be carried out, including the manner for transferring funds and personnel and for coordination of activities under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">EPA Health Advisories.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Preparation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>At the request of the Secretary of Defense, the Administrator shall, in a timely manner, prepare health advisories on hazardous substances. Such an advisory shall be prepared on each hazardous substance—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> for which no advisory exists;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> which is found to threaten drinking water; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> which is emanating from a facility under the jurisdiction of the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Content of health advisories</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Such health advisories shall provide specific advice on the levels of contaminants in drinking water at which adverse health effects would not be anticipated and which include a margin of safety so as to protect the most sensitive members of the population at risk. The advisories shall provide data on one-day, 10-day, and longer-term exposure periods where available toxicological data exist.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">DOD support for health advisories</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall transfer to the Administrator such toxicological data, such sums from amounts appropriated to the Department of Defense, and such personnel of the Department of Defense as may be necessary for the preparation of such health advisories. The Secretary and the Administrator shall enter into a memorandum of understanding regarding the manner in which this subsection shall be carried out, including the manner for transferring funds and personnel and for coordination of activities under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Cross Reference</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Section 104(i) of CERCLA (<ref>42 U.S.C. 9604(i)</ref>) applies to facilities under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of Defense in the manner prescribed in that section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Functions of HHS To Be Carried Out Through ATSDR</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The functions of the Secretary of Health and Human Services under this section shall be carried out through the Administrator of the Agency for Toxic Substances and Disease Registry of the Department of Health and Human Services established under section 104(i) of CERCLA (<ref>42 U.S.C. 9604(i)</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–499, title II, § 211(a)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-17">Oct. 17, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1722</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–25, title VII, § 701(j)(10)</ref>, <date date="1991-04-06">Apr. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 116</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title X, § 1084(d)(27)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2063</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2705.</num>
<heading> Notice of environmental restoration activities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Expedited Notice</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense shall take such actions as necessary to ensure that the regional offices of the Environmental Protection Agency and appropriate State and local authorities for the State in which a facility under the Secretary’s jurisdiction is located receive prompt notice of each of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The discovery of releases or threatened releases of hazardous substances at the facility.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The extent of the threat to public health and the environment which may be associated with any such release or threatened release.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Proposals made by the Secretary to carry out response actions with respect to any such release or threatened release.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The initiation of any response action with respect to such release or threatened release and the commencement of each distinct phase of such activities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Comment by EPA and State and Local Authorities.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Release notices</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall ensure that the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency and appropriate State and local officials have an adequate opportunity to comment on notices under paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Proposals for response actions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall require that an adequate opportunity for timely review and comment be afforded to the Administrator and to appropriate State and local officials after making a proposal referred to in subsection (a)(3) and before undertaking an activity or action referred to in subsection (a)(4). The preceding sentence does not apply if the action is an emergency removal taken because of imminent and substantial endangerment to human health or the environment and consultation would be impractical.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Technical Review Committee</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Whenever possible and practical, the Secretary shall establish a technical review committee to review and comment on Department of Defense actions and proposed actions with respect to releases or threatened releases of hazardous substances at installations. Members of any such committee shall include at least one representative of the Secretary, the Administrator, and appropriate State and local authorities and shall include a public representative of the community involved.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Restoration Advisory Board</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In lieu of establishing a technical review committee under subsection (c), the Secretary may permit the establishment of a restoration advisory board in connection with any installation (or group of nearby installations) where the Secretary is planning or implementing environmental restoration activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall prescribe regulations regarding the establishment, characteristics, composition, and funding of restoration advisory boards pursuant to this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The issuance of regulations under subparagraph (A) shall not be a precondition to the establishment of restoration advisory boards under this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Chapter 10 of title 5 shall not apply to a restoration advisory board established under this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary may authorize the commander of an installation (or, if there is no such commander, an appropriate official of the Department of Defense designated by the Secretary) to pay routine administrative expenses of a restoration advisory board established for that installation. Such payments shall be made from funds available under subsection (g).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Technical Assistance</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary may, upon the request of the technical review committee for an installation, restoration advisory board for an installation, community concerned with respect to an installation, or individual member of such community, authorize the commander of the installation (or, if there is no such commander, an appropriate official of the Department of Defense designated by the Secretary) to obtain from covered sources technical assistance for the committee, advisory board, community, or individual (as the case may be) to interpret scientific and engineering issues with regard to the nature of environmental hazards at the installation and the restoration activities conducted, or proposed to be conducted, at the installation. The commander of an installation (or, if there is no such commander, an appropriate official of the Department of Defense designated by the Secretary) shall use funds made available under subsection (g) for obtaining assistance under this paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The commander of an installation (or, if there is no such commander, an appropriate official of the Department of Defense designated by the Secretary) may obtain technical assistance under paragraph (1) for a technical review committee, restoration advisory board, community, or individual only if the technical assistance—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is likely to contribute to the efficiency, effectiveness, or timeliness of environmental restoration activities at the installation; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is a service described in paragraph (3).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> A service described in this paragraph is a service to improve public participation in, or assist in the navigation of, environmental restoration activities at an installation by the community concerned or an individual member of such community, including with respect to the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The interpretation of site-related documents, including documents concerning the nature of a release or threatened release at the installation, monitoring, testing plans, and reports associated with site assessment and characterization at the installation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The interpretation of health-related information.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> The interpretation of documents, plans, proposed actions, and final decisions relating to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an interim remedial action;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a remedial investigation or feasibility study;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a record of decision;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> a remedial design;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> the selection and construction of remedial action;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> operation and maintenance;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> a five-year review at the installation; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> a removal action at the installation.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Assistance with the preparation of public comments.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The development of outreach materials to improve public participation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> The provision of advice and guidance regarding additional technical assistance for which the community or individual, as the case may be, may be eligible.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> In this subsection, the term “covered source” means a private sector source, a Federal department or agency other than the Department of Defense (pursuant to a Federal interagency agreement), or a nonprofit entity (pursuant to a cooperative agreement entered into with such entity).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Involvement in Defense Environmental Restoration Program</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>If a technical review committee or restoration advisory board is established with respect to an installation (or group of installations), the Secretary shall consult with and seek the advice of the committee or board on the following issues:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Identifying environmental restoration activities and projects at the installation or installations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Monitoring progress on these activities and projects.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Collecting information regarding restoration priorities for the installation or installations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Addressing land use, level of restoration, acceptable risk, and waste management and technology development issues related to environmental restoration at the installation or installations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Developing environmental restoration strategies for the installation or installations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Funding</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall, to the extent provided in appropriations Acts, make funds available for administrative expenses and technical assistance under this section using funds in the following accounts:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In the case of a military installation not approved for closure pursuant to a base closure law, the environmental restoration account concerned under <ref>section 2703(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In the case of an installation approved for closure pursuant to such a law, the Department of Defense Base Closure Account established under section 2906(a) of the Defense Base Closure and Realignment Act of 1990 (part A of title XXIX of <ref>Public Law 101–510</ref>; <ref>10 U.S.C. 2687</ref> note).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–499, title II, § 211(a)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-17">Oct. 17, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1724</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title III, § 326(a)</ref>–(c), <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2712</ref>, 2713; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title III, § 324(a)</ref>–(d)(1), (e), <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 252–254</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title III, § 322(c)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2479</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title III, § 317(b)</ref>, title X, § 1043(c)(5), <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1432</ref>, 1612; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. B, title XXVII, § 2711(c)(4)(C)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 2144</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(a)(53)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4311</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title III, § 313</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 215</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2706.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title X, § 1061(22)(A)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1584</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2707.</num>
<heading> Environmental restoration projects for environmental responses</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Environmental Restoration Projects Authorized</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of a military department may carry out an environmental restoration project if that Secretary determines that the project is necessary to carry out a response under this chapter or CERCLA.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Treatment of Project</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any construction, development, conversion, or extension of a structure, and any installation of equipment, that is included in an environmental restoration project under this section may not be considered military construction (as that term is defined in <ref>section 2801(a) of this title</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Source of Funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Funds authorized for deposit in an account established by <ref>section 2703(a) of this title</ref> shall be the only source of funds to conduct an environmental restoration project under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Environmental Restoration Project Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “environmental restoration project” includes any construction, development, conversion, or extension of a structure, or installation of equipment, in direct support of a response.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title III, § 313(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2507</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title III, § 316(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1304</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title III, § 314(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3514</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title III, § 312(f)(1)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 215</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2708.</num>
<heading> Contracts for handling hazardous waste from defense facilities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reimbursement Requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Each contract or subcontract to which this section applies shall provide that, upon receipt of hazardous wastes properly characterized pursuant to applicable laws and regulations, the contractor or subcontractor will reimburse the Federal Government for all liabilities incurred by, penalties assessed against, costs incurred by, and damages suffered by, the Government that are caused by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the contractor’s or subcontractor’s breach of any term or provision of the contract or subcontract; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any negligent or willful act or omission of the contractor or subcontractor, or the employees of the contractor or subcontractor, in the performance of the contract or subcontract.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Not later than 30 days after such a contract or subcontract is awarded, the contractor or subcontractor shall demonstrate that the contractor or subcontractor will reimburse the Federal Government as provided in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Applicability</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraph (2), this section applies to each contract entered into by the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of a military department, and any subcontract under any such contract, with an owner or operator of a hazardous waste treatment or disposal facility during fiscal years 1992 through 1996 for the offsite treatment or disposal of hazardous wastes from a facility under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> This section does not apply to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any contract or subcontract to perform remedial action or corrective action under the Defense Environmental Restoration Program, other programs or activities of the Department of Defense, or authorized State hazardous waste programs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any contract or subcontract under which the generation of the hazardous waste to be disposed of is incidental to the performance of the contract; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any contract or subcontract to dispose of ammunition or solid rocket motors.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception to Reimbursement Requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Notwithstanding subsection (a), in the case of any contract to which this section applies, if the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of the military department concerned determines that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> there is only one responsible offeror or there is no responsible offeror willing to provide the reimbursement required by subsection (a) for such contract; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> failure to award the contract would place the facility concerned in violation of any requirement of the Solid Waste Disposal Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 6901</ref> et seq.),</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">then the contract may be awarded without including the reimbursement provision required by subsection (a).</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “hazardous waste” has the meaning given that term by section 1004(5) of the Solid Waste Disposal Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 6903(5)</ref>), except that such term also includes polychlorinated biphenyls.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “remedial action” has the meaning given that term by section 101(24) of the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 9601(24)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “corrective action” has the meaning given that term under section 3004(u) of the Solid Waste Disposal Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 6924(u)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “polychlorinated biphenyls” has the meaning given that term under section 6(e) of the Toxic Substances Control Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 2605(e)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Effect on Liability</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section shall affect the liability of the Federal Government under any Federal or State law or under common law.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title III, § 331(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1339</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title III, § 321</ref>, title X, § 1052(36), <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2365</ref>, 2501; <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title X, § 1004</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1748</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2709.</num>
<heading> Investment control process for environmental technologies</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Investment Control Process</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that the technology planning process developed to implement <ref>section 4811 of this title</ref> and section 270(b) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1997 (<ref>Public Law 104–201</ref>; <ref>110 Stat. 2469</ref>) provides for an investment control process for the selection, prioritization, management, and evaluation of environmental technologies by the Department of Defense, the military departments, and the Defense Agencies.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Planning and Evaluation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The environmental technology investment control process required by subsection (a) shall provide, at a minimum, for the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The active participation by end-users of environmental technology, including the officials responsible for the environmental security programs of the Department of Defense and the military departments, in the selection and prioritization of environmental technologies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The development of measurable performance goals and objectives for the management and development of environmental technologies and specific mechanisms for assuring the achievement of the goals and objectives.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Annual performance reviews to determine whether the goals and objectives have been achieved and to take appropriate action in the event that they are not achieved.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title III, § 323(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 562</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1867(e)(2)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4282</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2710.</num>
<heading> Inventory of unexploded ordnance, discarded military munitions, and munitions constituents at defense sites (other than operational ranges)</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inventory Required</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall develop and maintain an inventory of defense sites that are known or suspected to contain unexploded ordnance, discarded military munitions, or munitions constituents.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The information in the inventory for each defense site shall include, at a minimum, the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A unique identifier for the defense site.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> An appropriate record showing the location, boundaries, and extent of the defense site, including identification of the State and political subdivisions of the State, including the county, where applicable, in which the defense site is located and any Tribal lands encompassed by the defense site.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Known persons and entities, other than a military department, with any current ownership interest or control of lands encompassed by the defense site.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Any restrictions or other land use controls currently in place at the defense site that might affect the potential for public and environmental exposure to the unexploded ordnance, discarded military munitions, or munitions constituents.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Site Prioritization</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall develop, in consultation with representatives of the States and Indian Tribes, a proposed protocol for assigning to each defense site a relative priority for response activities related to unexploded ordnance, discarded military munitions, and munitions constituents based on the overall conditions at the defense site. After public notice and comment on the proposed protocol, the Secretary shall issue a final protocol and shall apply the protocol to defense sites listed on the inventory. The level of response priority assigned the site shall be included with the information required by subsection (a)(2).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> In assigning the response priority for a defense site on the inventory, the Secretary shall primarily consider factors relating to safety and environmental hazard potential, such as the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Whether there are known, versus suspected, unexploded ordnance, discarded military munitions, or munitions constituents on all or any portion of the defense site and the types of unexploded ordnance, discarded military munitions, or munitions constituents present or suspected to be present.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Whether public access to the defense site is controlled, and the effectiveness of these controls.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The potential for direct human contact with unexploded ordnance, discarded military munitions, or munitions constituents at the defense site and evidence of people entering the site.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Whether a response action has been or is being undertaken at the defense site under the Formerly Used Defense Sites program or other program.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The planned or mandated dates for transfer of the defense site from military control.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> The extent of any documented incidents involving unexploded ordnance, discarded military munitions, or munitions constituents at or from the defense site, including incidents involving explosions, discoveries, injuries, reports, and investigations.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> The potential for drinking water contamination or the release of munitions constituents into the air.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> The potential for destruction of sensitive ecosystems and damage to natural resources.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The priority assigned to a defense site included on the inventory shall not impair, alter, or diminish any applicable Federal or State authority to establish requirements for the investigation of, and response to, environmental problems at the defense site.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Updates and Availability</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall annually update the inventory and site prioritization list to reflect new information that becomes available. The inventory shall be available in published and electronic form.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall work with communities adjacent to a defense site to provide information concerning conditions at the site and response activities. At a minimum, the Secretary shall provide the site inventory information and site prioritization list to appropriate Federal, State, tribal, and local officials, and, to the extent the Secretary considers appropriate, to civil defense or emergency management agencies and the public.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exceptions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>This section does not apply to the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Any locations outside the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The presence of military munitions resulting from combat operations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Operating storage and manufacturing facilities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Operational ranges.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “defense site” applies to locations that are or were owned by, leased to, or otherwise possessed or used by the Department of Defense. The term does not include any operational range, operating storage or manufacturing facility, or facility that is used for or was permitted for the treatment or disposal of military munitions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “discarded military munitions” means military munitions that have been abandoned without proper disposal or removed from storage in a military magazine or other storage area for the purpose of disposal. The term does not include unexploded ordnance, military munitions that are being held for future use or planned disposal, or military munitions that have been properly disposed of, consistent with applicable environmental laws and regulations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “munitions constituents” means any materials originating from unexploded ordnance, discarded military munitions, or other military munitions, including explosive and nonexplosive materials, and emission, degradation, or breakdown elements of such ordnance or munitions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “possessions” includes Johnston Atoll, Kingman Reef, Midway Island, Nassau Island, Palmyra Island, and Wake Island.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The term “State” means the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, and the territories and possessions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The term “United States”, in a geographic sense, means the States, territories, and possessions and associated navigable waters, contiguous zones, and ocean waters of which the natural resources are under the exclusive management authority of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title III, § 311(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1048</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title X, § 1042(b)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1610</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title III, § 318(a)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2250</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2711.</num>
<heading> Annual report on defense environmental programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report Required</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than March 31 of each year, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to Congress a report on progress made by environmental programs of the Department of Defense during the preceding fiscal year.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each report under subsection (a) shall include, for the year covered by the report, the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> With respect to environmental restoration activities of the Department of Defense, and for each of the military departments, information on the Defense Environmental Restoration Program under <ref>section 2701 of this title</ref>, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the total number of sites at which such program was carried out;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the progress of remediation for sites that have not yet completed cleanup;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the remaining cost to complete cleanup of known sites; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> an assessment by the Secretary of Defense of the overall progress of such program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> An assessment by the Secretary of achievements for environmental conservation and planning by the Department.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> An assessment by the Secretary of achievements for environmental compliance by the Department.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> An assessment by the Secretary of achievements for climate resiliency by the Department.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> An assessment by the Secretary of the progress made by the Department in achieving the objectives and goals of the Environmental Technology Program of the Department.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consolidation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may consolidate, attach with, or otherwise include in any report required under subsection (a) any annual report or other requirement that is aligned or associated with, or would be better understood if presented as part of a consolidated report addressing environmental restoration, compliance, and resilience.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title III, § 317(a)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1359</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title III, § 314(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2503</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2712.</num>
<heading> Reporting on usage and spills of aqueous film-forming foam</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not later than 48 hours after the Deputy Assistant Secretary of Defense for Environment receives notice of the usage or spill of aqueous film forming foam, either as concentrate or mixed foam, at any military installation, the Deputy Assistant Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives notice of a usage or spill of greater than 10 gallons of concentrate, or greater than 300 gallons of mixed foam. Each such notice shall include each of the following information:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The name of the installation where the usage or spill occurred.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The date on which the usage or spill occurred.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The amount, type, and specified concentration of aqueous film-forming foam that was used or spilled.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The cause of the usage or spill.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> A summary narrative of the usage or spill.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Action Plan</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not later than 60 days after submitting notice of a usage or spill under subsection (a), the Deputy Assistant Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives an action plan for addressing such usage or spill. The action plan shall include the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A description of what actions have been taken to arrest and clean up a spill.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A description of any coordination with relevant local and State environmental protection agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title III, § 318(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3519</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2713.</num>
<heading> Native American lands environmental mitigation program</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may establish and carry out a program to mitigate the environmental effects of actions by the Department of Defense on Indian lands and on other locations where the Department, an Indian tribe, and the current land owner agree that such mitigation is appropriate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Program Activities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The activities that may be carried out under the program established under subsection (a) are the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Identification, investigation, and documentation of suspected environmental effects attributable to past actions by the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Development of mitigation options for such environmental effects, including development of cost-to-complete estimates and a system for prioritizing mitigation actions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Direct mitigation actions that the Secretary determines are necessary and appropriate to mitigate the adverse environmental effects of past actions by the Department.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Demolition and removal of unsafe buildings and structures used by, under the jurisdiction of, or formerly used by or under the jurisdiction of the Department.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Training, technical assistance, and administrative support to facilitate the meaningful participation of Indian tribes in mitigation actions under the program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Development and execution of a policy governing consultation with Indian tribes that have been or may be affected by action by the Department, including training personnel of the Department to ensure compliance with the policy.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Cooperative Agreements</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In carrying out the program established under subsection (a), the Secretary of Defense may enter into a cooperative agreement with an Indian tribe or an instrumentality of tribal government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding chapter 63 of title 31, a cooperative agreement under this section may be used to acquire property or services for the direct benefit of the United States Government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A cooperative agreement under this section for the procurement of severable services may begin in one fiscal year and end in another fiscal year only if the total period of performance does not exceed five calendar years.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The term “Indian land” includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any land located within the boundaries and a part of an Indian reservation, pueblo, or rancheria;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any land that has been allotted to an individual Indian but has not been conveyed to such Indian with full power of alienation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Alaska Native village and regional corporation lands; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> lands and waters upon which any federally recognized Indian tribe has rights reserved by treaty, Act of Congress, or action by the President.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “Indian tribe” means any Indian tribe, band, nation, or other organized group or community, including any Alaska Native village or regional or village corporation as defined in or established pursuant to the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<ref>43 U.S.C. 1601</ref> et seq.), which is recognized as eligible for the special programs and services provided by the United States to Indians because of their status as Indians.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section shall be interpreted to require, compel, or otherwise authorize access to any lands without the landowner’s consent.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title III, § 319(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3520</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title III, § 312</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1851</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2714.</num>
<heading> Perfluoroalkyl Substances and Polyfluoroalkyl Substances Task Force</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall establish a task force to address the effects of the release of perfluoroalkyl substances and polyfluoroalkyl substances from activities of the Department of Defense (in this section referred to as the “PFAS Task Force”).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Membership</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The members of the PFAS Task Force are the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Assistant Secretary of Defense for Energy, Installations, and Environment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Assistant Secretary of the Army for Installations, Energy, and Environment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Assistant Secretary of the Navy for Energy, Installations, and Environment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Assistant Secretary of the Air Force for Installations, Environment, and Energy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The Assistant Secretary of Defense for Health Affairs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Chairman</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Assistant Secretary of Defense for Energy, Installations, and Environment shall be the chairman of the PFAS Task Force.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Support</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Under Secretary of Defense for Personnel and Readiness and such other individuals as the Secretary of Defense considers appropriate shall support the activities of the PFAS Task Force.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duties</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The duties of the PFAS Task Force are the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Monitoring the health aspects of exposure to perfluoroalkyl substances and polyfluoroalkyl substances, as found by the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Identifying, and funding the procurement of, an effective alternative to firefighting foam containing perfluoroalkyl substances or polyfluoroalkyl substances.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Coordinating within the Department of Defense with respect to mitigating the effects of the release of perfluoroalkyl substances and polyfluoroalkyl substances.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Assessing the perceptions of Congress and the public of the efforts of the Department of Defense with respect to mitigating the effects of the release of perfluoroalkyl substances and polyfluoroalkyl substances from activities of the Department.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Supporting research efforts relating to perfluoroalkyl substances or polyfluoroalkyl substances.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Establishing practices to ensure the timely and complete dissemination of research findings and related data relating to perfluoroalkyl substances or polyfluoroalkyl substances to the general public.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2022, and annually thereafter through 2029, the Chairman of the PFAS Task Force shall submit to Congress a report on the activities of the task force.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “perfluoroalkyl substance” means a man-made chemical of which all of the carbon atoms are fully fluorinated carbon atoms.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “polyfluoroalkyl substance” means a man-made chemical containing a mix of fully fluorinated carbon atoms, partially fluorinated carbon atoms, and nonfluorinated carbon atoms.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title III, § 341(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1641</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title III, § 341(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2529</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title III, § 331</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 221</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2715.</num>
<heading> Testing for perfluoroalkyl substances and polyfluoroalkyl substances at military installations and facilities of the National Guard</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2022, the Secretary of Defense shall complete preliminary assessment and site inspection testing for perfluoroalkyl substances and polyfluoroalkyl substances at all military installations and facilities of the National Guard located in the United States that are identified as of <date date="2021-03-31">March 31, 2021</date>, as having a release of perfluoroalkyl substances or polyfluoroalkyl substances.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Determination of Contamination</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Testing conducted under subsection (a) at a military installation or facility of the National Guard shall determine—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> whether the installation or facility has contamination from a perfluoroalkyl substance or polyfluoroalkyl substance; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> whether activities in connection with such installation or facility have caused contamination from a perfluoroalkyl substance or polyfluoroalkyl substance outside of such installation or facility.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Additional Response Actions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Testing conducted under subsection (a) shall provide at least a preliminary basis for determining whether additional environmental response actions are necessary to address contamination from a perfluoroalkyl substance or polyfluoroalkyl substance.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Type of Testing</inline>.—</heading>
<content>When testing for perfluoroalkyl substances or polyfluoroalkyl substances under subsection (a) or any other provision of law, the Secretary shall use a method to measure for all perfluoroalkyl substances or polyfluoroalkyl substances in drinking water that has been validated by the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “military installation” has the meaning given such term in <ref>section 2801(c)(4) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The terms “perfluoroalkyl substance” and “polyfluoroalkyl substance” have the meanings given such terms in <ref>section 2714 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title III, § 341(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1642</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2716.</num>
<heading> Budget justification document for funding relating to perfluoroalkyl substances and polyfluoroalkyl substances</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of Defense shall submit to Congress, concurrent with the submission to Congress of the budget of the President for each fiscal year pursuant to <ref>section 1105(a) of title 31</ref>, a separate budget justification document that consolidates all information pertaining to activities of the Department of Defense relating to perfluoroalkyl substances or polyfluoroalkyl substances, including funding for and descriptions of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> research and development efforts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> testing;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> remediation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> contaminant disposal; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> community outreach.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title III, § 332</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 222</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>