<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 769—</num>
<heading>SALE OF SERVICEABLE MATERIAL</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7621.</num>
<heading> Quartermaster supplies: members of armed forces; veterans; executive or military departments and employees; prices</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of the Army shall procure and sell, for cash or credit—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> articles specified by the Secretary of the Army or a person designated by him, to members of the Army; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> items of individual clothing and equipment, to officers of the Army, under such restrictions as the Secretary may proscribe.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">An account of sales on credit shall be kept and the amount due reported to any branch, office, or officer designated by the Secretary. Except for articles and items acquired through the use of working capital funds under <ref>section 2208 of this title</ref>, sales of articles shall be at cost, and sales of individual clothing and equipment shall be at average current prices, including overhead, as determined by the Secretary.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall sell subsistence supplies to members of other armed forces at the prices at which like property is sold to members of the Army.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Secretary may sell serviceable quartermaster property, other than subsistence supplies, to an officer of another armed force for his use in the service, in the same manner as these articles are sold to an officer of the Army.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> A person who has been discharged honorably or under honorable conditions from the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, or Space Force and who is receiving care and medical treatment from the Public Health Service or the Department of Veterans Affairs may buy subsistence supplies and other supplies, except articles of uniform, at the prices at which like property is sold to a member of the Army.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> Under such conditions as the Secretary may prescribe, exterior articles of uniform may be sold to a person who has been discharged from the Army honorably or under honorable conditions, at the prices at which like articles are sold to members of the Army. This subsec­tion does not modify section 772 or 773 of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> Whenever, under regulations to be prescribed by the Secretary, subsistence supplies are furnished to any branch of the Army or sold to employees of any executive department other than the Department of Defense, payment shall be made in cash or by commercial credit.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary may, by regulation, provide for the procurement and sale of stores designated by him to such civilian officers and employees of the United States, and such other persons, as he considers proper—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> at military installations outside the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> at military installations inside the United States where he determines that it is impracticable for those civilian officers, employees, and persons to obtain those stores from private agencies without impairing the efficient operation of military activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">However, sales to officers and employees inside the United States may be made only to those residing within military installations.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<content> Appropriations for subsistence of the Army may be applied to the purchase of subsistence supplies for sale to members of the Army on active duty for the use of themselves and their families.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 257</ref>, § 4621; <ref>Pub. L. 87–651, title I, § 118</ref>, <date date="1962-09-07">Sept. 7, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 513</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 512(17)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2930</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–180, div. A, title III, § 313(c)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1074</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title XVI, § 1621(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1602</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title III, § 375(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 283</ref>; renumbered § 7621, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 808(d)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1839</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 924(c)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3826</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7622.</num>
<heading> Rations: commissioned officers in field</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Commissioned officers of the Army serving in the field may buy rations for their own use, on credit, from any officer designated by the Secretary of the Army. Amounts due for these purchases shall be reported monthly to the officer of the Army designated by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 258</ref>, § 4622; renumbered § 7622, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 808(d)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1839</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7624.</num>
<heading> Medical supplies: civilian employees of the Army; American National Red Cross; Armed Forces Retirement Home</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Under regulations to be prescribed by the Secretary of the Army, a civilian employee of the Department of the Army who is stationed at an Army post may buy necessary medical supplies from the Army when they are prescribed by an officer of the Medical Corps on active duty.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> With the approval of the Secretary, the Army Medical Department may sell medical supplies to the American National Red Cross for cash.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Any branch, office, or officer designated by the Secretary may sell medical and hospital supplies to the Armed Forces Retirement Home.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 259</ref>, § 4624; <ref>Pub. L. 90–329</ref>, <date date="1968-06-04">June 4, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 170</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 512(18)(A)</ref>, (B), <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2930</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XV, § 1533(a)(5)(A)</ref>, (B), <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1734</ref>; renumbered § 7624, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 808(d)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1839</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7625.</num>
<heading> Ordnance property: officers of armed forces; civilian employees of Army; American National Red Cross; educational institutions; homes for veterans’ orphans</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Any branch, office, or officer designated by the Secretary of the Army may sell articles of ordnance property to officers of other armed forces for their use in the service, in the same manner as those articles are sold to officers of the Army.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Under such regulations as the Secretary may prescribe, ordnance stores may be sold to civilian employees of the Army and to the American National Red Cross.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Articles of ordnance property may be sold to educational institutions and to State soldiers’ and sailors’ orphans’ homes for maintaining the ordnance and ordnance stores issued to those institutions and homes.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 259</ref>, § 4625; renumbered § 7625, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 808(d)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1839</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7626.</num>
<heading> Aircraft supplies and services: foreign military or air attaché</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Under such conditions as he may prescribe, the Secretary of the Army may provide for the sale of fuel, oil, and other supplies for use in aircraft operated by a foreign military or air attaché accredited to the United States, and for the furnishing of mechanical service and other assistance to such aircraft. Shelter may be furnished to such aircraft, but only without charge.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 259</ref>, § 4626; renumbered § 7626, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 808(d)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1839</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7627.</num>
<heading> Supplies: educational institutions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Under such regulations as the Secretary of the Army may prescribe, supplies and military publications procured for the Army may be sold to any educational institution to which an officer of the Army is detailed as professor of military science and tactics, for the use of its military students. Sales under this section shall be for cash.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 259</ref>, § 4627; renumbered § 7627, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 808(d)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1839</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7628.</num>
<heading> Airplane parts and accessories: civilian flying schools</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Army may sell, to civilian flying schools at which personnel of the Department of the Army or the Department of the Air Force are receiving flight training under contracts requiring these schools to maintain and repair airplanes of the Army furnished to them for flight training, the spare parts and accessories needed for those repairs.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 259</ref>, § 4628; renumbered § 7628, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 808(d)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1839</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7629.</num>
<heading> Proceeds: disposition</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The proceeds of sales of the following shall be paid into the Treasury to the credit of the appropriation out of which they were purchased, and are available for the purposes of that appropriation:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Exterior articles of uniform sold under <ref>section 7621 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Supplies and military publications sold to educational institutions under <ref>section 7627 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Fuel, oil, other supplies, and services for aircraft of a foreign military or air attache sold under <ref>section 7626 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 260</ref>, § 4629; renumbered § 7629 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII</ref>, §§ 808(d), 809(a), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1839</ref>, 1840.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>