<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 58—</num>
<heading>BENEFITS AND SERVICES FOR MEMBERS BEING SEPARATED OR RECENTLY SEPARATED</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1141.</num>
<heading> Involuntary separation defined</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A member of the armed forces shall be considered to be involuntarily separated for purposes of this chapter if the member was on active duty or full-time National Guard duty on <date date="1990-09-30">September 30, 1990</date>, or after <date date="1993-11-29">November 29, 1993</date>, or, with respect to a member of the Coast Guard, if the member was on active duty in the Coast Guard after <date date="1994-09-30">September 30, 1994</date>, and—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in the case of a regular officer (other than a retired officer), the officer is involuntarily discharged under other than adverse conditions, as characterized by the Secretary concerned;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in the case of a reserve officer who is on the active-duty list or, if not on the active-duty list, is on full-time active duty (or in the case of a member of the National Guard, full-time National Guard duty) for the purpose of organizing, administering, recruiting, instructing, or training the reserve components, the officer is involuntarily discharged or released from active duty or full-time National Guard (other than a release from active duty or full-time National Guard duty incident to a transfer to retired status) under other than adverse conditions, as characterized by the Secretary concerned;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> in the case of a regular enlisted member serving on active duty, the member is (A) denied reenlistment, or (B) involuntarily discharged under other than adverse conditions, as characterized by the Secretary concerned;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> in the case of a reserve enlisted member who is on full-time active duty (or in the case of a member of the National Guard, full-time National Guard duty) for the purpose of organizing, administering, recruiting, instructing, or training the reserve components, the member (A) is denied reenlistment, or (B) is involuntarily discharged or released from active duty (or full-time National Guard) under other than adverse conditions, as characterized by the Secretary concerned;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> in the case of an officer of the Space Force (other than a retired officer), the officer is involuntarily discharged or released from active duty under other than adverse conditions, as characterized by the Secretary of the Air Force; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> in the case of an enlisted member of the Space Force, the member is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> denied reenlistment; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> involuntarily discharged or released from active duty under other than adverse conditions, as characterized by the Secretary of the Air Force.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title V, § 502(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1551</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title V, § 503</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1644</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title V, § 542(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2767</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XVII, § 1722(i)(1)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 672</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1142.</num>
<heading> Preseparation counseling; transmittal of certain records to Department of Veterans Affairs</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Within the time periods specified in paragraph (3), the Secretary concerned shall (except as provided in paragraph (4)) provide for individual preseparation counseling of each member of the armed forces whose discharge (regardless of character of discharge) or release from active duty is anticipated as of a specific date. A notation of the provision of such counseling with respect to each matter specified in subsection (b), signed by the member, shall be placed in the service record of each member receiving such counseling.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In carrying out this section, the Secretary concerned shall use the services available under <ref>section 1144 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> In the case of an anticipated retirement, preseparation counseling shall commence as soon as possible during the 24-month period preceding the anticipated retirement date. In the case of a separation other than a retirement, preseparation counseling shall commence not later than 365 days before the anticipated date. Except as provided in subparagraph (B), in no event shall preseparation counseling commence later than 365 days before the date of retirement or other separation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> In the event that a retirement or other separation is unanticipated until there are 365 or fewer days before the anticipated retirement or separation date, or in the event a member of a reserve component is being demobilized under circumstances in which (as determined by the Secretary concerned) operational requirements make the 365-day requirement under subparagraph (A) unfeasible, preseparation counseling shall begin as soon as possible within the remaining period of service.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Subject to subparagraph (B), the Secretary concerned shall not provide preseparation counseling to a member who is being discharged or released before the completion of the first 180 continuous days of active duty of the member.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Subparagraph (A) shall not apply in the case of a member who is being retired or separated for disability.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of calculating the days of active duty of a member under subparagraph (A), the Secretary concerned shall exclude any day on which—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the member performed full-time training duty or annual training duty; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the member attended, while in the active military service, a school designated as a service school by law or by the Secretary concerned.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Matters To Be Covered By Counseling</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Counseling under this section shall include the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A discussion of the educational assistance benefits to which the member is entitled under the Montgomery GI Bill and other educational assistance programs because of the member’s service in the armed forces.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A description (to be developed with the assistance of the Secretary of Veterans Affairs) of the compensation and vocational rehabilitation benefits to which the member may be entitled under laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, if the member is being medically separated or is being retired under chapter 61 of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> An explanation of the procedures for and advantages of affiliating with the Selected Reserve.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> Provision of information on civilian occupations and related assistance programs, including information concerning—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> certification and licensure requirements that are applicable to civilian occupations, including State-submitted and approved lists of military training and skills that satisfy occupational certifications and licenses;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> civilian occupations that correspond to military occupational specialties; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Government and private-sector programs for job search and job placement assistance, including information regarding the placement programs established under sections 1152 and 1153 of this title and the Troops-to-Teachers Program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> If the member has a spouse, inclusion of the spouse, at the discretion of the member and the spouse, when counseling regarding the matters covered by paragraphs (9), (10), and (16) is provided, job placement counseling for the spouse, and the provision of information on survivor benefits available under the laws administered by the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of Veterans Affairs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Information concerning the availability of relocation assistance services and other benefits and services available to persons leaving military service, as provided under <ref>section 1144 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Information concerning the availability of medical and dental coverage following separation from active duty, including the opportunity to elect into the conversion health policy provided under <ref>section 1145 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Counseling (for the member and dependents) on the effect of career change on individuals and their families and the availability to the member and dependents of suicide prevention resources following separation from the armed forces.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> Financial planning assistance, including information on budgeting, saving, credit, loans, and taxes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> The creation of a transition plan for the member to attempt to achieve the educational, training, employment, and financial objectives of the member and, if the member has a spouse, the spouse of the member.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> Information concerning the availability of mental health services and the treatment of post-traumatic stress disorder, anxiety disorders, depression, suicidal ideations, or other mental health conditions associated with service in the armed forces and information concerning the availability of treatment options and resources to address substance abuse, including alcohol, prescription drug, and opioid abuse.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> Information concerning the priority of service for veterans in the receipt of employment, training, and placement services provided under qualified job training programs of the Department of Labor.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> Information concerning veterans small business ownership and entrepreneurship programs of the Small Business Administration.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> Information concerning employment and reemployment rights and obligations under chapter 43 of title 38.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<content> Information concerning veterans preference in Federal employment and Federal procurement opportunities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(16)</num>
<content> Information on home loan services and housing assistance benefits available under the laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs and counseling on responsible borrowing practices.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(17)</num>
<content> A description, developed in consultation with the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, of health care and other benefits to which the member may be entitled under the laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, and information regarding the means by which the member can receive additional counseling regarding the member’s actual entitlement to such benefits and apply for such benefits.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(18)</num>
<content> A description, developed in consultation with the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, of the assistance and support services for family caregivers of eligible veterans under the program conducted by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs pursuant to <ref>section 1720G of title 38</ref>, including the veterans covered by the program, the caregivers eligible for assistance and support through the program, and the assistance and support available through the program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(19)</num>
<content> Information regarding how to file claims for benefits available to the member under laws administered by the Secretaries of Defense and Veterans Affairs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Counseling Pathways</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Each Secretary concerned, in consultation with the Secretaries of Labor and Veterans Affairs, shall establish at least three pathways for members of the military department concerned (including one pathway for members of the reserve components) receiving individualized counseling under this section. The Secretaries shall design the pathways to address the needs of members, based on the following factors:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Rank.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Term of service.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Gender.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Whether the member was a member of a regular or reserve component of an armed force.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Potential or confirmed disability.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Potential or confirmed character of discharge (including expedited discharge and discharge under conditions other than honorable).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> Health (including mental health).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> Military occupational specialty.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(I)</num>
<chapeau> Whether the member intends, after separation, retirement, or discharge, to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> seek employment;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> enroll in a program of higher education;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> enroll in a program of vocational training; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> become an entrepreneur.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> The educational history of the member.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> The employment history of the member.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(L)</num>
<chapeau> Whether the member has secured—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> employment;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> enrollment in a program of education; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> enrollment in a program of vocational training.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(M)</num>
<content> Other factors the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Homeland Security, in consultation with the Secretaries of Labor and Veterans Affairs, determine appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Each member described in subsection (a) shall meet in person or by video conference with a counselor before beginning counseling under this section to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> take a self-assessment designed by the Secretary concerned (in consultation with the Secretaries of Labor and Veterans Affairs) to ensure that the Secretary concerned places the member in the appropriate pathway under this subsection;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> receive information from the counselor regarding reenlistment in the armed forces; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> receive information from the counselor regarding resources (including resources regarding military sexual trauma)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> for members of the armed forces separated, retired, or discharged;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> located in the community in which the member will reside after separation, retirement, or discharge.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> At the meeting under paragraph (2), the member may elect to have the Secretary concerned (in consultation with the Secretaries of Labor and Veterans Affairs) provide the contact information of the member to the resources described in paragraph (2)(C).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transmittal of Medical Information to Department of Veterans Affairs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In the case of a member being medically separated or being retired under chapter 61 of this title, the Secretary concerned shall ensure (subject to the consent of the member) that a copy of the member’s service medical record (including any results of a Physical Evaluation Board) is transmitted to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs within 60 days of the separation or retirement.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Joint Service Transcript</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary concerned shall provide a copy of the joint service transcript of a member described in subsection (a) to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> that member—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> at the meeting with a counselor under subsection (c)(2); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> on the day the member separates, retires, or is discharged; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Veterans Affairs on the day the member separates, retires, or is discharged.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title V, § 502(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1552</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title X, § 1061(a)(5)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1472</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. D, title XLIV</ref>, §§ 4401, 4441(b), 4462(b), <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2701</ref>, 2730, 2740; <ref>Pub. L. 103–35, title II, § 201(i)(1)</ref>, <date date="1993-05-31">May 31, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 100</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title XIII, § 1332(c)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1797</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title X, § 1087(a)(9)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–290; <ref>Pub. L. 107–103, title III, § 302(a)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-27">Dec. 27, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 991</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title V, § 594</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3281</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title X, § 1073(a)(13)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2473</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–56, title II, § 221(b)</ref>, <date date="2011-11-21">Nov. 21, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 716</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title V</ref>, §§ 513, 529, 533(c), <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1393</ref>, 1402, 1404; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title V, § 541(c)</ref>, title X, § 1076(f)(12), title XVI, § 1699(c)(1), <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1735</ref>, 1952, 2092; <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title V, § 552</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 823</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title V, § 562</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2138</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title V</ref>, §§ 541(a), 542(d), <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1393</ref>, 1395; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title V</ref>, §§ 552(a)(1), 553(b)(2), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1769</ref>, 1772; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title V, § 561</ref>, title XVII, § 1731(a)(26), <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1394</ref>, 1813; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title V, § 571</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 275</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title V, § 571</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1909</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1143.</num>
<heading> Employment assistance</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Employment Skills Verification</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Homeland Security with respect to the Coast Guard when it is not operating as a service in the Navy shall provide to members of the armed forces who are discharged or released from active duty a certification or verification of any job skills and experience acquired while on active duty that may have application to employment in the civilian sector. The preceding sentence shall be carried out in conjunction with the Secretary of Labor.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> In order to improve the accuracy and completeness of a certification or verification of job skills and experience required by paragraph (1), the Secretary of Defense shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> establish a database to record all training performed by members of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, and Space Force that may have application to employment in the civilian sector; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> make unclassified information regarding such information available to States and other potential employers referred to in subsection (c) so that State and other entities may allow military training to satisfy licensing or certification requirements to engage in a civilian profession.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that a certification or verification of job skills and experience required by paragraph (1) is rendered in such a way that States and other potential employers can confirm the accuracy and authenticity of the certification or verification.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Employment Assistance Centers</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall establish permanent employment assistance centers at appropriate military installations. The Secretary of Homeland Security shall establish permanent employment assistance centers at appropriate Coast Guard installations.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Information to Civilian Entities</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> For the purpose of assisting members covered by subsection (a) and their spouses in locating civilian employment and training opportunities, the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Homeland Security shall establish and implement procedures to release to civilian employers, organizations, State employment agencies, and other appropriate entities the names (and other pertinent information) of such members and their spouses. Such names may be released for such purpose only with the consent of such members and spouses.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> A State may—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> use a certification or verification of job skills and experience provided to a member of the armed forces under subsection (a); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in the case of members of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, and Space Force, request the Department of Defense to confirm the accuracy and authenticity of the certification or verification.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A response confirming or denying the information shall be provided within five business days.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Employment Preference by Nonappropriated Fund Instrumentalities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall take such steps as necessary to provide that members of Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, or Space Force who are involuntarily separated, and the dependents of such members, shall be provided a preference in hiring by nonappropriated fund instrumentalities of the Department. Such preference shall be administered in the same manner as the preference for military spouses provided under <ref>section 1784(a)(2) of this title</ref>, except that a preference under that section shall have priority over a preference under this subsection. A person may receive a preference in hiring under this subsection only once. The Secretary of Homeland Security shall provide the same preference in hiring to involuntarily separated members of the Coast Guard, and the dependents of such members, in Coast Guard nonappropriated fund instrumentalities.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Employment Skills Training; Skillbridge</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002065">1</ref> The Secretary concerned may carry out one or more programs to provide eligible members of the armed forces under the jurisdiction of the Secretary with job training and employment skills training, including apprenticeship programs, to help prepare such members for employment in the civilian sector. Such a program shall be known as “Skillbridge”.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Secretary of a military department shall carry out one or more programs under this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> A member of the armed forces is an eligible member for purposes of a program under this subsection if the member—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> has completed at least 180 days on active duty in the armed forces; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is expected to be discharged or released from active duty in the armed forces within 180 days of the date of commencement of participation in such a program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> To carry out this subsection, the Secretary concerned shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> assign not fewer than two full-time equivalent positions; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> develop for each fiscal year a funding plan that includes funding lines across the future-years defense program under <ref>section 221 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> For any program under this subsection, the Secretary concerned shall, on an annual basis—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> circulate, to members serving on active duty under the jurisdiction of such Secretary concerned, information about the program (including eligibility requirements and the application process); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> conduct outreach to inform potential employers about Skillbridge, participating members, and how the program operates, and to increase the number of, and types of, employers that hire program participants.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Any program under this subsection may be carried out at, through, or in consultation with such other departments or agencies of the Federal Government as the Secretary concerned considers appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Any program under this subsection shall be carried out in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary concerned.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title V, § 502(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1553</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title V, § 542(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2767</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title X, § 1073(a)(21)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1901</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–296, title XVII, § 1704(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2314</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title V, § 551</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1412</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title X, § 1076(f)(13)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1952</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title V, § 542(a)</ref>–(c), <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1394</ref>, 1395; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title V, § 562</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1395</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title V, § 572</ref>, title IX, § 924(b)(1)(J), (3)(R), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3643</ref>, 3820, 3821; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title V, § 561(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2598</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title V, § 572(a)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 275</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 1143a.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title V, § 553(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1772</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1144.</num>
<heading> Employment assistance, job training assistance, and other transitional services: Department of Labor</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Labor, in conjunction with the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, shall establish and maintain a program to furnish counseling, assistance in identifying employment and training opportunities, help in obtaining such employment and training, and other related information and services to members of the armed forces under the jurisdiction of the Secretary concerned who are being separated from active duty and the spouses of such members. Subject to subsection (f)(2), such services shall be provided to a member within the time periods provided under paragraph (3) of <ref>section 1142(a) of this title</ref>, except that the Secretary concerned shall not provide preseparation counseling to a member described in paragraph (4)(A) of such section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall cooperate with the Secretary of Labor in establishing and maintaining the program under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretaries referred to in paragraph (1) shall enter into a detailed agreement to carry out this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Elements of Program</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In establishing and carrying out a program under this section, the Secretary of Labor shall do the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Provide information concerning employment and training assistance, including (A) labor market information, (B) civilian work place requirements and employment opportunities (including apprenticeship programs approved under chapters 30 through 36 of title 38), (C) instruction in resumé preparation, and (D) job analysis techniques, job search techniques, and job interview techniques.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In providing information under paragraph (1), use experience obtained from implementation of the pilot program established under <ref>section 408 of Public Law 101–237</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Provide information concerning Federal, State, and local programs, and programs of military and veterans’ service organizations, that may be of assistance to such members after separation from the armed forces, including, as appropriate, the information and services to be provided under <ref>section 1142 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Inform such members that the Department of Defense and the Department of Homeland Security are required under <ref>section 1143(a) of this title</ref> to provide proper certification or verification of job skills and experience acquired while on active duty that may have application to employment in the civilian sector for use in seeking civilian employment and in obtaining job search skills.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Provide information and other assistance to such members in their efforts to obtain loans and grants from the Small Business Administration and other Federal, State, and local agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Provide information about the geographic areas in which such members will relocate after separation from the armed forces, including, to the degree possible, information about employment opportunities, the labor market, and the cost of living in those areas (including, to the extent practicable, the cost and availability of housing, child care, education, and medical and dental care).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Work with military and veterans’ service organizations and other appropriate organizations in promoting and publicizing job fairs for such members.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Provide information about disability-related employment and education protections.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> Provide information regarding the required deduction, pursuant to subsection (h) of <ref>section 1175a of this title</ref>, from disability compensation paid by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs of amounts equal to any voluntary separation pay received by the member under such section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> Acting through the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating, provide information on career and employment opportunities available to members with transportation security cards issued under <ref>section 70105 of title 46</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Participation</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraph (2), the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Homeland Security shall require the participation in the program carried out under this section of the members eligible for assistance under the program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Homeland Security may, under regulations such Secretaries shall prescribe, waive the participation requirement of paragraph (1) with respect to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> such groups or classifications of members as the Secretaries determine, after consultation with the Secretary of Labor and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, for whom participation is not and would not be of assistance to such members based on the Secretaries’ articulable justification that there is extraordinarily high reason to believe the exempted members are unlikely to face major readjustment, health care, employment, or other challenges associated with transition to civilian life; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> individual members possessing specialized skills who, due to unavoidable circumstances, are needed to support a unit’s imminent deployment.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of Personnel and Organizations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In carrying out the program established under this section, the Secretaries may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provide, as the case may be, for the use of disabled veterans outreach program specialists, local veterans’ employment representatives, and other employment service personnel funded by the Department of Labor to the extent that the Secretary of Labor determines that such use will not significantly interfere with the provision of services or other benefits to eligible veterans and other eligible recipients of such services or benefits;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> use military and civilian personnel of the Department of Defense and the Department of Homeland Security;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> use personnel of the Veterans Benefits Administration of the Department of Veterans Affairs and other appropriate personnel of that Department;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> use representatives of military and veterans’ service organizations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> enter into contracts with public entities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> enter into contracts with private entities, particularly with qualified private entities that have experience with instructing members of the armed forces eligible for assistance under the program carried out under this section on—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> private sector culture, resume writing, career networking, and training on job search technologies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> academic readiness and educational opportunities; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> other relevant topics; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> take other necessary action to develop and furnish the information and services to be provided under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Participation in Apprenticeship Programs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>As part of the program carried out under this section, the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Homeland Security may permit a member of the armed forces eligible for assistance under the program to participate in an apprenticeship program registered under the Act of <date date="1937-08-16">August 16, 1937</date> (commonly known as the “National Apprenticeship Act”; <ref>50 Stat. 664</ref>, chapter 663; <ref>29 U.S.C. 50</ref> et seq.), or a pre-apprenticeship program that provides credit toward a program registered under such Act, that provides members of the armed forces with the education, training, and services necessary to transition to meaningful employment that leads to economic self-sufficiency.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Program Contents</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The program carried out under this section shall consist of instruction as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> One day of preseparation training specific to the armed force concerned, as determined by the Secretary concerned.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> One day of instruction regarding—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> benefits under laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> other subjects determined by the Secretary concerned.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> One day of instruction regarding preparation for employment.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> Two days of instruction regarding a topic selected by the member from the following subjects:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Preparation for employment.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Preparation for education.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Preparation for vocational training.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> Preparation for entrepreneurship.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> Other options determined by the Secretary concerned.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary concerned may permit a member to attend training and instruction under the program established under this section—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> before the time periods established under <ref>section 1142(a)(3) of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in addition to such training and instruction required during such time periods.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title V, § 502(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1553</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title X, § 1061(a)(6)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1472</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. D, title XLIV</ref>, §§ 4462(c), 4469, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2740</ref>, 2752; <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title V, § 543(b)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2769</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–103, title III, § 302(b)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-27">Dec. 27, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 992</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title X, § 1048(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1227</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–296, title XVII, § 1704(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2314</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–56, title II</ref>, §§ 221(a), 224, 225, <date date="2011-11-21">Nov. 21, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 715</ref>, 718; <ref>Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title V, § 521(a)</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 755</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title V, § 553</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 823</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title V</ref>, §§ 563, 564(a), <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2138</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title V</ref>, §§ 552(b)(1), 553(b)(1), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1770</ref>, 1772; <ref>Pub. L. 117–328, div. U, title II, § 212</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 5453</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1145.</num>
<heading> Health benefits</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transitional Health Care</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> For the time period described in paragraph (4), a member of the armed forces who is separated from active service as described in paragraph (2) (and the dependents of the member) shall be entitled to receive—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> except as provided in paragraph (3), medical and dental care under <ref>section 1076 of this title</ref> in the same manner as a dependent described in subsection (a)(2) of such section; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> health benefits contracted under the authority of <ref>section 1079(a) of this title</ref> and subject to the same rates and conditions as apply to persons covered under that section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> This subsection applies to the following members of the armed forces:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A member who is involuntarily separated from active duty.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A member of a reserve component who is separated from active duty to which called or ordered under <ref>section 12304b of this title</ref> or a provision of law referred to in <ref>section 101(a)(13)(B) of this title</ref> if the active duty is active duty for a period of more than 30 days.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> A member who is separated from active duty for which the member is involuntarily retained under <ref>section 12305 of this title</ref> in support of a contingency operation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> A member who is separated from active duty served pursuant to a voluntary agreement of the member to remain on active duty for a period of less than one year in support of a contingency operation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> A member who receives a sole survivorship discharge (as defined in <ref>section 1174(i) of this title</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> A member who is separated from active duty who agrees to become a member of the Selected Reserve of the Ready Reserve of a reserve component.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> A member of the National Guard who is separated from full-time National Guard Duty to which called or ordered under <ref>section 502(f) of title 32</ref> for a period of active service of more than 30 days to perform duties that are authorized by the President or the Secretary of Defense for the purpose of responding to a national emergency declared by Congress or the President and supported by Federal funds.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> In the case of a member described in subparagraph (B) or (G) of paragraph (2), the dental care to which the member is entitled under this subsection shall be the dental care to which a member of the uniformed services on active duty for more than 30 days is entitled under <ref>section 1074 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraph (7), transitional health care for a member under subsection (a) shall be available for 180 days beginning on the date on which the member is separated from active service. For purposes of the preceding sentence, in the case of a member on active service as described in subparagraph (B), (C), (D), or (G) of paragraph (2) who, without a break in service, is extended on active service for any reason, the 180-day period shall begin on the date on which the member is separated from such extended active service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Except as provided in subparagraph (D), the Secretary concerned shall require a member of the armed forces scheduled to be separated from active service as described in paragraph (2) to undergo a physical examination and a mental health assessment conducted pursuant to <ref>section 1074n of this title</ref> immediately before that separation. The physical examination shall be conducted in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding subparagraph (A), if a member of the armed forces scheduled to be separated from active service as described in paragraph (2) has otherwise undergone a physical examination within 12 months before the scheduled date of separation from active service, the requirement for a physical examination under subparagraph (A) may be waived in accordance with regulations prescribed under this paragraph. Such regulations shall require that such a waiver may be granted only with the consent of the member and with the concurrence of the member’s unit commander.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary concerned shall ensure that each physical examination of a member under subparagraph (A) includes an assessment of whether the member was—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> based or stationed at a location where an open burn pit, as defined in subsection (c) of section 201 of the Dignified Burial and Other Veterans’ Benefits Improvement Act of 2012 (<ref>Public Law 112–260</ref>; <ref>38 U.S.C. 527</ref> note), was used; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> exposed to toxic airborne chemicals or other airborne contaminants, including any information recorded as part of the registry established by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs under such section 201.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The requirement for a physical examination and mental health assessment under subparagraph (A) shall not apply with respect to a member of a reserve component described in paragraph (2)(B) unless the member is retiring, or being discharged or dismissed, from the armed forces.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall, in consultation with the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, ensure that appropriate actions are taken to assist a member of the armed forces who, as a result of a medical examination under paragraph (5), receives an indication for a referral for follow up treatment from the health care provider who performs the examination.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> Assistance provided to a member under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> Information regarding, and any appropriate referral for, the care, treatment, and other services that the Secretary of Veterans Affairs may provide to such member under any other provision of law, including—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> clinical services, including counseling and treatment for post-traumatic stress disorder and other mental health conditions; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> any other care, treatment, and services.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Information on the private sector sources of treatment that are available to the member in the member’s community.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Assistance to enroll in the health care system of the Department of Veterans Affairs for health care benefits for which the member is eligible under laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(7)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A member who has a medical condition relating to active service that warrants further medical care that has been identified during the member’s 180-day transition period, which condition can be resolved within 180 days as determined by a Department of Defense physician, shall be entitled to receive medical and dental care for that medical condition, and that medical condition only, as if the member were a member of the armed forces on active service for 180 days following the diagnosis of the condition.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned shall ensure that the Defense Enrollment and Eligibility Reporting System (DEERS) is continually updated in order to reflect the continuing entitlement of members covered by subparagraph (A) to the medical and dental care referred to in that subparagraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Conversion Health Policies</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall inform each member referred to in subsection (a) before the date of the member’s discharge or release from active service of the availability for purchase by the member of a conversion health policy for the member and the dependents of that member. A conversion health policy offered under this paragraph shall provide coverage for not less than an 18-month period.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> If a member referred to in subsection (a) purchases a conversion health policy during the period applicable to the member (or within a reasonable time after that period as prescribed by the Secretary of Defense), the Secretary shall provide health care, or pay the costs of health care provided, to the member and the dependents of the member—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> during the 18-month period beginning on the date on which coverage under the conversion health policy begins; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for a condition (including pregnancy) that exists on such date and for which care is not provided under the policy solely on the grounds that the condition is a preexisting condition.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may arrange for the provision of health care described in paragraph (2) through a contract with the insurer offering the conversion health policy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> If the Secretary of Defense is unable, within a reasonable time, to enter into a contract with a private insurer to provide the conversion health policy required under paragraph (1) at a rate not to exceed the payment required under <ref>section 8905a(d)(1)(A) of title 5</ref> for comparable coverage, the Secretary shall offer such a policy under the Civilian Health and Medical Program of the Uniformed Services. Subject to paragraph (5), a member purchasing a policy from the Secretary shall be required to pay into the Military Health Care Account or other appropriate account an amount equal to the sum of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the individual and Government contributions which would be required in the case of a person enrolled in a health benefits plan contracted for under <ref>section 1079 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an amount necessary for administrative expenses, but not to exceed two percent of the amount under subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The amount paid by a member who purchases a conversion health policy from the Secretary of Defense under paragraph (4) may not exceed the payment required under <ref>section 8905a(d)(1)(A) of title 5</ref> for comparable coverage.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> In order to reduce premiums required under paragraph (4), the Secretary of Defense may offer a conversion health policy that, with respect to mental health services, offers reduced coverage and increased cost-sharing by the purchaser.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Health Care For Certain Separated Members Not Otherwise Eligible</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Consistent with the authority of the Secretary concerned to designate certain classes of persons as eligible to receive health care at a military medical facility, the Secretary concerned should consider authorizing, on an individual basis in cases of hardship, the provision of that care for a member who is separated from the armed forces, and is ineligible for transitional health care under subsection (a) or does not obtain a conversion health policy (or a dependent of the member).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned shall give special consideration to requests for such care in cases in which the condition for which treatment is required was incurred or aggravated by the member or the dependent before the date of the separation of the member, particularly if the condition is a result of the particular circumstances of the service of the member.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Physical Examinations for Certain Members of a Reserve Component</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary concerned shall provide a physical examination pursuant to subsection (a)(5) to each member of a reserve component who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> during the two-year period before the date on which the member is scheduled to be separated from the armed forces served on active service in support of a contingency operation for a period of more than 30 days;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> will not otherwise receive such an examination under such subsection; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> elects to receive such a physical examination.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary concerned shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> provide the physical examination under paragraph (1) to a member during the 90-day period before the date on which the member is scheduled to be separated from the armed forces; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> issue orders to such a member to receive such physical examination.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A member may not be entitled to health care benefits pursuant to subsection (a), (b), or (c) solely by reason of being provided a physical examination under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> In providing to a member a physical examination under paragraph (1), the Secretary concerned shall provide to the member a record of the physical examination.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “conversion health policy” means a health insurance policy with a private insurer, developed through negotiations between the Secretary of Defense and a private insurer, that is available for purchase by or for the use of a person who is no longer a member of the armed forces or a covered beneficiary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Coast Guard</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall implement this section for the members of the Coast Guard and their dependents when the Coast Guard is not operating as a service in the Navy.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title V, § 502(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1555</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. D, title XLIV, § 4407(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2707</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title V, § 561(i)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1668</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title V, § 542(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2768</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title V, § 561(h)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2026</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title V, § 571(h)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–134; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title VII, § 736(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1172</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–296, title XVII, § 1704(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2314</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title VII, § 706(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2585</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title VII, § 706(a)(1)</ref>, (3), (b), <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1983</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title VII, § 749</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3364</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title XVI, § 1637</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 464</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–317, § 4</ref>, <date date="2008-08-29">Aug. 29, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 3528</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title VII, § 734(a), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4513</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title VII, § 703</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2373</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title VII, § 706</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1474</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title X, § 1076(f)(15)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1952</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title V, § 511(b)</ref>, title VII, §§ 705, 706(a), <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1376</ref>, 1435, 1436; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title VII, § 704(b)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1438</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title VII, § 717</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1789</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title VII, § 702</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2647</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1146.</num>
<heading> Commissary and exchange benefits</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Members Involuntarily Separated From Active Duty</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations to allow a member of the armed forces who is involuntarily separated from active duty during the period beginning on <date date="2007-10-01">October 1, 2007</date>, and ending on <date date="2018-12-31">December 31, 2018</date>, to continue to use commissary and exchange stores during the two-year period beginning on the date of the involuntary separation of the member in the same manner as a member on active duty. The Secretary concerned shall implement this provision for Coast Guard members involuntarily separated during the same period.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Members Involuntarily Separated From Selected Reserve</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations to allow a member of the Selected Reserve of the Ready Reserve who is involuntarily separated from the Selected Reserve as a result of the exercise of the force shaping authority of the Secretary concerned under <ref>section 647 of this title</ref> or other force shaping authority during the period beginning on <date date="2007-10-01">October 1, 2007</date>, and ending on <date date="2018-12-31">December 31, 2018</date>, to continue to use commissary and exchange stores during the two-year period beginning on the date of the involuntary separation of the member in the same manner as a member on active duty. The Secretary concerned shall implement this provision for Coast Guard members involuntarily separated during the same period when the Coast Guard is not operating as a service in the Navy.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Members Receiving Sole Survivorship Discharge</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A member of the armed forces who receives a sole survivorship discharge (as defined in <ref>section 1174(i) of this title</ref>) is entitled to continue to use commissary and exchange stores and morale, welfare, and recreational facilities in the same manner as a member on active duty during the two-year period beginning on the later of the following dates:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The date of the separation of the member.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The date on which the member is first notified of the member’s entitlement to benefits under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Emergency Response Providers During a Declared Major Disaster or Emergency</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may prescribe regulations to allow an emergency response provider (as that term is defined in section 2 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<ref>Public Law 107–296</ref>; <ref>6 U.S.C. 101</ref>)) to use a mobile commissary or exchange store deployed to an area covered by a declaration of a major disaster or emergency under section 401 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 5170</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title V, § 502(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1556</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title V, § 561(i)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1668</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title V, § 542(a)(5)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2768</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title V, § 561(i)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2026</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title V, § 571(i)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–135; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title VI, § 651</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 162</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–317, § 5</ref>, <date date="2008-08-29">Aug. 29, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 3528</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title X, § 1075(b)(16)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4369</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title VI, § 631</ref>, title X, § 1076(f)(16), <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1781</ref>, 1952; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title VI, § 632</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3682</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1147.</num>
<heading> Use of military family housing</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transition for Involuntarily Separated Members</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of a military department may, pursuant to regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, permit individuals who are involuntarily separated during the period beginning on <date date="2012-10-01">October 1, 2012</date>, and ending on <date date="2018-12-31">December 31, 2018</date>, to continue for not more than 180 days after the date of such separation to reside (along with other members of the individual’s household) in military family housing provided or leased by the Department of Defense to such individual as a member of the armed forces.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned may prescribe regulations to permit members of the Coast Guard who are involuntarily separated during the period beginning on <date date="2012-10-01">October 1, 2012</date>, and ending on <date date="2018-12-31">December 31, 2018</date>, to continue for not more than 180 days after the date of such separation to reside (along with others of the member’s household) in military family housing provided or leased by the Coast Guard to the individual as a member of the armed forces.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rental Charges</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary concerned, pursuant to such regulations, shall require a reasonable rental charge for the continued use of military family housing under subsection (a), except that such Secretary may waive all or any portion of such charge in any case of hardship.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">No Transitional Basic Allowance for Housing</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section shall be construed to authorize the Secretary concerned to continue to provide for any period of time to an individual who is involuntarily separated all or any portion of a basic allowance for housing to which the individual was entitled under <ref>section 403 of title 37</ref> immediately before being involuntarily separated, even in cases in which the individual or members of the individual’s household continue to reside after the separation in a housing unit acquired or constructed under the alternative authority of subchapter IV of chapter 169 of this title that is not owned or leased by the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title V, § 502(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1556</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title V, § 561(i)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1668</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title V, § 542(a)(6)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2768</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title V, § 561(j)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2026</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title V, § 571(j)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–135; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title VI, § 632</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1782</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1148.</num>
<heading> Relocation assistance for personnel overseas</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Homeland Security shall develop a program specifically to assist members of the armed forces stationed overseas who are preparing for discharge or release from active duty, and the dependents of such members, in readjusting to civilian life. The program shall focus on the special needs and requirements of such members and dependents due to their overseas locations and shall include, to the maximum extent possible, computerized job relocation assistance and job search information.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title V, § 502(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1556</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title V, § 542(a)(7)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2768</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–296, title XVII, § 1704(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2314</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1149.</num>
<heading> Excess leave and permissive temporary duty</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of Homeland Security with respect to the Coast Guard when it is not operating as a service in the Navy, the Secretary concerned shall grant a member of the armed forces who is to be involuntarily separated such excess leave (for a period not in excess of 30 days), or such permissive temporary duty (for a period not in excess of 10 days), as the member requires in order to facilitate the member’s carrying out necessary relocation activities (such as job search and residence search activities), unless to do so would interfere with military missions.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title V, § 502(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1557</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title V, § 542(a)(8)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2768</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–296, title XVII, § 1704(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2314</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title X, § 1076(f)(17)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1952</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1150.</num>
<heading> Affiliation with Guard and Reserve units: waiver of certain limitations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Preference for Certain Persons</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A person who is separated from the armed forces during the period beginning on <date date="1990-10-01">October 1, 1990</date>, and ending on <date date="2001-12-31">December 31, 2001</date>, and who applies to become a member of a National Guard or Reserve unit within one year after the date of such separation shall be given preference over other equally qualified applicants for existing or projected vacancies within the unit to which the member applies.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limited Waiver of Strength Limitations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, a person covered by subsection (a) who enters a National Guard or Reserve unit pursuant to an application described in such subsection may be retained in that unit for up to three years without regard to reserve-component strength limitations so long as the individual maintains good standing in that unit.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Coast Guard</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section shall apply to the Coast Guard in the same manner and to the same extent as it applies to the Department of Defense. The Secretary of Homeland Security shall prescribe regulations to implement this section for the Coast Guard when it is not operating as a service in the Navy.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title V, § 502(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1557</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title V, § 514</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2406</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title V, § 561(j)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1668</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title V, § 542(a)(9)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2768</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title V, § 561(p)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2027</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title V, § 571(<i>o</i>)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–135; <ref>Pub. L. 107–296, title XVII, § 1704(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2314</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title X, § 1076(f)(18)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1952</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1151.</num>
<heading> Retention of assistive technology and services provided before separation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A member of the armed forces who is provided an assistive technology or assistive technology device for a severe or debilitating illness or injury incurred or aggravated by such member while on active duty may, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, be authorized to retain such assistive technology or assistive technology device upon the separation of the member from active service.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the terms “assistive technology” and “assistive technology device” have the meaning given those terms in section 3 of the Assistive Technology Act of 1998 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 3002</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title V, § 561(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2219</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1152.</num>
<heading> Assistance to eligible members and former members to obtain employment with law enforcement agencies</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Placement Program</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense, and the Secretary of Homeland Security with respect to the Coast Guard, may enter into an agreement with the Attorney General to establish or participate in a program to assist eligible members and former members of the armed forces to obtain employment as law enforcement officers with eligible law enforcement agencies following the discharge or release of such members or former members from active duty. Eligible law enforcement agencies shall consist of State law enforcement agencies, local law enforcement agencies, and Indian tribes that perform law enforcement functions (as determined by the Secretary of the Interior).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Eligible Members</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any individual who, during the 6-year period beginning on <date date="1993-10-01">October 1, 1993</date>, is a member of the armed forces and is separated with an honorable discharge or is released from service on active duty characterized as honorable by the Secretary concerned shall be eligible to participate in a program covered by an agreement referred to in subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Selection</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In the selection of applicants for participation in a program covered by an agreement referred to in subsection (a), preference shall be given to a member or former member who—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> is selected for involuntary separation, is approved for separation under section 1174a or 1175 of this title, or retires pursuant to the authority provided in section 4403 of the Defense Conversion, Reinvestment, and Transition Assistance Act of 1992 (division D of <ref>Public Law 102–484</ref>; <ref>10 U.S.C. 1293</ref> note); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> has a military occupational specialty, training, or experience related to law enforcement (such as service as a member of the military police) or satisfies such other criteria for selection as the Secretary, the Attorney General, or a participating eligible law enforcement agency prescribed in accordance with the agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Grants To Facilitate Employment</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense, and the Secretary of Homeland Security with respect to the Coast Guard, may provide funds to the Attorney General for grants under this section to reimburse participating eligible law enforcement agencies for costs, including salary and fringe benefits, of employing members or former members pursuant to a program referred to in subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> No grant with respect to an eligible member or former member may exceed a total of $50,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Any grant with respect to an eligible member or former member shall be disbursed within 5 years after the date of the placement of a member or former member with a participating eligible law enforcement agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Preference in awarding grants through existing law enforcement hiring programs shall be given to State or local law enforcement agencies or Indian tribes that agree to hire eligible members and former members.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Administrative Expenses</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Ten percent of the amount, if any, appropriated for a fiscal year to carry out the program established pursuant to subsection (a) may be used to administer the program.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirement for Appropriation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No person may be selected to participate in the program established pursuant to subsection (a) unless a sufficient amount of appropriated funds is available at the time of the selection to satisfy the obligations to be incurred by the United States under an agreement referred to in subsection (a) that applies with respect to the person.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority To Expand Placement To Include Firefighters</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary may expand the placement activities authorized by subsection (a) to include the placement of eligible members and former members and eligible civilian employees of the Department of Defense as firefighters or members of rescue squads or ambulance crews with public fire departments.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The expansion authorized by this subsection may be made through a program covered by an agreement referred to in subsection (a), if feasible, or in such other manner as the Secretary considers appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A civilian employee of the Department of Defense shall be eligible to participate in the expanded placement activities authorized under this subsection if the employee, during the six-year period beginning <date date="1993-10-01">October 1, 1993</date>, is terminated from such employment as a result of reductions in defense spending or the closure or realignment of a military installation, as determined by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title XIII, § 1332(a)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1793</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title V, § 543(d)</ref>, title XI, § 1132(a)(1), <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2771</ref>, 2872; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1503(a)(11)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 511</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title V, § 575</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2535</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title X, § 1073(a)(20)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1901</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–296, title XVII, § 1704(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2314</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1153.</num>
<heading> Assistance to separated members to obtain employment with health care providers</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Placement Program</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense, and the Secretary of Homeland Security with respect to the Coast Guard, may establish a program to assist eligible members of the armed forces to obtain employment with health care providers upon their discharge or release from active duty.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Eligible Members</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Except as provided in paragraph (2), a member shall be eligible for selection to participate in the program established under subsection (a) if the member—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is selected for involuntary separation, is approved for separation under section 1174a or 1175 of this title, or retires pursuant to the authority provided in section 4403 of the Defense Conversion, Reinvestment, and Transition Assistance Act of 1992 (division D of <ref>Public Law 102–484</ref>; <ref>10 U.S.C. 1293</ref> note) during the six-year period beginning on <date date="1993-10-01">October 1, 1993</date>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> has received an associate degree, baccalaureate, or advanced degree from an accredited institution of higher education or a junior or community college; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> has a military occupational specialty, training, or experience related to health care, is likely to be able to obtain such training in a short period of time (as determined by the Secretary concerned), or satisfies such other criteria for selection as the Secretary concerned may prescribe.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> For purposes of this section, a former member of the armed forces who did not meet the minimum educational qualification criterion set forth in paragraph (1)(B) for placement assistance before discharge or release from active duty shall be considered to be a member satisfying such educational qualification criterion upon satisfying that criterion within five years after discharge or release from active duty.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A member who is discharged or released from service under other than honorable conditions shall not be eligible to participate in the program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Selection of Participants</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense, and the Secretary of Homeland Security with respect to the Coast Guard, shall select members to participate in the program established under subsection (a) on the basis of applications submitted to the Secretary concerned not later than one year after the date of the discharge or release of the members from active duty or, in the case of an applicant becoming educationally qualified for teacher placement assistance in accordance with subsection (b)(2), not later than one year after the date on which the applicant becomes educationally qualified. An application shall be in such form and contain such information as the Secretaries may require.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense, and the Secretary of Homeland Security with respect to the Coast Guard, may not select a member to participate in the program unless the Secretary concerned has sufficient appropriations for the placement program available at the time of the selection to satisfy the obligations to be incurred by the United States under subsection (d) with respect to that member.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Secretaries shall provide under the program for identifying, during each fiscal year in the period referred to in subsection (b)(1)(A), noncommissioned officers who, on or before the end of such fiscal year, will have completed 10 or more years of continuous active duty, who have the potential to perform competently in employment positions with health care providers, but who do not satisfy the minimum educational qualification criterion under subsection (b)(1)(B) for placement assistance.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Secretaries shall inform noncommissioned officers identified under subparagraph (A) of the opportunity to qualify in accordance with subsection (b)(2) for placement assistance under the program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Grants to Facilitate Employment</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Homeland Security may enter into an agreement with a health care provider to assist eligible members selected under subsection (c) to obtain suitable employment with the health care provider. Under such an agreement, a health care provider shall agree to employ a participant in the program on a full-time basis for at least five years.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Under an agreement referred to in paragraph (1), the Secretary concerned shall agree to pay to the health care provider involved an amount based upon the basic salary paid by the health care provider to the participant. The rate of payment by the Secretary concerned shall be as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> For the first year of employment, 50 percent of the basic salary, except that the payment may not exceed $25,000.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> For the second year of employment, 40 percent of the basic salary, except that the payment may not exceed $10,000.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> For the third year of employment, 30 percent of the basic salary, except that the payment may not exceed $7,500.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> For the fourth year of employment, 20 percent of the basic salary, except that the payment may not exceed $5,000.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> For the fifth year of employment, 10 percent of the basic salary, except that the payment may not exceed $2,500.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Payments required under paragraph (2) may be made by the Secretary concerned in such installments as the Secretary concerned may determine.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> If a participant who is placed under this program leaves the employment of the health care provider before the end of the five years of required employment service, the provider shall reimburse the Secretary concerned in an amount that bears the same ratio to the total amount already paid under the agreement as the unserved portion bears to the five years of required service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned may not make a grant under this subsection to a health care provider if the Secretary concerned determines that the provider terminated the employment of another employee in order to fill the vacancy so created with a participant in this program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Agreements With States</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In addition to the agreements referred to in subsection (d)(1), the Secretary of Defense, and the Secretary of Homeland Security with respect to the Coast Guard, may enter into an agreement directly with a State to allow the State to arrange the placement of participants in the program with health care providers. Paragraphs (2) through (5) of subsection (d) shall apply with respect to any placement made through such an agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned may reserve up to 10 percent of the funds made available to carry out the program for a fiscal year for the placement of participants through agreements entered into under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “State” includes the District of Columbia, American Samoa, the Federated States of Micronesia, Guam, the Republic of the Marshall Islands, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Palau, and the Virgin Islands.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title XIII, § 1332(b)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1795</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title V, § 543(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2771</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–296, title XVII, § 1704(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2314</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1154.</num>
<heading> Assistance to eligible members and former members to obtain employment as teachers: Troops-to-Teachers Program</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Charter school</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “charter school” has the meaning given that term in section 4310 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Eligible school</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “eligible school” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> a public school, including a charter school, at which—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> at least 30 percent of the students enrolled in the school are from families with incomes below 185 percent of poverty level (as defined by the Office of Management and Budget and revised at least annually in accordance with section 9(b)(1) of the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 1758(b)(1)</ref>) applicable to a family of the size involved; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> at least 13 percent of the students enrolled in the school qualify for assistance under part B of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (<ref>20 U.S.C. 1411</ref> et seq.);</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a Bureau-funded school as defined in section 1141(3) of the Education Amendments of 1978 (<ref>25 U.S.C. 2021(3)</ref>); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a Job Corps center as defined in section 147 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<ref>29 U.S.C. 3197</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">High-need school</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “high-need school” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an elementary or middle school in which at least 50 percent of the enrolled students are children from low-income families, based on the number of children eligible for free and reduced priced lunches under the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 1751</ref> et seq.), the number of children in families receiving assistance under the State program funded under part A of title IV of the Social Security Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 601</ref> et seq.), the number of children eligible to receive medical assistance under the Medicaid program, or a composite of these indicators;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a high school in which at least 40 percent of enrolled students are children from low-income families, which may be calculated using comparable data from feeder schools;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a school that is in a local educational agency that is eligible under section 5211(b) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a Job Corps center as defined in section 147 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<ref>29 U.S.C. 3197</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Member of the armed forces</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “member of the armed forces” includes a retired or former member of the armed forces.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Participant</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “participant” means an eligible member of the armed forces selected to participate in the Program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Program</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “Program” means the Troops-to-Teachers Program authorized by this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Secretary</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Additional terms</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The terms “elementary school”, “local educational agency”, “secondary school”, and “State” have the meanings given those terms in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Program Authorization</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense shall carry out a Troops-to-Teachers Program—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to assist eligible members of the armed forces described in subsection (d) to meet the requirements necessary to become a teacher in a school described in paragraph (2); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> to facilitate the employment of such members—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> by local educational agencies or charter schools that the Secretary of Education identifies as—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> receiving grants under part A of title I of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<ref>20 U.S.C. 6301</ref> et seq.) as a result of having within their jurisdictions concentrations of children from low-income families; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> experiencing a shortage of teachers, in particular a shortage of science, mathematics, special education, foreign language, or career or technical teachers;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in elementary schools or secondary schools, or as career or technical teachers; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> as administrators and instructors of the Junior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps under <ref>section 2031(d) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Counseling and Referral Services</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may provide counseling and referral services to members of the armed forces who do not meet the eligibility criteria described in subsection (d), including the education qualification requirements under paragraph (3)(B) of such subsection.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Eligibility and Application Process</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Eligible members</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The following members of the armed forces are eligible for selection to participate in the Program:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> Any member who—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> on or after <date date="1999-10-01">October 1, 1999</date>, becomes entitled to retired or retainer pay under this title or title 14;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> has an approved date of retirement that is within one year after the date on which the member submits an application to participate in the Program; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> has been transferred to the Retired Reserve.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> Any member who, on or after <date date="2002-01-08">January 8, 2002</date>—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> is separated or released from active duty after four or more years of continuous active duty immediately before the separation or release; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> has completed a total of at least six years of active duty service, six years of service computed under <ref>section 12732 of this title</ref>, or six years of any combination of such service; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> executes a reserve commitment agreement for a period of not less than three years under paragraph (5)(B).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Any member who, on or after <date date="2002-01-08">January 8, 2002</date>, is retired or separated for physical disability under chapter 61 of this title.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Submission of applications</inline>.—</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Selection of eligible members of the armed forces to participate in the Program shall be made on the basis of applications submitted to the Secretary within the time periods specified in subparagraph (B). An application shall be in such form and contain such information as the Secretary may require.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> In the case of an eligible member of the armed forces described in subparagraph (A)(i), (A)(iii), (B), or (C) of paragraph (1), an application shall be considered to be submitted on a timely basis if the application is submitted not later than three years after the date on which the member is retired, transferred to the Retired Reserve, or separated or released from active duty, whichever applies to the member.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Selection criteria; educational background requirements; honorable service requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall prescribe the criteria to be used to select eligible members of the armed forces to participate in the Program.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> If a member of the armed forces is applying for the Program to receive assistance for placement as an elementary school or secondary school teacher, the Secretary shall require the member to have received a baccalaureate or advanced degree from an accredited institution of higher education.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> If a member of the armed forces is applying for the Program to receive assistance for placement as a career or technical teacher, the Secretary shall require the member—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> to have received the equivalent of one year of college from an accredited institution of higher education or the equivalent in military education and training as certified by the Department of Defense; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> to otherwise meet the certification or licensing requirements for a career or technical teacher in the State in which the member seeks assistance for placement under the Program.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> A member of the armed forces is eligible to participate in the Program only if the member’s last period of service in the armed forces was honorable, as characterized by the Secretary concerned. A member selected to participate in the Program before the retirement of the member, the transfer of the member to the Retired Reserve, or the separation or release of the member from active duty may continue to participate in the Program after the retirement, transfer, separation, or release only if the member’s last period of service is characterized as honorable by the Secretary concerned.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Selection priorities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In selecting eligible members of the armed forces to receive assistance under the Program, the Secretary—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> shall give priority to members who—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> have educational or military experience in science, mathematics, special education, foreign language, or career or technical subjects; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> agree to seek employment as science, mathematics, foreign language, or special education teachers in elementary schools or secondary schools or Job Corps centers or in other schools under the jurisdiction of a local educational agency; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> may give priority to members who agree to seek employment in a high-need school.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Other conditions on selection</inline>.—</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Subject to subsection (i), the Secretary may not select an eligible member of the armed forces to participate in the Program and receive financial assistance unless the Secretary has sufficient appropriations for the Program available at the time of the selection to satisfy the obligations to be incurred by the United States under subsection (e) with respect to the member.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Secretary may not select an eligible member of the armed forces described in paragraph (1)(B)(i) to participate in the Program and receive financial assistance under subsection (e) unless the member executes a written agreement to serve as a member of the Selected Reserve of a reserve component of the armed forces for a period of not less than three years.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Participation Agreement and Financial Assistance</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Participation agreement</inline>.—</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> An eligible member of the armed forces selected to participate in the Program under subsection (b) and to receive financial assistance under this subsection shall be required to enter into an agreement with the Secretary in which the member agrees—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> within such time as the Secretary may require, to meet the requirements necessary to become a teacher in a school described in subsection (b)(2); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> to accept an offer of full-time employment as an elementary school teacher, secondary school teacher, or career or technical teacher for not less than three school years in an eligible school to begin the school year after obtaining that certification or licensing.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Secretary may waive the three-year commitment described in subparagraph (A)(ii) for a participant if the Secretary determines such waiver to be appropriate. If the Secretary provides the waiver, the participant shall not be considered to be in violation of the agreement and shall not be required to provide reimbursement under subsection (f), for failure to meet the three-year commitment.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Violation of participation agreement; exceptions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A participant shall not be considered to be in violation of the participation agreement entered into under paragraph (1) during any period in which the participant—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is pursuing a full-time course of study related to the field of teaching at an institution of higher education;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is serving on active duty as a member of the armed forces;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> is temporarily totally disabled for a period of time not to exceed three years as established by sworn affidavit of a qualified physician;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> is unable to secure employment for a period not to exceed 12 months by reason of the care required by a spouse who is disabled;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> is unable to find full-time employment as a teacher in an eligible elementary school or secondary school or Job Corps center or as a career or technical teacher for a single period not to exceed 27 months; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> satisfies the provisions of additional reimbursement exceptions that may be prescribed by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Stipend and bonus for participants</inline>.—</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Subject to subparagraph (C), the Secretary may pay to a participant a stipend to cover expenses incurred by the participant to obtain the required educational level, certification, or licensing. Such stipend may not exceed $5,000 and may vary by participant.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Subject to subparagraph (C), the Secretary may pay a bonus to a participant who agrees in the participation agreement under paragraph (1) to accept full-time employment as an elementary school teacher, secondary school teacher, or career or technical teacher for not less than three school years in an eligible school.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The amount of the bonus may not exceed $5,000, unless the eligible school is a high-need school, in which case the amount of the bonus may not exceed $10,000. Within such limits, the bonus may vary by participant and may take into account the priority placements as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The total number of stipends that may be paid under subparagraph (A) in any fiscal year may not exceed 3,000.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The total number of bonuses that may be paid under subparagraph (B) in any fiscal year may not exceed 3,000.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> The combination of a stipend under subparagraph (A) and a bonus under subparagraph (B) for any one participant may not exceed $10,000.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Treatment of stipend and bonus</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A stipend or bonus paid under this subsection to a participant shall be taken into account in determining the eligibility of the participant for Federal student financial assistance provided under title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<ref>20 U.S.C. 1070</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Reimbursement Under Certain Circumstances.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reimbursement required</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A participant who is paid a stipend or bonus under this subsection shall be subject to the repayment provisions of <ref>section 373 of title 37</ref> under the following circumstances:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The participant fails to meet the requirements necessary to become a teacher in a school described in subsection (b)(2) or to obtain employment as an elementary school teacher, secondary school teacher, or career or technical teacher as required by the participation agreement under subsection (e)(1).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The participant voluntarily leaves, or is terminated for cause from, employment as an elementary school teacher, secondary school teacher, or career or technical teacher during the three years of required service in violation of the participation agreement.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The participant executed a written agreement with the Secretary concerned under subsection (d)(5)(B) to serve as a member of a reserve component of the armed forces for a period of three years and fails to complete the required term of service.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Amount of reimbursement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A participant required to reimburse the Secretary for a stipend or bonus paid to the participant under subsection (e) shall pay an amount that bears the same ratio to the amount of the stipend or bonus as the unserved portion of required service bears to the three years of required service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Interest</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any amount owed by a participant under this subsection shall bear interest at the rate equal to the highest rate being paid by the United States on the day on which the reimbursement is determined to be due for securities having maturities of 90 days or less and shall accrue from the day on which the participant is first notified of the amount due.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading> Exceptions to reimbursement requirement.—</heading>
<content>A participant shall be excused from reimbursement under this subsection if the participant becomes permanently totally disabled as established by sworn affidavit of a qualified physician. The Secretary may also waive the reimbursement in cases of extreme hardship to the participant, as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Relationship to Educational Assistance Under Montgomery GI Bill</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in subsection (e)(3)(C)(iii), the receipt by a participant of a stipend or bonus under subsection (e) shall not reduce or otherwise affect the entitlement of the participant to any benefits under chapter 30 or 33 of title 38 or chapter 1606 of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Participation by States.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Discharge of state activities through consortia of states</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may permit States participating in the Program to carry out activities authorized for such States under the Program through one or more consortia of such States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Assistance to states</inline>.—</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Subject to subparagraph (B), the Secretary may make grants to States participating in the Program, or to consortia of such States, in order to permit such States or consortia of States to operate offices for purposes of recruiting eligible members of the armed forces for participation in the Program and facilitating the employment of participants as elementary school teachers, secondary school teachers, and career or technical teachers.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The total amount of grants made under subparagraph (A) in any fiscal year may not exceed $5,000,000.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Report</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Not later than <date date="2022-12-01">December 1, 2022</date>, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the Program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The report required under paragraph (1) shall include the following elements:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The total cost of the Program for the most recent fiscal year.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The total number of teachers placed during such fiscal year and the locations of such placements.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> An assessment of the STEM backgrounds of the teachers placed, the number of placements in high-need schools, and any other metric or information the Secretary considers appropriate to illustrate the cost and benefits of the program to members of the armed forces, veterans, and local educational agencies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> In this subsection, the term “appropriate congressional committees” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Help, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Education and Labor of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Total Fiscal-year Obligations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The total amount obligated by the Secretary under the Program for any fiscal year may not exceed $15,000,000.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(k)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Sunset</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Program shall terminate on <date date="2029-07-01">July 1, 2029</date>, with respect to the selection of new participants for the program. Participants in the Program as of that date may complete their program, and remain eligible for benefits under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title V, § 541(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1729</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title X, § 1071(f)(14)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3510</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–95, title IX, § 9215(uuu)(2)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-10">Dec. 10, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 2190</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title V, § 554</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1773</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title V, § 551</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1734</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title V</ref>, §§ 573, 574, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 276</ref>, 277; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title V, § 572</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1909</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1155.</num>
<heading> Statement of benefits</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Before Separation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not later than 30 days before a member retires, is released, is discharged, or otherwise separates from the armed forces (or as soon as is practicable in the case of an unanticipated separation), the Secretary concerned shall provide that member with a current assessment of all benefits to which that member may be entitled under laws administered by—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Defense; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Veterans Affairs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Statement for Reserves</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary concerned shall provide a member of a reserve component with a current assessment of benefits described in subsection (a) upon release of that member from active duty.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title V, § 522(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1756</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>